<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<!-- DR edited -->

<string id="descr_bar_crazy_veterans_quest">
    <text>Barkeep: 'Duty values its reputation. So they want to do everything quietly. If your tough enough to destroy the boss named Lucky and then bring the PDA as evidence.'</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_bar_dolg_community_quest">
    <text>In order to join 'Duty' you must get the approval of one of the most respected fighters in the group. And also to prove to the leader of 'Duty' that you deserve to be one of them.</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_bar_dolg_svoboda_ambush_quest">
    <text>Barkeep: 'Your task - the elimination of Tyran who is the leader of a group of mercenaries. Detachment of mercenaries burst in Wild Territory, and camped at a construction site. Be careful there are some militants waiting in ambush at the approaches to the construction site. As soon as you bring me Tyran'a PDA you'll get your reward.'</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_bar_dolg_svoboda_leader_kill_quest">
    <text>General Voronin: 'The war with Freedom is coming to an end. Strelok you contributed to the cause, and now I want to put an end to this war. I want you to destroy the leader of Freedom.'</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_bar_dolg_test_quest">
    <text>Captain Ivantsov, '... before drawing conclusions, pass a little test. You've got to get the archive folder from an abandoned building across the street. Simply enter and take the folder and bring it to me. What could be simpler, right? When I have the folder I will then decide if you deserve to join Duty.'</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_bar_hunter_rifle">
    <text>Hunter: 'Bring me my family gun. I lost it near the home of the bloodsuckers. I'll put the coordinates on your PDA. And be careful out there, these creatures are very nasty.'</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_bar_kill_professor">
		<text>Wolfhound: 'We've got a little hunt going on here. We pinned the scientists in over there behind the chopper. My boys are putting some fire down on them from time to time to make sure they don't escape. Join in, we're about to go in and finish 'em off. If you help us I'll give you the scientists' suit... we found it in the chopper we took down. Your target is professor Kruglov. Kill him or he'll run away during the shootout, I know his type. If you kill him, the suit is yours, if you don't, you don't get jack.'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_bar_radar_deactivate">
		<text>Barkeep: 'You have the protective prototype to cover yourself against the Brain Scorcher. I know the coordinates of the bunker. Don't forget that the prototype can't protect against the emission forever, so you must get to the bunker under the antennae and shut down the Scorcher.'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_bar_resque_information">
		<text>Kruglov: 'Stalker help me! We were attacked by Mercs and half of our team is dead. Help us and you won't regret it. Be careful there are about fifteen of them. But we don't know for sure'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_bar_resque_information_2">
		<text>Kruglov: 'We were returning from Yantar when the Mercs shot us down. People say that they needed information, but I know better, they'll shoot us all. Take me out to Yantar and I'll tell you what I know about your Brain Scorcher, and Barkeep will pay you well for it. I am a lousy fighter, but I do know the way, so I'll lead and you cover us along the way.'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_bar_x16_documents">
		<text>Barkeep: 'You need to get through to the scientists and find out where Lab X-16 is located to find the missing documents.'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_after_agroprom_documents">
		<text>I looked through the documents found at the Institute. It appears that the Institute was used as a front for an unofficial lab called X-18 in the years preceding the accident. This lab hosted a number of very unusual experiments. Its location is not clear from the documents and the military don't seem to know anything about it either. Well, well... the plot thickens. But perhaps this is the starting point which the traders need. Now I have to travel further north to a trader known as Barkeep.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_bar_darklab_documents">
		<text>Hell... lab X-18 wasn't fun. And its current residents, yikes. I didn't think stalkers like that existed. I found some documents. I didn't understand much of what was written in them except that they contained technical specifications for some components for Kaimanov emitters. What's interesting is that the parts were destined for another lab with the codename X-16, and it's probably a secret one too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_bar_x16_documents">
		<text>Hmm... the traders have dug up a lot of information about these laboratories. Barkeep wasn't surprised to find out about the emitters and X-16. Now he's convinced that this Brain Scorcher is man-made. He thinks that Lab X-16 is near the scientists' camp by the lake in Yantar. It's interesting that they're studying emissions that resemble the effects of the Scorcher. So now I must pay a visit to the Zone's scientific community.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_before_darklab_documents">
		<text>I met with Barkeep. Having looked through the documents from the Institute he thinks that this X-18 is in the so called Dark Valley and asked me to go there to look for information and documents. He says he sent Duty scouts to get into the underground vaults but they have disappeared. Barkeep thinks they were captured by bandits who have a base nearby. If that's true everything those Duty guys found will be in the hands of Borov the leader of the bandits. Barkeep told me to be careful, but he clearly didn't tell me everything about these underground vaults. Oh well time to get to work, first of all I need to go pay Borov a visit and if the conversation goes well I'll explore the underground.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_before_radar_task">
		<text>Well I am ready to go to the 'Scorcher'. I found out from Crazy the times when the emission levels are lower. He told me about a safe place where I can wait out these periods. My Psi-protection won't work at other times anyway. I'll have to find a way into the underground bunker of Lab X-19. Inside I should be able to find the controls for the Brain Scorcher antennae.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_gordon_diary">
		<text>Gordon's PDA</text>
	</string>