<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<!-- DR edited 11 to many -->

<string_table>
<!-- first talk with Kostya upon finding him in his hole in the swamps -->
<string id="kostya_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello! Is that you sending the S.O.S.?</text>
</string>
<string id="kostya_dialog_1">
    <text>No, it's the Controller in that little farm, obviously to lure prey. Who are you, anyway?</text>
</string>
<string id="kostya_dialog_2">
    <text>Scar, they call me! The scientists in Cordon caught your signal and asked me to come here to help you. What have you heard about the Masters? And how did you get here?</text>
</string>
<string id="kostya_dialog_3">
    <text>The Cordon scientists, that's interesting! Okay I worked as a technician in a laboratory in the northern Zone. Lab X-8 it is called. One evening I was with two companions working in the lab studying a new type of mutant, zombie-like civilian, only transparent like water. The worst thing is when it's shot it does not splatter blood, but acid instead. My companions had gone away into the next room and I stayed in the room where there were 5 mini antennas. Then I heard footsteps. Thought at first that one of them was coming back. When I looked back I saw something strange. I aimed my weapon. Then I was being gestured to come to the door, and I heard a voice saying 'let's go'. Next I heard a radio. Many miracles in the zone but ghosts and UFOs I do not accept. Then a voice called 'BOSS, what to do with him? Two killed, and this kind of mind can come in handy'. Response was instantaneous 'In the Â Consumption'. I did not think I would survive. In the lab all the doors I coded, and one of these doors saved me. The door gave me a second life, and I locked the door. Between X-8 and X-18 is an underground passage. I got to X-18. Next door I updated the code. Codes I write as clues that point to date of high-profile events, 4 digits - the year, and hints in the form of words that not everyone will think of them. When out of the labs I was captured by Hog's bandits. Hints for the codes they had found, but did not realize what they ment. I was held in a basement then taken to Lebedev. That's how I got to Lebedev's base. Yesterday I escaped using a 'Black Hole', a one-time artefact. Talking with Lebedev I learned about the invisible ones, the 'Masters'.</text>
</string>
<string id="kostya_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, you and the beetle! I, at one time, had no idea how to get out of this base. I was blindfolded, and then a guide led me somewhere. I need to get into the Clear Sky base.</text>
</string>
<string id="kostya_dialog_5">
    <text>You might get in, but there are many guards there, all well armed. Why?</text>
</string>
<string id="kostya_dialog_6">
    <text>Well it is not for nostalgia sake. Help me Kostya! I must get back to Cordon after getting into the Clear Sky base. I don't know of any transitions to use. You, as I have come to realize, are very knowledgeable. Going?</text>
</string>
<string id="kostya_dialog_7">
    <text>Okay, if we get seperated head for the ruins in the south-west corner. I tend to use a route going via the pumping station.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to someone in the Cordon rookie camp -->
<string id="sidor_svalil_dialog_0">
    <text>Where did Sidorovich take off to?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_svalil_dialog_1">
    <text>Fuck knows, we sold the bunker for big money, and had the doors removed. He left on a chopper with Gastello who came for him. Why? We said nothing.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_svalil_dialog_2">
    <text>Now there's an old meanie. Maybe a Klondike was found, I suppose.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_svalil_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, really strange of course, that Sidor. At his age he is usually warming his buns on a stove, but he left urgently.</text>
</string>

<!-- after killing Hog and the Bax task - now with Drill in southern farm in Dark Valley -->
<string id="bur_ataka_gastello_dialog_0">
    <text>Done! The transition to Garbage is open again. Now it's up to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="bur_ataka_gastello_dialog_1">
    <text>Excellent Scar. Can you wait a bit? We've been warned that a wave of mutants are in the northeast valley.</text>
</string>
<string id="bur_ataka_gastello_dialog_2">
    <text>Don't tell me you called for a helicopter with that drunken buffoon Gastello at the controls?!</text>
</string>
<string id="bur_ataka_gastello_dialog_3">
    <text>Uhmm... well actually we did exactly that. I don't suppose you could take over?! After you kill the mutants come back to me and I will tell you how to get further on and into X-18. I may move to a new location in the Dark Valley, somewhere near X-18, we can have a chat. If you can't find me I suggest you try the Bar, or maybe Kostya in Cordon because you never know what he hears!</text>
</string>
<string id="bur_ataka_gastello_dialog_4">
    <text>Leave it to me I'm an expert and if all is successful I'll have aerial fire for the mutants that are in the northeast. After a good cleaning bandits too I'll head to the base near the entrance to X-18. See you there.\n\n</text>
</string>
 <string id="bur_ataka_gastello_dialog_5">
    <text>%c[255,255,128,1]Okay, screw Gastello. He is most likely drunk as a skunk. We must leave immediately to Lab X-18. And then to Hog's place. We need to advance, move out!</text>
 </string>

<!-- In the Cordon, having protected the scientists and the military - we talk to Dimak... prior to flying the helicopter... -->
<string id="dimak_poehali_bolota_0">
    <text>Well Dimak we beat the Mercenaries!</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_poehali_bolota_1">
    <text>Excellent Scar.... yes, and thanks for your help. The scientists do not need us any more. Well Scar if you ever go to Agroprom you will find our gunsmith there, he repairs armor, usually does a good job too. His name is 'Loser', talk to him he is a jack-of-all-trades and knows a lot of secrets. I'll give you coordinates. I'll give you the transition to CNPP from there you can get to Pripyat. Do you know how to fly a helicopter?</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_poehali_bolota_2">
    <text>Err... pardon?!</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_poehali_bolota_3">
    <text>Well we called our old friend 'Gastello' to fly us back to the north, but he is almost always drunk, and in that state he's maybe not the best pilot in the world. So if you fancy a go behind the wheel, it's pretty easy really. Let us all gather under the helicopter then you can get on-board too. All you have to do is head north to where we came in, and look for a 'Niva' car parked up on the hillside on the right side. The helicopter will set itself down. Well, do you think?</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_poehali_bolota_4">
    <text>Well... okay. I need to head that way to talk to Voronin. And for the transition and the info about your gunsmith I guess I owe you. So as Gastello would have said... 'come fly with me, let's fly, let's fly away'. If you can use some exotic booze... hmmm... well maybe not the booze.</text>
</string>


<string id="dimak_poehali_bolota_proval_0">
    <text>Blah, failed the task.</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_poehali_bolota_proval_1">
    <text>Yes. Well time is passing by. Thanks for your help. The scientists don't need us anymore. Will be on the Agroprom, find there our gunsmith, he usually repairs armor. His name is 'Loser'. Talk to him, he is a master of all trades and knows a lot of secrets. You will only have one-way coordinates. If you find yourself in CHAES2 you'll be able to get to Pripyat. Feel like flying a chopper?</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_poehali_bolota_proval_2">
    <text>Wow a chance to fly?!</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_poehali_bolota_proval_3">
    <text>Yep! We called Gastello our old friend. He is almost always drunk, and in that state the chopper smells like manure. Maybe you can sit at the helm. I know what you want head to the Bar. The transition to Landfill is where the 'Niva' is, and it's in working order too. We will continue to fly to Marsh. How do you like this plan?</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_poehali_bolota_proval_4">
    <text>Sounds good to me. I need to talk to Voronin anyway. Thanks for the transition and valuable information. Make a note on the PDA, your gunsmith Loser. Well, then we'll fly.</text>
</string>


<string id="lebed_tango_ataka_proval_0">
    <text>Battle was unsuccessful.</text>
</string>
<string id="lebed_tango_ataka_proval_1">
    <text>Bummer. Well time is passing by. Thanks for helping. The scientists don't need us now. Will be on the Agroprom, find there our gunsmith, he usually repairs armor and his name is 'Loser'. Talk to him because he is a master of all trades and knows a lot of secrets. You will only have one-way coordinates. If you find yourself in CHAES2 you'll be able to get to Pripyat. Feel like flying a chopper?</text>
</string>
<string id="lebed_tango_ataka_proval_2">
    <text>I flew a chopper before, so no problemo!</text>
</string>
<string id="lebed_tango_ataka_proval_3">
    <text>Yep! We called Gastello our old buddy. He is always drunk, and in that state the chopper smells like shit. Maybe you can sit at the helm and fly that thing. I know what you want to head to the Bar. The transition to Landfill is where near the 'Niva', and it's in working order. We will continue to fly to Marsh. Is this plan ok with you?</text>
</string>
<string id="lebed_tango_ataka_proval_4">
    <text>Yes, indeed, I need to talk to Voronin. Thanks for transition and information. Make a note on the PDA, your gunsmith Loser. Well, then time to fly!</text>
</string>

<!-- First time talking with Military commander Major Brazhnikov in Agroprom -->
<string id="agr_lebed_dialog_0">
    <text>Commander I come with grave news.</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_lebed_dialog_1">
    <text>And you did not get killed by the mercenary helicopters... that is frankly amazing. What is your news?</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_lebed_dialog_2">
    <text>At the request of scientists from Cordon I am here because their radio does not yet have full range. I have come to warn you that mercenaries plan to attack. A soldier was sent to the checkpoint with a note.</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_lebed_dialog_3">
    <text>Okay, well our radio was repaired. The soldier they sent fell into the hands of a bloodsucker, but we found a note on his body. So thanks for bringing the news but we are already waiting for them, they are due any minute now. Quite brazen is their leader Cygnus. We managed to communicate with the scientists in Cordon and they informed us about your visit. They say that you are not a novice stalker and if you help I'll throw in an advance in the form of bullets and a 'rucksack', and I'll put a marker to Cordon on your PDA. A good deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_lebed_dialog_4">
    <text>I see you are an expert in recruiting! Okay, I'll help.</text>
</string>


<string id="yan_saharov_laba_x10_dialog_0">
    <text>Here's your disc Professor. It was not easy, but now the 'Masters' no longer control the 'Scorcher'.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_saharov_laba_x10_dialog_1">
    <text>This is amazing, I never thought I'd see my disc again. Here you go, some money and a couple of recipes. I received a message from the 'Masters'. They promised to return the head of my wife if I delivered you. But I trust you, I know that you will do the impossible. It is a very pleasant and much quieter place than Yantar. I had thought to move into the bunker of the previous owner, but without the door it was less safe. But this place agrees with me perfectly, and I can trade and make repairs from here. Oh, I almost forgot, I called General Voronin and reported that you asked about stalkers from the Oleg Tango group, and after some confusion everyone is meeting in Wolf's Lair. Well, at least I think that's what was said.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_saharov_laba_x10_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes I think here is safer than the bunker without doors in Yantar... err, Amber. Anyway I am sure you will eventually settle down here. Dimon, as I understand went in search for his father in Wolf's Lair. What a holiday that should be. Thanks for everything professor.</text>
</string>

<!-- Second time talking with Military commander Major Brazhnikov in Agroprom, after repelling the raid -->
<string id="agr_lebed_dialog1_0">
    <text>Damn, that was tough! They were a mixed group, the mercenaries had with them a new dangerous group called the 'Masters'!</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_lebed_dialog1_1">
    <text>Yeah they were equipped with excellent armour. You helped save a lot of soldiers today stalker, I thank you. For your help I'll give you some more ammo, and a watch... to be honest I can't make it work, maybe you'll have more luck. It has menus, and you can set the timer for a time to discharge, and as well for the treatment of health and energy.</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_lebed_dialog1_2">
    <text>Your welcome. About the transition you mentioned, back to Cordon.</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_lebed_dialog1_3">
    <text>Pay attention, this is important... Lebedev is in Agroprom somewhere, maybe you can talk with him, he was seen due south of this building sometimes. If he won't share, shoot him and look for his PDA... that will open the transition for sure!</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_lebed_dialog1_4">
    <text>So, shoot Lebedev and getting his PDA that will open the route to Cordon. Gotcha!</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Igor having cleared up Agroprom -->
<string id="sniper_dialog_0">
    <text>I hear the military fixed their radio. It's a good thing I was there in Agroprom, as Lebedev attacked the complex with his 'friends', and I had to help the soldiers. I spoke to Lebedev, and he has threatened to attack Cordon and kill all the scientists. Oddly when I shot him he vanished. Poof! Wtf?</text>
</string>
<string id="sniper_dialog_1">
    <text>I'm just glad you survived, really. I know about the ability of Lebedev. Kostya told me how you took the absolutes from the base. Anyway we need your help again. We have heard that a sniper is coming to kill us, sent by Lebedev.</text>
</string>
<string id="sniper_dialog_2">
    <text>You all need to hide, particularly Vasilina with her pert buns and...</text>
</string>
<string id="sniper_dialog_3">
    <text>NO! Vasilina explained that if we all hide the sniper will know something is wrong. At the military base lies an enhanced SVD. In a rucksack in one of the trees. It's the best rifle in the Zone, as it has target tracking built in. If you get on the roof of the barracks building in the southern military base you should see the rucksack. Hopefully that information is correct. Bring it back and we can talk more.</text>
</string>
<string id="sniper_dialog_4">
    <text>Ok, so I head south to the military base to find an enhanced SVD. I need to get on the roof to see the rucksack which is in a tree. Easy as cake!</text>
</string>
<string id="sniper_dialog_5">
    <text>Excellent Scar. Just be careful, and then come back and we can talk again.</text>
</string>


<string id="sniper_dialog1_0">
    <text>I found the SVD. It's in great shape. I agree it may well be the best gun in the Zone, as it has autolock built into its sight.</text>
</string>
<string id="sniper_dialog1_1">
    <text>I hate to say I told you so. Oh, wait, I did. lol.</text>
</string>
<string id="sniper_dialog1_2">
    <text>Okay, I forgive you. So who will I shoot?</text>
</string>
<string id="sniper_dialog1_3">
    <text>Who? I have no idea, just some paid sniper. I suggest you take a position on the roof of the building next to us, climb up high, onto the chimney, used the truck's engine cover to jump up to the roof. I think there will be three SMS before the sniper arrives. Use the scope SVD 'Tiger' to track him. He will come from the north-west side. Take him out!</text>
</string>
<string id="sniper_dialog1_4">
    <text>I am afraid of heights. I never wanted to be a chimney sweep.</text>
</string>
<string id="sniper_dialog1_5">
    <text>Quit bitch'n and get up on the roof before more of us get killed.</text>
</string>


<string id="dimak_repair_0">
    <text>Well I it appears you repair weapons or armor?</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_repair_1">
    <text>Ah, you see the rifle in a vice. Yes I do. So what do you need repaired? I always say, work hard and get paid accordingly. Basically this is my hobby. Tell me what you want repaired. \n\n My rates:</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_repair_2">
    <text>Repair my pistol.</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_repair_3">
    <text>Repair my weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_repair_4">
    <text>Repair my armor.</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_repair_5">
    <text>Wait here, I'll get more money!</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_repair_6">
    <text>Excellent! Wait a minute... (Took an hour) is now almost ready (it took another two hours) is almost ready (just you wait)... \n\n Finished!</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_repair_7">
    <text>Let's see, somewhere I have a tape... Yeah there! Oh, I love halturka (Dimych immersed in the work). \n\n Ok, here ya go Scar.</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_repair_8">
    <text>Well it looks like you did a good job. Okay, thank you. No fluff!.</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_repair_9">
    <text>(Meticulously looking wafers) Nuuu like Nitsche so he can live. I have to go, the Zone is calling.</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_repair_10">
    <text>Anything else to patch up?</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_repair_11">
    <text>Yeah, let's see. \n\n Vot my rates:</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_repair_11">
    <text>Yes as grain you. That is broken, then? But I warn you to fix a lot of money will come if you bring absolutely rubbish. \n\n Vot my rates:</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Zhora in Wolfs Lair, after Oleg -->
<string id="aver_goga_0">
    <text>You are Zhora? My name is Scar. I'm told some money is missing?</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_goga_1">
    <text>Yes I'm Zhora. Yes, we know about the missing money, and we all have our suspicions.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_goga_2">
    <text>You are an unusual group, a real mix of different sorts, a real rarity. I was once in a group called Arrow.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_goga_3">
    <text>Well good to meet you Scar! I've heard of you of course. Come on I want a cup of tea, and we need to have a serious conversation. You should to talk with Dimon, he should be arriving sometime soon, keep an eye open. Hmmm, did you see Airborne? Now where did he go?!</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Dimak after waiting for 8am with Fairy - and talk to Airborne afterwards? -->
<string id="dimak_s_bara_0">
    <text>Hi Dimak! Looks like you spent the night boozing at the bar! You okay? You seem a little weird. Upset?</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_s_bara_1">
    <text>The Bar in the evening was rock'n, but now the anarchists just came in and rule there. Victor as always is smashed and now instead of sleeping it off he is trying to protect the camp and the pool of funds we hold for many stalkers. Talk to Airborne, he pulled a short straw and is on lookout up on those rocks with the heavy machine gun. Just watch out he is rather angry right now. You Scar talk to him and get to know him, one thing is for sure he does not want to talk to us. I owe you thanks to your help as my son should appear here pretty soon, so I'm going to wait here for him.</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_s_bara_2">
    <text>Okay Dimak I'll talk to Airborne, and the fact that Dimon is here I think everyone is pleased he has found you. Talk to him and know that we support you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dimak_s_bara_3">
    <text>Thank you, Scar!</text>
</string>

<!-- Talking to Oleg after Airborne in Wolfs Lair -->
<string id="oleg_kabak_0">
    <text>Hey Oleg! How ya doing? What's with Airborne? He seems a bit upset about something.</text>
</string>
<string id="oleg_kabak_1">
    <text>Being the lookout is an boring job, really no fun at all, and he doesn't like to take orders. You Scar I hear many things about you so I'll tell you a secret, when Airborne was guarding our base money went missing. There's a group called Navy, I'm not sure how they're connected to anything though. Frankly this is all very confusing. Talk to Zhora Dalnoboy, he'll be by the truck, just over there. You didn't notice him before?</text>
</string>
<string id="oleg_kabak_2">
    <text>Well okay I'll talk to Zhora, and you Oleg should trust but always verify. The missing money is a serious problem. On the mainland some kill for a loaf of bread.</text>
</string>
<string id="oleg_kabak_3">
    <text>Yep, shit happens here Scar. The devil must be what is behind it all. We'll see. Go see Zhora!</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Airborne after talking with Dimak in Wolfs Lair -->
<string id="vdv_s_bara_0">
    <text>Pleased to meet you Airborne! You seem a bit upset?</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_s_bara_1">
    <text>Go talk with Oleg, he's sitting near the campfire, he's the asshole in the cowboy hat. I am in no mood to talk to anyone about anything.</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_s_bara_2">
    <text>Okay I'll talk with Oleg. Sorry about what happened!</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_s_bara_3">
    <text>Aah, get lost!</text>
</string>

<!-- the farce in the wolfs Lair continues, now we talk to Dimon -->
<string id="aver_vdv_sms_0">
    <text>Dimon, hello brother! Welcome back! Did you happen to come across a man in military armor?</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_vdv_sms_1">
    <text>Good to see you Scar! Yeah I saw such a guy, he was running like he needed the bushes for a great movement. I prey his case was full of toilet paper?</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_vdv_sms_2">
    <text>A case? Then it is clear, it must have been him. Thanks Dimon, and it surely was not toilet paper. Well I'll tell Oleg.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_vdv_sms_3">
    <text>I see... Oleg... sure, okay.</text>
</string>

<!-- the farce in the wolfs Lair continues, now we talk to Oleg after Dimon... -->
<string id="aver_vdv_s_ebal_0">
    <text>Oleg, Dimon saw a military stalker running with a case, which means that he must have taken your common fund.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_vdv_s_ebal_1">
    <text>Wow Scar you're better than Poriot and Colombo! Help us catch up with him and get that case, and we will give you what you want, within reason of course. Money is hard to earn these days.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_vdv_s_ebal_2">
    <text>Well, I will help you get the fugitive, will do everything in my power.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_vdv_s_ebal_3">
    <text>%c[255,255,128,1]No Oleg, I have other things to do. And I am to tired.</text>
</string>

<string id="vdv_dostat_na_pri_0">
    <text>Well Dimych what's the situation?</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_dostat_na_pri_1">
    <text>You can go. The signal from the PDA informs about Airborne in being in East Pripyat. Lets go before we loose the signal.</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_dostat_na_pri_2">
    <text>Well I do not know much about that place. That son of a bitch! We're going there, so let the shit hit the fan. Ha-ha!</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_dostat_na_pri_3">
    <text>Let's boogie!</text>
</string>

<string id="vdv_dostat_pri_0">
    <text>Well how we getting there?</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_dostat_pri_1">
    <text>Eggbeater!!</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_dostat_pri_2">
    <text>Okay Dimak take action!</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_dostat_pri_3">
    <text>Time to ramble on!</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Oleg in Wolfs Lair after fighting off the beasts and masters squad -->
<string id="vdv_dostat_0">
    <text>Well, Oleg, how do we get to East Pripyat?</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_dostat_1">
    <text>Zhora said that on the far side of the forest he fired on two helicopters which means they are here. I guess Airborne is giving our money to them. Airborne will probably fly on one of those choppers. We need to attack them and capture a helicopter. You can fly that helicoper. This is the only chance to catch up with Airborne. I know the transition to East Pripyat, but it's a long trip as a walking group, so a helicopter is mandatory. You need to find a PDA too. This will be a long trip.</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_dostat_2">
    <text>Then decide who will attack the military stalkers? Someone has to stay in the camp.</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_dostat_3">
    <text>Ah shit we do not know where the pilot Gastro is! Well we'll gather around the campfire and decide who does what, but I think you will go with six or seven guys looking for the helicopter, and the others will remain here. Once controlling the helicopter a transition will be available in the north to go to East Pripyat. There we'll get our hands on Airborne and his PDA.</text>
</string>

<!-- in Pripyat -->
<string id="trup_vdv_nashli_0">
    <text>Zhora is this Airborne's PDA?</text>
</string>
<string id="trup_vdv_nashli_1">
    <text>It seems like it, but something ain't kosher here!</text>
</string>
<string id="trup_vdv_nashli_2">
    <text>So he was here, he could not have gone far.</text>
</string>
<string id="trup_vdv_nashli_3">
    <text>For sure!</text>
</string>

<!-- back in Wolfs lair, delivering the money to Oleg, before the rest of the team are back -->
<string id="prishli_s_up_0">
    <text>Hi Oleg, we found the case.</text>
</string>
<string id="prishli_s_up_1">
    <text>Wow you guys are amazng! Where are the rest of the guys? Come on and rest a while. When all are gathered we'll open the case.</text>
</string>
<string id="prishli_s_up_2">
    <text>They're coming. Okay, rest, so be it.</text>
</string>
<string id="prishli_s_up_3">
    <text>Excellent!</text>
</string>

<!-- In Jupiter after big fight and heli crash - some of Oleg's guys are trapped -->
<string id="keys_goni_0">
    <text>Well well well, look who we have here! Give us the case and release my friends otherwise do not expect any mercy. Dimon and Torych, blah blah blah...</text>
</string>
<string id="keys_goni_1">
    <text>Dimon and Torych caught me before I could trap them. Scar, Dimon, Torych listen I have enough money for you all, your children, grandchildren and great-grandchildren. I suggest that we split up the money and you let me go. And Dimon, well, let your father die in the trap. If they are released no one will forgive me and you'll be dancing on my grave.</text>
</string>
<string id="keys_goni_2">
    <text>So you suggest that Dimon lets his own father fry in the anomaly, and we leave our friends behind. I say no to your conditions. Tell me about the trap anomoly now!</text>
</string>
<string id="keys_goni_3">
    <text>Ok, ok, Dimak and your friends are 30 meters from here. Go out the gate, turn left, jump down to the lower level. There are two metal garages, they are in one of them. But they are trapped behind an anomoly. So I say let me take the case 20 meters and then I will set the timer. You will have 5 minutes to find the deactivator. It will be in a white case somewhere here in the yard.</text>
</string>
<string id="keys_goni_4">
    <text>Your not going anywhere! How about you don't walk 20 meters, and you leave the case, and you disable the trap. Or I shoot you in the face. \n\n</text>
</string>
<string id="keys_goni_5">
    <text>%c[255,255,128,1]Up yours! We will figure out how to disable the trap ourselves, and get the case with the deactivator. And then I will shoot you in the face.</text>
</string>

<!-- Talking to Dryka to call in the helicopter -->
<string id="dryka_svoy_dialog_0">
    <text>Why did you come here? Are you the one who shot down the helicopter?</text>
</string>
<string id="dryka_svoy_dialog_1">
    <text>To help out and I only found you by accident. I had gotten here a week ago. We were heading to the transition to East Pripyat. The transition collapsed after a powerful explosion. Someone set off a strong mine and some of our guys died. We were 16 people and now only 10 are left. We went to the Yanov railway station and ran into military stalkers. They were like cockroaches all over the place, and we ran into more traps, and we had to eat disgusting rare animals. I met up with Oleg by chance and he explained the situation. He wanted me to shoot down the helicopter. He said he would give me 25% of there money to do that. Then later he would not give me the money. I bitched and then they started to gang up on me, and luckily some military stalkers appeared and started shooting at us. I ran like the wind. Now I do not know were to go. If Oleg and his group leave I will be happy. Gastello's callsign was heard recently too. He apparently is not drunk.</text>
</string>
<string id="dryka_svoy_dialog_2">
    <text>Well I think most of our problems are over now. Oleg I think should be pleased, after all, if it were not for Oleg then Navy would have gotten away and he would be miles from here.</text>
</string>
<string id="dryka_svoy_dialog_3">
    <text>Even if Gastello flies this thing I'm afraid the helicopter will not cope with 9 people. The whole thing is damaged from salt, too many flight-hours, little servicing and radiation.</text>
</string>
<string id="dryka_svoy_dialog_4">
    <text>Let's gently get into the Hind cockpit. Even if it is in poor condition maybe we can still fly it.</text>
</string>

<!-- again - why -->
<string id="dryka1_svoy_dialog_0">
    <text>How did you get here? Are you the one who shot down the chopper?</text>
</string>
<string id="dryka1_svoy_dialog_1">
    <text>I only found you by chance. I came here a week ago. We were heading to the transition to East Pripyat. The transition collapsed after a powerful explosion. Someone set off a strong mine and some of our guys died. We were 16 people and now only 10 are left. We went to the Yanov railway station and ran into military stalkers. They were like cockroaches all over the place, and we ran into more traps, and we had to eat disgusting rare animals. I met up with Oleg by chance and he explained the situation. He wanted me to shoot down the chopper. He said he would give me 25% of there money to do that. Then later he would not give me the money. I bitched and then they started to gang up on me, and luckily some military stalkers appeared and started shooting at us. I ran like the wind. Now I do not know were to go. If Oleg and his group leave I will be happy. Gastello's callsign was heard recently too. He apparently is not drunk.</text>
</string>
<string id="dryka1_svoy_dialog_2">
    <text>Well I guess most of our problems are over now. Oleg I think should be happy, after all, if it were not for Oleg then Navy would have gotten away and he would be far away by now.</text>
</string>
<string id="dryka1_svoy_dialog_3">
    <text>Even if Gastello flies this thing I'm afraid the chopper will not lift with 9 people. The whole thing is trashed from salt, too many flight-hours, little servicing and radiation.</text>
</string>
<string id="dryka1_svoy_dialog_4">
    <text>Let's gently get into the chopper cockpit. Even if it is in shitty condition maybe we can still fly it.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Zhora after Oleg in Wolfs Lair -->
<string id="dryka_neytral_0">
    <text>You're Dryka, Oleg suggested we talk. Do you know what's going on, because I'm now really very confused.</text>
</string>
<string id="dryka_neytral_1">
    <text>Hey bro. Wait until everyone is here, then talk to all of us.</text>
</string>
<string id="dryka_neytral_2">
    <text>Jee thanks, that cleared everything up!</text>
</string>
<string id="dryka_neytral_3">
    <text>I suggest you try Dimon. You might need to wait for a couple of SMS's before he arrives. Honestly, I don't have a clue either, all I know is that a lot of money got stolen a while back. Hey have you seen Airborne?</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Fairy in Wolfs Lair -->
<string id="bratva_gde_0">
    <text>Wow, such a diva, and in the woods! You must be a brave lady. Question, where's this grandfather Shchukar guy? And umm, want to play a game?</text>
</string>
<string id="bratva_gde_1">
    <text>Want your stick in a knot? Shchukar lives in a hut over the hill south of here at the end of a path. He is my grandfather and was here recently, you just missed him.</text>
</string>
<string id="bratva_gde_2">
    <text>Thank you for that info. And what do you do here? Surely you don't sell cosmetics?</text>
</string>
<string id="bratva_gde_3">
    <text>If I did sell cosmetics I could hide that ugly scar of yours. I trade items stalker. Also know that you can leave items here in the safe. 5000 roubles for the lock code.</text>
</string>

<!-- Talking to Fairy in Wolfs Lair, at the wrong time to meet the group -->
<string id="bratva_pridet_0">
    <text>Hello sweety-pie. Your group sent me an SMS stating that they have to come back here.</text>
</string>
<string id="bratva_pridet_1">
    <text>Hello yourself handsome. Well the group returns here between 8 am and 9 am every day, so I suggest you wait or come back later.</text>
</string>

<string id="bratva_prishla_0">
    <text>Good morning gorgeous lovely Fairy. Did your guys not get in touch with you yet? And by the way, maybe if they're running late we could find some way to pass the time.</text>
</string>
<string id="bratva_prishla_1">
    <text>Unlucky for you and me Scar, they've just arrived.</text>
</string>
<string id="bratva_prishla_2">
    <text>What... wow it's like they were instantiated by a script or something. I guess the script writer didn't want us to have any time together. Anyway lovely darling Fairy, how about you and me sweetie-pie get it on one of these days?</text>
</string>
<string id="bratva_prishla_3">
    <text>You know, if you were cuter, younger, had a good body, and didn't smoke, drink and smell bad and... well, if I wasn't a lesbian and obsessed with dildos, then maybe I wouldn't find you completely repulsive. Oh, and life's a bitch, so what are you going to do about it?</text>
</string>

<!-- Handing the case to Oleg in Wolfs lair, post Jupiter  - trapped members did not died -->
<string id="keys_prines_ok_0">
    <text>Hey Oleg I have the case with me, take it. Airborne had access to explosives on him and when he was shot he exploded. lol!</text>
</string>
<string id="keys_prines_ok_1">
    <text>That's good. Is everything intact?</text>
</string>
<string id="keys_prines_ok_2">
    <text>Yes, even Gastello is back. He has nowhere to go now that his helicopter is trashed. As you know he helped us get out of Jupiter, but the crash into that large swamp save our lives. Softer than concrete!</text>
</string>
<string id="keys_prines_ok_3">
    <text>Yea, we heard an explosion. Here as promised is a half million rubles and also two of Airborne's caches. The contents are yours. I think you will be happy. One cache is under the boulders where Airborne used to stand guard, and the second cache is on a branch of a dead tree near our camp slightly up a hill.</text>
</string>
<string id="keys_prines_ok_4">
    <text>Wow thanks Oleg!</text>
</string>

<!-- Handing the case to Oleg in Wolfs lair, post Jupiter - trapped members died -->
<string id="keys_prines_proval_0">
    <text>Here's the case, take it. Know that Airborne was rigged with explosives and is now in a million pieces.</text>
</string>
<string id="keys_prines_proval_1">
    <text>That's good. Is everything else okay?</text>
</string>
<string id="keys_prines_proval_2">
    <text>Unfortunately six members were killed before I could turn off the trap with a timer. We had nowhere to go. Then Gastello helped us get out of Jupiter, but the chopper could not stand the strain, because of his old age I guess. And we crashed in the large swamp. We are lucky to have survived.</text>
</string>
<string id="keys_prines_proval_3">
    <text>Yea we heard an explosion. It's really bad losing some of our guys. We are all happy to have gotten our money back. Keep a little money as a reward. Okay, for the lose of their souls we drink, and in memory of Dimak and the others.</text>
</string>
<string id="keys_prines_proval_4">
    <text>Okay, let us remember them! [gulp gulp]</text>
</string>

<!-- talking with the Pilot Gastello in the swamps in Wolfs lair after the crash -->
<string id="gastello_dialog_0">
    <text>Wow, nice crash! Are you still learning to fly or practicing crashing?</text>
</string>
<string id="gastello_dialog_1">
    <text>Fuck you... only a great pilot would have got us down in a swamp in one piece. If we'd crashed anywhere else onto something hard we would all be dead. You my friend would also be dead!</text>
</string>
<string id="gastello_dialog_2">
    <text>Okay, okay, yeah I guess you're right. Sorry! I guess airworthy helicopters are rare in the zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="gastello_dialog_3">
    <text>Well I need another way out of here now that the chopper is trashed. I need you to help me get to the Oleg's camp. I'm really shaken up. I can't focus or anything... help me, you owe me!</text>
</string>
<string id="gastello_dialog_4">
    <text>Yea yea yea, okay, let's go, one-for-all and all-for-one for the Motherland.</text>
</string>

<!-- Almost our first conversation - two jobs - get a gun, then help Dimon -->
<string id="start_dialog_shram_0">
    <text>Incredible! Vasilina brought you out of that coma state. We all thought you were dead when we found you. You'd been there so long all your clothes were rotted, but by some some kind of mystical fate you were still alive and unharmed. Well apart from the scar on your face.</text>
</string>
<string id="start_dialog_shram_1">
    <text>A scar I have, so in the Zone Scar I'm called. What an imaginative bunch these stalkers are. Jeez my head, my head... it hurts real bad. Where am I and how did I get here? Chernobyl I guess... so... where's Lebedev and Strelok? I have their names in my mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="start_dialog_shram_2">
    <text>The head will be ok in an hour or so according to Vasilina. Mind you Lebedev's only the cook and mostly drunk, so who knows what he is up too. If you know those names then the picture becomes clearer, you may be a former mercenary. I heard some rumour that they accidentally discovered some military secrets from those who examined CNPP. Strelok I do not know where he is, but in your PDA your job was protection of another called Arrow, but that was 2 years ago. We cleaned up your PDA and updated it, so at least it's now in a working state. Oh and we deleted those pictures... you know the ones! Anyway, Lebedev has not helped us, and in fact has become a treacherous enemy. He now helps brand new clans in the Zone. Plucking our skills, he gave all the new research to a horrible group that announced themselves as masters of the Zone - a group called 'Masters'. Amazing how they come up with such names, no? Oh and another new group there is called 'Witches'. But not all surprises are bad, as you might notice present is the opposite sex. But generally this really doesn't matter.</text>
</string>
<string id="start_dialog_shram_3">
    <text>So can you tell me if Strelok is alive?... HANG ON... I slept for 2 years and not dead, what?! And there are women in the Zone? I must be dreaming.</text>
</string>
<string id="start_dialog_shram_4">
    <text>Yes must have a strange gift because mutants and blowouts didn't kill you. We asked around when we read your PDA, and a stalker called Strelok was found in the truck of death. He was sent to hunt and kill a stalker called Arrow by a team of scientists involved with the C-Consciousness. The story gets odd as it seems he destroyed himself but also lived. Anyway he helped many clans, including us. Later he was able to turn off the brain burner barrier between north and south, and so earned almost all Zone's groups respect. It seems Strelok then got to the center of the Zone again, helped his close friends and stopped the C-Consciousness. Since then many areas have opened up in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="start_dialog_shram_5">
    <text>Wow! And it turns out I slept through all that? Listen Igor I need to make an urgent call to the Mainland. I had a seriously ill daughter there under the care of a friend. I need to find out what happened. Oh and I may need to find Arrow and maybe Lebedev. Frankly it's a bit confusing, just like badly translated Russian can be.</text>
</string>
<string id="start_dialog_shram_6">
    <text>At the moment we don't have a working transmitter, even on a good day its best range is 10 km. I'll be brief. We too are like refugees. We arrived here with the military, with the generator to try to study and then stablise the Zone, but all the new groups are violent. Generators have been set up to hold open the transitions, but it was impossible to leave these in place with such enemies. Now we have one goal, and as a former military I say here's the safest place because we closed the old transitions, but without transitions and connections with friendlies we may not survive. Even the military at the checkpoint have been forgotten by the authorities. We need to open the transition to Garbage to find a broken transmitter. It was junked on a radioactive heap, which is near to some woods and a little swamp. Bring it back and we can try to repair it. Last time we tried to go into the Garbage we get shot at. But you have such a gift for survival we will give you one artifact to hang on your belt. You'll still need a gun and some ammunition and then you can go. You just take your time and try and scrounge something from a local merchant Sidorovich, and then talk to Dimon who is sitting near the campfire. It was he who brought you here from the military. He also has a goal, he's looking for his father, and since he said he will help we gave him the activator switch to Garbage. He was going tomorrow talk to him first!</text>
</string>
<string id="start_dialog_shram_7">
    <text>Oh god, Sidorovich! I forgot about him, he's such a miser and even in two years of sleep I cannot forget him. I'll talk to Dimon and then Sidorovich and then we'll go get the damaged transmitter.</text>
</string>
<string id="start_dialog_shram_8">
    <text>What... really... err, well okay... here you go, and be careful there are many mutants. And seeing as how you're... well, keen for adventure, I'll give you a transition to the Marsh, just be careful we've heard of some unsavoury groups there. Try to find a bag of rare artifacts and see if you can find Kostya, he might be able to help you. If you bring them back, we'll try to find you a route to Vasilina. Let's be honest, you owe us anyway. Here's the artifact, you can't keep it, so don't sell it!</text>
</string>
<string id="start_dialog_shram_9">
    <text>Ok, after 2 years I guess I could do with a bit of fresh air. I'm off to Dimon and then to Sidorovich.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Dimon -->
<string id="esc_dima_dialog_0">
    <text>Nice weather for this time of year Dimon. I was told that you are on some mission?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dima_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah, good news travels fast huh?! I hear you have some work too, maybe we can help each other. I am looking for my father. They say he was in the Zone center, but where to find him I don't really know.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dima_dialog_2">
    <text>I'll help you. I need help too. The scientists said that they gave you an activator get you to Garbage. Is that true?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dima_dialog_3">
    <text>True. We might get together to find the transmitter somewhere amongst all the trash. I could not do that last time, too much radiation. But you need a gun pal, unless you so plan to go naked? I left Sidorovich my shotgun which I brought from home, but no bullets. Cartridges you'll have to negotiate with Sidor. You'll need to stand outside his door for a minute so because it takes him a while to unlock the door. You'll get a few SMS's which from him too. He's certainly greedy, but you can talk try talking to him. When you get a gun with bullets come back and we'll go together to activate the transition.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dima_dialog_4">
    <text>Good man, thank you! I'll visit Sidorovich.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Sidorovich in his Cordon bunker -->
<string id="esc_sidor_dialog_0">
    <text>Who's that arrogant mug barking at the door? A year ago these bloody do-gooders arrived, and it's thanks to them that we are stuck here making no money at all since the transitions shut down! So are you going to open up the Zone or your salvation? And history repeats itself no doubt.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_dialog_1">
    <text>For my salvation? No! But 2 years ago there were more intelligent individuals, and at the moment I see only a fool. I need the gun that Dimon left you and some ammunition. Three boxes at least. You will profit from me old man, and a re-opened Zone. I am Scar.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_dialog_2">
    <text>Hah.... ok Scar, ha-ha-ha-ha. No you do not get the gun yet, you can help me with a little matter. Here in Cordon is my wax stuffed head. I can give you the approximate location, and you better remember it!! Bring it to me then the gun and cartridges are yours. Well?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_dialog_3">
    <text>A freak'n wax head? Really... and you want it back. Wow! Ok Sid, I guess I don't have a choice do I.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_dialog_4">
    <text>No you don't if you want something. Listen, consider it good-will. Only God knows why I'm suddenly so generous, it's like someone is in control of my actions. Anyway just get me the wax head. Literally it's a model of my head. Some Hunter friends made it for me. I just like it, ok? Don't look at me that way!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_dialog_5">
    <text>%c[255,255,128,1]Search for it yourself dickhead and give me Dimon's gun, or I'll piss on your desk.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="esc_sidor_dialog_6">
    <text>Ok wise ass here you go, and get the fuck out of here. Here are 2 rounds. If you have a misfire you'll have one more chance, or you can use it to shoot yourself in the head.</text>
 </string>

<!-- At the northern checkpoint in the Garbage - talking to Duty - they ask you to negotiate with bandits -->
<string id="prapor_dveri_0">
    <text>Prapor, money could cause your death, you'll eat too much, grow fat and have a heart attack. I need to get to the Bar for the scientists who, right now, are in Cordon and need help. 'Masters' and Mercenaries are heading there to attack them. Voronin is expecting at the Bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="prapor_dveri_1">
    <text>Yes, yes, I see by your eyes that you're on a mission. But look, can you help us negotiate with some bandits?</text>
</string>
<string id="prapor_dveri_2">
    <text>What is the deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="prapor_dveri_3">
    <text>Well, Hog sends bandits to persuade us to leave the checkpoint and go to the Bar. We hear that he wants to move out of Dark Valley. The purpose of this no one can predict. Can you try to persuade them to change their minds and go quietly back into Dark Valley. Of course all for a good fee. Well?</text>
</string>
<string id="prapor_dveri_4">
    <text>Okay, I need the money and if you persuade me with the amount of the fee. Whisper the amount in my ear or write on down a piece of paper.</text>
</string>
<string id="prapor_dveri_5">
    <text>Uhmm... just go to them now, we can talk afterwards.</text>
</string>

<!-- returning the tranmitter to Vasilina in Cordon -->
<string id="andersen_peredatchik_dialog_0">
    <text>Here's the transmitter from Garbage. It weighs 30kg, and was a real pain to bring back!</text>
</string>
<string id="andersen_peredatchik_dialog_1">
    <text>Now that's something! Thank you! I'm going to work on it right now. I think the relationship between us and you will work out. Talk to Oleg if you want some more work.</text>
</string>
<string id="andersen_peredatchik_dialog_2">
    <text>Here take it. I need to earn a lot of money. I need to send money to my daughter, she is sick.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Dimon in Cordon -->
<string id="esc_dima1_dialog_0">
    <text>Ok I have your gun, though Sidrovoch is still a big pain to deal with.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dima1_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, you have a gun... he switched it. That's not the one I gave him.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dima1_dialog_2">
    <text>A substitute? I'm gonna slap his silly fat arrogant face.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dima1_dialog_3">
    <text>No, do not, Scar. We need to get on the way, and Sidor used my gun for some rabbit hunting and bashed it around a bit, I think he had to get it repaired after. So I think you might be better off with this one. Anyway, we better run to open the crossing to The Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dima1_dialog_4">
    <text>Dimon... well, whatever. Let's go!</text>
</string>

<!-- returning the wax head to Sidrovich in the Cordon -->
<string id="esc_sidor_art_done_0">
    <text>Here you go, your head. I hope you enjoy it as much as I didn't. I think it looks like a football. I pissed on it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_art_done_1">
    <text>Well, no thanks to you, means you get nothing! Ya see Scar, you talk like a splat punk kid.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_art_done_2">
    <text>A splat punk kid - what!? Look, just give me the gun and three packs of ammo, oh and any other bits you have free. Otherwise, well, I'm close to the fire and if I recall wax melts quickly.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_art_done_3">
    <text>Ok ok, calm down and to hell with you. Look here's your stuff and some money. If I were you I'd buy a Fort 12, it's a great pistol for the money. Oh, and get yourself a sleeping bag.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_art_done_4">
    <text>That's it, you cheapskate?! See ya!</text>
</string>

<!-- Talking to Igor in Cordon, after returning with the second antenna -->
<string id="uch_dialog_0">
    <text>What's up?</text>
</string>
<string id="uch_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, not everything is going according to plan. I was expecting from Agricultural Industry three scientists, Professor Solvador, Dr. Klenov and his partner. They would have gotten here by themselves but must be lost due to heavy fog and ran. They are supposedly near the tunnel with strong radiation. While Vasilina will repair and adjust the antenna, will you bring them to the camp? Solvador is very dear to me. I would give you my 'Thunderstorm', but I only have 10 rounds of ammo. Well will you do it?</text>
</string>
<string id="uch_dialog_2">
    <text>Sure, I'll help you.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to lost scientists -->
<string id="solvador_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi scientists! Lost huh? I'm here to collect you guys, now let us go to the rookie camp.</text>
</string>
<string id="solvador_dialog_1">
    <text>We have absolutely no weapons. We got lost and ended up here. There are bandits operating in the area.</text>
</string>
<string id="solvador_dialog_2">
    <text>Bandits and mutants don't bother me. Stay five steps behind me. Keep your distance. I'll likely be shooting at something.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Dimak in the bar for the first time -->
<string id="prinesty_dimaku_stvol_0">
    <text>Greetings!</text>
</string>
<string id="prinesty_dimaku_stvol_1">
    <text>You must be Scar, I saw you talking to Anya. Oleg told me about you and the problem the scientists are having in Cordon. I am glad to meet you, call me Dimak!</text>
</string>
<string id="prinesty_dimaku_stvol_2">
    <text>Nice to meet you too, how come you're not carrying a gun?</text>
</string>
<string id="prinesty_dimaku_stvol_3">
    <text>Yep, you're right. Some jerk threw my rucksack over a wall here near the Bar. I'll be brief, I need help, if you can be trusted. So I have a job for you, bring me my rucksack contents, flamethrower and two gas tanks. To find it go through the north-western checkpoint, get over the fence to your left, head south down the road, turning left at the t-junction, so you're heading east. Somewhere there near a spruce bush should be my backpack. Just be careful people say there are many dogs around there.</text>
</string>
<string id="prinesty_dimaku_stvol_4">
    <text>Right... more dogs... great... my nickname should be Dogfood.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Dimak in the bar for the second time, returning his flamethrower -->
<string id="prines_dimaku_stvol_0">
    <text>Here's your flamethrower and gas-tanks. It is the first time I have see this design for a flamethrower.</text>
</string>
<string id="prines_dimaku_stvol_1">
    <text>Thank you Scar I will introduce you to our gunsmith. He makes such things.</text>
</string>
<string id="prines_dimaku_stvol_2">
    <text>It's a good looking flamethrower, well engineered, it looks accurate and reliable too.</text>
</string>
<string id="prines_dimaku_stvol_3">
    <text>Yep, there's nothing on par with it, believe me. Okay then let's talk, it's time to open a shorter way to Cordon avoiding Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="prines_dimaku_stvol_4">
    <text>Bypassing Garbage?! So it is possible!</text>
</string>

<!-- after successful negotiations with the bandits at the northern checkpoint in Garbage -->
<string id="prapor_na_babki_0">
    <text>Ok, where's my money?</text>
</string>
<string id="prapor_na_babki_1">
    <text>You'll need to pick it up from Voronin in the Bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="prapor_na_babki_2">
    <text>Great, more bull shit. I thought Duty were supposed to stand by their word? But nooooooooo! I have done Duty a few favors, and I want you know I need the money badly. My daughter has blood cancer and needs financial support, but you probably forgot that 'your word is your bond' or that 'one good turn deserves another'. You saw how the bandits were armed. They have enough weapons to send your smoking remains to the moon. I hope they come back and kick your ass.</text>
</string>
<string id="prapor_na_babki_3">
    <text>Well, it's like... you know... booooooooo hoooooooooooo! Go take your sob story to someone who gives a damn.</text>
</string>
<string id="prapor_na_babki_4">
    <text>Nice guy, you putz! I'll be sure to inform Voronin about your attitude.</text>
</string>

<string id="prapor_na_babkip_0">
    <text>We had a deal, but the guys started shooting at everything that moved causing problems. So I am still entitled to the money.</text>
</string>
<string id="prapor_na_babkip_1">
    <text>If you are not happy you can try crossing this picket line, but you'll receive abuse. My guys are as tough as mercenaries.</text>
</string>
<string id="prapor_na_babkip_2">
    <text>No one else could have done a better job. Oh wait you never intended to help me anyway. That's it you piece of shit. So listen up. I am not suicidal but I intend to help my daughter. And I see you don't give a damn. I hope I am here sipping brew when someone else comes here and kicks your ass. It will be a nice show to watch. I'll remember this event, asshole!</text>
</string>
<string id="prapor_na_babkip_3">
    <text>We don't care what your reasoning is, you don't belong in 'Duty' territory. Do you want the barrel of my Kalash between your cheeks?</text>
</string>
<string id="prapor_na_babkip_4">
    <text>I'll be using your cheeks if you don't get out of my way!</text>
</string>

<!-- negotiating with the bandits in the Garbage -->
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_0">
    <text>Wow, bandits!</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_1">
    <text>Wow, a jerk! You should walk away from here, you will live a little longer.</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_2">
    <text>C'est la vie! I bet you still hold a candle to Hog. In fact Hog has sent you to your death if you try to take this checkpoint. You know you won't last long, this place is too busy with Stalkers, Military, Duty and Freedom, all your natural enemies. And Hog, what does he give you, nothing except an extra piece of butter on some bread. Just remember Voronin has snipers that do not miss. Also the fact that Duty and Freedom have a truce, you must know even in your Dark Valley you do not know about the new and dangerous enemies, the 'Masters', which may find you at any time before you and your Hog can prepare. And have you met the 'Witches' yet?</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_3">
    <text>Hah, we know the 'Masters' already, and the 'Witches' we shoot or capture them to torture. So what do you want to offer, uncle jerk?</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_4">
    <text>Bring all your friends, and let's fight you bandit scum, and the last man standing can take this checkpoint, all for no profit. And if you win then you can enjoy your victory until the snipers arrive.\n\n</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_5">
    <text>%c[255,255,128,1]Look Drill, can I call you Drill? My name is Scar. I think we both know there is no money at this checkpoint, not now and most liley not ever. It just does not make any sense to make more enemies, including General Voronin with all his resources. Not for this god forsaken place.</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_6">
    <text>So moot it is! AH! As you say, we want to live too... so brother all right tell your Duty friends they can keep their checkpoint on this day. Maybe it is time for coalition, it has worked so well for the US and France.</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_7">
    <text>Fine I'll tell them. I think our paths will cross again Drill.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Bullet in Dark Valley -->
<string id="dark_pulja_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Bullet! I slept for two years, but you in that time period, well, you just became invisible. That's cute!</text>
</string>
<string id="dark_pulja_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello Scar, long time no see... 'he-he'... 'no see', get it?! Well, whatever. While you were sleeping, as you say, for two years, the science which is now under the rule of  the 'Masters' invented a new type of camouflage outfit. As you cannot see, which I am wearing. Now wait until 8pm, and I can give you more detailed instructions about Borov. You can take a nap if you like, but it is better that you don't go anywhere to far away.</text>
</string>
<string id="dark_pulja_dialog_2">
    <text>Ok Bullet how do I kill Borov?</text>
</string>
<string id="dark_pulja_dialog_3">
    <text>It's not easy, my friend, you by now have seen the snipers in the towers? Well RPGs hurt, and though we are far away, from their PDA, they can see us, and they have no hesitation on silencing the living individual. Ok, now to business. The crossbow arrows are bloody useless from any distance, only real snipers know the right weapons to bring. To hit Hog you need to go a bit north and although there's no mark on your map I've marked the ground with an army med-kit. About 20:00 Hog goes onto a roof easily visible from that point. So shoot him from that point. Yes, even after a successful or unsuccessful shot immediately depart south towards the Cordon, from whence you came. In the mean time I will open a transition point, so keep an eye on the PDA for that location, a transition to Wolf's Lair.</text>
</string>
<string id="dark_pulja_dialog_4">
    <text>I have nothing to add. The mission is set. To wait for the hour of execution. To the position.</text>
</string>
<string id="dark_pulja_dialog_5">
    <text>Ok... I'll wait until 8pm.</text>
</string>

<!-- first chat with the old man informant, Fairy's grandfather, in Wolfs Lair -->
<string id="ded_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello old man, I see your time is short. I need a crossbow!</text>
</string>
<string id="ded_dialog_1">
    <text>Fuck you for your arrogance, I already drafted Ekibastuz. I don't have a crossbow, and why in this area is everyone so full of shit... you're so full of it even your eyes are brown.</text>
</string>
<string id="ded_dialog_2">
    <text>Riiiiiight! Well, Voronin told me you had a crossbow and I urgently need it. So if you value your remaining lifetime old man and if you want to stay friends with Voronin, then tell me where it is.</text>
</string>
<string id="ded_dialog_3">
    <text>Voronin! What, like I care?! Voronin is an arse. To hell with him and you... splat punks both of you! Oh, and if you know Voronin then you need to check for lice. Anyway the crossbow is lost in the wetlands, in a swamp in the south west of Wolf's Lair, set in a deep ravine, so you will have to go for a swim to find it. I'll mark the area on your PDA. I also lost a pack of arrows near three huge boulders, just above the swamp, when a giant mutant appeared. I barely had the chance to run. So if you want it... well, you can go get it... you ass. Oh and if you want the transition to Hog, kill the mutant for me. Ah what the hell, follow me and I'll take you to the three huge boulders.</text>
</string>
<string id="ded_dialog_4">
    <text>Lead on... ol' timer.</text>
</string>

<!-- another chat with the old man informant in Wolfs Lair -->
<string id="ded_dialog_ok_0">
    <text>What a day! Honestly, I'm not sure my socks will ever dry out.</text>
</string>
<string id="ded_dialog_ok_1">
    <text>Get lost you two-bit punk, like I care. I've got my fire to dry my socks and my soups to keep me warm. So tell me, did you kill the mutant, or did you pee your pants and run away?</text>
</string>
<string id="ded_dialog_ok_2">
    <text>Oh yes old man, I killed your mutant, even with soggy socks, and I barely had to run as fast as your mother to do it!</text>
</string>
<string id="ded_dialog_ok_3">
    <text>Aaah, just get lost you punk, I wonder if anyone likes you. You've got the crossbow and the arrows I lost. Well I hope they get you killed. I don't like Hog any more than the next man, but I prefer him to you. If I didn't think Voronin would send me early to heaven, I'd kill you myself. As it is, I'll give you the transition to Dark Valley, and of course Hog. May he kill you slowly, you splat punk. When you get there head to the northeast corner and look for... aaah.... well, you need to find an invisible stalker called Bullet, he'll help you - but try not to turn up much before 20:00 hours. Check your PDA as the transition marker can fade in and out!</text>
</string>
<string id="ded_dialog_ok_4">
    <text>An invisible guy called Bullet... northeast corner... and a fading PDA marker... yeah right. Oh, and just so you know old man I pissed in your soup pot. Two meals ago.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Kruglov in the cave in Wolfs lair -->
<string id="aver_kruglov_dialog_0">
    <text>Come on, get up, what makes you think that I have come to kill you?</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_kruglov_dialog_1">
    <text>Jeez! Your in my face and your scar makes you look so mean. I thought that you were sent for my life.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_kruglov_dialog_2">
    <text>Ah come on, my name is Scar. General Voronin sent me after Sidorovich heard your alarm. Tell me more about the 'Masters'.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_kruglov_dialog_3">
    <text>I was sending a signal until the battery died. Okay, the 'Masters' base is somewhere in Zaton or in Jupiter. The power of the group is growing by leaps and bounds. The group itself consists of former factions from both the military and hirings, and unfortunately a few scientists. The organizer/boss is a psychopath, but then again very clever. The leader is Lebedev. They created a serious recruitment plan. When I was a prisoner, I could hear some of there discussions. One guy had a name like  Mark, Markan or Marco. They talked about big money. Large money transfers between Master, mercs and Witches. And there are some with invisible exoskeletons. It is easier to fight them at night. And they will soon have in full scale production another exoskeleton that they call the 'Tank'. It's not a vehicle but like a Universal Soldier-Cyborg thing. Supposedly they cannot be killed with a standard weapon. They must be crushed or the use of a gravity gun is needed. When the 'Tank' is in production they will sell them to anyone. To my knowledge they already have orders from the Mainland. Lebedev makes the deals. It all started after the last 2 global emissions. There is a unique artifact and a new science because of them being special. Progress will be made, but not for the benefit of science. I managed to escape from the Masters to Amber through the Wild Territory. But my boss, Sakharov did not run with me because the 'Masters' held his wife hostage and forced him to work for them. I made my way through Wild Territory at night, because it's full of mercenaries, and I also saw 'Witches' there. I got from Wild Territory to here through a transition only I know, and I came here to hide.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_kruglov_dialog_4">
    <text>Wow! You mean so... he was taken to Amber and he will not ever return. I'll try to release Sakharov, your boss, we all need to stop this 'Tank' thingie. Now tell me the number of stalkers in Amber.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_kruglov_dialog_5">
    <text>Scar, are you sure or what? I warn you there is, within a radius of 100 meters, a Zone of protection, with a timer. Without special protection from it no one can survive for more than just one minute, and with 61 seconds comes instant death. Protection can be disabled, the switch is in the bunker. I think there's only Sakharov and 5 guards there. Four usually outside, and one guard inside the bunker. Follow Sakharov, you'll need to get close to the bunker, kill the guards without hurting Sakharov, all within a minute! We need to get to the cave under the marsh to get through to Wild Territory, but there are now two Controllers in the cave and sometimes a bloodsucker. So follow me please, I need you to clear out the cave so we can go to Wild territory. Ok? On the way out at the upper level is a box with a nice outfit and gun. So make sure you pick them up. Oh and sorry about yet more Iron Maiden.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_kruglov_dialog_6">
    <text>Nice tip Professor, I will check the box on the way out. I know the cave you mean and I think there are marsh cockroaches along the way too, so let's go together. When we reach the swamp it's best you wait for me in the swamp near the underwater cave entrace while I clear out the cave. Once I am out I will look for you there. Another Iron Maiden track, really?! I think Led Zepplin's 'In Through The Out Door' would be more appropriate!</text>
</string>
 <string id="aver_kruglov_dialog_7">
    <text>%c[255,255,128,1]Time does not wait, so let's go brother! No music we need to listen carefully to the Zone!</text>
 </string>

<!-- talking to Kruglov after clearing out the underwater caves -->
<string id="aver_kruglov_dialog_perehod_0">
    <text>All done, I've cleared out the cave. A couple of Controllers were there, and one nasty bloodsucker.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_kruglov_dialog_perehod_1">
    <text>Cleared? Scar always watch out for bloodsuckers, some can disquise themselves. Okay come with me through the cave. We'll go to the hill side entrance in a ravine, and we can then go to Wild Territory. Ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_kruglov_dialog_perehod_2">
    <text>Okay, let's go.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Kruglov half way through Wild Territory -->
<string id="ros_kruglov_ustal_0">
    <text>How are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="ros_kruglov_ustal_1">
    <text>I'm ok, thank you Scar. Rest, catch your breath, you look a bit shaken up.</text>
</string>
<string id="ros_kruglov_ustal_2">
    <text>I don't understand anything, let alone much of what I read. The second time I shot Lebedev he disappeared quickly, and now I'm getting headaches and funny SMS's from him in poor grammer, and he threw me on the top of the crane, and it almost killed me getting down. He is driving me wacko! Is Lebedev a magician, like the beatnik looking guy Doug Henning?!</text>
</string>
<string id="ros_kruglov_ustal_3">
    <text>You do not understand correctly Scar, he might be mysterious, but a magician I don't believe. Sakharov should be able to help.</text>
</string>
<string id="ros_kruglov_ustal_4">
    <text>Well I'm rested, time to move Professor. All our hopes are with Sakharov. God forbid if he will not help me to solve a number of problems. Come on let's go!</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Krulgov just getting to Yantar -->
<string id="yan_kruglov_new_dialog_0">
    <text>How did you fall into the clutches of the 'Masters'?</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_kruglov_new_dialog_1">
    <text>I was freezing my buns off and noticed a fire. So I go there and the Masters jumped out and captured me. It was a freak'n trap. And they interrorated me too. You know, waterboarding me to get me to talk. Check your PDA, I gave you a recipe for an artifact conversion.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_kruglov_new_dialog_2">
    <text>For the recipe thanks. Okay go warm yourself and I'll talk to your boss. Who are these 'Masters' for crying out loud?!</text>
</string>

<!-- Recipe conversation with Sakharov in Yantar/Amber -->
<string id="yan_saharov_laba_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, thanks for the recipe. What does it mean? And what about X-16?</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_saharov_laba_dialog_1">
    <text>It means you need to disable the installation of a new Laboratory in X-16. The problem is that there is no transition into X-16, so to enable a transition you'll need to find a activator/deactivator for the Psi-field that is around the entrance. It's similar to the field that was around the bunker, but it only has a radius of 80 meters and a timer for 1 minute. You'll need to think and act quickly. One thing, how many 'Masters' guards that are near the entrance to the lab I do not know, and know that some may be invisible. You have to be careful and smart. They always have Radar. But at least I know roughly where the deactivator is. The best stradigy is to run in and kill one or more of them and then run back out before the timer finishes, over and over again, until they are all dead.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_saharov_laba_dialog_2">
    <text>So where is it?</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_saharov_laba_dialog_3">
    <text> The Deactivator is in the brick building to the entrance to the lab, it's on the 3rd floor in the window opening, in a rucksack. Well, unless it's been moved. It's not a complex device. Disabling the protection zone will automatically open the transition into Lab X-16 and it will appear on your PDA map. I beg of you Scar to disable this protection field, and I will tell you a lot about some of the valuable modifiers. Take this tuned Psi helmet. Voronin promised to send his men to guard this bunker.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_saharov_laba_dialog_4">
    <text>Ah Voronin's guys, that's good. There is this guy called Dimon who is looking for his father. Maybe you know something about that. If anything he would be a great guard for you. The Psi-helmet looks horrible, hope it works, but thanks anyway! Well I'm off I go into X-16.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Saharov/Sakharov after rescuing him in Yantar with Kruglov dead -->
<string id="yan_kruglov_new_dialog1_0">
    <text>Are you okay Professor? What happened to Kruglov?</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_kruglov_new_dialog1_1">
    <text>You know Kruglov too? Well it was the worst of bad timing, Kruglov came round the corner just as I arrived with my guards, they recognized him and shot him on sight. They would have shot me too if you hadn't intervened.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_kruglov_new_dialog1_2">
    <text>Damn, I'm sorry, I shouldn't have let him get ahead. We were coming to rescue you... damn it to hell. Well at least I got here in time to save you. So let's complete Kruglov's plan, how many of these 'Masters' are there in Amber? Or do you call it Yantar? Even approximately?! Oh, by the way, do you remember me?</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_kruglov_new_dialog1_3">
    <text>You are Scar? I heard Kruglov mention that name. Aaaah this is pointless. The 'Masters', as they are called, are invisible and almost impossible to kill. Only at night do you stand a chance. I don't know what Kruglov was thinking. All he loved was the Zone, the anomalies, the company of mutants. Oh brother what a pity he came back and got killed! Yantar or Amber, they both mean here, call it what you like.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_kruglov_new_dialog1_4">
    <text>Yes they call me Scar. I wish I had come here alone, but I did not know the transitions. The penalty was for your partner. Now Professor I've seen... well, not seen, complete invisibility in Dark Valley. Now tell me everything.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_kruglov_new_dialog1_5">
    <text>Well there's six guards. A guard in the bunker, which watches me, but sometimes two watch when they change shifts. Outside is a third and two that are invisible. And those two you just eliminated. From the bunker, within 120 meters approximately, is an active Psi radiation field. You will only be able to be in it for about 45 seconds, and if you fall under its influence you will live only as long as an ordinary lit match, so there's no way you can take them on with this active Psi field. I see one single option Scar. My 'Masters', ahem, allow me out here for fresh air, and I have no Psi-protection, for that you need special armour and an injection. They open temporary one-way teleports to move around. The return teleport device, a URT, is left under a truck, a ZIL. I can adjust the URT but I will need to warm it up for five minutes by the fire, if the return teleport opens too early they will be very suspicious and be ready and waiting. In the meantime you stop any zombies that come close, don't kill any more than you have to as they will attack the Masters too. Then I'll take the URT and try and use it over there, a little closer to the bunker, and we may need to do some waving of our arms to see each other. Next you will, in a very short time, you will be able to teleport into the bunker through a bubble next to me, and remove the guard immediately and send me an SMS that the guard is removed. Then I will teleport in and turn off the Psi-field and lock all the doors. Then you are free, without injections or Psi-helmet, to eliminate those guards outside. Well how do you like my plan Scar?</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_kruglov_new_dialog1_6">
    <text>Wow you think quick Prof! So, we have a plan and it means we live Professor. Ingenious too! No wonder I once decided to help scientists and... I hear something coming... ok Prof it's time to act quickly!!</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Saharov after teleport into the bunker -->
<string id="yan_saharov_new_dialog_0">
    <text>Well professor, so far so good. But how do I get outside to finish the job?</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_saharov_new_dialog_1">
    <text>Excuse me Scar. Indeed, I see that the door is now also locked from the outside.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_saharov_new_dialog_2">
    <text>Come on teleport me back. I don't know how we're getting out otherwise.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_saharov_new_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes Scar, ok the teleport is behind you, just walk up to the far PC on the table.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_saharov_new_dialog_4">
    <text>See you soon!</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to General Voronin after defending the scientists in Cordon, he sends you to kill Hog -->
<string id="voronin_borov_prapor_start_0">
    <text>I'm back General. I hope you have calmed down after the kidnapping of your wife. Question why not strengthen positions at the southern exit from the Bar?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_borov_prapor_start_1">
    <text>Well the place has sort of calmed down a bit. I was informed of your exploits in Cordon. You did a great job. Listen now, I have a proposal for you. Before I learned about the kidnapping of my wife I was haunted by the excessive arrogance of Hog, the bandit leader in Garbage. Then I found out that Prapor takes bribes for passage to the Bar, rather than following his orders. Before I could act Prapor escaped, but I don't think he will have gone far, as he knows almost no one well, and his legs are short. I know we are weak to the south, but the only real danger would come from Wild Territory. Lebedev's clans rule there for the moment at least. We heard about your negotiations with the bandits at the checkpoint and really appreciate your ability to gain some temporary peace with them, and so our group will act with respect even though you are a former mercenary. I have some news for you. Your friends here in the Zone have managed to get your daughter moved to Germany into a good hospital, but her treatment will be cost 2,000,000 in Rubles. So I suggest you try to find jobs.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_borov_prapor_start_2">
    <text>Thank you General for the news. I must thank my friend some day. How will I raise 2 million rubles?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_borov_prapor_start_3">
    <text>Well now, seeing as you asked... have you worked with silent weapons?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_borov_prapor_start_4">
    <text>Well in my youth I loved archery and knife throwing.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_borov_prapor_start_5">
    <text>Excellent! If you shoot a bow then you should cope with a crossbow. I want you to eliminate Hog in Dark Valley. I currently do not have any good snipers, but I have good intelligence, the best in fact. If you accept this job I'll give you an advance of 100,000 rubles, and after a successful completion you'll get another 400,000. To get to Dark Valley you will have to go through Wolf's Lair now. The transition I will put on your PDA. In a forest hut find grandfather Shchukar. I'll notify him you're coming. He is my informant. I warn you now that he can be... aah... difficult. Anyway he will tell you everything and he will supply you with a crossbow. He will then give you a transition to Dark Valley. There you will have to find my best scout, he is called 'Bullet'. Whatever you do, don't go straight to the bandit base, which is located in the Northeast part of the Dark Valley, because they have a Psi field which is very effective. Three of our men have already died trying to approach the base. Bullet said Hog always goes for a brief break onto a roof top for a breath of fresh air from 20.00h to 21.00h. Bullet will have detailed instructions and can tell you the best place to shoot from.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_borov_prapor_start_6">
    <text>Well that sounds pretty simple General. Just make a note on my PDA so that nothing is missed, and I guess I'll be back pretty soon.</text>
</string>

<!-- Talking to Voronin at Bar after killing Hog -->
<string id="voronin_borov_prapor_ok_0">
    <text>Well General Hog is dead.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_borov_prapor_ok_1">
    <text>Bravo! A job well done. Would you like to join us?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_borov_prapor_ok_2">
    <text>Thanks General, but no I don't want too join your group at this point in time.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_borov_prapor_ok_3">
    <text>Ok, well as for your fee, I have yet to see your work.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_borov_prapor_ok_4">
    <text>What does that matter, all you need to know is Hog is dead.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_borov_prapor_ok_5">
    <text>I am saying that I only have your word that Hog is dead. While you were in Wolf's Lair Sidorovich called, his radio detected an alarm - it was very short, but clear. From what Sidrovich could work out the signal was close, only about 2 km away from his hut in the 'Wolfs Lair'. Previously there were scientists working to study the caves there. There are a few caves in Wolfs Lair, one near the hut, and one under the central marsh, but the signal indicated the Northwestern part of the Lair, and somewhere in that area should be a third cave about the same place where the Oleg Tango group camps. So be a friend and find the cave and see what's there. Say 'yes' and you'll get your money. Sidorovich asked you to see him when you arrive.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_borov_prapor_ok_6">
    <text>I wonder... well, okay General, 'yes', I will go in search of the cave. The air in a cave is cleaner and with fewer anomalies at least. As for Sidorovich I will go to his hut and see if he has any additional information.</text>
</string>

<!-- second talk with Kostya about getting to Clear Sky base -->
<string id="kostya2_dialog_0">
    <text>Ok, so how do I get to the Clear Sky base?</text>
</string>
<string id="kostya2_dialog_1">
    <text>Well then Scar... we need to use the artifact 'Black Hole'. I'll give you one now. Let me explain how this works: go and stand somewhere sensible, then put the artefact in your pistol hand and 'use' it, like pulling the trigger. This creates the return point from the Clear Sky base. I'll create a transition to take you to the base, so stand a little way away from me. When you get to the base you will have to find another 'Black Hole' to create the return transition. Go to the house that used to hold the repairman, get up on the boards to the right and you will get to the roof. There is a rucksack in a tree, and you need to jump on that side gable roof to reach it. In that rucksack you'll find another anomaly 'Black Hole', so you can create the return connection to the first Black Hole you used. But there is one thing - when the two anomalies are activated, anything can use it, any livestock, including hostile stalkers. So before you activate the return anomaly from the base, from the building that held Lebedev, find the five absolutes. You must pick them up and bring them to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="kostya2_dialog_2">
    <text>Uhmmm, so I use the first Black Hole you give me, this creates my return point. Then using your transition I go to Clear Sky base, to find another Black Hole in order to return. What are the Absolutes, and why do you need them so badly?</text>
</string>
<string id="kostya2_dialog_3">
    <text>The absolutes I will take to the scientists to study, and, with care, they will create versions of black holes. About Lebedev, meet with him, shoot straight, and then you will convince him, in your abilities. Lebedev's out there now, I think in the Bar, hiding because he planned some crimes in the area, and the military would arrest him if he was to leave, so be careful Scar! Now I set the teleport to one side, and you activate your 'black hole'... just stand back a bit further away... go on, away... Oh and be careful in the Clear Sky base, it is occupied by many Mercenaries!</text>
</string>
<string id="kostya2_dialog_4">
    <text>Okay, I'll activate the 'black hole'...</text>
</string>

<!-- third talk with Kostya upon return from the Clear Sky base -->
<string id="kostya3_dialog_0">
    <text>Done! I found some Artifacts and Absolutes. Lebedev was not at the base, just a few guards that, well, I had to eliminate.</text>
</string>
<string id="kostya3_dialog_1">
    <text>Excellent Scar! You're a genius. Lebedev now cannot be invulnerable without them. Worn on the belt they create a portal radius. If threatened then teleporting to another location is possible. Whoever has this artifact on their belt has almost nothing to fear because they can teleport to another location within about 500 meters from where they are.</text>
</string>
<string id="kostya3_dialog_2">
    <text>Well your the genius. Where did you get so much information? Here take the Absolutes. I do not need them and I surely don't want to understand them by reading an encyclopedia. To much reading makes my brain-cloud act up.</text>
</string>
<string id="kostya3_dialog_3">
    <text>I'm not just a technician, I am a technician with experience!</text>
</string>

<!-- forth talk with Kostya upon return from the Clear Sky base -->
<string id="kostya4_dialog_0">
    <text>What the hell was that?</text>
</string>
<string id="kostya4_dialog_1">
    <text>I don't know... these Absolutes... can do wonders... however not all wonders are wonderful. I put a couple of recipes on your PDA, look at them at your leisure. Now let's get to Cordon.</text>
</string>
<string id="kostya4_dialog_2">
    <text>Impressive, but I would say those wonders we just killed where not fake. Well yea it's time to the Cordon. It's straight past the church. It's a shame we cannot just transition there like Lebedev.</text>
</string>
<string id="kostya4_dialog_3">
    <text>Gee... run or walk?!</text>
</string>
 <string id="kostya4_dialog_4">
    <text>Either will work for me. Let's move to Cordon.</text>
 </string>

<!-- first conversation with General Voronin in the Bar -->
<string id="voronin_dialog_bar_0">
    <text>Greetings General, you look a little out of sorts? Are you constipated?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_dialog_bar_1">
    <text>No, my wife has been kidnapped. I just found out. She worked in journalism. She once told me journalist are untouchable! Fool! The kidnapper's leader says for her freedom he wants a complete dismantling of 'Duty'. I now have the benefit of a month for reflection. I already know why you came, and about the latest developments in Cordon and in Agroprom. When you are finished with the scientists we need to talk. The 'Tango' group is here in the Bar. Go talk to the clown wearing the cowboy hat, then talk to the sexy bitch in black leather.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_dialog_bar_2">
    <text>I am sorry to here about your wife General. Well I'll talk to clown now.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_dialog_bar_3">
    <text>Thanks, see ya Scar.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Vasilina -->
<string id="and_muzlo_dialog_0">
    <text>Well I assume the transceiver is working. Can we listen to some music?</text>
</string>
<string id="and_muzlo_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes! We like to listen to music too, and it also keeps the mutants away.</text>
</string>
<string id="and_muzlo_dialog_2">
    <text>Pump up the volume gorgeous.</text>
</string>
<string id="and_muzlo_dialog_3">
    <text>Sure, no problem.</text>
</string>

<!-- Talking to Lebedev in Agroprom -->
<string id="agr_lebedev_dialog_0">
    <text>Hmmm, Lebedev, what an ass, the former head of the 'Clear Sky' faction, and now the leader of some criminals. You of all people... really?! In your sixties too. To hell you will go, and that is just around the corner!</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_lebedev_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh Scar! Don't be so sanctimonious. How many innocent souls have you yourself put under the cross. Or does my memory play tricks... anyway... I called you to seriously discuss your existence.</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_lebedev_dialog_2">
    <text>This is how to understand my existence? What do you want? I had one such conversation two years ago about my existence.</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_lebedev_dialog_3">
    <text>I want you to work for me. I need you because no one else knows the Zone better than you or I. It is better to help these soldiers who have no country. Look, I know where they hide, those renounced famed eggheads. They cheated me and are hiding in Cordon. But not for long will they find Cordon a paradise. Some time tomorrow they will find out! Scar, I'll give you invulnerability and a lot of money. Look I tell you, my daughter is very sick, as they say, for the sins of the parents are afflicted upon their children. I steal yes, but to get money for an operation in the most expensive clinic.</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_lebedev_dialog_4">
    <text>I'll find my own way Lebedev.</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_lebedev_dialog_5">
    <text>What... you are a fool Scar! In the Zone there is a stalker who got rid of the same disease as that of your daughter. Believe me right here in the zone. To shoot me I do not advise. I'll throw you a kilimeter into the air and you will splat on the ground. Just guts, in different directions. Ha-ha-ha! You know what I mean - thud, splat, slop all over!</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_lebedev_dialog_6">
    <text>I am aware of your abilities you bastard. If activator goes with you, then I'm gonna bust it out of you like a coin from a piggy bank. As for those absolutes that you use to be invulnerability, well I have taken them from you. Do not be surprised, I was in your base, so that I know that you can 'jump' away from bullets.</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_lebedev_dialog_7">
    <text>What? How could this happen? Where are my absolutes you bastard scumbag?! Give them to me or regret it.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Oleg in Cordon, group Tango went there from the bar to protect the scientists -->
<string id="lebed_tango_ataka_dialog_0">
    <text>Wow, we all finally made it.</text>
</string>
<string id="lebed_tango_ataka_dialog_1">
    <text>Looks that way to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="lebed_tango_ataka_dialog_2">
    <text>I have an idea, why don't you mumble incoherent semi-russian-serbo-croatian at me?</text>
</string>
<string id="lebed_tango_ataka_dialog_3">
    <text>Ok, no prablymskio! Victor needed to leave the Bar because he was as drunk as a skunk, and they told him to get out. There is another stalker called Airborne who is on a mission. Now you must go to Demyan, his concealed camp is to the west.</text>
</string>
<string id="lebed_tango_ataka_dialog_4">
    <text>Ok! While we are waiting, I have one more question.</text>
</string>
<string id="lebed_tango_ataka_dialog_5">
    <text>What?</text>
</string>
<string id="lebed_tango_ataka_dialog_6">
    <text>You said you would have more information. And this Strelok guy is always one step ahead of everyone. Have you questioned all the others?</text>
</string>
<string id="lebed_tango_ataka_dialog_7">
    <text>I can vouch for them... they are my buds. Anyway I have a funny feeling that in a little while the bad guys will arrive, probably from the North. It's just a hunch of course.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Pr. Goryunov at the end of X-10 - after clearing out the scientists and guards - only Tank left -->
<string id="x10_uch_dialog_0">
    <text>Well it seems that I run the installation now, and in that case you should come to the surface. Only I wonder, what do you have. If you do not comply then I will shoot you, and if you comply then you can live, but without weapons. Going up?!</text>
</string>
<string id="x10_uch_dialog_1">
    <text>Please do not kill me! I was forced to work here. I have nothing to do with anything. To start the installation we still have to wait at least a week, and now all...</text>
</string>
<string id="x10_uch_dialog_2">
    <text>I don't believe you. I met the scientists a few days ago and they do not usually know how to handle weapons but these thugs carry machine guns and fight tenaciously. And you're here to try to resume what was once disabled by a stalker nicknamed 'Strelok'. He did it to save lives and you for money... aaahh scumbags. Now tell me who's in charge here, these 'Masters'? And where to find them?</text>
</string>
<string id="x10_uch_dialog_3">
    <text>I really do not know. Only one thing I can say. They are somewhere in the far north in the Zone and run a radio with a distorted voice. Please do not kill me!</text>
</string>
<string id="x10_uch_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, okay. One thing, where's the DVD with Professor Sakharov's formulas?</text>
</string>
<string id="x10_uch_dialog_5">
    <text>The drive?! Oh... it's behind that door, but it should not be opened. Behind that door is a faulty copy of the cyborg 'Tank'. He is here to experience a large dose of Psi radiation. We planned to start the installation soon and on this cyborg we experiment.</text>
</string>
<string id="x10_uch_dialog_6">
    <text>Come on open it up, let's look at your can'tank'erous cyborg reject. I'll kick its ass! I'll pick up the DVD and then we can get out of here.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Drill in the southern farm building in Dark Valley -->
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_val_0">
    <text>Well, your friend Hog, he, uhmm, had an accident. Yea, that's it, he fell onto a bullet.</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_val_1">
    <text>What? Hog?! Wow... and... uh... hey aren't you Scar?</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_val_2">
    <text>Yes I'm Scar... you remember me from the Duty checkpoint in Garbage. Good! Anyway Voronin sent me. Now tell me how to disable the artificial Psi-radiation field around the northern factory. Our mutual friend told me about it. He had asked me to remove Hog and any other stalkers that get in my way. So help me to disable this damn field.</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_val_3">
    <text>Okay Scar, welcome! Now we too like you cannot pass through this area because Hog disabled our defenses against it, which is issued to each guard in Hog's clan. The protection area effective up to 80 meters. You can only disable it with a deactivator which I think is in the camp near the garages. There is simply no antidote, and I'm sure you've realize that. But there's a 'reformed' Psi-dog, white in colour, that we call 'Bax'. And he has been trained to steal. You can use Bax to fetch a deactivator. However, Hog hated that dog and has it locked in a basement. In short Scar you'll go to the southern gate of the northern factory and command Bax to steal it for you. Afterwards he'll then run towards the transition to Garbage. Try not to lose sight of him. There he'll drop the deactivator and go through the transition to Garbage. After you've got the deactivator your PDA will be updated so you are immune to the Psi field. Then all you have to do is break into the base and find the documents. Just do it! Oh and the dog, Bax aways sleeps at night, so go there in the afternoon.</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_val_4">
    <text>So go to the southern gate of the northern factory, give a command, watch for the dog, follow it to the transition, pick up the 'thingie', go back to the base, kill all the bandits, find how to deactivate the force field? Are you joking?! Give me a hint or two at least?!\n\n</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_val_5">
    <text>%c[255,255,128,1]Yeah sure... what the hell... why not... I'll wing it. If I pull this off they will write a song about me - 'Who let the dog out?'.</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_val_6">
    <text>C'mon Scar, you know you love a challenge. To help clean up the area as best you can of bandits would be greatly appreciated. If Bax's tail pops up then run straight to the fire truck near the refueling building. Don't get to close or you'll turn into a zombie. If you pull this off then I owe you. We heard that you have a daughter that is seriously ill. Perhaps we can help you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_val_7">
    <text>Thanks, I appreciate your thoughts about my daughter. With Hog gone you could be the next great bandit 'Kahuna'.</text>
</string>

<!-- DR seems like they are not used
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_val_1_0">
    <text>What is going on here?</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_val_1_1">
    <text>Will you help capture the base and force Hog out?</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_val_1_2">
    <text>It would be better if you told me how to disable the artificial Psi-radiation. A representative told me about it. I'll help you if you help me.</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_val_1_3">
    <text>Hey Scar, nice to see you. We cannot pass through this area of the Zone because Hog has Psi defenses, and we can only get within 80 meters of it. His guys are protected in hourly increments because they have the antidote. There is a deactivator that turns off their defense and also opens a transition to Garbage. Duty is there and has a disk with instructions on how to disable this protection. This deactivator should be in or near the garage. Deactivator not normally carry and hide in nychku - near the garages. There simply no antidote, not to fall, but there is a bonus. We once had stopped psevdosobachiny female and she was a puppy. Mates took pity and took small to him. Otpoili, fattening. Chases stuck - 'Bucks'.  He grew up and started to pull all the base. Arts, even brought. One day, dragged and tried to put on a gas mask. We ugaral over him. Fun was vaasche! Next Hog ordered his patrol to determine.
    Ie kitsch in the basement there, and who kichmane - to protect them. Then vaasche, methylene blue repaint it caused that different from his, blood. Bucks like to blame, apparently, but it at Hog Jail identified himself already as 2 months. He became very angry. I took pity, and otognul grid so that it can fall down, but he does not run for some reason. Maybe this time - get through? In short, Scar... We used to trust Bax deactivator zone, ie Click 'Bucks Bucks - Deactivate!' He rushes to Nychko and Deactivate enough so that from the teeth, without difficulty, not to vomit. If you did not manage to pull out, they had to run after him, to the transition to a landfill. There he spat Deactivate and we opened the transition. And, if you go and click bucks? The point of closest approach to a window that goes from the basement of Kichi - I throw off you on the PDA, and you try, as much as we used to, to make him take the Deactivate? Just click it! Me, he probably will not listen to you, and you people, like, new here, and suddenly - a ride? Yes, the Bucks late in the evening, night, can not jump, so - better to go in the morning or afternoon.</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_val_1_4">
    <text>Do I look like a Cynologist or circus actor? I know nothing about dogs. From my canine, either from your entire Codlea - a ballerina! Found acrobat!.</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_val_1_5">
    <text>I wish you were! Not many stalkers claim to be dog handlers in the Zone, Ha-ha! And that.. Not a bad idea. Possible and handlers in the Zone, to pretend. Ha-ha!</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_val_1_6">
    <text>That's good, Scar. Well, then, - Bucks very angry at us for kichu and that he rushed to tear everyone, that is, Tale-based, and took deactivator, if you spec, the Strip, where possible, the yard, and as snipers from towers - better off. If the Bucks with kichmanskoy tails pop up, then run straight to the fire truck, and right - to fill the building. Zone before it is lacking, but near 3 meters you approach - just turn into zombarey. By kichmanskomu window is also not suitable, because zone before it gets. If you do not know where the box, then I'll explain: It is the near corner of the construction site, seen here, ie there and a basement with kichmanom. If it works, then I owe you. When we at the base, I'll show you sekretik Hog, though, I did not really boom-boom, but you have this infa probably Hotness. We the bazaar thy ensigns - listened to, and that you have a daughter in the will of the sick something in nature, serious. Can help than any.. Th!</text>
</string>
<string id="dja_dja_dialog_val_1_7">
    <text>But sniff like a woman, not good! Not in the Fe - ES-be! INFA really need you. To hell with you. Went to turn into a dog handlers. If everything is OK, then give you back the throne Hog. infa but with you, and for shit - not a ride with me.</text>
</string>
-->


<!-- Talking to Igor on return from Marsh -->
<string id="uch_dialog2_0">
    <text>I found a good guy in the Marsh called Kostya. Teleport specialist. Will undoubtedly be useful to you. Was a great help to me in entering Lebedev's base. Lebedev was not there, just mercenary guards, and I found a few absolutes that once belonged to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="uch_dialog2_1">
    <text>Excellent Scar! We sent a message to the checkpoint in Agroprom about who disappeared. First contact was with him, but Scar, I still don't know if the message has got to the military team in Agroprom. The military helped the scientists to get to us, and we have to warn them. Yes, I'll give you coordinates to the transition to Agroprom, used by the scientists. It may be better to go through the Dump, as we've seen mercenaries, and strong radioactive field if you arrive there from our Cordon. I'll give you some ammo. Well, like to go?</text>
</string>
<string id="uch_dialog2_2">
    <text>Good! I'll go to Agroprom and talk with the Military Commander in Agroprom. I'll go through the Garbage, see if I can find a trader maybe...</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Igor about the rescued scientist who just got shot -->
<string id="uch_dialog1_0">
    <text>Whoa, what happened there... where's the sniper and who did he shoot?</text>
</string>
<string id="uch_dialog1_1">
    <text>Hell... the scientists will need to hide in the cellar, they can rest there too. Solvador informed me that accidentally intercepted conversation between the mercenaries and Lebedev. They are preparing to attack the complex SRI in Agroprom. But the radio for the military does not work at the moment. Scar can you go and warn the commander of the Research Institute of the impending attack on the complex? And also in the Marsh we got a steady SOS signal. Who needs help is not known. Yep, that's another matter. Look as long as you help us I'll give you an AK74, scope, and some ammo, it's all yours, though a bit old. The commander of the checkpoint is a bit weird, he lets his troops drink on duty, so be careful around them. I'll put coordinates for the transition to the Marsh on your PDA. Well, Agroprom or Marsh?</text>
</string>
<string id="uch_dialog1_2">
    <text>To the SOS in the Marsh! About Agroprom, we sent a messenger to the roadblock. It's a long time since I was in the Marsh.</text>
</string>
<string id="uch_dialog1_3">
    <text>You wanted to contact someone, remember?</text>
</string>
<string id="uch_dialog1_4">
    <text>No I do not remember.</text>
</string>
<string id="uch_dialog1_5">
    <text>Okay, no matter, we'll try General Voronin and see if something comes up. He has great communications. You have saved a bit of information about your friend.</text>
</string>
<string id="uch_dialog1_6">
    <text>Another name - Alex Alfeorov.</text>
</string>
<string id="uch_dialog1_7">
    <text>Clear! Go into the Marsh, once he decided. Do not forget to check the label on the PDA, the SOS signal, and no screwing around Scar. And try to avoid getting into a fight since the forces are not in your favour!</text>
</string>
<string id="uch_dialog1_8">
    <text>Agreed. I'll go to the Marsh.</text>
</string>

<!-- Talk to Igor after killing the sniper -->
<string id="uch_dialog3_0">
    <text>The sniper is dead meat.</text>
</string>
<string id="uch_dialog3_1">
    <text>Damn... you're cold... well... okay, thanks, you've saved us Scar. We have one more request. Since Lebedev wants to kill us we need help from the Bar. No one wants to go, so please go to the Bar and talk to Voronin and the 'Tango' group members, and ask them to come and protect us for a fee? The 'Tango' group leader is called Oleg. They are loners and no one really knows what they are usually up too. Voronin is a tough cookie so don't be a wise ass with him. The duty guys at the checkpoint will let you through. I'll give you a recipe that I just aquired yesterday.</text>
</string>
<string id="uch_dialog3_2">
    <text>I heard of a group called 'Tango'. I'll go and talk to them for you. Besides I need to wet me whistle.</text>
</string>

<string id="uch_dialog33_0">
    <text>Damn, Fans is dead. I wonder if he was a target too!</text>
</string>
<string id="uch_dialog33_1">
    <text>Since Lebedev wants to come here and take over we need the assistance a group of stalkers that hang out in the Bar. Getting to the Bar can be a real hassel. Solvador I spoke about an interesting group that has helped them break free from the clutches of some mercenaries, and escorted them to the military in Agroprom. The leader of this group is Oleg 'Tango'. They are loners, but their true purpose is unknown. Could you Scar go to the Bar and ask them help us? For a fee! In Garbage at the 'Duty' checkpoint the leader is called Prapor. They say that to get to the Bar he takes money. If he can't get any money he will threaten you somehow. Tell him you need to talk to General Voronin. I know him well, he is a ass. I put a recipe on you PDA. Well?</text>
</string>
<string id="uch_dialog33_2">
    <text>Yes I will persuade them to let me pass. The Bar seems is an interesting place. Well if this 'Tango' guy and his group are in the Bar then I will talk to them.</text>
</string>

<!-- first chat with Oleg Tango in the Bar -->
<string id="bar_tango_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi, I've been sent on behalf of the scientists who helped you way back when. They are in danger in Cordon. Lebedev knows their whereabouts and plans to attack Cordon. They ask you to help them, not for free, of course. If your group does not mind I'll go with you to help protect the scientists.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_tango_dialog_1">
    <text>We have a problem. There is a group of 'Arrow' stalkers that are always a step ahead. What their purpose is we just don't know. They must be under some sort of contract and are paid large fees, according to rumors anyway. I have been told about you and your positive actions, but how do I trust you? Your up for hiring, so anyone could hire you! Okay, I'm sorry, I have bad nerves this week. Okay so be it we go to Cordon. If you're with us get to know our group first. Talk to Anya the girl in the black cat suit.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_tango_dialog_2">
    <text>I am with you for sure. I'll go get acquainted with the lady in leather.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Sakharov after shutting down X-16 - god knows what's going on with wife-kidnappings... a very confusing 'sub-plot'... -->
<string id="yan_saharov_laba_est_dialog_0">
    <text>Ok so I've done what Strelok did and X-16 is turned off again. I wonder what exactly that machine does... Hey, I need a transition to Radar. I am sure that Strelok went that way.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_saharov_laba_est_dialog_1">
    <text>Thank you Scar! You are a valiant stalker. If you decide to go to Radar, then I have a warning for you. The 'Masters' are guarding it as they are working hard to accelerate the restart of the Brain Scorcher. If you're lucky Scar find my disk with formulas that was half of my life's work and return it to me. Please! I've been told that Strelok was in the Laboratory X-10, which is in Radar. In the laboratory there might also be some scientists recruited for work, under the protection of the 'Masters'. Starting the Brain Scorcher and the 5 Psi antennas can only be done from inside this laboratory. I will try to contact the military to support you in Radar, and I hope that his wife was released. The Masters tried to communicate with him and then with me. I said nothing! Frankly I'm confused.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_saharov_laba_est_dialog_2">
    <text>Rather than ramble on in semi-Russian Professor, I'll just say that you should go to Cordon. It's not safe here. I'm now very confused about who kidnapped who's wife, but let's hope it gets sorted out. Ask Dimon to take you to the Cordon. If you're lucky, I will be able to return your drive.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Drill in Dark Valley at the southern farm -->
<string id="bur_val_one_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, what are you doing here Drill?</text>
</string>
<string id="bur_val_one_dialog_1">
    <text>Well hello uncle hardened mercenary. We three had to run because Hog has not forgiven us for the contract I made with you at the 'Duty' checkpoint in Garbage. So we are here hiding in the dark. Hog in general is a bit of a hard-ass, his whole head is stoned like a freak. Well that's my life, what about yours?</text>
</string>
<string id="bur_val_one_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm here to kill Hog. And I need to get into Lab X-18.</text>
</string>
<string id="bur_val_one_dialog_3">
    <text>Yeah, sounds good to me. Is there some way I can help out?</text>
</string>
<string id="bur_val_one_dialog_4">
    <text>Maybe, but not right now. By the way, I like the outfits you guys are wearing.</text>
</string>

<!-- Talking to Loser in Agroprom, after protecting the scientists in the Cordon -->
<string id="start_taynik_0">
    <text>Hello gunsmith! Dimak suggested we talk. My name is Scar and I have a question. Did you know stalker nicknamed Strelok? Also, Dimak hinted at some mystery about Arrow?</text>
</string>
<string id="start_taynik_1">
    <text>Sure I know Dimak. Strelok asked me to upgrade some of his things a few times. After he successfully disabled the Brain Scorcher he went to the north of the Zone and I've never seen him again. He left the teleport which blocks the entrance to the catacombs here in Agroprom. It looks like a key to his puzzle is down there. One stalker found his notebook in a bandit stash, it describes an alternate way into the underground, and some necesssary device. The place where this device was hidden was not clear, the only clue - 'Rise above the iron way viewpoint'. Lots of folks have searched Agroprom and found nothing. My thought is that 'Iron way' is a railway track, or something related, but honestly a child could work that part out?! To be frank I wouldn't want to find the way in because of the strong waves of mutants in that dungeon. I tell you, some nights the ground shakes from their excited state underground. Anyway if you find the rucksack with the device there will be another note, which should give more details. If you want, you can look around the tracks here in Agroprom, buildings and towers around ir. Of course it could all just be another myth in the zone I guess.</text>
</string>
<string id="start_taynik_2">
    <text>'Rise above the iron way vewpoint'... 'Iron way'... that's great... just great...</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Raphael first in Military Warehouses -->
<string id="raf_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Raphael my name is Scar. Some friends of mine have a big problem. Their partner in the military was to communicate with you. This guy betrayed them and I need from you what you two talked about. They say you approached him.</text>
</string>
<string id="raf_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh, Navy with a blue beret. I met him a week ago in Radar. We drank a lot of vodka, but vodka was bad. I passed out. Later we were caught by a specialist from the 'Arrows' group.</text>
</string>
<string id="raf_dialog_2">
    <text>Provide specifics, how did you get here and why was he in Radar? You seem very young to be in the zone. Please keep it short too, my ability to interpret Russian is not so good.</text>
</string>
<string id="raf_dialog_3">
    <text>I'm nearly 18, and I have a black belt, and I can do moonwalks like Michael Jackson. I am in good shape, and I ... ... sorry what was the question?</text>
</string>
<string id="raf_dialog_4">
    <text>You're nobody special. I said, 'keep it short'!</text>
</string>
<string id="raf_dialog_5">
    <text>Ok in short, I wanted to come to this area because I was bored working with my father. He is in agriculture and grows potatoes. I met Gastello by accident and he brought me here to this house. I tried to go to Radar but Cap at the barrier sent me to Lukash. I said to Lukash that I wanted to join Freedom. He said I was to young, and just a brat. But he let me go to Radar where I met Navy. Navy sure does drink a lot.</text>
</string>
<string id="raf_dialog_6">
    <text>Navy, what an idiot. I would have slapped him silly and kicked him in the arse. How did he manage to get out of there? What did you two talk about?</text>
</string>
<string id="raf_dialog_7">
    <text>Yes, he said he had fled! I didn't think Navy was like that, to run away that is. When I met him for the first time he was cheerful, chattering like a machine gun, and this time he had not said much, as if scared. Navy had a stash in Red Forest, he showed it to me. There he had military binoculars, and so much more. But when I checked yesterday the stash again it was empty.</text>
</string>
<string id="raf_dialog_8">
    <text>Like my friends say, crawling won't get you to far! And it's not right to pry into the affairs of aquaintances. Anyhow, thanks for the information.</text>
</string>
<string id="raf_dialog_9">
    <text>Listen, I found a box of dynamite. I found it in a little swamp. Almost dried up.</text>
</string>
<string id="raf_dialog_10">
    <text>Okay I'll buy the dynamite, on one condition. I found a weapon in a swamp and it is heavily rusted. Needs a special lubricant 'Menstr', it is called. Girlfriend is out of town. Feng, she does not want to talk to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="raf_dialog_11">
    <text>And this 'Menstr', don't the merchants have any?</text>
</string>
<string id="raf_dialog_12">
    <text>None so far. Of course there are the 'Witches', but they just shoot at anything that moves. So maybe you will have better luck with the girl in the barn.</text>
</string>
<string id="raf_dialog_13">
    <text>Okay I'll go see 'Feng'. No girl resists me. I'll get you the lubricant.</text>
</string>
<string id="raf_dialog_14">
    <text>Okay I'll wait.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Anya in the bar for the first time -->
<string id="vedma_reklama_0">
    <text>Attractive blonde girl dressed in tight black leather in the Zone, I never would have thought of that. What are you doing here? You're not a 'Witch' member are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="vedma_reklama_1">
    <text>A 'Witch'? Well, if you meet one you'll know for sure, no I'm not! What you are doing here?</text>
</string>
<string id="vedma_reklama_2">
    <text>Errm... sure go ahead... answer them. I am not here for love, that's for sure.</text>
</string>
<string id="vedma_reklama_3">
    <text>I have a small video clip which explains your fascination very well.</text>
</string>
<string id="vedma_reklama_4">
    <text>Go ahead, put it on the screen.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Anya in the bar post video clip -->
<string id="vedma_reklama_0_1">
    <text>If they're 'Witches' then I have little to fear... other than drowning in drool.</text>
</string>
<string id="vedma_reklama_1_1">
    <text>Ha, meet a 'Witch', then ask to yourself how do they differ from that video. If I were you I wouldn't draw any conclusions from what you've just seen.</text>
</string>
<string id="vedma_reklama_2_1">
    <text>So you're not a beginner in the Zone?</text>
</string>
<string id="vedma_reklama_3_1">
    <text>So you did come to the right conclusion. Well done little man. Now buzz off and talk to Dimak and do not answer with any sharp replies.</text>
</string>
<string id="vedma_reklama_4_1">
    <text>It will be my pleasure.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Dimon in Yantar/Amber after the Bunker is clear of scum -->
<string id="yan_dima_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey Dimon, what brings you here? Have you found your father?</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_dima_dialog_1">
    <text>No, I've not found him, but Gastello sent me here to look. I learned about my father from watching B-Ski-B, he was on 'Crimewatchski', with that hot Scottish girl hosting it.... err... anyway, he is wanted for stalkery and sneakery. On his chest is an animal of some kind, from the 'Order of the Cat'. His nickname is Dimak.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_dima_dialog_2">
    <text>Gee? I'm familiar with your father. He presented me with a weapon like yours. He is with a group that lives in Wolf's Lair, but they are not always there.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_dima_dialog_3">
    <text>Scar ... this is ... this is the best news I've heard in ages!</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Dimon in Yantar/Amber after the Bunker is clear of scum -->
<string id="yan_dima_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Dimon the Professor is in danger and I need to get to the Elbe, and you should stay here as long as you can?</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_dima_dialog_1_1">
    <text>I would have gone with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_dima_dialog_2_1">
    <text>Thanks Dimon but no, I have immunity to the Psi-field there, you don't.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_dima_dialog_3_1">
    <text>Okay Scar, I'll stay here. Be careful!</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Oleg in Wolf's Lair after Jupiter -->
<string id="oleg_na_as_0">
    <text>I found the thief's cache, Airborne! Strange! I found 5 absolutes. The only time I had the occasion to see absolutes of this type was at the base of Lebedev in Marsh. Coincidence?</text>
</string>
<string id="oleg_na_as_1">
    <text>Anything can happen. Well I just can't believe that Airborne could do this to us! You say that he was carrying explosives, well Airborne never liked carrying explosives. Even Anya does not carry explosives. However, recently Airborne has conducted himself in a strange way. But why I wonder?</text>
</string>
<string id="oleg_na_as_2">
    <text>What if the cache was not Airborne's, then whose would it be?</text>
</string>
<string id="oleg_na_as_3">
    <text>What do you mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="oleg_na_as_4">
    <text>Possibly we where fooled by a double agent or a twin?!</text>
</string>
<string id="oleg_na_as_5">
    <text>Double agent? Twin? Humm, Airborne was on an assignment a week ago in Radar. For a day he did not make contact with us and then he just shows up out of the blue. Previously he was proud to wear his Russian Airborne Troops beret, but since his return he wears a full exoskeleton. I asked him why he isn't wearing his beret, and he said nothing and just laughed. However he did mention that he met a young stalker named Raphael in Warehouses, and he mentioned Lukash didn't like the kid. He also mentioned that Raphael had been talking to some x-army guy.</text>
</string>
<string id="oleg_na_as_6">
    <text>Oleg, I need to talk to this kid Raphael, but I will need a transition to Army Warehouses.</text>
</string>
<string id="oleg_na_as_7">
    <text>The transition to Army Warehouses is just north of the Bar. I'll bluetooth it to your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="oleg_na_as_8">
    <text>Thanks! I have the vague impression that the history of Airborne is far from over. I'll go talk to this Raphael and see what's going on.</text>
</string>

<!-- Talk to Feng after she hits Raphael with her rifle butt in Army Warehouse -->
<string id="ari_menstra_0">
    <text>Well, you are the queen of all bitches.</text>
</string>
<string id="ari_menstra_1">
    <text>So was it you who sent this boy with this story of lubricant?</text>
</string>
<string id="ari_menstra_2">
    <text>Yes I sent him, but not to talk to the butt of your rifle. What the hell is wrong with you?</text>
</string>
<string id="ari_menstra_3">
    <text>All of these men acts like kids. I have to slap them them around when they act stupid, and now you know what will happen if you act stupid. Go see if Raphael is ok. Pervert!</text>
</string>
<string id="ari_menstra_4">
    <text>I'll pervert you later biatch. You must have lots of friends. I'll be back!</text>
</string>


<!-- ----------------------------------- DR HALF WAY ----------------------------------- -->
<!-- talking to Raphael after Feng wacks him -->
<string id="raf2_dialog_0">
    <text>Are you ok?</text>
</string>
<string id="raf2_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes! I see you have a huge scar. I've only been in the Zone for a short time. I hope I don't end up looking like you.</text>
</string>
<string id="raf2_dialog_2">
    <text>All right, that's enough with the jokes. Have you seen any military stalkers with Airborne?</text>
</string>
<string id="raf2_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes and they were going to Pripyat I believe.</text>
</string>
<string id="raf2_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, show me the dynamite you want to sell.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Lukash after Raphael blows up the wall of the Military Base -->
<string id="as_lukash_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Lukash, you're looking healthy.</text>
</string>
<string id="as_lukash_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello Scar, you're as charming as ever. This bozzo Raphael has blown a huge hole in our bloody wall. I guess he found the explosives left over from the war with 'Duty'. That war was about six months ago, and Strelok was here helping us. So this asshole, in one fell swoop, has demolished our defences. I was warned that this guy was a liability.</text>
</string>
<string id="as_lukash_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, do not be angry at him. He is an interesting guy once you get to know him.</text>
</string>
<string id="as_lukash_dialog_3">
    <text>Interesting? Really?! Then Raphael can start doing some work in Pripyat. We do have one little problem here though. So he can prove himself. Three days ago we shot two creatures near the railway tunnel. We know from special sensors that they are about to come again. How many of them I do not know. But usually 2 or 3. Creatures look a little like civilian zombies, but somewhat translucent. And they cause death by splashing some kind of green crap into the eyes. At first they thought that was some kind of acid, but I'm not so sure. Anyway if that punk kid wants to redeem himself he can kill those creatures. If you want to help him, do so from a distance, otherwise he is not doing any real work.</text>
</string>
<string id="as_lukash_dialog_4">
    <text>Hmm... Raphael has already shown himself to be dangerous. Maybe he can prove he has some talents, or usefull liabilities if you prefer. I'll talk to him.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Raphael after Lukash offers a tunnel mission in the Military Base -->
<string id="raf3_dialog_0">
    <text>Well Lukash suggests you clear the tunnel entrance. You do know how to shoot a weapon, right? If not you could always build him a new wall.</text>
</string>
<string id="raf3_dialog_1">
    <text>Sure I can shoot!</text>
</string>
<string id="raf3_dialog_2">
    <text>A gun... not your other weapon, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="raf3_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, err no... ah, well I do like to use my other weapon too. But I don't have any guns right now. I believe Feng knows of three boxes with a Flamethrower, a Remington and an AK-104. Scar can you talk to Feng and ask which weapon I can use? I'll owe you a favour or two! Else Lukash will make me build a new wall.</text>
</string>
<string id="raf3_dialog_4">
    <text>Well asshole, take the Flamethrower! I'll support you but only from a distance, and then if uncle Lukash still does not like you then you can start building the wall.</text>
</string>
<string id="raf3_dialog_5">
    <text>Well asshole, keep the Remington! I'll support you but only from a distance, and then if uncle Lukash still does not like you can build a wall.</text>
</string>
<string id="raf3_dialog_6">
    <text>Well asshole, take the AK-104! I'll support you but only from afar, and if Lukash still does not like you can build that wall.</text>
</string>
<string id="raf3_dialog_7">
    <text>Okay, and not for the first time uncle Scar is perplexed! Well you'll get something out of your three choices, and maybe a Rambo fucking too! I'll go talk to Feng about your dynamite, which disappeared with the wall. He-he!</text>
</string>

<!-- Talking to Lukash after you/Raphael clear the tunnel entrance -->
<string id="as_lukash_dialog_ok_0">
    <text>Hello Lukash, I see you're still healthy! Anyway the tunnel is cleared and your boyfriend has survived.</text>
</string>
<string id="as_lukash_dialog_ok_1">
    <text>Well I guess you can get out the crisco and celebrate. Ha-ha-ha!</text>
</string>
<string id="as_lukash_dialog_ok_2">
    <text>Well enough of the sick jokes. I need to see your trader Skinflint.</text>
</string>
<string id="as_lukash_dialog_ok_3">
    <text>Yes he's called Skinflint, and he has radiation sickness. He is now in a small wooden hut that is on stilts in a little swamp here in Army Depots where previously lived some old guy called Stalkerstein. You know the place, it's in the middle of the mine field! Have fun getting through that mine field! Anyway go and see Skinflint if you want, just do not kill him nor get to close to him. No one really knows how sick he is, it's like he's a zombie or meshuggah.</text>
</string>
<string id="as_lukash_dialog_ok_4">
    <text>A zombie? Meshuggah? Really? I could go to Sakharov, I think he knows something about the treatment of zombies. Geez... it's a heck of a trip, since he left Yantar to go to Cordon because it's much safer there.</text>
</string>
<string id="as_lukash_dialog_ok_5">
    <text>Seriously! Sakharov could cure him? Ok, I'll give you a trail that leads into a forest and then to Cordon through Garbage. If you can save Skinflint it would be a good deed. I may even reward you.</text>
</string>

<!-- Talking to Lukash after Raphael dies clearing the tunnel entrance -->
<string id="as_lukash_dialog_proval_0">
    <text>Damn, it's my fault! I'm afraid Raphael didn't make it! His black-belt was useless against those mutants.</text>
</string>
<string id="as_lukash_dialog_proval_1">
    <text>Yeah ok, well, whatever. His boots are full of fodder now. However I thought he would do better. I was going to give you a reward too.</text>
</string>
<string id="as_lukash_dialog_proval_2">
    <text>Really?! Well I tried! I have a question for you? I need to see your dealer.</text>
</string>
<string id="as_lukash_dialog_proval_3">
    <text>He's called Skinflint, and he has radiation sickness. He is now in a small wooden house that is on stilts in a small swamp here in Army Depots where previously lived some old guy called Grunter-Hunter. You know the place, it's in the middle of a freak'n mine field! Have fun trying getting through it! Anyway go and see him if you want, just do not kill him nor get to close to him. No one really knows how sick he is, it's like he's a zombie or wacked.</text>
</string>
<string id="as_lukash_dialog_proval_4">
    <text>A zombie... wacked? Really? I could go to Sakharov, I think he knows something about the treatment of zombies. Geez... it's a hell of a trip. He left Yantar to go to Cordon because it's much safer there.</text>
</string>
<string id="as_lukash_dialog_proval_5">
    <text>Seriously! Sakharov could cure him? Ok, I'll give you a trail that leads to Wolf's Lair and then to Cordon through Garbage. If you can save Skinflint it would be a good deed. I may even give you something.</text>
</string>

<!-- talk to Feng after Lukash gives job to kill the monsters -->
<string id="ari_ak_dialog_0">
    <text>Feng, listen, that old dynamite you gave Raphael nearly killed him! You shafted him... which I guess he's used to by now... but still... Anyway he didn't die and he wants the contents of a box you promised him.</text>
</string>
<string id="ari_ak_dialog_1">
    <text>Wow... really? The dirty little guy survived, he's tougher than I thought. Ok, so I'll give him a gun, but he will be like a monkey with a grenade I warn you. Listen I need an ARF-F, also known as an AK-203 or even an AK-9. I can tell you where to find one, and I'm not going there because of the hordes of mutants that hang around that area. Bloodsuckers for the most part. Well it's in the water tower somewhere upstairs. If you bring it back I'll pay you, and I'll see what I can give him from the box.</text>
</string>
<string id="ari_ak_dialog_2">
    <text>Here's your AK-203. A good looking weapon.\n\n</text>
</string>
<string id="ari_ak_dialog_3">
    <text>%c[255,255,128,1]Well then I will go get it. I need some money. And fighting bloodsuckers, well you know, it's a whole lotta fun!</text>
</string>
<string id="ari_ak_dialog_4">
    <text>Hot dogs, I've been wanting for this AK-203 for a long time, so here's what I promised.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Lukash after injecting Skinflint with the cure to his zombie infection -->
<string id="as_lukash_skr_ok_0">
    <text>Done! Skinflint, that miser, does not want to talk right now. He is a bit of a fucktard right now, but he remembered the way back here and is already in his workshop.</text>
</string>
<string id="as_lukash_skr_ok_1">
    <text>Are you serious? Skinflint is there?</text>
</string>
<string id="as_lukash_skr_ok_2">
    <text>I'll go check him out. Even though his gerbal brain is not working correctly yet he should be somewhat useful.</text>
</string>
<string id="as_lukash_skr_ok_3">
    <text>Ha, he never had much to say anyway. I'd say he's still wacko sicko! Scar you are invaluable so take this as a reward. Another skin receipe in your PDA. You will always be happy if you join our group.</text>
</string>
<string id="as_lukash_skr_ok_4">
    <text>Thanks for the offer, but for the moment I am satified with my endeavors in the Zone. If anything comes up that you think I might like, notify me. Now I'll try to get an intelligent word out of Skinflint.</text>
</string>

<!-- talk to Skinflint once he's back in his trading room in Warehouses -->
<string id="skr_zdrav_dialog_0">
    <text>How are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="skr_zdrav_dialog_1">
    <text>Hunskydorsky sort of, more or less, give or take. Bit of a headache though. Thank you, you saved me. So I'll give you really good prices for anything you bring me. I owe you bro!</text>
</string>
<string id="skr_zdrav_dialog_2">
    <text>Sakharov really should be thanked. If not for his antidote you would have become a full zombie! I have a deal for you. I know that you know the stalker who recovered from cancer of the blood caused by the Zone. My daughter also suffers from this.</text>
</string>
<string id="skr_zdrav_dialog_3">
    <text>Sakharov, yes definitely thanks to him! I am indebted to both of you. For cancer of the blood, I do not remember. I do not think my head works correctly yet. If you recall the name let me know. Here's a recipe I'll put in your PDA. Later when the hands will remember the craft, then contact will be made. I'll fix your weapon, if necessary, and throw in some NATO rounds. And if you see Sakharov before I do please pass thanks from me to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="skr_zdrav_dialog_4">
    <text>Okay I'll pass your thanks on to Sakharov. Scar is my name. I would say nothing usually, but then I trust you as a stalker who overcame a nasty disease in the Zone. When your memory is back immediately let me know. Okay it's time for me to return to Wolf's Lair to see some friends.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Voronin in Bar after WArehouse -->
<string id="voronin_zashita_dialog_0">
    <text>What's going on General?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_zashita_dialog_1">
    <text>Scar I called upon you because you are trustworthy. There is a contract out on me! I have a lot of enemies, and do not know exactly who they are. For having Hog killed maybe, but this revenge could be because of someone else. So I ask you to protect me.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_zashita_dialog_2">
    <text>Uhmmm, well okay, but do I need to be in this room like a sentry at the mausoleum?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_zashita_dialog_3">
    <text>Scar, sometimes I think you have to many splinters in the windmills of your mind. No! Just stay in the Bar room. You should easily spot those who signed for this contract.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_arena_start_0">
    <text>Well you make me laugh! I will certainly go check on the situation.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_arena_start_1">
    <text>Oh I almost forgot. Someone called into the Bar and said that the iron doors to the upper level of the arena had been opened. There were mutants running around between the first and second levels. Go check it out. We never know what that son of a bitch Arnie is doing over there.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_arena_start_2">
    <text>I need to ask you something. Why do you keep only mutants?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_arena_start_3">
    <text>My nagging wife said 'me or the mutants'. So now I just feed those creatures now. I need some kind of job. Yes I know I am a fool, but I love my wife.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_arena_start_4">
    <text>A noble heart you have. I did not know about the arena until a few days ago. Well I'll monitor the situation and check out the arena.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Navy the blue-beret in the Bar. yikes so much text. -->
<string id="vdv_nast_dialog_0">
    <text>Seems to me that you are Airborne's twin. Airborne recently stole the Tango group's funds.</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_nast_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes I am, and he I  not be! I am called Navy. What are you doing here Scar?</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_nast_dialog_2">
    <text>You know me, that's good. I met your twin one evening in Jupiter. I thought he was you at first. There is a matter with the group's money having been taken. I was at Warehouses and met a young guy Raphael who talked about you and how you had gotten into a drunken delirium with the military stalkers. Oleg had sent me there to find out about you and about taking money from them.</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_nast_dialog_3">
    <text>I definitely was delirious after that counterfeit vodka. I remember that guy and how he licked his weapons clean. I remember drinking a lot and eating nothing. Gastello befriended the guy, and the guy wanted a map showing a stash in Radar. Then I remember nothing. I woke up in Pripyat in a former kindergarten. Anyway, I left. I later found out from Palenque that my twin was involved with some contractors. I though this must be nonsense. Oleg needs to be updated on the situation. It turns out that the 'Tango' group has long been persecuted by the military.</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_nast_dialog_4">
    <text>Oleg told me that you know the trails between Wolf's Lair and Garbage. So can you show me these trails?</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_nast_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes, sure why not. Look at your PDA, I'll give you a couple of transitions. But could you talk to Oleg and let everyone know that I'm alive and well and innocent. Understand? I'll be behind you. What if they are all drunk and shoot me instead of my twin! Ha-ha-ha!</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_nast_dialog_6">
    <text>Well now I believe it's the humor that is different between you twins. Well I'll tell Oleg to set a place at the table for you. Maybe the mutants will dance with delight when you show up. Oleg once told me that he was surprised to see you, err... Airborne, attired in an exoskeleton suit rather that your favorite beret.</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_nast_dialog_7">
    <text>Yeah well screw those forklifts with all the hoses, gears and no pee tube. No longer will I wear them. I would rather wear a padded bullet-proof jacket. Let Oleg, Kuzma and Dimak resemble organs on metal legs!</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_nast_dialog_8">
    <text>Did you by chance hear about Strelok and his group?</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_nast_dialog_9">
    <text>Not completely, but I do know of one guy from that group that is in a prison somewhere in the center of Peacekeeping. He is called Mole.</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_nast_dialog_10">
    <text>Mole? I think he is a member of Duty. I heard that there is someone else locked up with Mole, but I do not remember his name. I am also wanted by those military stalkers. Do you know the coordinates of the transition to Peacekeeping?</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_nast_dialog_11">
    <text>No I do not, but Sidorovoch must surely know. I warn you that place is fortified very well with armoured vehicles and helicopters. It is very difficult to pass the defensive perimeter on foot, however if you had wings then it might be doable. In any case I do not recommend that you go there!</text>
</string>
<string id="vdv_nast_dialog_12">
    <text>Well I will leave now. Sidorovich moved to Wolf's Lair. I will try to find a way past the defensive perimeter. Humm, by air might be possible. Maybe I can fly a chopper there. Thanks for the info. I'll go to Oleg and Sidrovich now.</text>
</string>

<!-- you've escaped the Arena and killed Arnie, saving Voronin -->
<string id="voronin_zashita_dialog_ok_0">
    <text>We know who the killer is. He was the one who put a contract out on your head. Arnie the former owner of the arena. He was going to kill you while I was away.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_zashita_dialog_ok_1">
    <text>Jeez, I would have not believed it of him, and me who had offered him a position as first order too. Peace to his soul, he went to join his Gladiators in Valhalla. I have news for you. I contacted the clinic where your daughter is and her condition is stable. I'll give you as thanks for saving my life 500,000 rubles. It will take you a while to complete the transfer once you have all the money. So now I will go check all my buttheads to see what they are up too. Understood?!</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_zashita_dialog_ok_2">
    <text>Yep, got it! Thanks!</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_zashita_dialog_ok_3">
    <text>I am grateful for sure and thank you, but remember I don't owe you my life!</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_zashita_dialog_ok_4">
    <text>I suppose if I saved 'your' wife then this mission would not have been a priority.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_zashita_dialog_ok_5">
    <text>Scar why are you so... well, of course the life of my wife would have been more rewarding, anyway we have another matter. I have sent several teams to search Eastern Pripyat to spy on the 'Witches', but no results yet. We are also searching Jupiter which is a high risk area with ambushes, Psy-zones and other vermin. Are you still willing to work to save your daughter?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_zashita_dialog_ok_6">
    <text>Obviously yes! I want to find a stalker who survived the disease that my daughter has. Strelok had it two! Navy is at the Bar and I need to talk to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_zashita_dialog_ok_7">
    <text>I understand you Scar. Keep in touch. After a while the transfer of the money to the hospital will be complete. Good luck!</text>
</string>


<!-- Voronin is alive and you've collect 2 Million -->
<string id="voronin_klinika_ok_0">
    <text>Well I've got the 2 million rubles to treat my daughter.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_klinika_ok_1">
    <text>You do not have to worry Scar, all of the money will be used for her treatment, you have my word.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_klinika_ok_2">
    <text>Thank you General, music to my ears!</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_klinika_ok_3">
    <text>Just rest and relax! I'll make sure everything is ok!</text>
</string>

<string id="vedma_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello! I didn't expect to see females in the Zone. Are you a real woman? What are you doing here? Are you one of the 'Witches'?</text>
</string>
<string id="vedma_dialog_1">
    <text>Do I look like a android?! I am just a modern woman surviving in the Zone. Do you expect me to prove it?</text>
</string>
<string id="vedma_dialog_2">
    <text>Android... good enough for me. I'll use you! Show me my dear, show me!</text>
</string>
<string id="vedma_dialog_3">
    <text>How about I show you my female size 11 boot!</text>
</string>

<!-- in prison with Mole in Peacekeeping -->
<string id="krot_pred_dialog_0">
    <text>Well if it ain't Mole in a hole! I thought I'd come here to help out, but did not expect to rescue myself. What is wrong with these guys and why do thay act like fascists? I see the Doctor is here too.</text>
</string>
<string id="krot_pred_dialog_1">
    <text>I don't know this Swamp Doctor. I heard he owned a farm in Swamps that burned down. I think he lost everything he ever cared about, as he is now supposedly quite bitter. These idiots are using us as bait. Hence you came to help us. Who are you and what are your plans?</text>
</string>
<string id="krot_pred_dialog_2">
    <text>They call me Scar. I'm looking for Strelok. Some kind stalkers that I know suggested that you knew Strelok and that you were located here. I suppose the bait worked.</text>
</string>
<string id="krot_pred_dialog_3">
    <text>It is best to talk with Doctor. Strelok, he knows more about wtf is going on around here. But he supposedly is not around here.</text>
</string>

<!-- in prison with the Doctor in Peacekeeping -->
<string id="doktor_pred_start_0">
    <text>What's going on Doctor?</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_pred_start_1">
    <text>I recognize you from the appearance of your scar, Scar. And now I suppose you want to finish the task that was not completed a couple of years ago, you know: 'Find a Stalker named Fang and kill him'.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_pred_start_1_1">
    <text>Oh hang on... I think I am remembering!! I can feel an explanatory video flashback coming on or it could be an LSD flashback. On the plus side I think we've run out of Iron Maiden tracks to play.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_pred_start_2">
    <text>%c[255,255,128,1]I remember now!!! I called to him and he was shot by a sniper. A few seconds later I heard a muffled sound characteristic of a long range shot. It was too late to distinguish who had fired, but I spotted the place where the sound came from. I was looking for Strelok, I needed information about him and the only names that I was aware of where 'Fang' and 'Ghost'. I wanted to ask them about Strelok. I had a picture on my PDA and I was told me that it was that of 'Ghost'. But in the Lab X-16, I found a corpse with the identity of 'Ghost', but it did not look like the picture.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_pred_start_3">
    <text>Scar we have to escape... I have stolen and kept hidden a few things since I came here... can you help us escape? You need to escape too. I heard them saying that they will sell you soon. Look the guards always sleep around this time, or at least get drowsy, but not for long, so try to open the door using your knife. The door has a flash-bang wired to it so be careful. But it's old and damp so it should not explode and wake up the guards. Then keep quiet and get to the upper level of the cave. There's a metal box up there there somewhere. Search for it, there should be guns in it. I suggest you don't betray us, as I must survive and get to Cordon for you to find what you seek. One important thing, you must let Mole and me use the transition first before you go through, otherwise we might not make it. Don't ask me to explain why! Look for a PDA too, one of the guards might have one.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_pred_start_4">
    <text>He's going to sell me... what the... well this place has really gotten a lot more evil than I remember it being from a couple of years ago. Oh well, here goes.</text>
</string>

<!-- DUPLICATE - just escaped from prison with the Doctor Peacekeeping 
<string id="doktor_pred_perehod_0">
    <text>Well, that was fun. Did you get the PDA?</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_pred_perehod_1">
    <text>Yes!</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_pred_perehod_2">
    <text>Excellent! Give me the PDA and we'll go to Cordon.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_pred_perehod_3">
    <text>Oh... goodie tu-shoes. Well then off to Cordon we jolly well go!</text>
</string>
-->

<!-- talking to Sahkarov to cure Skinflint of the zombie infection -->
<string id="skrjaga_shp_dialog_0">
    <text>Professor, I come here with a heavy heart, er... I mean on business. You said that you have developed an antidote to reverse the first stage of becoming a zombie? Well the trader in Army Warehouses, Skinflint, has become infected and is at the first stage. So his behavior does not correspond to being completely irradiated. Do you have such an antidote?</text>
</string>
<string id="skrjaga_shp_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, of course. But it is only a prototype Scar, so... ah... well... I only have two syringes. But since Skinflint can become a pioneer for medicine let's do it. Scar I will give you one syringe.</text>
</string>
<string id="skrjaga_shp_dialog_2">
    <text>Excellent professor, now how do I inject him because he does not recognize anyone and is prone to very extreme violence? Ordinarily I'd just shoot him, but that isn't exactly a cure.</text>
</string>
<string id="skrjaga_shp_dialog_3">
    <text>Wait for night or late evening. Even the zombie body is inclined to sleep. When Skinflint calms down, go up to him and try to quickly make a dialogue with him, then abruptly inject the antidote. But be careful Scar, keep you gun handy as I can't promise what effect the prototype antidote will really have.</text>
</string>
<string id="skrjaga_shp_dialog_4">
    <text>I'll inject him somehow. Thanks for the words of reassurance.</text>
</string>

<string id="skr_zombi_dialog_0">
    <text>I am a nurse and I have medicine to give you. Bend over!</text>
</string>
<string id="skr_zombi_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah right, well your are ugly like a head nurse.</text>
</string>
<string id="skr_zombi_dialog_2">
    <text>Give me the keys to the locomotive. Are they under your pillow?</text>
</string>
<string id="skr_zombi_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, the keys, here, ugly head nurse.</text>
</string>
<string id="skr_zombi_dialog_4">
    <text>Here take your medicine. I hope it hurts.</text>
</string>

<!-- chatting with Oleg in Wolfs Lair after being in Warehouses dealing with Raphael and Skinflint -->
<string id="oleg_s_as_0">
    <text>It is confirmed... the young Raphael also saw the military stalker twin. They drank and compared each others weapons. Navy said he was going to look for Airborne. Possibly you could introduce yourself to this twin, Navy.</text>
</string>
<string id="oleg_s_as_1">
    <text>That's good. Did he say where to look for Airborne?</text>
</string>
<string id="oleg_s_as_2">
    <text>He said he was taken to Pripyat to help fix weapons, and he escaped from there, as it was dangerous there.</text>
</string>
<string id="oleg_s_as_3">
    <text>Well ... we need is a plan. While waiting Voronin wants to see you urgently. He has information for you. Yes Scar I've got one of the 4-digit codes. You did a lot for us so take it. The daughter will need you more than me. I heard about one such veteran neutral stalker, but I do not know who exactly he is. In the interior of the Zone he could not get away and somewhere, either he went to the Bar or Garbage. Surely you can stir up some trouble.</text>
</string>
<string id="oleg_s_as_4">
    <text>Thanks for the code Oleg! I'll talk to the guys first and then go to Voronin and find out what he wants.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Oleg after talking to Navy in the Bar -->
<string id="oleg_vdv_nast_0">
    <text>Today for sure feels like a holiday!</text>
</string>
<string id="oleg_vdv_nast_1">
    <text>Yeah we here real party animals. And you Scar, still wandering around in circles?</text>
</string>
<string id="oleg_vdv_nast_2">
    <text>I've got a bit of news for you. I found Airborne's twin, called Navy, and he'll be here in a minute or so. I need to talk to Sidorovish.</text>
</string>
<string id="oleg_vdv_nast_3">
    <text>Ok... that's good news, another reason to celebrate!</text>
</string>
<string id="oleg_vdv_nast_4">
    <text>Well don't celebrate too hard he looks like a military stalker so try not to shoot him!</text>
</string>

<!-- talking with Sidorovich in WL after bringing the Navy over, before being made a zombie -->
<string id="aver_sidor_pred_0">
    <text>Sidorovich, I need some information.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_sidor_pred_1">
    <text>Really? How interesting... and what's in it for me ugly?</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_sidor_pred_2">
    <text>Sid, you said that you know the transition from Cordon to Peacekeeping. Well I need it urgently and in return you'll receive my everlasting respect and a Christmas card every year.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_sidor_pred_3">
    <text>Well look Scar, I like you, you know... and... well, as it happens I'm in need a small favour. On the way to the Dark Valley transition is an old quarry which is nearby a pond, and there is a dumptruck there too. There are two Controllers hanging around there, and turning into zombies all who get in their way. So if you kill them in your normal vicious style then I'll give you a transition to Peacekeeping. I hope you can find the location because I have no way to mark your PDA. There is an abandoned trailer and fuel truck nearby the path that you will have to travel on. Two old hags used to live there in a trailer, and once had Karina held captive there. I'm sure you know the spot. How many of them that will appear I do not know. If you get infected head for Sakharov in Cordon immediately, but remember you will be eveyone's enemy, except scientists, until he fixes you up. Have fun!</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_sidor_pred_4">
    <text>Okay Sidorovich, I'll kill the Controllers, just please tell me the location of the transition to Peacekeeping when I get back.</text>
</string>

<!-- I GUESS - talking with Sidorovich in Wolf's Lair after killing the two controllers and becoming a zombie -->
<string id="sidor_protivojadie_0">
    <text>Damn... Sidorovich... damn... what have you done? Freak'n antidote gives me the... jeez, I need the damn antidote.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_protivojadie_1">
    <text>Why did you come here you damn fool!? I told you only Sakharov can help you and he is in Cordon! Jesus, you look like you're dying, run man, run!</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_protivojadie_2">
    <text>You ass... you didn't tell me the pain could be this bad... my head... my head... it's bursting.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking with Sidorovich after being cure from being a zombie -->
<string id="sidor_kontrik_ok_0">
    <text>I've done your favour Sidorovich now give me the transition to Peacekeeping.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_kontrik_ok_1">
    <text>Seriously Scar do you even know why you want to go to Peacekeeping? I tell you only death awaits lone stalkers in that place. Besides, ha ha, you looked beautiful as a zombie. And seeing you now I believe that the zombie infection can be cured. Tenacious you are Scar!</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_kontrik_ok_2">
    <text>You hairless douchebag, because of your little job I had to defend myself against all the good environmentalists and clans. They hate me now.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_kontrik_ok_3">
    <text>They were shooting at you to survive just as you shoot others to survive. You don't care about the ones you shoot do you? Well I'm trying to survive here too thanks to my brains and your feet, and Scar you are still alive so get over it. I use you and you use me, so we're even. Ok?! As for the transition to Peacekeeping go to the area outside the northern checkpoint in Cordon, it's where you arrive direct from the Bar, using the Tango group's transition. Stay outside the fence and go to the southern gates in Cordon, south of the military checkpoint. Use the southern fence as your guide and go to its eastern corner, then look southeast, up a hill, you should see two small Christmas trees standing close together. Well there between the two Christmas trees is the transition. A tip... in Peacekeeping rules are similar to the Soviet laws of 1937. I have heard there's lots of loot there so I advise you to remove excess weight before heading to Peacekeeping or take a rucksack. Oh and unlike here the military pretty much fire without warning, so I suggest you take a few spare grenades too. So good luck, and errr... goodbye Scar.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_kontrik_ok_4">
    <text>I never would have guessed! No wonder no one has found this transition to Peacekeeping before. Okay I'm outta here!</text>
</string>

<!-- Taking to Sakharov in Cordon, as he cures you from zombie infection -->
<string id="sahar_kontrik_ok_0">
    <text>Professor! HELP ME!!!</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_kontrik_ok_1">
    <text>You look like your dead... ok ok Scar!</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_kontrik_ok_2">
    <text>Hurry!</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_kontrik_ok_3">
    <text>Yes yes, now close your eyes Scar... yes, that's it!</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_kontrik_ok_4">
    <text>Ouch, ahhh that hurts!! The controllers they were dressed in long black coats.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_kontrik_ok_5">
    <text>Yes, we have already seen those mutants! Maybe a little of what made them human remains. We will need to study them more.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_kontrik_ok_6">
    <text>Wow... I'm feeling better already... wow, now I want a vacation for a year.</text>
</string>

<!-- SPLATTER - talk to Navy, after you met him in Bar, now in Wolfs Lair, after talking with Oleg HUGE dialogue -->
<string id="aver_vdv_nast_dialog_0">
    <text>How's the mood?</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_vdv_nast_dialog_1">
    <text>Excellent!</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_vdv_nast_dialog_2">
    <text>How did you become a member in Oleg's group?</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_vdv_nast_dialog_3">
    <text>I do not want to say this more that once, but since you and I think the same way I will give you a recipe and tell you a story. Listen carefully Scar and do not interrupt me, I don't want to repeat myself. It all started with the fact that at the Cordon checkpoint we came face to face with a jerk. Who he was I didn't know, and he was wearing glasses and was in civilian clothes. He was following a map and went directly to the commander. After that he went to get cleaned up. I am not completely sure what they were talking about. The commander was angry, they had argued like a couple of bloodsuckers. The commander said 'fly to East Pripyat and deliver this cargo to those eggheads there'. This guy said there were to many mutants there. Then this guy caught sight of Batyn and shut up and then went to Valerka. Anyway we all flew to Pripyat and met with a guy called Prometheus, and he says come over he, we've been waiting for you. Then we went in the direction of the Office of Community Services. As we walked I saw something shining nearby, it looked a little like Grandmother Beads. I thought it could go to 'R/D' if Sidorovich would trade for some vodka. Anyway we meet with some egghead in a white coat, and next to him is a case. He was very overweight. The scientist in the robe comes over and says to handcuff the case to my arm and to go to the helicopter. 
 I assumed there was valuable information in this case. Valerka asks if I new where we were. I said: duh we are in East Pripyat. He then said there won't be many stalkers around in the daytime. I said: why the hell does this heavy box have to be secured to an arm. What then began: this asshole in a bathrobe jumped with anger. Yelling at us and called us uneducated morons among other words. He said that the case has important and sensitive information. And that half of the scientific world would give up their sex life for it. So Valerka and I and the case go to the chopper. We boarded up and flew away. I still do not understand why Lenin and Meresyev decided to fly through the Military area! The military shot us down with RPG's. The next thing I new was that I was on a stretcher. Mercenaries, their mother is not there and not so! Four or five of them at once opened fire on us. Egghead with flyer immediately ran, and we fell back behind the decks. So they, bitch, throw grenades started. Well, a little hooked, concussions me. Came to, and they are over Valerka and something of their fluttering.
 Then one of them, the main they see it was bent and the hand to which the case had been fastened, Valerka snapped. My God, that was the cry of death. I will not forget such a cry, it was worse than a bloodsucker. Valerka well alive was when he his hand And then they have finished it. I reached out to get his AKMS. Do not believe me right, I would not have believed it. Do you remember saying that some kind of crap is found in Pripyat. So this is it those bullets, or rejected, or slowed down, or all at once did. And the armor was good for me. And then ... I open my eyes and the room was mostly white and some girl was holding my hand. I think to myself, yeah I'm in paradise. And then began some pain. I thought that my brain will explode. The girl is looking at me and injected me with something. I passed out. Several times I had awakened with pain and each time the girl gave me a shot of painkiller. And then I completely woke up, and I was in a little room next to the young guy. I have didn't have any pain, but there was pressure on my chest as if a tank drove over it. I move one arm then the other, then I tried to sit up. There are miracles. I am still alive. Then a doctor came in and updated me on the situation. The military sent a patrol to collect corpses, and well, they found you and brought back to the base. You where identified by hospital personnel. 
 I could smell perfume from his handkerchief. I got up and left and went to the base commander to introduced himself and asked for permission to contact Batya to get a chopper ride back. I was ordered to remain on the base for a couple of more days until transport was available. Well, orders are orders, I remained. I decided to wander around the area and talk to people. Maybe even find vodka. I go walking around and there were four barracks. I tried to go into one of them and they wouldn't let me enter. I noticea at the entrance of a barn nearby a guy in full gear as if ready to go somewhere. I found no one that could help me including him. In the evening before going to sleep I decided to have a smoke. I went out on the porch and saw at the gates a truck driving into the base. And it went straight to the barracks where that fully outfitted guy was. I quietly approached the barracks and saw people in white coats climb into the truck. Of course I was very surprised. I was wondering why would these people be in the Zone? Conventional eggheads I tought, but they all had special suits on. Well the truck left went through the gate and took the fork in the road that led to Radar. So now I go back to get some sleep. And in the morning Batya came in and gave me a lift to the Bar. I was drinking and told Oleg about my experience. He allowed me to be part of his Tango group. To this day I still have no idea where those people in the white outfits where going. I can only assume that they where going to some lab.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_vdv_nast_dialog_4">
    <text>What a story! I myself suspected in Warehouses many phenomena. Mutants appear from nowhere. For the recipe thanks. I'll go speak to Sidorovich.</text>
</string>

<string id="doktor_stvol_0">
    <text>Keep the weapon and ammunition.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_stvol_1">
    <text>Excellent.</text>
</string>
<string id="krot_stvol_0">
    <text>Keep the gun and ammo.</text>
</string>
<string id="krot_stvol_1">
    <text>Fantastic.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Doctor in Cordon after escaping from Peacekeeping -->
<string id="doktor_ne_verit_shram_0">
    <text>Now do you believe me when I say that I am trustworthy Doctor?</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_ne_verit_shram_1">
    <text>Of course not! But thanks for the help Scar. Then again your help can have a double meaning and an insidious hidden intent.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_ne_verit_shram_2">
    <text>What can I do to make you trust me?</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_ne_verit_shram_3">
    <text>Go to the grave of Fang. It is in Army Warehouses close to where he was killed. I was there and saw the grave, there is an inscription on it. If you think that the X-16 corpse is really him, then bring the corpse here and we will see for sure. To find the grave look for a place close by where he was shot, near a wooden cross on the edge of the village and close by is a two story brick electricity tower.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_ne_verit_shram_4">
    <text>All right since you do not believe me then I'll go. I'll find a grave and I will also bring you the body from X-16 and then you can decide what's what.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_ne_verit_shram_5">
    <text>Yeah, fuck you Doctor I'm bored with your dry old hatred of life. I'll find the grave, but I am no hearse. If necessary you go and look for the body in X-16.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_ne_verit_shram_6">
    <text>The corpse is certain not to please you, it will be heavy I know. Go to Garbage, then to the forest behind the fallen tree. Last year I left a neutral exoskeleton there. I doubt it will be in good conditon now, but it can carry 70-80 kg, with little effort. If it's still there use it. It's close by the transition from Cordon, and to your right as you arrive.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_ne_verit_shram_7">
    <text>Okay Doctor I'll take a look but I have little doubt it will still be there, or useable.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_ne_verit_shram_8">
    <text>Your karma will lead you!</text>
</string>

<!-- Talking to Swamp Doctor in Cordon, returning the body from X16, pt 1 -->
<string id="doktor_verit_shram_0">
    <text>'Habeas Corpus' Doctor. The unbearable stench! That grave, the date of death doesn't match the time of the shooting of Fang. I departed after the shooting, so Doctor there is a discrepancy.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_verit_shram_1">
    <text>I see Scar, yes, I see... oh my!</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_verit_shram_2">
    <text>What do you think? Where do you want the body?</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_verit_shram_3">
    <text>This is not Ghost! Well it is his armor but not his teeth. Someone made up the rumors. Ghost could make up any nonsense and then use someone else's corpse. But why?! To hide from himself? It looks like he really killed Fang by mistake and after that he could not look Archer in the eye. So he decided to escape and leave the corpse of this unfortunate stalker. We will bury him properly.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_verit_shram_4">
    <text>So Doctor are you saying that all three of them Strelok, Ghost and Fang may still be alive. Wow, if I really knew what was going on I'd be quite excited.</text>
</string>

<!-- Talking to Swamp Doctor in Cordon, returning the body from X16, pt 2 -->
<string id="doktor_verit2_shram_0">
    <text>Now do you trust me Doctor?</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_verit2_shram_1">
    <text>Ha, trust you Scar? No, never, men like you are never to be trusted. However I think this time you have told the truth. Listen Scar, Lebedev destroyed everything I had. Costa said that the artifact which protected him from bullets has already lost much of its energy, and I hear he is weak and now tired of fighting. According to my information he is at the base in the Marsh. I think he has gone back there to die.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_verit2_shram_2">
    <text>Go on...</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_verit2_shram_3">
    <text>If you make up your mind to confront him, and I suggest you hurry, then please also find my documents on the 'Study of  Mutants'. He took them from me before he burned my farm in Swamp. The documents should be at this base or nearby. If you bring back my documents I'll be happy, and not just me. Oh, I almost forgot, there is a big stash of weapons in the Marsh somewhere in the middle near or on a very small island where there are two dead trees. Bandits hang around there a lot, and it can have the information which will possibly lead to Strelok. If he is still alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_verit2_shram_4">
    <text>Ok Doctor, well I too am growing old and tired, so perhaps I too should go to the Marsh.</text>
</string>

<!-- Talking to Gastello after crashing the helicopter in the Marsh -->
<string id="mar_gastello_dialog_0">
    <text>Sorry about your new helicopter... errr... where did you come from?</text>
</string>
<string id="mar_gastello_dialog_1">
    <text>I can't believe that I found a working helicopter only for you to crash it! Oleg sent me a message telling me you might need help.</text>
</string>
<string id="mar_gastello_dialog_2">
    <text>Is this going to be another one of those vaguely confusing and pointless conversations?</text>
</string>
<string id="mar_gastello_dialog_3">
    <text>Yep that seems pretty likely to me. Oh, Oleg said don't forget to see if you can find the arms cache in the centre of the Marsh to the northwest on a small island with two dead trees. One thing to note, the two transitions you and Kostya created to go to and from the Clear Sky base may well have merged into only one way by now. Make sure you walk through it slowly to allow it to work. Just don't ask me how I know, ok?!</text>
</string>
<string id="mar_gastello_dialog_4">
    <text>Well that reminds me I also need to find the documents in the former Clear Sky base in Marsh to take back to Doctor while you stay here. Hmm... yes, this feels very much like another one of those pointless conversations to me. Let's hope we only have it once.</text>
</string>

<!-- SPLAT The final meeting with Lebedev in Clear Sky base -->
<string id="lebed_doki_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Lebedev. Where are the Doctor's documents?</text>
</string>
<string id="lebed_doki_dialog_1">
    <text>They are all in the next room.</text>
</string>
<string id="lebed_doki_dialog_2">
    <text>Who's the leader of the Masters and where do I find him, and where is Voronin's wife?</text>
</string>
<string id="lebed_doki_dialog_3">
    <text>The main base is in Zaton, and how to get there is very simple. Here is a picture, give it to Sakharov, he should be able to tell you who is on it. Voronin's wife is under the supervision of the Witches, but where she is being held right now I do not know.</text>
</string>
<string id="lebed_doki_dialog_4">
    <text>Since you lost control of everything where will you go now?</text>
</string>

<!-- post heli ride to kill monsters in NE of Dark Valley - talking to Drill to get him to move to the gas station SPLAT -->
<string id="bur_val_baza_ok_dialog_0">
    <text>So what's next?</text>
</string>
<string id="bur_val_baza_ok_dialog_1">
    <text>We need to wait.</text>
</string>
<string id="bur_val_baza_ok_dialog_2">
    <text>What is there to wait for?</text>
</string>
<string id="bur_val_baza_ok_dialog_3">
    <text>Did Bax get the deactivator? If so we can push on to the gas station.</text>
</string>
<string id="bur_val_baza_ok_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, well let's get a move on we don't have all day.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Sakharov after returning from Clear Sky base where Lebedev shoots himself -->
<string id="esc_sahar_zhena_0">
    <text>Here Professor, Lebedev gave me a picture of an old woman and said she was the leader of the so called 'Masters' faction. And he added that you know her.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sahar_zhena_1">
    <text>That's interesting. Give me the photo. Did Lebedev say anything else?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sahar_zhena_2">
    <text>Here you go, and no Lebedev didn't say much at all.</text>
</string>

<!-- returning to Sakharov with news that his wife heads the Witches/Msters/whatever -->
<string id="esc_sahar_zhena_poshla_na_0">
    <text>Are you feeling ok?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sahar_zhena_poshla_na_1">
    <text>No! This is my wife. How could she do that?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sahar_zhena_poshla_na_2">
    <text>Are you serious? Lebedev said that she is the patriarch of that faction. What is the name of your wife?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sahar_zhena_poshla_na_3">
    <text>Jana Markovna. But how, how? What should I do?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sahar_zhena_poshla_na_4">
    <text>Kruglov vaguely heard that someone called the leader Mark, or Marquand. That's where the dog is from too. They most likely said Markovna. Looks like you ignored her a little too much. I'm sorry Professor.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sahar_zhena_poshla_na_5">
    <text>You do not have to be sorry Scar, I'm a little guilty of her actions, I have spent too much time with my research and not enough with my wife. She had to find compensation for my lack of interest in her. She is rebelling against my research and the company. She was most likely influenced by Lebedev who is one of her friends, and she is very smart. For her money has become more important than science. This breaks my heart. I had thought she would be sent to me in pieces. But no, it was all a lie, she wasn't kidnapped. She had merely found a new life. Oh well, to hell with her.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sahar_zhena_poshla_na_6">
    <text>I'm sorry Professor. But at least you have escaped and know the truth. I've got to go now. Good luck.</text>
</string>

<!-- hugely confusing conversation with Navy in Wolf's Lair -->
<string id="dvd_bazar_dialog_0">
    <text>Get that weapon out of my face. I already had enough 'Masters' in my face.</text>
</string>
<string id="dvd_bazar_dialog_1">
    <text>Why did you not mention anything about the Absolutes? I would have given them back.</text>
</string>
<string id="dvd_bazar_dialog_2">
    <text>Actually I recognized the artifacts as my own, the missing five were stolen by Lebedev. So how did you come by them? Did you have a relationship with that bastard Lebedev?</text>
</string>
<string id="dvd_bazar_dialog_3">
    <text>I don't appreciate the allegations. I'll send you to hosiptal in a petri dish!</text>
</string>
<string id="dvd_bazar_dialog_4">
    <text>For what services did Lebedev share my artifacts with you?</text>
</string>
<string id="dvd_bazar_dialog_5">
    <text>Ok ok... I have a name, Margelov. I will not fight with you. He was showing off the Absolutes. He said he had won them from a commando. But later on he had fallen into a carousel anomaly. Many can attest to this fact. So I took the artifacts. The Absolutes you can keep, you earned them honestly. How was I to know that they were yours! Blah blah blah! Listen wait here for a minute or so and I'll open a transition to Zaton, or Backwater as your PDA shows it. Once you're there follow the trail of notes, you'll need to be able to navigate using 'degrees:minutes:seconds' coordinates. So make sure you have the compass from Agroprom or similar. There's a door code you'll need, '1986', best write that down! Then again everyone on Earth knows that year. Oh, and this is really important, if you get into the tunnels and the doors won't open then blast them with a shotgun, it should free them up. Try shooting the side doors first. One or two shots should do it.</text>
</string>
<string id="dvd_bazar_dialog_6">
    <text>Ok I'll wait for the transition. I've the funniest feeling that I should travel light, but with two good weapons. Maybe a Flamethrower, AA-12, plenty of ammo, a couple of spare rucksacks, a few GPS's, and a whole lot of health related items and food. Let's go!</text>
</string>

<!-- At the gas station with Drill, in Dark Valley SPLAT -->
<string id="bur_val_baza_dialog_0">
    <text>Here we are!</text>
</string>
<string id="bur_val_baza_dialog_1">
    <text>Good job, thank you Scar!</text>
</string>
<string id="bur_val_baza_dialog_2">
    <text>Will you occupy the post of Hog?</text>
</string>
<string id="bur_val_baza_dialog_3">
    <text>Hah! To become the new bandit leader and have even more enemies than I have now, so no I will not take over for him. Did you find the document with the X-18 code in Hog's room? If you've not searched the buildings yet then know that on the ground floor is the arsenal, but there are no good weapons there. Hog I think moved them to a new base. I do not know where it is because Hog keeps many secrets. But I'm not that stupid. I hear things and there's a stalker called 'Ace'. I might be able to put something on your PDA. I'm not sure exactly where he is, but Ace is supposedly somewhere between Dark Valley and Cordon in the territory of Garbage. It's pretty radioactive around there. The rumors among the lads who went out there is that there is a river/creek/pond, whatever, and some Klondikes. Hog planned to move there a long time ago. Frankly I've no idea what you should expect. Look if you find any documents in X-18 take them to Kostya in Cordon. Okay?</text>
</string>
<string id="bur_val_baza_dialog_4">
    <text>Sure! That's great, thank you for the info. I'll go into the base if I haven't already got that document, hang on... let me check.</text>
</string>

<!-- Talking to Swamp Doc after final mission to Clear Sky base - returning with his documents -->
<string id="doktor_lebed_ok_dialog_0">
    <text>I am finished Doctor. I collected your documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_lebed_ok_dialog_1">
    <text>Thank you Scar, I thought these were lost forever... you.... you've pleased the old man after all. So now I must tell you a story that you have a right to know. Two years ago when you went to the Clear Sky base what did you to do for your first mission?</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_lebed_ok_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, I woke up in the base, then Lebedev told me a little about the Zone and its impact on the world, and why they where there. The first task was helping at one of their outposts. Well I was running there and ran into three wild boars, and there was no one around to help me, and then a PDA message displayed about an emission coming, and I had to climb a tower to save my life, and then I went unconscious. Later I woke up back at the base in the same bed.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_lebed_ok_dialog_3">
    <text>Let me say that it was premeditated. Lebedev wanted to test your extraordinary ability to resist emissions. He saw in you all the profit that he could learn from the 'C-Consciousness' and he could call in for additional funding and staff. Next Strelok's corpse after being shot no one could find it. He was in the company of killers who where going to the 'death truck'. Strelok just got the job to kill Arrow. 'C-Consciousness' demanded Lebedev give a refund, but the inhabitants of Chernivtsi bolted to east Pripyat and settled there. The money was great and it did not cost much to create a new clan. He knew that they would survive in any release, as the 'C-Consciousness' had given protection, and you are alive for a third time despite all the dangers of the Zone. Why did Lebedev want Strelok killed?</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_lebed_ok_dialog_4">
    <text>Lebedev told me that the cause of emissions is that Strelok had made it to the 'Brain Scorcher' and screwed with it.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_lebed_ok_dialog_5">
    <text>So we put everything in its place. I already know you started looking for Strelok, and you where going to thee north. I hope that he and his friends Ghost and Fang are alive. I would like to see all three here in Cordon. Once again I thank you, and if they are found then immediately inform me. We will also share information as long as communication is possible. Be careful. Oh, Voronin called, he wants to see you. Good luck!</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_lebed_ok_dialog_6">
    <text>Thanks. I guess I will go see Voronin.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_lebed_ok_dialog_7">
    <text>Hold it, I completely forgot. While you where in Swamps Airborne contacted me and wants you to see him about your artifacts. He is in Wolf's Lair. I immediately thought about how Lebedev took your Absolutes. He told me that Lebedev gave 5 of your Absolutes to Airborne for good service. Kostya just showed me similar artifacts, but I don't know if they are yours.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_lebed_ok_dialog_8">
    <text>Now I see that it is not a coincidence. Things are not as they seem. Thanks for the information. I'll go talk with the Airborne.</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_lebed_ok_dialog_9">
    <text>Roger that Scar. Be careful!</text>
</string>

<!-- End of the first episode -->
<string id="voronin_final_dialog_0">
    <text>I am finished General. I have some news for you. The 'Witches' have your wife, but I do not know where. According to Lebedev the leader of the 'Masters' is Sakharov's wife, Jana Markovna, and their base is somewhere in Zaton.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_final_dialog_1">
    <text>I suppose that is some good news! All is not lost then. Sakharov's wife? Well that's why she had requested to work in Zaton six months ago. The professor will never get over it!</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_final_dialog_2">
    <text>The professor will be ok. This news makes it easier to deal with the situation. Maybe we can do something before his wife ends up in pieces. I need to get to Pripyat, but I do not know where the transition is located.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_final_dialog_3">
    <text>Since you are looking for Strelok, I have a request for you. If you learn about my wife then let me know. I can get help. I could send a chopper to rescue her. In Pripyat and Chernobyl there are mainly leftover mercenaries from Lebedev's group, and a few monoliths that are less numerous. Inside the central area is controlled by the 'Masters' and the military and they also share Jupiter, but Zaton is largely controlled by the 'Masters'. Only some really small independent clans survive in this sector, and certainly 'Masters' selling artifacts and other trinkets. Basically, that's the situation. So in summary the place is a total madhouse!</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_final_dialog_4">
    <text>Strelok is perhaps also in captivity there, however I hope not. I will do my best to find out what has become of your wife. We must hope that she is held in Jupiter, since I am a little familar with it. On the other hand though there are some active deadly areas that are inaccessible.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_final_dialog_5">
    <text>That's right that area of the Zone is real bad! Even our choppers cannot go into some areas. We had one disintegrate while in the air. By the way Skinflint wants to see you. He remembered something to tell you, and he might know how to get to Pripyat. Oh and don't let his name fool you because he often has the best prices. You might need some supplies, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_final_dialog_6">
    <text>Thank you General! I have one request and that is to take care of my daughter by keeping in touch with the clinic where my daughter is located. If anything of importance takes place please let me know by PM! I'll go see Skinflint. Oh, I almost forgot, what is the current relationship between the military and your group?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_final_dialog_7">
    <text>Politics, brother, politics! Some of the supreme leaders believe that I created a group on their account. To me it's just all about money, you know what I mean. Yes I will look after your daughter Scar. I have a surveillance camera with a recording of Strelok passing by here. Probably heading towards the 'C-Consciousness'! I must admit that there is much to learn about our friend Strelok, the 'legendary' stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_final_dialog_8">
    <text>Okay, let's watch the first episode's film before going to the next episode!</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_final2_dialog_0">
    <text>I am finished General! Lebedev's flew off, he's gone!</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_final2_dialog_1">
    <text>This is good news, amen brother!</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_final2_dialog_2">
    <text>I need to get to Pripyat, but I have no idea where the transition is located.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_final2_dialog_3">
    <text>I understand that you're going after Strelok. I have a request that if you have any information on my wife to let me know, or if you find her please contact me and I will send a helicopter to smuggle her out. So you know, Pripyat and Chernobyl are mainly mercenaries and remnants of Lebedev's monoliths which are less numerous. Inside the plant is controlled by the 'Masters' and military stalkers. These two latter groups also share Jupiter, but in Zaton it is mostly in the hands of the 'Masters'. However there are a few independent clans in that area. That's as much as we know!</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_final2_dialog_4">
    <text>Strelok might be in imprisoned there too. I will do my best to find out about your wife. Hopefully she is be held in Jupiter rather that Zaton. Those places are really dangerous.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_final2_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes some of those areas are really dangerous. Best to avoid them for sure. Even in the air is unsafe. We lost a chopper there not to long ago. Maybe you can get some information from Skinflint. He wants to see you anyway. He remembered something he forgot to tell you. He just might know how to get to Pripyat. Before you go back on the road do you have a special request to make?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_final2_dialog_6">
    <text>Thank you General! If I am in need of anything I'll let you know. However I do have one important request and that is to check on my daughter at the clinic every so often. I'll let you know of any information I find. I'm going to see Skinflint now. Does your group and the military get along at all?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_final2_dialog_7">
    <text>Not always, politics, you know! The military are somewhat paranoid. They think I put this group together just to spite them. Making money seems to be the biggest problem. Yes I will keep an eye on your daughter. After all I don't have much to do here except surveillance. I have a video of the 'legendary' stalker Strelok passing by!</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_final2_dialog_8">
    <text>Okay, it's time to watch the first episode's film before moving to the next episode!</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Kostya in Cordon after Agroprom -->
<string id="esc_kostya_dialog_0">
    <text>Damn, you move fast!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kostya_dialog_1">
    <text>This is due to the Absolutes!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kostya_dialog_2">
    <text>At least you weren't caught short. I once had a Simbion, it was awesome. Do you know if there is a recipe to create one?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kostya_dialog_3">
    <text>Of course, it's in X-18. In a room behind a coded computer room door. If you get in there then you can have it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kostya_dialog_4">
    <text>Why on Earth did you leave the recipe in there?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kostya_dialog_5">
    <text>Oh jeez I guess it's a game to me and I wouldn't want anyone trying to get in there to get bored!! Anyway I barely had time to shut the damn door and code it. There where several mutants after me. I was running low on ammo and there was this freak'n attacking dinosaur looking thingie. In the north of the Zone I came across some really strange things. But in the X-18 it was like miracles taking place.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kostya_dialog_6">
    <text>Dinosaurs appearing! Damn must be awesome. I always wanted a T-Rex for a pet.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kostya_dialog_7">
    <text>Yep a whole lotta fun! Just so you know there is an 'hour of horror' that will happen when it's least convenient. It doesn't happen everywhere, mostly in the northern zone, but also sometimes in Marshes and Garbage. Here in Cordon never. It is like the 'night of the living dead', mutants, mutants and more mutants. In X-18 there should be documents from our archives. If you find any then pick them up and bring them back to me. Horrors exist in there and sometimes the PDA goes nuts! One time I found a PDA that had a white spot on the map between Cordon and Dark Valley, and the PDA text stated Hannah Montana was going to sing there.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kostya_dialog_8">
    <text>I hate going into those labs, however on occasion I am forced to search them for documents, etc. Sorry, please continue.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kostya_dialog_9">
    <text>It's weird... all of this weird stuff on that PDA. This gap between Cordon and Dark Valley is strange. According to old documents nothing was ever there. But there must be some kind of clue. If you look at the global map along the Pripyat River you will see the old railway tracks, which oddly divides this mysterious area. Luminosity spots appeared a year ago after the destruction of the Marksman units fo the C-Consciousness at Chernobyl. The luminosity was explained as being some unknown energy field. Other than that, nobody knows anything. Choppers could not sustain flight over the hills there. And there was reported anomalous radioactivity fields. Maybe there is some sort of explanation in the archives in Lat X-18. To find local people who lived in these places before the 1986 accident was scarce. Yes, if needed, Black Holes, flesh eyes, poltergeists, and artifacts Flash or Moonlight. Activate only 'Black Hole' next to the neutrals, and to Cordon I do not advise to do so. The PDA had a special section with lot of disk imaging.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kostya_dialog_10">
    <text>A real mystery, but quite interesting since the terrain is not all visible and yet a trail must be there somewhere. If destined to be in X-18 then I will check for archives.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Kostya after finding the X-18 documents -->
<string id="esc_kostya2_dialog_0">
    <text>I found an old document in X-18, and a map too.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kostya2_dialog_1">
    <text>You survived X-18... wow, that's kewl. Let me have a look at the documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kostya2_dialog_2">
    <text>Here you go... is it anything special?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kostya2_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, no. It just confirms the passage of the railway through that strange territory. This area was just a dump before 1986, but I don't understand the lit area on the PDA. Who knows what it's really like there now.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kostya2_dialog_4">
    <text>My information is that Hog is planning to change the location of his base, but to where is not known.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kostya2_dialog_5">
    <text>Hell if I know. Well, we will look for clues. You will have to head back to the north. Be careful Scar. If anything turns up I'll be in touch.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_kostya3_dialog_0">
    <text>On the way to Hog's base there is some kind of artificial radiation being generated. You do not know how you can disable it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kostya3_dialog_1">
    <text>I was also surprised about that. Maybe it can be deactivated by the dog who was guarding me in the basement.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kostya3_dialog_2">
    <text>Come on, tell me more.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kostya3_dialog_3">
    <text>There is a dog named Bax. An Albino pseudodog that is all white. Where they got the dog or keep it I do not know, however it did not like thugs. They kept it in the street outside the basement where I was sitting. The command was: 'Bax, take Deactivate' Bax jumped up and ran to the territory somewhere to a garage cabinet, grabbed something like a PDA, so fast that the bandits were after him as yelling kids. They fled in the direction of Garbage and only there to take away the Deactivate. That area was switched off for sure. If you want to act like a Cynologist and try commanding the dog, it is best to give the command in a tower near the first gate seen from the south side. Come close to the basement as the psy-zone should not be active there. Bax late in the evening is very aggressive so it's better to go in the morning or afternoon. Hog and Bax did not like each other. Bax once bit Hog. He-he! Anyway, Can I go with you?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kostya3_dialog_4">
    <text>No, stay here! I'll try shooting from a bush. The tower should be no issue to climb. I will try to work the dog like a Cynologist. Seems like all is going smoothly to far.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kostya3_dialog_5">
    <text>Careful Scar and good luck. Remember that it is better to go in the morning or afternoon.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_teleport_dialog_0">
    <text>I have a Flash and two eyes. Can I have two Black Holes?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_teleport_dialog_1">
    <text>Here you go.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_teleport_dialog_2">
    <text>Ok here.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_teleport2_dialog_0">
    <text>I have a Moonlight and two eyes. Can I have two Black Holes?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_teleport2_dialog_1">
    <text>Here you go.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_teleport2_dialog_2">
    <text>Ok here.</text>
</string>

<!-- Finding Sidorovich in Wolf's Lair -->
<string id="zdarovo_0">
    <text>Sidorovich you actually brought that stupid door with you! Don't get me wrong, she could pull something of mine any time she wants. Anyway, I thought you flew off to the Zone center?</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_1">
    <text>Up your's Scar. I had hoped that this hut was out of the way from everyone, and it was one way I was sure not to see your ugly face again. Well, so much for that plan! So, did you talk to Fairy and Torych yet? It's worth it, trust me.</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_2">
    <text>So do you still trade counterfeit vodka? I guess it helps around here to suppress any bestiality concerns.</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_3">
    <text>Aaaaa you idiot!! Yeah the counterfeit vodka from hell. Can you taste a difference? I have a wholly organic product, never filtered to preserve... uhmm... well... it has natural flavors... here try a bottle... it's unlikely to kill you... I think.</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_4">
    <text>I'll pass!</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_5">
    <text>You did a good job when you were in Cordon Scar. Go on, drink up!!</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_6">
    <text>Well okay, for good luck.</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_7">
    <text>Yes yes drink, and then I forgive everything. God forbid you should die! Why you make a face?</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_8">
    <text>Because it tastes like Chimera fodder! What's not to wince at... phew... my teeth have gone numb. Sidorovich who taught you to make moonshine? Not the Swamp Doctor that's for sure.</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_9">
    <text>He-he it's my grandfather's recipe. Handed down from generation to generation. I'll never share it. Have another one, as they say: 'between the first and the last'.</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_10">
    <text>Those generations should have had a big gap along the way. Well, for life I guess!</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_11">
    <text>Eat, I say. Pig out!</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_12">
    <text>Yeah I am a bit hungry too. I got the munchies. Do you know what is going on around these parts?</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_13">
    <text>I even know zombie names. Rumors are coming to me like a river. Maybe you and I will become zomppiess one day! You must keep your vits around hera, you might enadannger odhers.</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_14">
    <text>Predstttttaaaaavlyayu! I zzombie sttttttrelyayu left nnnnapravo haha!</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_15">
    <text>Yep yurrir hooked. This is serious Moonshine, it's not stalker vodka.</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_16">
    <text>Ddddavay, pour!</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_17">
    <text>Ddddavay, zzzzza that drink?</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_18">
    <text>Ggggggy, Ssssidivich, DDA you tttozhe zzatsepilo old fuck! Well, zzza is my daughter!</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_19">
    <text>Zzzzzza your daughter, let nnnu Scar! A daughter - this is your ppppushka?</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_20">
    <text>Hhhren you Ssidrch! Daughter, my rrrrodnaya krrrovinushka.</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_21">
    <text>Nnnu then for it yet hryapnem!</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_22">
    <text>Nnnalivay!</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_23">
    <text>Ddddddderzhi. Well, Dry-Z Africa your daughter! Aw, you threw in rrrrecipe PDDDA. Pppolzuysya until I dddobry.</text>
</string>
<string id="zdarovo_24">
    <text>Ddavay! For her! Ssidrch, ddddavay sppppoem.</text>
</string>

<!-- Talking to Duty guy at the north Garbage outpost after going into X-18 -->
<string id="prapor_sebal_0">
    <text>Hey, where did your commander go?</text>
</string>
<string id="prapor_sebal_1">
    <text>Yeah, fuck knows Scar? Sort of went to pee and he's still not back. The guys think he's a runner now since his PDA is off, so can't look for him.</text>
</string>
<string id="prapor_sebal_2">
    <text>Oh, he's the son of a bitch! He owes me money. Oh well, the earth is round so we'll meet him again, don't know where, don't know when, but I know we'll meet again some sunny day.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Torych in Wolf's Lair 1st time -->
<string id="aver_tor_nout_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi, you've got a tough job guarding that girl.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_nout_dialog_1">
    <text>What makes you think she needs protecting fella, and just who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_nout_dialog_2">
    <text>Scar, people call me Scar. I'm hear on a job.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_nout_dialog_3">
    <text>Scar... yes I've heard about you. Nice face with that huge scar. Magpie mentioned you. He said you liked to work odd jobs?</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_nout_dialog_4">
    <text>Nice face with that huge nose. Sure I work odd jobs, if the money's right.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_nout_dialog_5">
    <text>You want a job? The scientists had a link established for access to the internet, but a drunken asshole drinking with Gastello in his shack threw the laptop into a little swamp. It was a good laptop too and the problem is they were so drunk they don't remember which little swamp. It seems like there are two options - either the little swamp near the northern path, or the larger swamp in the middle of the southwest area. I warn you you're going to have to look very carefully. I would look myself but I hate getting my feet wet. I'll give you a good reward if you find it working. How does that sound?</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_nout_dialog_6">
    <text>Right... well okay I'll look for the laptop, although I can't see it ever working again!</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_nout_dialog_7">
    <text>Yeah, well let's pray it does. Watch out for those giant cockroaches and gargoyle looking chimeras.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_nout_dialog_8">
    <text>That's just great! Tell them to buy a freak'n desktop next time.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Torych in Wolf's Lair second time -->
<string id="aver_tor_nout_ok_0">
    <text>I found the laptop. It's dead as a door nail!</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_nout_ok_1">
    <text>Thanks Scar. These drunks amaze me.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_nout_ok_2">
    <text>My reward?</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_nout_ok_3">
    <text>The old man won't give a reward for a busted laptop. So sorry I've nothing for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_nout_ok_4">
    <text>Right, sure, great, schumck. I almost got killed there by some huge mutant.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_nout_ok_5">
    <text>Look Scar maybe Fairy can repair the hardware. She is good with hard things. He-he! But we do not have needed software. Sidorovich has only old software. However I have a friend right now at the Bar, Coulter, he's at the Duty checkpoint from Garbage. Check him out, he has a DVD full of software. Do me a favor and go get it and I'll share important info and you will know everything I know. Just to warn you the transition I know delivers you behind the Bar so you'll have to climb over a fence or jump down a little cliff. Watch out for dogs there.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_nout_ok_6">
    <text>Okay, I'll get to it sooner or later. I need to make a decision now, to the Bar for the DVD, or to Dark Valley to kill Hog.\n\n</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_nout_ok_7">
    <text>%c[255,255,128,1]Screw it, keep your junk. I really don't think I need any more of 'your' help!</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_nout_ok_8">
    <text>Okay Scar!</text>
</string>

<!-- Talking to Sidrovich after talking Voronin, after killing Hog, on the way to search caves -->
<string id="aver_sidor_haker_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey Sidorovich I hear you are bored?</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_sidor_haker_dialog_1">
    <text>Scar, wow, it's like you're wearing x-ray glasses.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_sidor_haker_dialog_2">
    <text>Yeah, with the new invisible frames from Eye-Savers. So what's up?</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_sidor_haker_dialog_3">
    <text>Well I decided to access the Internet and immediately got a virus from one of those Russian download sites. It pops up some guys ugly mug with a grin on the screen and displays the text - 'Your computer is infected with the most dangerous virus', and to destroy the virus it gives you an account number to send money to, which is in Nigeria. When they get the money you get a code to eliminate the virus, otherwise the virus destroys the system. It's like they have found a sucker, me, as if there is an ATM machine in the cave under the swamp. I wonder if it is a Carthaginian virus.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_sidor_haker_dialog_4">
    <text>Well Sid it seems like a Trojan, not the Carthaginian virus. This can be done by anyone anywhere. No shit, even on sites with pictures, one infected jpg could cause a problem. I suggest you download AVG or Avira or similar. Anyway I can help in the deletion of the virus. Throw the laptop into a swamp, I think your virus will not survive. Ha-ha!</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_sidor_haker_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes, that is very funny. A trojan you think? I have one such a stalker in mind who could fix this. A pharmacist, he collects different plant roots and soil samples. Anyway I paid him for a job, but he just ran off with my money. A little later I found out that he half set up a database for General Voronin, and then ran with his money too. But now I hear that a group of bandits in Cordon have him in their company. They settled near the ruins before reaching the bridge. Look there, then to the left side of the road. How they got to Cordon, only hell knows, but I think the pharmacist led them there for some reason. I don't know why?</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_sidor_haker_dialog_6">
    <text>You probably want me to go to Cordon and deal with all the bandits, see the pharmacist and bring him here? Or would you prefer I just get your money back?</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_sidor_haker_dialog_7">
    <text>Stop Scar, no need to kill him. Just talk it out with the bandits and the pharmacist. Give him a hint it was better for you to come, not Voronin or me. Anyway I think he may be pleased to see you as I think the bandits have taken him hostage. So after their death... err I mean... after you talk to them, he will be in your debt. Bringing him here is not necessary. Just talk to him and give him the transition to come here, and I will give you a tip for a Klondike artifact. It is not 100%, but still good info. Oh and do not forget to get info from him about the plans of the bandits. I'll give you a GPS tracker, sell it cheap, and enable it for this moron... err... I mean scientist... my map will light up like Christmas and I'll watch him.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_sidor_haker_dialog_8">
    <text>You can be very persuasive Sid, this nerd apparently is the only one who did not fall for it. I must admit it, but you're right. So give me the beacon and I'll play James Bond in Cordon for you.</text>
</string>

<!-- Talking to Invisible Bullet after going into X-18 -->
<string id="gar_baks_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi Bullet! Have you seen a big white dog called 'Bax'? I thought I saw it here a while ago. I need it to help open the transition from Dark Valley to Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_baks_dialog_1">
    <text>Certainly I've seen it. It is running aroud here somewhere. It and I have long been familiar. When it first ran up to me I was taken back a little, pseudodogs are rarely friendly, and I've never seen a white one, but we became friends. I was in Dark Valley for a while on the orders of Voronin, Strelok too. It helped me fighting criminals. For that I was very grateful. I give it food too. Did you lure Bax here?</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_baks_dialog_2">
    <text>Bax came here on its own, it didn't like Hog. Drill suggested how to lure Bax out, and use it to disable the radiation zone. All hail Bax the hero!</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Bullet while still invisible at the Garbage Duty checkpoint -->
<string id="gar_baks2_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, nice to see you again.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_baks2_dialog_1">
    <text>I received from Barkeep and Voronin a transition to Garbage. Scar there is a matter I need you to handle!</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_baks2_dialog_2">
    <text>Geez, what now?</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_baks2_dialog_3">
    <text>You're not going to Dark Valley by chance, are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_baks2_dialog_4">
    <text>I do have some business there. Is there something I can do for you?</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_baks2_dialog_5">
    <text>If you go there get my armor from a bandit. I cannot leave here right now. I'll give you a good unique veteran outfit as well as a bandit stash with artifacts. I'll put the transition point from Garbage to Dark Valley on your PDA and also mark the cache location. Voronin gave the okay to declassify this transition and also the transition from the Bar to Wild Territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_baks2_dialog_6">
    <text>All right. I'll bring you your armor.\n\n</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_baks2_dialog_7">
    <text>%c[255,255,128,1]I apologize brother! It's not on my way. I am really busy right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_baks2_dialog_8">
    <text>Okay I'll find someone else, but I'll put the transition location on your PDA anyway.</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Bullet while still invisible at the Garbage Duty checkpoint -->
<string id="gar_baks3_dialog_0">
    <text>Take your armor. Most of the artifacts from the stash turned into shit and are useless.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_baks3_dialog_1">
    <text>Thanks Scar! You may keep the armor. A gift! Now watch this! Abracadabra! Boo! He-he!</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_baks3_dialog_2">
    <text>I've seen magic tricks, but then again I must admit that you surprised me! Nice one!</text>
</string>


<!-- talking to Pharmacist in Cordon for Sidrovich -->
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_0">
    <text>So Pharmacist you got into a little trouble here! I would have thought you would be in good company with dogs, bandits and other scum.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, how dare you insult me??? Who the hell are you wise ass?</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_2">
    <text>Shut up dude. Tell me what these bandits are up to. If you think that you do not need me I would be happy to help you join your bandit friends here. If I hadn't helped you you could have ended up as boiled food. You understand me?</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_3">
    <text>Really, which bandits, the ones standing or the ones sleeping?</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_4">
    <text>They are all in permanent sleep now.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_5">
    <text>What makes you think I need you? I've got plenty of other friends south of here.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_6">
    <text>The problem with your logic is that I am between you and the south. Listen you clown tell me what their plans were!</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_7">
    <text>Their plans are no secret to smart people, they want to establish a bandit's hacker network here. Why they came to me I'll never know, I'm a respected scientist. They made this camp since Cordon is the most convenient place. I could not refuse them because, well, they promised the same thing as you and that is death.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_8">
    <text>Well you can thank Sidorovich for your life, he sent me. You remember Sid who you ripped off and General Voronin? You took their money. Now scumbag to save your life and your debt he needs your help because his laptop was trashed by your bandit idiots. He's in the Wolf's Lair and suggests you go to help him. It's quieter there than even here in Cordon. The route to Sid I will put on the PDA. Take your time to think, but remember, alone you are nothing here but another unarmed victim waiting for the dogs to rip you to pieces. So thief... what do you say?</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_9">
    <text>I'll think about it. I guess I could try fixing it.</text>
</string>


<string id="kalter_disk_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi! Torych said you have a CD with software. I'm here to pick it up.</text>
</string>
<string id="kalter_disk_dialog_1">
    <text>I would give it up, but I don't have it anymore.</text>
</string>
<string id="kalter_disk_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh that's bloody great, where you drunk when you lost it? Anyhow, forget it, just tell me where it is.</text>
</string>
<string id="kalter_disk_dialog_3">
    <text>Hey go easy on me, Torych said he'd finished with it so I sold it to someone who then threw it in the trash when they were done with it. The trash gets thrown over the fence, but who knows which fence it could have been. If you have the time and desire, then jump over the fences, and have a look. However rumors have it that it might be somewhere around the the guys at the northern exit from the Bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="kalter_disk_dialog_4">
    <text>Shit, oh well, I guess I'll have to play leapfrog!</text>
</string>
<string id="kalter_disk_dialog_5">
    <text>Well if you find it just give it to Torych. Look I like Torych I tell you. I think he may be near the exit to Warehouses, around the Duty post now.</text>
</string>

<string id="aver_tor_disk_ok_0">
    <text>Oh what fun I've had. Dima had sold the CD to a guy who'd then lost it. However after a bit of fun and games I found it. No problem really, just a bunch of teleporting 'Witches'. Oh, and Dima says 'hello'.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_disk_ok_1">
    <text>So, what's up?</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_disk_ok_2">
    <text>What's up...! Look friend first I received a strange message about a Teleport 'Y', then when I picked up the disc there were 'Witches' falling like snow flakes from the sky. It was a madhouse! What the hell are they about?</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_disk_ok_3">
    <text>No shit! Teleport 'Y'?! I once heard something about 'Witches', but I do not remember anything specific, it was many moons ago.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_disk_ok_4">
    <text>Okay here ya go, take the disc.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_tor_disk_ok_5">
    <text>So I'll tell you about a great cache in Radar that is somewhere in the Red Forest. A chest with a cache from a guy called 'Semetsky'. Just watch out because electro-chimeras are there. Oh, and the area is under the control of the 'Masters'. Another bunch of crazies!</text>
</string>

<!-- talking to Sid in wolfs lair after talking to the Pharmacist -->
<string id="escape_dimon_0">
    <text>Well Sidor do you see the Pharmacist nerdy thief on your PDA?</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_dimon_1">
    <text>Damn, I do not see any marker. Do you lie just for the reward?</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_dimon_2">
    <text>Have you had your marbles tested recently Sid? I talked to the Pharmacist, heart to heart, he will fix your laptop. He was going to help set up a hacker network in Cordon. I stopped everything!. However the bandits had weapons that I have never seen before. Now give me a tip to find the Klondike as promised.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_dimon_3">
    <text>Yeah, okay, I see that ninny now. You must have reasoned well with him. When he gets here I will give you the tip about the Klondike. After all you did do a good job in Cordon. Ask me about something else and I'll try to answer.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_dimon_4">
    <text>Then tell me about Semetsky as I have received many SMS's on his death in many places.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_dimon_5">
    <text>Okay, I thought you knew. Semetsky was a merchant and very close friend to the scientists. Swag flowed through him like beer and urine. He loved to collect all sorts of stuff like, PDA's, lighters, watches, etc. PDA's was his disease. One day he was hit by a strong release, and it hit him hard, and later he disappeared. At first they thought that he was lost or moved to the mainland. But later one of the bandit stalkers said that he saw Semetsky in Cordon. The stalker said he had found Semetsky and announced it on the network. Many stalkers went there and the stalker who said he saw Semesky was dead and was holding one of Semetsky's PDA's. Then from the SMS there was a message about Yuri Semetsky was killed in Cordon by a Springboard. Later there were two cases of deaths in Garbage announced by SMS's. One was a neutral and the other a bandit who also died immediately after using PDA'a from Semetsky's stash. The neutral was all chewed up by pseudodogs and the bandit was killed by an Aspic. Where these deaths caused by some kind of curse created by Semetsky? Fuck knows, but stalkers say they do not believe in any hocus-pocus nonsense. The fact is that in some way Semetsky now lives and dies over and over again, and is sometimes seen by roaming stalkers.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_dimon_6">
    <text>Yes, Sidor, utter weirdness, but it is interesting.</text>
</string>

<!-- Talking to Sid after the scientist fixes hi PC -->
<string id="aver_dimon_0">
    <text>I see your nerd arrived.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_dimon_1">
    <text>Yes, he finished his work and is now leaving.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_dimon_2">
    <text>Did he clear up your virus?</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_dimon_3">
    <text>Yes! So as your reward I'll tell you a place where there's lots of really good artifacts. Although this Klondike field is not verified it should be in Radar in the Red Forest close to where you can find the Semetsky's stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_dimon_4">
    <text>Well, you're pseudodog fodder! I was expecting a simple retrieval process.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_dimon_5">
    <text>Don't be so sour Scar, a reward is a reward. It's in your favor. This Klondike field has many valuable things. Well that's what I was told.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_dimon_6">
    <text>Sidor where in the area do the abnormal grenades come from, the ones with strange and anomalous properties?</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_dimon_7">
    <text>I have done much research on the subject and in the end I have no freak'n idea. I read some garbled notes about them coming from boxes of grenades left too close to anomolies, but honestly, does it really matter? This feels like a conversation with no purpose to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="aver_dimon_8">
    <text>I hear ya!</text>
</string>


<string id="umnik_kod_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello comrade! I have info that you hold one of the 4-digit codes. I would like you to buy it.</text>
</string>
<string id="umnik_kod_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes I do, 50,000 rubles ok?</text>
</string>
<string id="umnik_kod_dialog_2">
    <text>It's a deal!</text>
</string>
<string id="umnik_kod_dialog_3">
    <text>You must be crazy charging those prices. Forget it!</text>
</string>


<string id="voronin_lam_0">
    <text>Well have you managed to raise two million rubles for your daughter?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_lam_1">
    <text>Possibly, but I need to check my accounts.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_lam_2">
    <text>I'll check them on my computer. Nope your short.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_lam_3">
    <text>Ugh, shit. So I don't have enough.</text>
</string>


<string id="igor_pda_dialog_0">
    <text>Anything else?</text> 
</string>
<string id="igor_pda_dialog_1">
    <text>When your PDA was serviced there was a beacon found that was disabled. Looks like it was installed about two years ago. We also think that you where trackable with that beacon, and that beacon could capture information from other PDA's that were within a distance of 500 meters. Anyway we enabled the part that captures information only.</text> 
</string>
<string id="igor_pda_dialog_2">
    <text>Interesting, but why would you help me?</text> 
</string>
<string id="igor_pda_dialog_3">
    <text>Simply put we don't have a choice due to a recent successful experiment. Now talk to Dimon.</text> 
</string>
<string id="igor_pda_dialog_4">
    <text>Thank you, I'll go talk to Dimon.</text> 
</string>

<!-- talking the Fairy in Wolf's Lair about the fee for the combo for the safe -->
<string id="feja_parol_dialog_0">
    <text>I made up my mind. Take the 5000, and I hope that no one will figure out the code.</text> 
</string>
<string id="feja_parol_dialog_1">
    <text>You can trust the code - three sevens, as the saying goes - Jackpot! Write it down noob.</text> 
</string>
<string id="feja_parol_dialog_2">
    <text>Nothing ventured nothing gained, as they say. Thanks!</text> 
</string>


<string id="che_za_hernja_0">
    <text>What the hell Dimon, where did the security guards go wrong? Sure is a strange situation.</text> 
</string>
<string id="che_za_hernja_1">
    <text>An explosion Scar? Explosion was big too. Maybe they stepped on a tripwire.</text> 
</string>
<string id="che_za_hernja_2">
    <text>Okay I will not go near that area just in case.</text> 
</string>


<string id="kostya_dialog_par_0">
    <text>%c[255,255,128,1]This area is really weird, have you seen the ghost locomotive?</text> 
</string>
<string id="kostya_dialog_par_1">
    <text>What the hell, a ghost locomotive, what have you been smoking?</text> 
</string>
<string id="kostya_dialog_par_2">
    <text>%c[255,255,128,1]Forget it, let's go.</text> 
</string>


<string id="bar_tango_do_0">
    <text>Welcome! I know where you're going. I have already been alerted. Go to Voronin, then come back and we'll talk.</text> 
</string>
<string id="bar_tango_do_1">
    <text>See ya!</text> 
</string>


<string id="infa_stalk_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello gunsmith! I, on the recommendation of Dimak, came to see you. He says you do good work. My name is Scar and I have a question.</text> 
</string>
<string id="infa_stalk_dialog_1">
    <text>I've heard about your affairs Scar. Your reputation preceeds you. Recently a stalker died in a train tunnel. Get his information and then we'll talk. Keep the loot... not for service, but for friendship.</text> 
</string>
<string id="infa_stalk_dialog_2">
    <text>Okay, gunsmith. I'll go see who died in the tunnel.</text> 
</string>


<string id="infa_stala_dialog_0">
    <text>Here is some info. I feel bad for the guy. Part of the cave fell on him. I saw that weird ghost train again. I don't understand anything about that area.</text> 
</string>
<string id="infa_stala_dialog_1">
    <text>Thank you for the info! Supposedly the ghost train is ridden by a wandering band of zombie stalkers. I heard that whoever sees this train immediately dies.</text> 
</string>
<string id="infa_stala_dialog_2">
    <text>I wonder where the rumors came from?</text> 
</string>


<string id="kluchi_davay_0">
    <text>Do not move, asshole!</text> 
</string>
<string id="kluchi_davay_1">
    <text>Your etiquette leaves a lot to be desired. Anyway don't kill me!</text> 
</string>
<string id="kluchi_davay_2">
    <text>The keys to the car! You got five seconds otherwise you'll be breathing through your ass!</text> 
</string>
<string id="kluchi_davay_3">
    <text>You going on vacation or something? You know, the road is infested with stalkers using RPG's. Aaaaah, take the keys, good riddance, just do not kill me!</text> 
</string>
<string id="kluchi_davay_4">
    <text>Okay now down on the ground and hands behind your head, or I'll blow your olives off.</text> 
</string>


<string id="buusty_gar_perehod_0">
    <text>Look, I found the hiding place. The most valuable thing was a flamethrower, and there was some information too. Lebedev blocked the transition to Garbage. The transition from Cordon to the Bar is trashed.</text> 
</string>
<string id="buusty_gar_perehod_1">
    <text>For good work, keep the flamethrower. It might come in handy someday.</text> 
</string>
<string id="buusty_gar_perehod_2">
    <text>Thank you for the flamethrower. I'll keep it with me.</text> 
</string>


<string id="af_kristal_zp">
    <text>'The Gift'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_kristal_zp">
    <text>Legendary artifact was found only once in some vast area and sold for huge money to the scientists. They gave it another name - 'Explorer'. The main quality is protection against radiation. But all other protections are useless.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_kristal_blue">
    <text>'Aquamarine'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_kristal_blue">
    <text>%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255Aquamarine %c[255,255,1,1]+250 \n %c[default]This is an extremely rare mutation of the artifact Crystal, and it is very radioactive. Under the enveloping film is aa thin layer of pure platinum of the highest standard. How this change in structure happens is still not clear, but the fact that two kilograms of platinum are very expensive. Remove the film and all the properties are lost, but how to do that is only known by a few stalker. Another name for the artifact, 'Fighter', a great defense in combat situations, but it increases the perception of burns and electric shock. Using and transporting is only possible with artifact that protect against radiation.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_repei">
    <text>'Bur'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_repei">
    <text>Artifact is some form of mutated seeds of such plants as 'Hvatalka' and 'Burn'. But only when separated from the parent in a very short period of time (5-20 min). Able to protect the skin from cuts, also prevents the passage of electric waves through the body. Artifact is common. Price is average.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-indilian">
    <text>'Indilian'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-indilian">
    <text>This extremely rare artifact is called 'Dream Hunter'. It protects against many creatures of the Zone. One major negative effect is a very slow recovery of health. Use only with the artifacts which increase health.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-mushroom">
    <text>'Mushroom'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-mushroom">
    <text>Artifact resembles a mushroom. Spawns from the anomaly 'Springboard' and is extremely rare. Forms within 0.3 meters of a strong force field. 'Field' can alter bullet trajectories with (100-150) meters. The artifact has a number of negative features, such as weakening of the burn healing, weakening the body to gravitational areas and the rapid depletion of body energy. Also has inflated humidity, so it will conduct electricity. Many stalkers finding this artifact usually rent it because of its negative features. The artifact should not affect ammo.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_dummy-star_monolith">
    <text>'Monolith Star'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-star_monolith">
    <text>A mysterious artifact. There are two versions of its appearance. \n 1. According to rumors when stalkers of the clan 'Monolith' went into the Zone's center and found the altar, they asked the Monolith gave them a sign that it exists. That night the artifact fell from Heaven to Earth. Gullable fanatics thought it was a sign from the Monolith. \n 2. According to scientists it was formed by the merger of several air anomalies. A very rare specimen and it is formed only in the area of the Chernobyl nuclear power plant.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-seashell">
    <text>'Shell'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-seashell">
    <text>Artifact found near the Bar by drunk stalker. He took it to the Barkeep first and tried to get a lot of money from him. But Barkeep would not pay much so the stalker went to the scientists. Useful properties of the artifact are a small increase in health and chemical protection. But will reduce bulletproof properties.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-djoker">
    <text>'Joker'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-djoker">
    <text>%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+15 \n %c[default]The origin of the artifact is not known. The Zone has only produced it a few times. Artifact gives wearer good protection from strikes, but reduces the endurance of his body. It is radioactive.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-dumbbell">
    <text>'Dumbbell'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-dumbbell">
    <text>It is called, a Dumbbell. The artifact itself is small, but in spite of that it weighs 18Kg. (Hence the name). Artifact also is incredibly strong. I cannot be cut, melted, or crushed. Place of creation is not known. Carrier wears artifact immediately begins to feel cheerful, it improves health too. Artifact decrease radiation. Negative features are none except its weight.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_dummy-vertyshka">
    <text>'Pinwheel'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-vertyshka">
    <text>The exact origin of the artifact is unknown. Scientists argue that the artifact originated at the confluence of two anomalies - 'Springboard' and 'Elektra'. Stalkers say that is the heart of the unknown purple vortex 'Black Angel'. The artifact is located right in the middle of the anomaly and makes it rotate, taking the form of a devastating whirlwind. Artifact offers good protection from electricity. Of the negative properties the deterioration of bullet resistance and reduced radiation protection.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-coal">
    <text>'Coal'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-coal">
    <text>The artifact has appeared recently in the Zone. Scientists believe it is a medium modification of the artifact 'Stone Flower'. Stalkers also believe that this artifact is nothing more than a dark soul from stalkers who perished horribly. Artifact looks like a lump of coal, but never leaves any surface residue. Artifact also perfectly absorbs Psi waves and is a good resistance to radioactive contamination, but with a greatly increased body fatigue. To avoid injury it should be used in conjunction with an energy artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-quill">
    <text>'Needle'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-quill">
    <text>%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+5 \n %c[default]Artifact generated by 'Burn'. It protects the skin from burns and media impact. Slightly radioactive.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-wool">
    <text>'Fire Wool'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-wool">
    <text>It occasionally can be found in areas of high temperature and density of air molecules and are often amenable to movement. Represents vatoobraznoe body red. Toughing it with bare hands is not recommended. In some versions of symbiosis is formed by 'Hot' and 'Burning'. Not very easy to transport. Experienced stalkers use metal containers. If the artifact has water poured on it it then will turn into a solid dark mass and lose all its properties. Demanding among scientists.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-bonanza">
    <text>'Octopus'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-bonanza">
    <text>Substance is formed at the confluence of anomalies 'Fountain' and 'Jelly'. Has a number of positive qualities and some negative. Was found recently by a stalker nicknamed Gadget. From his exoskeleton he saw a small 'Fountain' of gelatinous body and climbed it to get to the anomaly. Powerful fountain of substances escaping from the ground stripped half of Gadget's exoskeleton right hand away. He received a good reward for which he purchased a mechanical prosthetic hand.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-mercury_ball">
    <text>'Mercury Ball'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-mercury_ball">
    <text>%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+7 \n %c[default]Artifact often can be found in the infected areas. The ball is surrounded by smaller mercury balls spinning around the core. Do not touch with bare hands. The scientists found that this artifact actually consists of mercury, and because experiments revealed that under certain conditions the artifact can be produced from most drugs, it is concidered dangerous.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-bezi">
    <text>'Burning Leaves'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-bezi">
    <text>Scientists believe that this new mutation is known to just about everyone. It was first found by a stalker working in academics. Surveying a sample they found it has useful properties. It was later revealed that this type of mutation appeared as a result of experiments in the Laboratories X-18 and X-16. Scientists believe that something like an infected Snork could make help produce it. Has the property of a positive effect on the body support, speeding up recovery from chemical components, but also slows the process of blood clotting.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-glow">
    <text>'Glow'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-glow">
    <text>Artifact formed in the anomaly 'Elektra' from a variety of metal objects and alloys. Artifact glows. After detailed studies scientists have found that the artifact produces electricity in small amounts. Usually not too expensive. Artifact can make the carrier's skin much softer - hence increasing the risk of getting easily cut. Also the resistance of the body is lowered for radioactive contamination. Positive attributes - increased resistance to burns.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_dummy-node">
    <text>'Node'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-node">
    <text>%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+20 \n %c[default]Scientists have been struggling to solve the mystery of this artifact. It is harder than titanium and harder than diamond. However, it does not reach even the weight of 1kg. Creates a slight protective field, diverting path of bullets within (20-40) meters. Adverse effects are radiation and reduced resistance to impact injury.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_kosi">
    <text>'Fairy Braid'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-kosi">
    <text>Artifact formed by the merger of three anomalies - 'Fountain,' 'Hot' and 'Jelly'. It is extremely rare. Formation of this artifact is not understood by scientists yet. But it's obvious that in order to merge 3 anomalies into this is dangerous. Artifact can redirect bullets trajectory and gives the carrier a big burst of energy. Makes skin feel soft and support vulnerable. Also observed a slight rise in body temperature when used due to the heavy flow of blood in the body.</text>
</string>

</string_table>
