<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<!-- DR edited -->

<string_table>
<!--****************************-->
<!-- Sleeping Bag -->
<!--****************************-->
<string id="enc_equipment_abc_bag">
    <text>Good hypnotic much needed thing in the long hikes.</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_bag">
    <text>Bank of sleeping pills</text>
</string>
<string id="unlimited_time_id">
    <text>Time</text>
</string>
<string id="one_hour_id">
    <text>1/4 tablet</text>
</string>
<string id="tree_hours_id">
    <text>1/2 tablet</text>
</string>
<string id="nine_hours_id">
    <text>1 tablet</text>
</string>
<string id="sleep_cap_id">
    <text>Sleep:</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_invs_leep_exit">
    <text>I do not want</text>
</string>

<!--****************************-->
<!-- ABC Repair Tools -->
<!--****************************-->
<string id="enc_equipment_abc_kit">
    <text>Tools repair kit taken from company ABC.</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_kit">
    <text>Tool repair kit</text>
</string>
<string id="weapon_repair">
    <text>Repair Weapons:</text>
</string>
<string id="automatic_slot">
    <text>Automatic</text>
</string>
<string id="suit_control">
    <text>Management Costume:</text>
</string>
<string id="repair_cap_id">
    <text>Repair tools:</text>
</string>
<string id="remove_hemelt_id">
    <text>Eject Helmet</text>
</string>
<string id="add_hemelt_id">
    <text>Add Helmet</text>
</string>
<string id="repair_suit_id">
    <text>Repair</text>
</string>
<string id="helmet_removed_id">
    <text>Helmet repair.</text>
</string>
<string id="helmet_added_id">
    <text>Added helmet.</text>
</string>
<string id="suit_noneedrepair_id">
    <text>No need of repair. State:</text>
</string>
<string id="suit_repaired_id">
    <text>Costume repaired:</text>
</string>
<string id="suit_cantrepair_id">
    <text>Your skill is not enough.</text>
</string>
<string id="weapon_noneedrepair_id">
    <text>No need to be repaired. State:</text>
</string>
<string id="weapon_repaired_id">
    <text>Repaired Weapon:</text>
</string>
<string id="weapon_cantrepair_id">
    <text>Your skill is not good enough.</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_portal_id">
    <text>Teleport</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_yes_id">
    <text>Yes</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_no_id">
    <text>No</text>
</string>

<!--****************************-->
<!-- Money looting -->
<!--****************************-->

<!--**********************************************************-->
<!-- Enc. Story - BLOW, Portals, Inferno, Chernobyl, Weather -->
<!--**********************************************************-->
<string id="Blowout-waves">
    <text>Wave blowing</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_blowout_waves-story">
    <text>'Whiff blow wave' will be the result of regular intervals under a huge wave of energy and psychotropic gravitional podmetut through the region, causing it due to 'blow out.' Reuslt powerfull anomaly will come in the form of five waves of changing the whole environment zones near zone of the core. \n\n Waves may include everything from radiation, the earth start to shake, flash appears the sky turns red, then black, white and many other produce results 'post-Duht', which can cause: human mutations, blackouts, alucinations and many other unknown deadly effect. \n \n There will be no safe place for the blast, some stalkers prefer to refer to it as 'a load of BLOM' (Big blowout mutants or mutants), because the earth start to be shocking and models of each mutant are outside of their hiding places. Fool \n \n those believe it is safe in the basement of a bad, you can only be safe in real bunkers and underground tunnels. Whiff is going to happen when, make sure you have a set of anti-radiation, vodka, enough ammo and your weapons ready! and do not look to the sky, you could not become blind, only fool would do.</text>
</string>
<string id="Portals">
    <text>Portal</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_portals-story">
    <text>Powerfull anomaly can open a portal to a different place. Stalkers believe that m Portals can be a window to a different size, Monolith faction believes this could be their way to heaven and others say it may even be a strobe Inferno. \n number \n experienced Stalkers bizarre cases reported after portal creation and saw that bizarre creatures come from him, but saw no myth Inferno, perhaps because those who have seen, never come back. Be aware that anything can come from the portal.</text>
</string>
<string id="Inferno">
    <text>Inferno</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_inferno-story">
    <text>This myth was born in 1986, right after the first Chernobyl nuclear disaster. In the Ukrainian language, Chernobyl is the name of grass, wormwood (absinth) and Artemisia Pominov bible book revelatons - which fortells end of the world ... \n rev 8:10 \n and the third angel sounded, and there fell a great star from heaven, burning as it were a lamp, and it fell upon the third part of the rivers and on the fountains of waters; \n rev 8:11 \n and the name of the star called Wormwood: and the third part of the waters became wormwood, and many men died of the waters, because they were made bitter. \n\n Therefore the fact that a religious Stalkers believe that 'hell aka Inferno made man' in 1986 and since then, many people have seen things bizzare, from ghosts and mutations 'dead walkers' and the people believe it is an animal becuae, Kotor Inferno here .</text>
</string>
<string id="Story-1986">
    <text>Year 1986</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_disaster-story">
    <text>On the Friday evening of the 25th of April, the crew of the reactor at Chernobyl-4, prepared to test the test the next day to see how long it would keep turbines spin and generate power when the power went off the line. It was a dangerous test, but it's been done before. As part of the preparation, they took some of the critical system controlling system - including the automatic shutdown safety mechanisms. \n \n shortly after 1:00 am on April 26, the water supply has fallen and coolant strength began to increase. \n \n at 1:23 am, the operator moved to shut down the reactor in a low power mode, and the domino effect of previous errors caused severe power surges, causing a tremendous steam explosion which blew the 1000 ton cap on the nuclear containment vessel to smithereens. \n \n Some of the 211 control rods melted and then a second explosion, the cause of which is still the subject of disagreement among experts, threw out the parts of the burning radioactive fuel core and allowed air to rush in - igniting several tons of graphite insulating blocks. \n \n was this graphite fire released most of the radiation in the atmosphere and bespokoyasch spikes in atmospheric radiation were measured thousands of miles away. Radiation \n \n remains in Chernobyl area for the next 48,000 years, but people can start repopulating area in about 600 years - give or take three centuries. Experts predict that, by then, the most dangerous elements disappear - or rather after they are diluted into the air, soil and water rest of the world.</text>
</string>
<string id="Chaotic">
    <text>Chaotic weather</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weather-story">
    <text>Waves of blowout and massive doses of radiation in the atmosphere. The weather has become quite chaotic. One hour it could be a perfectly clear sky and in the next hour there could be quite a storm. You can experience some black-and white noise during these changes.</text>
</string>

<!--****************************-->
<!-- Cabrobro NPC 				-->
<!--****************************-->
<string id="esc_speed_bio">
    <text>Dimon came to the Zone to find his father.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_speed_name">
    <text>Dimon</text>
</string>

<!--****************************-->
<!-- Wish Granter				-->
<!--****************************-->
<string id="abc_wish_desire_1">
    <text>I want the zone to disappear.</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_wish_desire_2">
    <text>I want to be rich.</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_wish_desire_3">
    <text>I want to rule the world.</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_wish_desire_4">
    <text>Mankind has to be controlled.</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_wish_desire_5">
    <text>I want immortality.</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_wish_desire_6">
    <text>I want the perfect gear.</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_wish_desire_7">
    <text>I want a perfect artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_wish_granter">
    <text>Wish Granter</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_wish_speak">
    <text>You can only make one wish a day.</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_no_desire">
    <text>Okay, I'll come later.</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_wish_granter">
    <text>Wish Granter</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_wish_granted">
    <text>Danger Level 1</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_wish_remember">
    <text>Worked teleport - 'Y'</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_wish_vendetta_1">
    <text>No, you're one to disappear.</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_wish_vendetta_3">
    <text>No, we have a lot and we are going to control you.</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_wish_vendetta_4">
    <text>Mankind is controlled and that you will.</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_wish_vendetta_5">
    <text>The capture is yours, I give you the immortal army.</text>
</string>

<!--****************************-->
<!-- Nano Artifact Upgrade -->
<!--****************************-->
<string id="suit-power-upgrade">
    <text>Lifting Force</text>
</string>
<string id="suit-power-upgrade_desc">
    <text>High-tech artifact Nano: Increase power suit.</text>
</string>
<string id="suit-health-upgrade">
    <text>Ascent Health</text>
</string>
<string id="des-health-upgrade">
    <text>High-tech artifact Nano: Increase cell regeneration.</text>
</string>
<string id="suit-kev1-upgrade">
    <text>The rise of 10% Kevlar</text>
</string>
<string id="des-kev1-upgrade">
    <text>High-tech artifact Nano: 10% protection from kevlar.</text>
</string>
<string id="suit-kev2-upgrade">
    <text>The rise of 20% Kevlar</text>
</string>
<string id="des-kev2-upgrade">
    <text>High-tech artifact Nano: 20% protection from kevlar.</text>
</string>
<string id="suit-kev3-upgrade">
    <text>The rise of 30% Kevlar</text>
</string>
<string id="des-kev3-upgrade">
    <text>High-tech artifact Nano: 30% protection from kevlar.</text>
</string>

<!--****************************-->
<!-- 	Artifacts				-->
<!--****************************-->
<string id="af-electra-teleport">
    <text>Black hole</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-teleport">
    <text>Portal artifact to the end and not learned, creates an anomaly, 'Black Hole', and two of these anomalies on one level a chance to move teleporting from one to the other anomalies.</text>
</string>
<string id="af-repair-battery">
    <text>Battery Repair</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-repair-battery">
    <text>The beginning of this subject shrouded in scientific mystery. It is clear that it is made in terms of dielectric elements, but science does not know the physical conditions in which it was formed, one of insteresting properties that it can repair weapons and suits.</text>
</string>
<string id="af_wish-granter">
    <text>Wish Granter</text>
</string>
<string id="des_wish-granter">
    <text>Perfect Granter artifact yields to the desire itself.</text>
</string>

<!--****************************-->
<!-- 	ABC News and Zombied -->
<!--****************************-->
<string id="abc_bar_news">
    <text>After returning from a raid stalkers can relax and unwind in the bar. Especially for you, prices are reduced by 30 percent!</text>
</string>

<string id="abc_gar_news">
    <text>ATTENTION ALL! APPEARED TO DUMP unknown enemy!</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_agr_news">
    <text>ATTENTION ALL stalkers alone! APPEARED ON AGROPROM unknown enemy!</text>
</string>

<string id="abc_dar_news">
    <text>SCAR guard! IN THE VALLEY HAS ANOTHER Gangster clan!</text>
</string>

<string id="abc_ros_news">
    <text>Stalker! FACTORY 'Rostok' will be a new sexually transmitted infections? 'Witch' .. WARNING!</text>
</string>

<string id="abc_brain_news">
    <text>STALKER Scar! In the laboratory penetrated what that enemy forces! Some of our staff are not clean on hand to sell what that groups not END mood PROTOTYPE VIP PROTECTION!</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_rad_news">
    <text>ATTENTION ALL! On the radar APPEARED UNKNOWN WITH LARGE NUMBER OF GROUP!</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_bun_news">
    <text>The labeled! In the X-10 EXCEPT monoliths SOMEONE ELSE HAS! CAUTION!</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_pri_news">
    <text>WARNING! WRONGFUL DEATH! GLORY monoliths!</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_pry_news">
    <text>WARNING! WRONGFUL DEATH! WITCHES IN FIRE!</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_sar_news">
    <text>WARNING! WRONGFUL DEATH! GLORY monoliths!</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_mil_news">
    <text>HELP fight off the monster! In the long stay!</text>
</string>

<string id="fre_abc_reply">
    <text>Thanks for the hospitality BARTENDER will be time, go...</text>
</string>
<string id="dol_abc_reply">
    <text>GLORY long! THANK BARTENDER WILL TIME Zayd...</text>
</string>
<string id="ban_abc_reply_2">
    <text>DEBT draw FEET from the landfill...</text>
</string>
<string id="ban_abc_reply_3">
    <text>MOLE, ZAROYSYA better...</text>
</string>

<string id="ved_abc_reply_11">
    <text>GOATS! Scary! We hang...</text>
</string>
<string id="mon_abc_reply_11">
    <text>Death of a witch!</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_abc_reply_11">
    <text>DAMMIT! THESE whore witch! VALLE them...</text>
</string>
<string id="kil_abc_reply_11">
    <text>Extinguish stalkers...</text>
</string>
<string id="dol_abc_reply_11">
    <text>Bring down SAMI freak!</text>
</string>
<string id="ban_abc_reply_11">
    <text>Bring down SAMI freak!</text>
</string>
<string id="ved_abc_reply_3">
    <text>GOATS! Scary! We hang ..</text>
</string>
<string id="kil_abc_reply_3">
    <text>Extinguish fighters...</text>
</string>

<string id="ban_abc_reply_5">
    <text>You cho CROW Snuffles! Arriving at the bar, and stuffed the horn YOU HDDs, flash drives and your personal PDA!</text>
</string>
<string id="ban_abc_reply_8">
    <text>Hey, sucker MONOLITOVSKIE? Your blood pressure is up! Bring down!</text>
</string>
<string id="ban_abc_reply_6">
    <text>Uh, PROFESSOR! WE PROTECT YOU PAN prepare? IF NOT, THEN WE OWN YOU FOR CONDUCTING TESTS WILL!</text>
</string>
<string id="ban_abc_reply_7">
    <text>Uh, PROFESSOR! You cho U.S. soared that IFP no defense? And at your goblin why that is! Why not the mood? If any of us will turn into a zombie, WE FROM YOU AND MAKE YOUR FUFLYZHNIKOV zombie but without hands and feet! YOU UNDERSTAND PROFESSOR?</text>
</string>

<string id="abc_zat_news">
    <text>Beware Scar.</text>
</string>

<string id="ved_abc_reply_55">
    <text>SOMEONE entered the territory! 're Finding the enemy!</text>
</string>

<string id="mon_abc_reply_3">
    <text>Disaster! MONOLIIIIIIIIIIIIIT!</text>
</string>

<string id="ved_abc_reply_5">
    <text>BARTENDER! SOON YOU WILL VARFALAMEEVSKAYA NIGHT WILL hang ....</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_abc_reply_5">
    <text>BARTENDER you're dead! SOON TO GET YOU!</text>
</string>

<string id="ved_abc_reply_7">
    <text>You're dead .. SCIENTIST YOU ZOMBIE ...</text>
</string>
<string id="ved_abc_reply_8">
    <text>WITCH WAY .. KHAN monoliths! ..</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_abc_reply_8">
    <text>VALLE QMS MONOLITOVSKIH!</text>
</string>

<string id="dol_abc_reply_8">
    <text>Monoliths PI ... dec!</text>
</string>

<string id="dol_abc_reply_1">
    <text>SIDOROVICH! NOT YOUR sisy!</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_news_zombied">
    <text>Amazing! Scar a zombie!</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_need_anti">
    <text>I have the antidote!</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_need_anti_money">
    <text>I'll give antizombin for 15,000 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_give_anti">
    <text>I'll pay.</text>
</string>
<string id="abc_give_anti_nope">
    <text>Thanks, but later.</text>
</string>

<!-- SPLAT - after clearing the bunker outside in Yantar - talking to Prof -->
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_0">
    <text>Well I had no trouble getting back in, the doors are blown off. That blast was as powerful as an atomic bomb. Thank god you are alive still. By the way did you know Strelok?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_1">
    <text>Yeah, it knocked me into the next room, but it's a good bunker, cold war stock, very solid and reliable, but with no mini-bar, and the doors can be ordered off of Amazon or eBay. Strelok helped find some spare doors a year or so ago before he went inside the Lab X-16 complex. Did Sidorovich tell you about that?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_2">
    <text>Nope! My memories are very poor these days. I only have few memories of Strelok and nothing more.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_22">
    <text>So you want to know?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_23">
    <text>I heard he turned off the Brain Scorcher?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_24">
    <text>Yes, he not only disabled the Brain Scorcher, but the whole installation inside Laboratory X-16 as well. Sadly it turned out to be nothing much as far as we could tell.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_25">
    <text>Why nothing?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_26">
    <text>Well Strelok first disabled the machines in X-16, and found his friend the stalker nicknamed 'Ghost' dead. He also found a videotape left by others, and yet he brought back a memory that he lost about 2 years ago, entering to the center of the Zone that has helped us greatly. Then he was able to turn off the Brain Scorcher in Laboratory X-10 in Radar earning the admiration of all the clans, from Duty to Clear Sky, even the military as well. He'll get free vodka forever.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_27">
    <text>Ok, then what happened?.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_28">
    <text>Well, then he seemed to disappear. Then about six months ago everyone was talking about a new violent clan with whom you have already met Scar. At first they thought it was just a rumor and Jan Markovna didn't believe it. I told her not to fly to Zaton, she did anyway. I'm afraid for her. I wonder what will happen to her now?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_29">
    <text>Then your wife isn't being held hostage there?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_291">
    <text>No, not there. Jan has worked in the past six months in Zaton and one day I received a message that she was captured. I was told that if I run away or just give up on this Khozyainov work, then they will send me Jan bit by bit, and so I had to give them all the keys from Amber, and most of the scientific formulas. Their goal I initially thought was to control the protection of the Zone and then extend it's capabilities. Anyway, they managed to get set up again, and I think they are trying to restart the Brain Scorcher to cover further work. Did you know Strelok?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_292">
    <text>Do I didn't know Strekok, but did hear of him, and I heard he traveled the Zone without being able to speak Russian. Oh my! I have to go all the way to Radar. Well Professor I will see what I can do about your wife. The main thing is not to lose heart and to have faith professor.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_33">
    <text>I want to believe she can be freed soon, but I don't know how. Oh I almost forgot. I'll put on your PDA a recipe, be sure to read it.</text>
</string>

<!-- SPLAT - this may be key - perhaps suggesting Scar must bring the 5 special artifacts to Sakharov for the cure of his daughter, maybe... although the gameplay xml suggests not -->
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_0">
    <text>Professor I need to know if there are ways to treat cancers of the blood, and what you know about it?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_1">
    <text>That is strange, why would a mercenary be interested in the treatment of this disease?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_2">
    <text>My daughter is sick! Understand Prof it is very necessary. They have tried all methods but nothing works. For me the hunt goes on because my daughter without my help will surely die. She is now in Germany in a hospital. I need a lot of money too. Lebedev hinted of meeting a stalker who had gotten rid of this illness here in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_3">
    <text>There was one case, but I never met the stalker, and I don't know his name, unfortunately cannot remember it. I was told that by Skinflint. They say that the stalker had driven to an area of anomalies near a pack of wild boars. He was returning from a raid, and the artifacts were with him. He run out of bullets and, well, he panicked, hung on his belt all the artifacts and pushed his way into the anomalies, to die there rather than be eaten alive, but believe it or not Scar he got through!</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_4">
    <text>Professor, that is certainly interesting, but I was asking about a treatment.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_5">
    <text>Yes Scar! I am bringing you back to what you asked. He was the stalker who had blood cancer, but after that incident he went on the mend. Wacko, so to speak!</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_6">
    <text>I see, but what and how was his blood cancer cured?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_7">
    <text>You need to find this stalker and what artifacts he had. If he won't speak to you then send him to me. Start by talking to Skinflint.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_8">
    <text>Okay Professor thank you on this one. I'll ask this Skinflint guy.</text>
</string>
</string_table>

