<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 -->
<!-- Text editing by: Martin Pallo 09/12/11-->
<!-- Translated and corrected by Steve90k for fluency and ease of reading. Edited and proofed by Sword2012 for clarity, brevity, and consistency. 13 Mar 16 -->
	<string id="mil_freedom_commander_7000">
		<text>Thanks a lot, Marked One! Looks like we did it, damned crazy bastards! Those Monolith nutjobs aren't the worst things around here though. Lately, mutants have been trying to break through from the Radar area. They're pretty fast, and not everyone can shoot a moving target! We used to have a flamethrower for dealing with those freaks, but now it's bust. Our technician, Screw, built it for us - so he might be able to fix it. Trouble is we're all stuck here, and can't spare a single man as a courier. There's scarcely a minute's rest for us... Well, here's a reward for you... Do you accept cash?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_commander_7001">
		<text>Sure, I don't have a problem with money...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_commander_7002">
		<text>Do you have anything else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_commander_7003">
		<text>Well, as you can imagine, we're short of funds here. The Monolith rarely carry any, and the mutants certainly don't. How about I give you 1,000 and that old flamethrower... It's no good to us, since none of us can fix it. But you're a smart guy - take it to Screw, do a deal with him... You never know, he's bound to have some ideas for it. Believe me, it's worth a lot more when it's working!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_commander_7004">
		<text>No thanks. I have no use for it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_commander_7005">
		<text>Hmm, I think a flamethrower could come in useful</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1000">
		<text>Hey, Screw, can you do anything with this? It's totally busted. Hey, don't look at me like that - it was your friends who broke it doing their job! I helped them a little, and they gave it to me in return - said you might be able to fix it. What do you reckon?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1001">
		<text>Goddammit... I spent a lot of time making this flamethrower! Imbeciles... I can't believe they've fucked it up! The fuel hose is missing - what the hell? Did they just throw it into every anomaly in the Zone to see if it'd change into something else? Or did they give it to a Chimera as a chew toy? Shit! There's a lot to be done on it. Seeing as how you've helped my guys, though, I'll help you. But just this once! I'll make a list of all the parts we'll need to replace. I've got most of them already, and some I can sponge off the guys around here, but there some specialised items you're going to have to get hold of before it'll work. But are you sure you want to run all over the Zone looking for them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1002">
		<text>No, not really. Do you want to take it off my hands for 2,500?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1003">
		<text>All over the Zone? That's all I've done since I arrived here... Tell me what you need</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1004">
		<text>As you wish. Yeah, I'll take it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1005">
	<!-- MF minor rewrite -->
		<text>Right. Here's what we need:\n \nFirst off, we need a Fireball artefact. The thrower's got more holes in it than a Stalker caught cheating... I could weld most of them, but not until until after the winter. With a Fireball, though, there'd be no wait. Believe me, that is one useful artefact...\nSecond, we need new reinforced pipes and fuel lines. The ones I have are barely good enough for watering a garden. Talk to Sidorovich - rookies often bring him garbage like this from, well... from the Garbage! And say hello to him for me.\nThird, we need a new pressure regulator, or else you'll be the one getting torched. God, it looks like they opened beer cans with the old one. Fucking morons... Find it wherever you can - anywhere industrial. I'd start in the Agroprom area. There used to be a lot of engineering research going on there, so you'll have a better chance of finding the right type...\nNext, we need an ignition source - a burner, the most important part. The original one was made of titanium. How the hell did they break it? You won't get a burner from our guys here. They use them for smoking sausages! Of course, you can look for one in the barracks, but I didn't say that... Actually, I know a better method. Go to Barkeep. He's a packrat, so he'll probably have something like that. Make sure you actually buy the burner, to guarantee it works. Just don't say it's for me - if Duty think I'm making weapons here, I'll be a marked man...\nFinally, the most important part - 'Spiritus Vini'. You'll know it as alcohol. It has so many uses - degreasing parts, killing germs, cooking outdoors, and other things too... Got it? I need a strong motivation to fix something this damaged, so bring me some vodka...I reckon five bottles should be enough... maybe seven... Oh, what the hell, bring me ten bottles - as backup. As I said, there's a lot of work needs to be done, and I need to concentrate...\nThat should do it, and afterwards you'll have yourself a lovely working flamethrower...\nOh, and could you look for the vodka first? I'd be very grateful...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1006">
		<text>Seems like I need to do some serious hunting. I hope this is worth it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1007">
		<text>Trust me, it'll be worth it. Oh, and it will cost you 5,000 for the labour. That's including discount...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1008">
		<text>What? You said nothing about money!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1009">
		<text>Hey, it's my design, and I'm supplying most of the parts. There's nobody else can fix it. I could get several hundred thousand for that kind of tool, if I made another! Believe me, I'm doing you a favour, and it'll be worth much more than 5,000 once it's working</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1010">
		<text>Okay, okay, but don't die from vodka osmosis before I come back, cleaning all those parts...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_flamethrower_dialog_0">
		<text>Hey, Sidorovich, Screw sends his regards!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_flamethrower_dialog_1000">
	<!-- MF minor rewrite -->
		<text>Screw? Screw... My memory's not as good as it used to be, Marked One... Ah, wait a minute...I remember a Stalker called Screw. He could fix anything, from a dosimeter to a car. He was a devil for the vodka, though. He'd have drunk my store dry if I'd let him. I'd have thought he'd be dead from alcohol poisoning by now. Heh... but he brought me some rare items in his younger days, and his hands are those of a real master. So, he's still alive?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_flamethrower_dialog_1001">
	<!-- MF minor rewrite -->
		<text>Yes, he is. He said you might have something I need... I'm looking for some small diameter steel pipe, about this long... Screw's helping me repair something... Do you have anything like that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_flamethrower_dialog_1002">
	<!-- MF minor rewrite -->
		<text>Why the hell would I keep steel pipe? Look at this place! Do you think I've space for stuff I can't sell?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_flamethrower_dialog_1003">
		<text>Okay, any idea where I can find such a length of pipe?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_flamethrower_dialog_1004">
	<!-- MF minor rewrite -->
		<text>Well, I'm very happy that Screw is still alive. I'd suggest you go to Alexey Tambovsky. He's always making things out of junk. He's in the Garbage now, looking for parts for some new kind of detector that picks up life-forms. I'll give you his coordinates</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_flamethrower_dialog_1005">
		<text>You're actually giving me advice for nothing? Well, that's a first!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_flamethrower_dialog_1006">
		<text>Sorry, what did you say? It seems that loss of memory is not my only problem...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_flamethrower_dialog_1007">
		<text>I said 'Thanks a lot!' For the advice and info. And stay well, Sidorovich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_flamethrower_dialog_1008">
		<text>Yeah, my health isn't as good as it used to be, either...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flamethrower_0">
		<text>Hi there, what do you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flamethrower_1000">
	<!-- MF minor rewrite -->
		<text>Sidorovich told me you might have some small diameter steel pipe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flamethrower_1001">
		<text>Like fuel pipe, eh? Hmm... I saw a few lengths on one of those radioactive hills, but I can't get at them - my outfit's not good enough. I wrote down the coordinates, though. I can give them to you for free, but can I ask you a favour? Whilst up on the hills earlier I thought I saw something interesting higher up, but all I brought back with me was a large dose of radiation. I just cleaned up the nosebleed... How about you spare me some Antirad, and I'll give you the coordinates?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flamethrower_1002">
	<!-- MF minor -->
		<text>Sorry, I don't have any Antirad, but thanks for the advice. I'll look for the pipe myself</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flamethrower_1003">
		<text>Sure, but you need to be more careful around all this radiation. It's a killer! Here you go...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flamethrower_1004">
	<!-- MF minor -->
		<text>Give me your PDA... There you go, I've inputted the coordinates. I'm sure the pipes are still there - nobody would have had a need for them...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flamethrower_1005">
		<text>Thanks, friend. Good luck with your new devices</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_flamethrower_task_0">
		<text>Hi. Do you have a decent burner for sale?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_flamethrower_task_1000">
		<text>A burner? Interesting. Pardon me for asking, but what do you need it for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_flamethrower_task_1001">
		<text>A Stalker I met said they were just the thing for smoked sausages...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_flamethrower_task_1002">
		<text>Really? Okay, it's none of my business. Yes, I have one, and it seems to be working properly. Yours for 250 roubles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_flamethrower_task_1003">
		<text>250 for this? No wonder they're not so common. I'll find one somewhere else...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_flamethrower_task_1004">
		<text>Fair price. Thanks. Here's your money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parts_completed_0">
		<text>You got all the parts? I hope you got the vodka as well?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parts_completed_1000">
	<!-- MF minor rewrite -->
		<text>I got everything, including the vodka - to make sure everything's clean... I have your money too, but only after you've shown it me working...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parts_completed_1001">
		<text>No problem. Give me a day, and I'll give you your toy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parts_completed_1002">
		<text>Deal. See you tomorrow, same time...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parts_completed_10111">
		<text>Well, how did the repair go? Is it working?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parts_completed_1003">
		<text>Whoa, M-M-Mark... Heh-heh, how you doin' buddy? What you want from me?... Oh, yeah, your fire pistol... Did someone tell you it was done already? What time is it? Uhh, sorry man, I think I had a little too much to drink...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parts_completed_1004">
		<text>Are you kidding me? You said drinking helps you focus. I bet if you could work without drinking, you'd make a fortune selling flamethrowers, and nobody would dare attack Freedom. I'll come back again when you're sober...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parts_completed_1013">
		<text>How are you feeling now? And how's my flamethrower?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parts_completed_1005">
		<text>Yeah, I'm good now. Look, I'm really sorry about the other day. Here's your flamethrower, good as new!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parts_completed_1006">
		<text>Wow, I never thought you'd actually make it. It looks great. Let's have a closer look...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parts_completed_1007">
		<text>Hey, hold on. I'm not so drunk today. It's 10,000 roubles for the repairs, remember?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parts_completed_1008">
		<text>One moment... We agreed on 5,000 roubles. Or would you prefer Duty to act as arbitrators?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parts_completed_1009">
		<text>Okay, calm down. Yes, I remember now. It was 5,000 roubles after discount... Take your flamethrower. Now you can set fire to things without going the extra distance... Oh, there's something else... The fuel tank holds enough for about a minute of torching - then it'll be empty... Come back here and I'll refuel it for a price. You'll also need a canister of gasoline, and a balloon tank of colloidal gas. I could get them myself, but it'd cost you a lot more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parts_completed_1010">
		<text>A balloon tank? Where would I find one of those?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parts_completed_1011">
		<text>Colloid gas - the eggheads brought a load of them to the Zone for their experiments. It's perfect for flame fuel. You'll probably find some in Agroprom, and pretty much anywhere industrial. Better start looking for it straight away, for spares, okay? Don't forget, a can of fuel and a balloon tank of colloidal gas</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parts_completed_1012">
		<text>Yeah, got it. Thank you. Have fun with the rest of your vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_text">
	<!-- MF A Pressuremeter -->
		<text>I need to find the items on the list Screw gave me:\n \n1. A Fireball artefact.\n2. Steel pipe - he said Sidorovich might have some.\n3. A pressure regulator - maybe in the Agroprom Research Institute.\n4. A burner - see Barkeep about one.\n5. Ten bottles of vodka for this inebriate.\n \nIt's going to be a long day...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trubka_descr">
		<text>Steel pipe. Right diameter. Bent slightly, but looks strong enough to straighten. Should be okay for the flamethrower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gorelka_descr">
		<text>Medium size burner. As Stalkers say, any sausage tastes wonderful when it's been smoked on this thing. I need it to ignite the high-temperature gel in the flamethrower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="manometr_descr">
	<!-- MF Pressuremeter -->
		<text>A simple pressure regulator, from some old Soviet processing equipment. The glass on the gauge is cracked, but that shouldn't stop it working. Otherwise looks in good condition. It should be fine for the flamethrower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flama_descr">
		<text>A pitiful creation, which would have wielded blistering power when in its prime. But maybe a good specialist will be able to breathe some fire back into its lungs. Now, where do I find such an expert?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_descr">
		<text>Handmade weapon by Screw, based upon a standard army flamethrower. With no accuracy required, it's a devastating weapon in close-combat, capable of taking down hordes of mutants in packs. Best used in bursts, since only a touch of its breath will stop an enemy in its tracks. On a full charge it will give you a full minute of overwhelming, protective firepower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_no_parts_0">
		<text>Shit, I forgot something. I'll be back</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_flamethrower_bad_name">
	<!-- MF articles -->
		<text>A broken flamethrower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="manometr">
	<!-- MF minor correction -->
		<text>A pressure regulator with gauge</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trubka">
	<!-- MF articles -->
		<text>A pipe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gorelka">
	<!-- MF articles -->
		<text>A burner</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flamethrower_basic">
		<text>Flamethrower - hand-made, but with great skill. It can be refueled at the Freedom base by Screw. Very rare in the Zone, so fuel is scarce. Requires ordinary gasoline (stored in standard canisters) and a special colloidal gas (stored in specially marked red containers). Screw says that there are many of them in the Agroprom area, but they can be found elsewhere too. He could go and find them himself, but he'd need to charge a lot more if he did this. His skills in exchange for mine, then - and, as always, he'll need vodka just to get him started...</text>
	</string>
