<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 chgd to Military PDAs, minor edits, Artyom, Krysjuk "The Rat", something, Core, repair kit -->
<!-- Names changed as commented below - Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16 -->
<!-- Changed all 'Mother's Beads' to 'Glassbeads' - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->
<!-- Reworked up to Line 267 - Sword2012 - 09 Jan 17 -->
<string_table>
	<string id="barman_musik_dialog_0">
		<text>Would you please change the music! It's annoying...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_musik_dialog_1">
		<text>It's five roubles to change the music...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_musik_dialog_2">
		<text>Fair enough. He who pays the piper...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_musik_dialog_10">
		<text>Pay to listen to more crap? No way!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_musik_dialog_3">
		<text>Hey, if I didn't charge, these guys would be asking all the time!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_musik_dialog_4">
		<text>Okay, put on anything retro...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_musik_dialog_5">
		<text>How about some rock 'n' roll?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_musik_dialog_6">
		<text>Anything. Just not this sentimental shit...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_musik_dialog_7">
		<text>Something a bit more modern...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_musik_dialog_41">
		<text>I also prefer retro...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_musik_dialog_51">
		<text>Okay, but don't expect Elvis...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_musik_dialog_61">
		<text>I'll drink to that!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_musik_dialog_71">
		<text>Okay, let's see what I've got...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_musik_dialog_8">
		<text>Can't make up your mind?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello, Stalker...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Well, can we talk?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_11_dialog_0">
		<text>One of your men told me I can deal with you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_11_dialog_1">
		<text>I'm told you helped out one of my men, Mongol. For that, I give my sincere thanks. I'll put the word out. Any Bandit in this valley who attacks you will answer to me and my boys. If you want to trade, feel free to talk to Core. He's just outside my office...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_11_dialog_2">
		<text>I've been told you have a key to the underground laboratory...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_11_dialog_3">
		<text>Ah, it's the key you want! But you won't be the first. Everything of any value went long ago, and there's nothing but mutants down there now. Yes, I've got a key, but don't think I'm going to hand it over for free. You'll have to earn it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_11_dialog_4">
		<text>No problem. Nothing in the Zone comes easy...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_11_dialog_5">
		<text>Well, if you've got the balls, I've got a task for you. A helicopter crashed here recently - nearby, to the east of the bog. I don't know why, but it came from the center of the Zone. I sent some of my men to check it out, but they say there's a den of chimeras close by, and they couldn't get any closer. They reported seeing a couple of corpses in hazmat suits near the helicopter, and an artefact case nearby. So, if you want to try your luck, go and have a rummage around there and bring me everything you find, in exchange for the key...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_11_dialog_6">
		<text>Chimeras and hazmat suits! I knew this wouldn't be easy. Yeah, I'll go check it out...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_11_dialog_7">
		<text>Chimeras are very territorial. I really don't fancy going up against a den of them...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_12_dialog_0">
		<text>I found the helicopter, and you can tell your guys that the chimeras won't bother them again...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_12_dialog_1">
		<text>I sent my morons to track you, but I've not received their report yet. What was there? In the helicopter?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_12_dialog_2">
		<text>There was nothing. Just a couple of dead scientists, that's all. Someone must have already got there...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_12_dialog_3">
		<text>I found a container that I didn't want to risk opening, and some documents. That's all...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_12_dialog_21">
		<text>Nothing, you say? And after the deal we made! My men saw you carrying a container...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_12_dialog_42">
		<text>Yes, and I dropped it when the chimeras came after me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_12_dialog_31">
		<text>Well, it's been a pleasure to deal with you. I'll have the container and documents, please...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_12_dialog_32">
		<text>Here's your loot. Do you have the key?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_12_dialog_33">
		<text>Ha, Borov always keeps his word! Here's your key. And I've some other business for you, if you're interested...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_12_dialog_34">
		<text>Sounds good. When I'm ready I'll let you know...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_12_dialog_22">
		<text>And your men saw nothing? From the ones I've seen they were probably too drunk to see their own noses...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_12_dialog_23">
		<text>This is not necessary. There's been too much drinking here. Let's try again to work as a team. Can we turn to one more order of business?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_21_dialog_0">
		<text>What is it you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_21_dialog_1">
		<text>One of my men known as Rat has gone missing, along with my PDA. Coincidence? I think not! That PDA was full of our internal communications... Now to business, find this Rat and my PDA. How you get it is up to you - just bring me the PDA and we'll discuss your reward. Having someone like you on our side, whom people trust, can always be advantageous to both of us...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_21_dialog_2">
		<text>The Zone's a big place. Where should I start looking?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_21_dialog_3">
		<text>He was spotted recently at the Cordon, but it's highly unlikely someone like him will have got out alive. Do we have an agreement?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_21_dialog_4">
		<text>Yes, I'll try to find your Rat...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_21_dialog_5">
		<text>No, not at the Cordon. The Military are all over that place, and if it gets out that I'm helping a bandit...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_22_dialog_0">
		<text>Greetings, Borov. I found your Rat...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_22_dialog_1">
		<text>Well done. I hope he's dead. Where's the PDA?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_22_dialog_2">
		<text>Where's my reward?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_22_dialog_3">
		<text>Show me the PDA, and I'll give you your reward</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_22_dialog_4">
		<text>Fair enough. Do you recognize this PDA?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_22_dialog_51">
		<text>Wonderful! Here's the key to the underground lab I promised, and the location of a cache. Also the supply room is open to you, so take anything you need. The cache is located at the north of the Army Warehouses, near the fallen helicopter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_22_dialog_52">
		<text>Excellent! Here's the location of a cache. It's located at the north of the Army Warehouses, near the fallen helicopter. Also, check the supply room. It should now be open to you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borov_22_dialog_6">
		<text>Good. You kept your word...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Hey, Stalker! Come closer. Let's talk...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Hey, Rat?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_start_dialog_2">
		<text>Krysjuk! My surname is Krysjuk!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_11_dialog_0">
		<text>Okay! Calm down, I know Rat's not your real name! I have some business for you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_11_dialog_1">
		<text>What business could I possibly have with you? I've not dealt with you before...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_11_dialog_2">
		<text>Borov. You've got his PDA, and he wants your head...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_11_dialog_3">
		<text>Yes, I took it. It has the coordinates of places Borov keeps his caches. But I can share this information with you if you'll help me out...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_11_dialog_41">
		<text>Look, I know you're a thief, so I can't trust you. Why shouldn't I just shoot you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_11_dialog_42">
		<text>What kind of help are we talking about?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_11_dialog_51">
		<text>Kill me if you want, but it won't help you find the PDA. It's hidden in a secret place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_11_dialog_52">
		<text>Listen, please. I've been hiding here for days, but I can't get past the soldiers. I won't live long if Borov finds me. If you can get the Barman to let me pass through, Borov can't come after me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_11_dialog_621">
		<text>I'll talk to the Barman, but I can't promise you anything...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_11_dialog_622">
		<text>Yes, you have gone! Have got! Go there, go here....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_11_dialog_61">
		<text>It is good that I have joked, and you have laughed... What commission do you have?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_11_dialog_62">
		<text>Ah, you young reptile! You will tell me everything!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_12_dialog_0">
		<text>I talked with the Barman. He will let you pass, but only if you give up all your loot...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_12_dialog_1">
		<text>Okay, I'll show you where it is, but who will go and collect it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_12_dialog_2">
		<text>Don't worry. I'll get it, and also take it to the Barman</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_12_dialog_3">
		<text>Okay, write down these coordinates in the Dark Valley. In the cache are three Moonlights and a Glassbeads. Take them all to the Barman. If he agrees to my passage, I'll tell you where the PDA is</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_13_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello, Barkeep! We have a request from a bandit...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_13_dialog_1">
		<text>Hmm, you're dealing with criminals now. Why did I not see this coming?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_13_dialog_2">
		<text>Very funny. This Krysjuk, aka Rat needs to hide from Borov. Might it be in your interest help him out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_13_dialog_3">
		<text>I've no interest in this thief. Bandits are a blight on honest Stalkers. If he wants total safety, tell him it'll be my neck on the line, and he'll need to pay. I want all the loot from his cache. Once you bring me everything of use in there, I'll allow him safe passage. Tell him that...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_13_dialog_4">
		<text>Okay, I'll let him know your terms</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_14_dialog_0">
		<text>Greetings, station master of the Underground Railroad...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_14_dialog_1">
		<text>Fuck off, Marked One. What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_14_dialog_2">
		<text>Krysjuk told me where his cache is. I went there and found three Moonlights and a Glassbeads</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_14_dialog_3">
		<text>That'll be enough to buy him passage. Give them here, and tell him we have a deal. I'll ask the block posts to let him pass...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_14_dialog_42">
		<text>All of them? I've done all the work. Don't I get a share?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_14_dialog_41">
		<text>Keep the lot if you want. Do you think I give a shit about a fucking bandit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_14_dialog_51">
		<text>Okay, I'll find Rat and let him know. Thanks...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_14_dialog_52">
		<text>Go ahead and leave. Just fuck off...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_15_dialog_0">
		<text>The Barman agrees to let you through. Does this solve your problem?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_15_dialog_1">
		<text>Yes, thank you. I just want live a quieter life...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_15_dialog_2">
		<text>I gave the Barman everything in your cache. Do I end up with anything out of this, other than saving your life?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_15_dialog_3">
		<text>Don't worry, do you really think I gave the Barkeep everything? Your share is waiting for you in Agroprom... In the meantime, here's how to make a Medusa artefact. You'll need to throw the head of a Tushkano, a bandage, a sausage, and a can of food into an Electro...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krysyk_15_dialog_4">
		<text>Thanks, I'll go and look... I really hope you've changed but, if you've lied to me, I promise that Borov won't be the only one after you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_wolf_sak">
		<text>Wolf</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustryi_sak">
		<text>Nimble</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_sak">
		<text>Fox</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_provodnik_sak">
		<text>Guide</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dm_novice_sak">
		<text>Jurik</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_sak">
		<text>Bes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_sak">
		<text>Mole</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_bandit_krisyk_sak">
		<text>Krysjuk 'The Rat'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_bandit_krisyk_name">
		<text>Krysjuk 'The Rat'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_0">
		<text>Greetings man of science! What are you offering?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_1">
		<text>And greetings to you also, Marked One. Here, I modify PDAs to detect mutants...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_2">
		<text>This sounds extremely useful! How does it work?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_3">
		<text>Each mutant emits a different energy signal. But I need mutant DNA, and up to date mapping information, to calibrate the detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_4">
		<text>So which mutants can you detect?</text>
	</string>
	<!-- string id="bar_docent_5"> old/deleted - aleks1970
		<text>I Suspect the most dangerous:\n - Burer,\n - Chimera,\n - Librarian,\n - Warewolf,\n - Bloodsucker,\n - Pseudo-Giant,\n - and the Controller. Which one are you interested in detecting?</text>
	</string -->
	<string id="bar_docent_dialog_13">
		<text>Well, I've chosen the most dangerous:\n - Burer,\n - Chimera,\n - Librarian,\n - Werewolf,\n - Bloodsucker,\n - Pseudogiant,\n - Controller.\nWhich would you prefer?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_51">
		<text>Definitely bloodsuckers. You can never have too much notice of those bastards!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_52">
		<text>Pseudogiants are far better bypassed, once you know where they are!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_53">
		<text>The most dangerous mutant in the Zone would have to be a Controller!</text>
	</string>
	<!-- string id="bar_docent_54"> old/deleted - aleks1970
		<text>To me in general all the same, I and so with them I will consult...</text>
	</string -->
	<string id="bar_docent_dialog_58">
		<text>To me in general all the same, I and so with them I will consult...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_61">
		<text>For proper adjustment I need a pair of Bloodsucker tentacles, and 20 Military PDAs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_62">
		<text>For proper adjustment I need two hands from a Pseudogiant, and 15 Military PDAs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_63">
		<text>For proper adjustment I need two hands from a Controller, and 30 Military PDAs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_71">
		<text>I'll find these parts for you, and the PDAs. I'm looking forward to this upgrade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_72">
		<text>Those giants are a bastard to take down, but I'll bring you their hands and the PDAs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_73">
		<text>It's going to be tough, but I'll find you those Controller hands and the PDAs somehow</text>
	</string>
	<!-- string id="bar_docent_74"> old/deleted - aleks1970
		<text>When there will be concrete results, then will talk.</text>
	</string -->
	<string id="bar_docent_dialog_78">
		<text>When there will be concrete results, then will talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_docent_detector1">
		<text>For alteration of a PDA into a detector which reacts to Bloodsuckers, it is necessary to extract a pair of tentacles from one of these Bloodsuckers and to collect 20 Military PDAs. To bring all it is to the Associate and he will alter my PDA.</text>	<!-- Changed 'Senior Lecturer' to 'Associate'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="tex_docent_detector2">
		<text>For alteration of a PDA into a detector which reacts to Pseudo-Giants, it is necessary to extract 2 parts of a body from different Pseudo-Giants and to collect 15 Military PDAs. To bring all this to the Associate and he will alter my PDA.</text>	<!-- Changed 'Senior Lecturer' to 'Associate'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="tex_docent_detector3">
		<text>For alteration usual PDA in the detector which reacts on Controllers, it is necessary to extract 2 parts of a body of the Controller and to collect 30 Military PDAs. To bring all this to the Associate and he will alter my PDA.</text>	<!-- Changed 'Senior Lecturer' to 'Associate'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<!-- new text for the new minimap icon/spot - aleks1970 -->
	<string id="tex_docent_detector4">
		<text>For alteration usual PDA in the detector which reacts on Wolfs, it is necessary to extract 3 parts of a body of the Wolf and to collect 20 Military PDAs. To bring all this to the Associate and he will alter my PDA.</text>	<!-- Changed 'Senior Lecturer' to 'Associate'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="tex_docent_detector5">
		<text>For alteration usual PDA in the detector which reacts on Chimeras, it is necessary to extract 4 parts of a body of the Chimera and to collect 40 Military PDAs. To bring all this to the Associate and he will alter my PDA.</text>	<!-- Changed 'Senior Lecturer' to 'Associate'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="tex_docent_detector6">
		<text>For alteration usual PDA in the detector which reacts on Burers, it is necessary to extract 4 parts of a body of the Burer and to collect 15 Military PDAs. To bring all this to the Associate and he will alter my PDA.</text>	<!-- Changed 'Senior Lecturer' to 'Associate'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="tex_docent_detector7">
		<text>For alteration usual PDA in the detector which reacts on Librarians, it is necessary to extract 1 parts of a body of the Librarian and to collect 30 Military PDAs. To bring all this to the Associate and he will alter my PDA.</text>	<!-- Changed 'Senior Lecturer' to 'Associate'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_1dialog_0">
		<text>I Welcome, the master!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_1dialog_1">
		<text>It is good to see you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_1dialog_2">
		<text>I Have collected the necessary items for the detector on the Bloodsucker. Here they are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_1dialog_3">
		<text>This is excellent, now it is possible to make the modification. Here, now your PDA is adjusted to detect Bloodsuckers within 30-40 metres</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_1dialog_4">
		<text>Thanks! that's great.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_2dialog_0">
		<text>Senior lecturer, the requirements are present!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_2dialog_1">
		<text>Yes in this cellar what health...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_2dialog_2">
		<text>I have collected PDAs and the parts of the giant. Here take away...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_2dialog_3">
		<text>Well the mechanism is ready, take the PDA adjusted for Pseudo-Giants. Now it is possible to find them in advance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_2dialog_4">
		<text>Well my friend. Thanks from me is due!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_3dialog_0">
		<text>How's life, Associate?</text>	<!-- Changed 'Senior Lecturer' to 'Associate'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_3dialog_1">
		<text>In general, in comparison with Sementsky - it is quite good...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_3dialog_2">
		<text>Yes! I have brought the parts for the detector.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_3dialog_3">
		<text>Well now the Controllers can't hide! Detection radius of 50 metres!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_3dialog_4">
		<text>Have a Bottle on me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_4dialog_0">
		<text>It's nice to see you again...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_4dialog_1">
		<text>How is going?...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_4dialog_2">
		<text>I have collected PDAs and the claws of the Werewolf. Here take away...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_4dialog_3">
		<text>Well, now the Werewolf can't hide! Detection radius of 40 metres!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_4dialog_4">
		<text>Now back to the hunt...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_5dialog_0">
		<text>How are your business on these days, Associate?</text>	<!-- Changed 'Senior Lecturer' to 'Associate'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_5dialog_1">
		<text>Well, you're coming from the hunting, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_5dialog_2">
		<text>I Have collected the necessary items for the detector on the Chimeras. Here they are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_5dialog_3">
		<text>Well I upgraded the PDA, it is now adjusted for the Chimeras! Now you'll be able to see these Chimeras on long distance...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_5dialog_4">
		<text>Ahh, you're my lifesaver...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_6dialog_0">
		<text>Hi, there...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_6dialog_1">
		<text>Excellent, you're back already!?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_6dialog_2">
		<text>Yes, I have brought the required Burer hands and PDAs for the detector!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_6dialog_3">
		<text>This is great, now it is possible to make new modification on the PDA! Here, take the PDA. It is now adjusted to detect Burers within 40-50 metres</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_6dialog_4">
		<text>Now, these ugly Burer creatures will become extinct in the ZONE...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_7dialog_0">
		<text>Greetings, Senior lecturer...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_7dialog_1">
		<text>What do you need!?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_7dialog_2">
		<text>I have collected PDAs and hand of the Librarian. Here take away...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_7dialog_3">
		<text>Well I upgraded the PDA, it is now adjusted for the Librarians!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_7dialog_4">
		<text>Well my friend. Librarians are waiting for me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_dialog_11">
		<text>Hello, do you want to see another mutant on your PDA scanner!?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_dialog_12">
		<text>Yes, please advise me which mutant to choose first!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_dialog_5">
		<text>I Suspect the most dangerous:\n - Burer,\n - Chimera,\n - Librarian,\n - Warewolf,\n - Bloodsucker,\n - Pseudo-Giant,\n - and the Controller.\nWhich one are you interested in detecting?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_dialog_54">
		<text>Werewolf. those creepy night creatures brrr...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_dialog_55">
		<text>Chimeras, better to avoid them, it is too fast for me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_dialog_56">
		<text>Burers, I do not wish to come close to them!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_dialog_57">
		<text>Librarian. That is big and scary mutant...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_dialog_59">
		<text>Not now, I'll come back later...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_dialog_64">
		<text>For proper adjustment I need paws of the Werewolf, 3 paws And 20 Military PDAs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_dialog_65">
		<text>For proper adjustment of detecting the Chimeras, it's necessary to collect 4 claws and 40 Military PDAs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_dialog_66">
		<text>For proper adjustment of the detector, which will show Burer on the map, it's necessary to collect 4 hands and 15 Military PDAs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_dialog_67">
		<text>For proper adjustment I need hand of the Librarian, 1 hand and 30 Military PDAs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_dialog_74">
		<text>I will find these Werewolf paws and bring the PDAs! No more hiding places in the ZONE for them...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_dialog_75">
		<text>These Chimeras. I often come across on to them, I will bring their claws and the PDAs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_dialog_76">
		<text>These Burers creatures are powerful and ugly...\n... I will bring their hands and the PDAs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_dialog_77">
		<text>I will find one hand from the Librarian and bring the PDAs!</text>
	</string>
	<!-- new text for the new minimap icon/spot -END- - aleks1970 -->
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_0">
		<text>Associate, I need some help finding someone.</text>	<!-- Changed 'Senior Lecturer' to 'Associate'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_1">
		<text>Basically we can trace all un-coded personal PDA, and I could produce a mark defined on your PDA map. Bring any five Military PDAs and for a small fee I will find the location of the necessary person.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_2">
		<text>Give we will be adjust...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_3">
		<text>I agree, I will collect PDAs and return...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_4">
		<text>Agreed! And whom do you want to find?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_61">
		<text>And who is concrete?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_8">
		<text>It is ready! Now on your PDA have is a mark!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_9">
		<text>I Respect!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_51">
		<text>The Acquaintance of one from the Cordon...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_52">
		<text>In the Garbage there was one person...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_53">
		<text>In the Dark Valley saw it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_711">
		<text>A Stalker by the name of Fox.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_712">
		<text>There was there a fellow - Nimble.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_713">
		<text>Wolf I want to find.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_714">
		<text>Blinn! I have no idea where he could be...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_721">
		<text>For Jurika I search, business I have with him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_722">
		<text>It is necessary to find Bes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_723">
		<text>A conversation with Mole is necessary.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_731">
		<text>This Bandit, Krysjuk "The Rat". I need to find him...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_732">
		<text>Guide I want to find.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_docent_npc_dialog_733">
		<text>Artyom of the Culinary specialist where to find?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_dialog_0">
		<text>Hi,it is necessary to see the repairman.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_dialog_1">
		<text>It is simple so I will not pass...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_dialog_3">
		<text>Instead of it is simple so? What you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_dialog_4">
		<text>How about you give me some anti-rad and I will let you pass, Have we an agreement?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_dialog_5">
		<text>Nice try, I do not use them. I prefer vodka. Now step aside</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_dialog_6">
		<text>Do not have any anti-rad...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_dialog_7">
		<text>How about a medkit, military grade?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_dialog_71">
		<text>Its simple, will you accept?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_dialog_72">
		<text>Yes, here you are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_dialog_73">
		<text>On me is a scientific medkit, it is much better!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_dialog_74">
		<text>I don't have any first-aid sets...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_dialog_75">
		<text>Simple? Give two then you will pass.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_dialog_76">
		<text>Garik you redneck? Take.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_dialog_77">
		<text>Its a small world Garick, again we will meet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_dialog_8">
		<text>Have agreed! Pass!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_0">
		<text>I need some supplies...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_1">
		<text>I can trade certain supplies in exchange for Artefacts... What exactly do you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_2">
		<text>Ammunition, Grenades...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_3">
		<text>I need a decent Weapon...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_4">
		<text>Medical Supplies...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_5">
		<text>Field Repair Kits...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_21">
		<text>I can offer the following:\n \n1. 12x70 buck for a Medusa artefact\n2. RG-5 Grenades(x2) for a Quirk artefact\n3. 5.45x39mm cartridges for a Droplet artefact\n4. 7.62x39mm cartridges for a Stone Blood artefact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_54">
		<text>I've changed my mind...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_22">
		<text>I'll take the Shotgun Shells...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_23">
		<text>I'll take the Grenades...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_24">
		<text>I'll take the 5.45x39mm cartridges...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_25">
		<text>I'll take the 7.62x39mm cartridges...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_222">
		<text>I'll give you 3 packs of 12x70 buck for the Medusa...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_221">
		<text>Sounds good to me... here you are...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_232">
		<text>I'll give you RG-5 Grenades(x2) for the Quirk...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_231">
		<text>Hand over the Grenades then...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_242">
		<text>Here's three packs of 5.45x39mm cartridges for the Droplet...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_241">
		<text>You've got yourself a deal...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_252">
		<text>Two packs of 7.62x39mm cartridges for the Stone Blood...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_251">
		<text>I can always use more bullets...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_666">
		<text>I don't have the right artefact, sorry...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_31">
		<text>Here's what I can offer:\n \n1. TOZ-34 Shotgun for a Flash artefact\n2. Saiga-12K for a Meat Chunk artefact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_32">
		<text>Give me the TOZ-34...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_33">
		<text>I'll take the Saiga-12k...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_322">
		<text>For the TOZ-34, I'll need a Flash artefact...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_321">
		<text>Yes, here you are then...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_332">
		<text>I'll swap the Saiga12k for a Meat Chunk...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_331">
		<text>Here you go... one Meat Chunk artefact...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_41">
		<text>Here's what I can do:\n \n1. Medkits for a Stone Flower artefact\n2. Vodka for a Quirk artefact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_42">
		<text>I can always use more medkits...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_43">
		<text>You can never have enough Vodka...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_422">
		<text>How does eight medkits for a Stone Flower artefact sound?...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_421">
		<text>Sounds good to me... hand 'em over...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_432">
		<text>Three bottles of Vodka in exchange for a Quirk artefact...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_431">
		<text>You've got yourself a deal...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_51">
		<text>Here's the deal:\n \n1. armor Repair Kits in exchange for a Gravi artefact\n2. Weapon Repair Kits in exchange for a Stone Flower artefact...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_52">
		<text>I'll take the armor Repair Kits...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_53">
		<text>I'll need the Weapon Repair Kits...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_522">
		<text>Three 10% armor Repair Kits for one Gravi...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_521">
		<text>Sounds good to me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_532">
		<text>Three 10% Weapon Repair Kits for one Stone Flower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sidor_531">
		<text>There can't be enough said about keeping your Weapons in check...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_0">
		<text>I would like to purchase some equipment...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_1">
		<text>The Main currency in the zone is artefacts!\nWhat exactly is necessary?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_2">
		<text>Ammunition, equipment...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_3">
		<text>Good Weapons....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_4">
		<text>First-aid...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_5">
		<text>Repair sets...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_21">
		<text>My ammunition supply is:\n1. Cartridges 5,45x39mm for an artefact Flash;\n2. Grenades RGD-5 for an artefact Stone Flower;\n3. Cartridges 5,56x39mm for an artefact Slime;\n4. Cartridges 9x39mm for an artefact of Gravi.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_54">
		<text>Nothing for me today...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_22">
		<text>Cartridges for the AK-74 I will take...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_23">
		<text>I will take Grenades...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_24">
		<text>Cartridges 5.56 for NATO weapons I need...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_25">
		<text>Cartridges 9x39mm for the Vintorez and Groza I will take...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_222">
		<text>I Can give five packs simple or three packs armor-piercing for one Flash... Which do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_221">
		<text>Five simple I will take...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_2211">
		<text>Give the armor-piercing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_232">
		<text>Three grenades RGD5 for a Stone Flower... You agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_231">
		<text>I need Grenades.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_242">
		<text>I Give five packs simple or three packs armor-piercing for one Slime...you agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_241">
		<text>Give the simple.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_2411">
		<text>Armor-piercing I will take.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_252">
		<text>Five packs simple or four sniper or three armor-piercing for one Gravi... which do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_251">
		<text>Give five simple.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_2511">
		<text>Sniper I will take.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_25111">
		<text>Armor-piercing - they bring quick death to the bloodsucker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_666">
		<text>Do not have it, another time...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_31">
		<text>Here's my best weapons:\n1. The automatic Special Val (AS Val), is created on the basis of a silent Rifle Vintorez. Its one of the most deadly weapons in the zone. A bargain for two artefacts Fireball;\n2. Automatic-grenade launcher Complex OC-14 Groza - a variant of an assault rifle for close quarter combat: compact, reliable, and at the same time universal and powerful, for an artefact the Night star.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_32">
		<text>Val This is what I need...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_33">
		<text>Groza I've been looking for one of these!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_322">
		<text>For Val two Fireballs I take... you agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_321">
		<text>I agree, give me the Val...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_332">
		<text>Groza only in exchange for Night star... Agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_331">
		<text>I agree! Gimme!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_41">
		<text>For First-aid I offer:\n1. First-aid sets for an artefact Sparkler;\n2. Vodka which reduces radiation, for an artefact Stone Blood.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_42">
		<text>First-aid sets I will take...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_43">
		<text>I need the Vodka...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_422">
		<text>For five first-aid sets one Sparkler...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_421">
		<text>First-aid sets are not easy to find, so you've got a deal...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_432">
		<text>Five vodka in exchange for Stone Blood... You agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_431">
		<text>Yes I agree....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_51">
		<text>For repair I can offer:\n1. repair sets for armor for an artefact Meat Chunk;\n2. repair sets for weapons for an artefact Fireball.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_52">
		<text>For armor I will take.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_53">
		<text>I need The Weapon kits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_522">
		<text>For three ten-percentage complete sets one Meat Chunk... you agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_521">
		<text>I agree...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_532">
		<text>Three ten-percentage weapon complete sets in exchange for Fireball... You agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_barman_531">
		<text>Yes, I agree...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_0">
		<text>I need some equipment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_1">
		<text>If you have the Artefacts? Then I have the goods...\nWhat are you looking for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_2">
		<text>Ammunition, equipment...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_3">
		<text>Good Weapons...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_4">
		<text>First-aid...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_5">
		<text>Repair sets...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_21">
		<text>I Can offer:\n1. Cartridges 7,62x54mm for a Droplet artefact;\n2. Under barrel VOG-25 grenades for a Stone Blood artefact;\n3. Cartridges 7,62x39mm for a Medusa artefact;\n4. DUTY armor for a Mica artefact...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_54">
		<text>I will take nothing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_22">
		<text>I need Sniper cartridges.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_23">
		<text>I Will take the VOG grenades.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_24">
		<text>For the AK-47 give ammo...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_25">
		<text>Give me the armor....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_222">
		<text>The Bullet 7x13 has big enough (under sniper requirements) dispersion even on average distances, however, possesses the raised penetrative action.\n7N1 (CENTRAL PROCESSING UNIT) - the regular sniper cartridge in 2-3 times exceeds 7N13 on dispersion indicators. However, does not possess high penetrative properties.\nOn a shooting grouping 7N14 it is equivalent to a sniper cartridge 7N1, however, considerably surpasses it in armor-piercing action, thanks to introduction in a design of a bullet of the pointed tempered steel core.\nFor one Droplet artefact I give two packs of simple either sniper cartridges, or one pack of the armor-piercing... What you will choose?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_221">
		<text>Give simple, two packs...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_2211">
		<text>Exact sniper cartridges are necessary To me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_2212">
		<text>I Will take armor-piercing, they are exact and lethal...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_232">
		<text>For one artefact Stone Blood I can offer four VOG-25 or three VOG-25p. Which will you take?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_231">
		<text>Give four twenty fifth...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_2311">
		<text>Three, but more powerful...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_242">
		<text>Three packs of standard cartridges or two armor-piercing - a Medusa artefact.... Choose...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_241">
		<text>Standard, there is more of them...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_2411">
		<text>Armor-piercing certainly...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_252">
		<text>OYAG-91D Universal protection! An excellent protective suit for the Zone. In structure: overalls OYAG-9D, system has a closed breathing cycle, a built in system of suppression of abnormal fields. Gives qualitative protection against bullet and fragmental hits. - Mica\nThe Duty Exoskeleton will manage in two artefacts!... I will trade for three Micas...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_251">
		<text>Well give Universal protection</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_2511">
		<text>Exo? Give, I will test...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_666">
		<text>You ask Too much...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_31">
		<text>I have sniper rifles:\n1. Sniper Vintora Dragunova (SVD) for an Urchin artefact;\n2. A sniper Rifle Truncated Automatic Developing (SVU-AS) for the Soul artefact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_32">
		<text>SVD though is heavy, but very accurate, I will take it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_33">
		<text>The SVD expert is lighter, I will take it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_322">
		<text>For SVD a the Urchin I take... you agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_321">
		<text>Yes, I agree...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_332">
		<text>SVD expert only in exchange for Soul... You agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_331">
		<text>Yes, Soul not a rarity...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_41">
		<text>I have only military first-aid sets in stock...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_42">
		<text>What do you want for them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_422">
		<text>For three first-aid sets one Stone Flower... you agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_421">
		<text>Yes I agree...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_petrenko_51">
		<text>I don't have any Repair sets....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_0">
		<text>I can receive Equipment from you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_1">
		<text>In general it is against rules, we don't usually offer this service, but considering your reputation.. What sort of equipment are you looking for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_2">
		<text>Ammunition, equipment...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_3">
		<text>Advanced weapons...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_4">
		<text>First-aid...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_5">
		<text>Complete sets for weapon and armor repair...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_21">
		<text>The Choice of equipment from me is:\n1. Charges for the M72-M Gauss for an artefact the Night Star;\n2. M72-M SuperGauss for an artefact Spring;\n3. Overalls SSP-99M Vega The fighting Ecologist suit for an artefact Crystal;\n4. Shotgun shells 12x70 mm for an artefact Sparkler.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_54">
		<text>I Have changed my mind, I will come back later...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_22">
		<text>Charges for the Gauss-rifle please</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_23">
		<text>SuperGauss? Lets see what the fuss is all about...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_24">
		<text>Give me the overalls, I hope they are green?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_25">
		<text>Shot-gun shells I will take...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_222">
		<text>For one power capacity with ready lethal 9ìì elements in a clip 10 rounds we ask from you for one artefact the Night Star... Agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_221">
		<text>I agree!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_232">
		<text>For three power capacities of SuperGauss a Spring</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_231">
		<text>Whatever it costs...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_242">
		<text>Certainly the green Overalls SSP-99M of Vega! Protection of a torso against bullet and fragmental damage. Effective protection against radiation and biological anomalies. Resistant to chemically-excited environments and other influences harmful to the organism!\nAnd we ask for it only one artefact Crystal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_241">
		<text>Direct advertising, give!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_252">
		<text>We have cartridges for a shot-gun of three kinds and are ready to offer them to you for an artefact Sparkler:\nthe Usual cartridge of 12 gauge equipped with buckshot. Five packs!\ The Dart has a stabilised flight that positively affects accuracy. Three packs!\nThe heavy Slug - Zhekan. Two packs!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_251">
		<text>I find that normal Buckshot works on the majority of mutants - I'll have that, please...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_2511">
		<text>Exact Dart - that's what is necessary!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_2512">
		<text>Lethal Slugs Zhekan - here's a medicine for mutants!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_666">
		<text>Do not have it, another time perhaps...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_31">
		<text>The weapons which we can offer you are:\n1. Smooth-bore shot-gun SPAS 12 for an artefact Slug;\n2. M72-M Gauss-rifle in exchange for three Glassbeads artefacts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_32">
		<text>The Shotgun Spas12? I will take that!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_33">
		<text>The Gauss-rifle! I dreamt for a long time of owning one!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_322">
		<text>Smooth-bore shot-gun SPAS 12 is distinguished by high reliability and flexibility. Perhaps, the best weapon for close combat in the Zone. And only one Slug does the job...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_321">
		<text>I agree! I will take the Spas12!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_332">
		<text>The Gauss-rifle - Works almost silently as ammunition is made from the energy of artefacts instead of gunpowder. Despite enormous capacity of shot, the recoil of a gauss-rifle is very insignificant. In accuracy and destructive power it surpasses all classical small arms. Fully penetrating any bullet-proof vest. We would like to receive for it three Glassbeads artefacts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_331">
		<text>Three pieces?! Rob me blind why don't you! I will Take it anyway...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_41">
		<text>For health we can recommend:\n1. First-aid sets scientific for an artefact Thorn;\n2. Anti-radiating preparations, for an artefact Slime.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_42">
		<text>First-aid sets scientific? How many? And are they good?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_43">
		<text>Antirad? That will help me save vodka...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_422">
		<text>The Medical set developed specially for work in the conditions of the Zone. The set structure is designed for both wounds and radiation sickness, and also reduces a dose of saved up radiation. For four sets only one Thorn... Agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_421">
		<text>Well if these first-aid sets are so good, I will take...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_432">
		<text>Antirad medication COMPLETELY reduces radiation. Five dose for one Slime. will you accept?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_431">
		<text>I accept.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_51">
		<text>In general we don't stock repair supplies, but someone by mistake has delivered two boxes with complete sets for armor repair... Therefore I with a clear conscience can offer you two repair sets for an artefact of Gravi</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_52">
		<text>Only two sets? for such a valuable artefact!.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_522">
		<text>Okay... For three complete sets one Gravi... Agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sakharov_521">
		<text>I agree...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_0">
		<text>So do you trade in any goods?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_1">
		<text>If you've got Artefacts then I've got the goods...What exactly do you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_2">
		<text>Cartridges, grenades, armor...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_3">
		<text>Good Weapons...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_4">
		<text>First-aid...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_5">
		<text>Accessories for repairs...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_21">
		<text>From ammunition I can offer:\n1. Cartridges 5.56 for NATO weapons for an artefact Slime;\n2. Grenades F-1 for an artefact Thorn;\n3. Cartridges for machine gun PKM for an artefact the Crystal Prickle;\n4. Cartridges 5.7x39mm to Belgian FN P90 for an artefact of Gravi.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_54">
		<text>I don't need anything...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_22">
		<text>Give cartridges 5.56...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_23">
		<text>I need Grenades...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_24">
		<text>Cartridges for the PKM I will take...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_25">
		<text>Cartridges for the 5.7x39mm Belgian FN P90 I will take...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_222">
		<text>For one slime I can give five simple packs or three armor-piercing... Well?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_221">
		<text>Give five simple...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_2211">
		<text>Armor-piercing is better...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_232">
		<text>Two grenades for a Thorn... You want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_231">
		<text>I need Grenades.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_242">
		<text>Two boxes of cartridges - for an artefact the Crystal Prickle... You agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_241">
		<text>I agree...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_252">
		<text>Four packs of cartridges - Gravi... you agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_251">
		<text>I agree!...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_666">
		<text>Do not have it, another time perhaps...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_31">
		<text>I can offer:\n1. Belgian FN P90 for an artefact Goldfish;\n2. FN2000 - automatic with a 40mm grenade launcher with a sight-module, and fire control for three artefacts of Soul.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_32">
		<text>Give me the Belgian FN P90...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_33">
		<text>I've wanted for a long time to get my hands on a FN2000...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_322">
		<text>Where is the Goldfish?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_321">
		<text>Here, take away...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_332">
		<text>The cost is three Souls...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_331">
		<text>Here take these Souls...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_41">
		<text>While I can offer:\n1. First-aid sets for a Medusa artefact;\n2. Antirad for a Quirk artefact...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_42">
		<text>First-aid sets I will take...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_43">
		<text>In the ZONE without Antirad you will not live...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_422">
		<text>For five first-aid sets one Medusa... agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_421">
		<text>Yes I agree...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_432">
		<text>Five Antirad in exchange for a Quirk... You accept?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_431">
		<text>Yes I accept....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_51">
		<text>While I can offer:\n1. Repair kits for weapons for an artefact Stone Flower.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_52">
		<text>For armor I will take.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_53">
		<text>Weapon repairs are more necessary.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_522">
		<text>For three ten-percentage complete sets one Gravi... agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_521">
		<text>I agree...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_532">
		<text>Three ten-percentage weapon complete sets in exchange for Stone Flower... You accept?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_skraga_531">
		<text>Yes, I accept...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_repair_dialog_0">
		<text>Can you explain for me how I go about using this Repair Kit?..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_repair_dialog_1">
		<text>To use the Kit : Open it up, and use salvaged parts that you pick up.. the Repairs to the armor will be applied to the armor being worn at present. In the case of Weapons, the repairs will be applied to the weapon that is currently equipped. If something is too badly damaged, then repairs of any sort may NOT be possible, and you should receive a PDA message indicating so... Quite simple, really...</text>
	</string>
	<!--string id="sidor_repair_dialog_2">
		<text>And what is this parts bag for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_repair_dialog_3">
		<text>It's simply a carrying case for salvaged parts from weapons and armor. I've added some parts for you already... try it out for yourself... and, be careful not to lose it out there, otherwise you won't be able to carry any parts at all...</text>
	</string -->
	<string id="sidor_repair_dialog_4">
		<text>I will make sure to keep it on me at all times, thanks!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_0">
		<text>I need some equipment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_1">
		<text>You understand for trade only artefacts are accepted... What exactly is necessary?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_2">
		<text>Cartridges, grenades, a bullet-proof vest...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_3">
		<text>Good Weapons...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_4">
		<text>First-aid...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_5">
		<text>Repair sets...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_21">
		<text>I Can offer:\n1. Sniper cartridges for an artefact a Meat Chunk;\n2. Cartridges 9x39 to the Shaft and Vintorez for an artefact of Gravi;\n3. Charges for the Gauss for an artefact Fireball;\n4. Excellent Army CKAT-10 for armor for 3 Urchin artefacts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_54">
		<text>Nothing at the moment, thanks...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_22">
		<text>Sniper cartridges how many?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_23">
		<text>Vintorez cartridges I will take</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_24">
		<text>Gauss, how many?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_25">
		<text>SKAT10 armor, how much?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_222">
		<text>The Bullet 7x13 has big enough (under sniper requirements) dispersion even on average distances, however, possesses the raised penetrative action.\n7N1 (CENTRAL PROCESSING UNIT) - the regular sniper cartridge in 2-3 times exceeds 7N13 on dispersion indicators. However, does not possess high penetrative properties.\nOn a shooting grouping 7N14 it is equivalent to a sniper cartridge 7N1, however, considerably surpasses it in armor-piercing action, thanks to introduction in a design of a bullet of the pointed tempered steel core.\nFor one artefact a Meat Chunk I give two packs of simple either sniper cartridges, or one pack of the armor-piercing... What you will choose?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_221">
		<text>Give simple, two packs...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_2211">
		<text>Exact sniper cartridges are necessary...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_2212">
		<text>I Will take armor-piercing, they are exact and lethal...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_232">
		<text>Five packs simple either four sniper or three armor-piercing for one Gravi... choose?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_231">
		<text>Give five simple.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_2311">
		<text>Sniper I will take.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_2312">
		<text>Armor-piercing - they bring down the Bloodsucker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_242">
		<text>One completely charged node for one artefact Fireball...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_241">
		<text>I agree, here's a Fireball</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_252">
		<text>Three Urchins and the SKAT10 is yours...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_251">
		<text>Here's three Urchins...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_666">
		<text>Do not have it, another time perhaps...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_31">
		<text>I can offer a special Vintorez (BCC Vintorez) intended for silence and suppressed flash for sniper shooting, supplied with integrated muffler...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_32">
		<text>And what do you ask for it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_33">
		<text>Saiga - that's quite something!.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_322">
		<text>Only one Crystal... agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_321">
		<text>I agree!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_332">
		<text>Saiga only in exchange for a Meat Chunk... Sound Good!?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_331">
		<text>Yes, a Meat Chunk is not a rarity...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_41">
		<text>I have only military first-aid sets.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_42">
		<text>And what you ask?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_43">
		<text>In the ZONE without vodka you will not live...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_422">
		<text>For three first-aid sets one the Crystal Prickle... agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_421">
		<text>I agree...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_432">
		<text>Five bottles in exchange for a Quirk... You Take?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_431">
		<text>I agree....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_51">
		<text>While I can offer:\n1. Repair kits for armor for an artefact Flash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_52">
		<text>And how many complete sets?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_53">
		<text>For Weapons are necessary.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_522">
		<text>For three ten-percentage complete sets one Flash... agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_521">
		<text>I agree...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_532">
		<text>Three ten-percentage weapon complete sets in exchange for a Stone Flower... You Take?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sak_531">
		<text>Yes, I will take....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_0">
		<text>Im looking for some equipment...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_1">
		<text>I can help, unfortunately artefacts are necessary... What did you want to find?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_2">
		<text>Cartridges...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_3">
		<text>Good Weapons...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_4">
		<text>First-aid...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_5">
		<text>Repair sets...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_21">
		<text>From ammunition I can offer:\n1. Cartridges for shot-guns for an artefact Thorn;\n2. Grenades RGD-5 for an artefact Slime;\n3. Cartridges 5,56x39 mm for a Droplet artefact;\n4. Cartridges 7,62x39 mm for an artefact Flash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_54">
		<text>Nothing for now, thanks...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_22">
		<text>Give shot-gun shells, how many you will give?...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_23">
		<text>I need Grenades...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_24">
		<text>Cartridges for NATO weapons I will take...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_25">
		<text>AK-47 cartridges...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_222">
		<text>For five packs of shot-gun shells a Thorn... agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_221">
		<text>Yes I agree...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_232">
		<text>Five grenades for one Slime... You accept?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_231">
		<text>I need Grenades.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_242">
		<text>Three packs of cartridges - Droplet artefact... You want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_241">
		<text>I accept...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_252">
		<text>Three packs of cartridges - Flash... agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_251">
		<text>Yes, the stopping power is tremendous!...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_666">
		<text>Do not have it, another time perhaps...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_31">
		<text>While I can offer:\n1. Sniper SiG. This weapon was created for conducting fights in the urban conditions. To facilitate weight, some components have been machined or replaced, the weight has decreased almost twice, deterioration of the weapon - minimum. The weapon is supplied by an un-removable optical sight of the raised frequency rate... I Will trade for artefacts Mica;\n2. Old, kind, and reliable AK-47 for the Soul artefact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_32">
		<text>And how many artefacts for the sniper SIG?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_33">
		<text>AK-47!! give it to me!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_322">
		<text>Three Micas and the SIG is yours...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_321">
		<text>Here take these artefacts...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_332">
		<text>Soul that is?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_331">
		<text>Is available, have specially reserved...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_41">
		<text>While I can offer:\n1. First-aid sets for an artefact Slug;\n2. Antirad, for an artefact Stone Flower.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_42">
		<text>First-aid sets for what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_43">
		<text>Antirad! how many?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_422">
		<text>Three Scientific sets for one Slug... agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_421">
		<text>I agree...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_432">
		<text>Five Antirad in exchange for one Stone Flower... You want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_431">
		<text>I accept...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_51">
		<text>I have only Repair kits for weapons.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_52">
		<text>For armor I will take.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_53">
		<text>And what do you want for them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_522">
		<text>For three ten-percentage complete sets one Gravi... agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_521">
		<text>I agree...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_532">
		<text>Three ten-percentage weapon complete sets in exchange for a the Crystal Prickle... You want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_doktor_531">
		<text>Yes, I will take.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_0">
		<text>And who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_11">
		<text>I'm in charge of provisions here. We need supplies badly, I can make it worth your while.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_12">
		<text>Do you have weapons and ammo? What kind of supplies do you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_1">
		<text>We don't need any money or artefacts. Those Duty bastards are trying to cut off our supplies and starve us out. And so far they have been doing a good job of it. What we need is food and fresh water. If you can get some beer and cigars that would be great also.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_2">
		<text>What kind of cartridges do you offer?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_3">
		<text>Do you have any good weapons?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_4">
		<text>What kind of medical supplies do you have?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_5">
		<text>Do you have any repair sets?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_21">
		<text>For cartridges:\n1. Five Sandwich gets you one 5.45x39mm Cartridges\n2. Two Bar of chocolate gets you one RGD-5 Grenade\n3. Two 100*Rads gets you one 9x19mm +P+ Cartridges\n4.Five Bread gets you one F1 Grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_54">
		<text>Nothing to trade today...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_22">
		<text>I will take the cartridges for the AK-74...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_23">
		<text>I need the RGD-5 Grenades...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_24">
		<text>I'll take the 9x19 armor piercing please...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_25">
		<text>I will take the F-1 grenade.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_222">
		<text>Give me the sandwich first and then you can have your cartridges.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_221">
		<text>Yes, here they are...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_232">
		<text>These are my favorite!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_231">
		<text>I'll see if I can get you some more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_242">
		<text>Energy drinks are needed here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_241">
		<text>Go On, have a drink...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_252">
		<text>This Bread better not be radioactive! Half the guys here have a bad case of the shits already from radioactive food!...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_251">
		<text>Give me the Grenades.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_666">
		<text>Don't have it, perhaps another time...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_31">
		<text>You want weapons? Well choose:\n1. The AN-94 'Abakan' will cost you 10 Canned Food\n2. The HK MP5 will cost you five Sausage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_32">
		<text>I need an Abakan...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_33">
		<text>MP-5, I will take one...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_322">
		<text>Hand over the Canned food...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_321">
		<text>Here you are, enjoy!...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_332">
		<text>There better not be maggots!...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_331">
		<text>Its good, check for yourself...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_41">
		<text>This is what's available from our infirmary:\n1. Two Flasks gets you one medkit\n2. Five Sandwiches gets you one Cossacks vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_42">
		<text>The medkit I will take...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_43">
		<text>I'll take the vodka...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_422">
		<text>Finally, some fresh water.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_421">
		<text>There you are, drink up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_432">
		<text>Five sandwiches for a bottle...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_431">
		<text>Vodka... you can never have enough, gimme...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_51">
		<text>Repair Kits:\n1. Three "Zone" Beer will get you one Armor Repair-Kit\n2. Three Cuban Cigar will get you one Weapon Repair-Kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_52">
		<text>I,ll take the armor kit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_53">
		<text>Weapon kits are what I need. Here, enjoy these Cuban cigars.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_522">
		<text>Where's the Beer at.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_521">
		<text>Here's three beers, enjoy!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_532">
		<text>Its been too long since I enjoyed one of these.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_jlob_531">
		<text>There not easy to get in the zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_0">
		<text>You Can sell equipment?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_1">
		<text>Yes I do, but not for cash. Bring vodka first, and the we can make a deal... Depends on the quantity of bottles you bring...\nWhat exactly do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_2">
		<text>Cartridges, grenades, and also some armor...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_3">
		<text>An assault rifle or a machine gun?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_4">
		<text>Military medkits are unique, I need some...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_21">
		<text>Well, I can exchange for vodka:\n1. Cartridges 5,45x39mm for the AK-74;\n2. Grenades F-1;\n3. Machine gun PKM cartridges 7.62;\n4. Good armor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_22">
		<text>Cartridges for the AK-74 I will take...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_23">
		<text>Give me F-1 grenades, very powerful...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_24">
		<text>I will take the PKM rounds...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_25">
		<text>I sell two version of that kind of ammo;\n1. small box for the 7 bottles of Vodka\n2. bigger box for the 12 bottles of Vodka\n \nChoose what you need...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_27">
		<text>I will take the armor, only if its new...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_222">
		<text>I Can give five packs simple or three packs armor-piercing for three bottles... up to you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_221">
		<text>Five Simple I will take...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_2211">
		<text>Give me the armor-piercing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_232">
		<text>Grenade F-1 = One vodka... You Want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_231">
		<text>I need Grenades.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_241000">
		<text>I agree...</text>
	</string -->
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_241">
		<text>One box of 100 cartridges for seven bottles...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_243">
		<text>One box of 250 cartridges for twelve bottles...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_250">
		<text>I really need it though, I will accept SKAT-9...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_252">
		<text>The armor is just came from the warehouse!\nBeside that, I have two type of these:\n1. SKAT-9 for Fifteen bottles,\n2. SKAT-10 for the twenty-five bottles\nBut, SKAT-10 isn't available at the moment!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_251">
		<text>Have you gone nuts! Ehh... Ok Military SKAT-10, I'll take...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_254">
		<text>The armor is just came from the warehouse!\nBeside that, I have two type of these:\n1. SKAT-9 for Fifteen bottles,\n2. SKAT-10 for the twenty-five bottles!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_666">
		<text>Do not have enough, maybe another time...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_31">
		<text>I Can get:\n1. Abakan supplied with a 3h-fold optical sight for conducting sniper fire. The optics built in in the case possesses more zoom, than standard sights.;\n2. Machine gun PKM - tough and heavy, but is very powerful with hard hitting rounds and a 100 shot magazine capacity. Bring on the Chimeras!!....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_32">
		<text>Abakan sniper? How many bottles?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_33">
		<text>For the PKM machine gun how much vodka is necessary?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_322">
		<text>The Gun is First class! Fifteen bottles I want... agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_321">
		<text>Its a deal, here's your vodka...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_332">
		<text>This is no small task, it is difficult to take out the PKM Machine gun without being seen... A case of vodka! 20 bottles! Well do you want it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_331">
		<text>I agree! Give!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_333">
		<text>This is no small task, it is difficult to take out the PKM Machine gun without being seen...\n.... Ups, it seems that I already sold the last one...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_334">
		<text>I really need this weapon, I'll be back for a day or two....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_41">
		<text>Yes the Military first-aid sets are a twice improved in comparison with the usual kits...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_42">
		<text>And how many will you give?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_422">
		<text>Two first-aid sets for a bottle...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_sherstyk_421">
		<text>I agree!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_0">
		<text>You spoke it is possible to approach you if I needed some gear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_1">
		<text>Bring vodka and then I will help you out... By quantity of bottles...\nWhat exactly do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_2">
		<text>Cartridges, grenades, and some good armor...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_3">
		<text>The assault rifle or a machine gun can be acquired?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_4">
		<text>Military-med kits are unique, can I get some...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_21">
		<text>Well, I can exchange for vodka:\n1. Cartridges 5,45x39mm for the AK-74;\n2. Grenades RGD5;\n3. To AK-47 cartridges 7.62;\n4. Sniper cartridges.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_54">
		<text>Nothing for now...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_22">
		<text>Cartridges for the AK-74 I will take...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_23">
		<text>I need grenades.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_24">
		<text>AK-47 ammo will take...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_25">
		<text>The Sniper - the king of the Zone, give me some cartridges...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_222">
		<text>I Can give five packs simple or three packs armor-piercing for three bottles... up to you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_221">
		<text>Simple five I will take...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_2211">
		<text>Give me the armor-piercing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_232">
		<text>Two grenades = One vodka... You Take?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_231">
		<text>I need Grenades.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_242">
		<text>Cartridges only armor-piercing - five bottles for three packs...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_241">
		<text>I agree...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_252">
		<text>A Pack of sniper cartridges - three bottles...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_251">
		<text>If that's what it costs...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_666">
		<text>Do not have it, another time perhaps...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_31">
		<text>I Can get:\n1. Abakan. A reliable, powerful weapon.\n2. AK-47 it is a classic weapon, it is reliable and deadly...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_32">
		<text>Abakan? How many bottles you ask?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_33">
		<text>AK-47!! how much vodka?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_322">
		<text>Ten bottles I want... agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_321">
		<text>Certainly! Here's the vodka...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_332">
		<text>It is cheap... Eight bottles and it's yours.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_331">
		<text>I agree! Give!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_41">
		<text>Approximately twice the strength compared to normal kits... Military men always protect their health...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_42">
		<text>And how many will you give?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_422">
		<text>Two first-aid sets for a bottle...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trade_dialog_kuznezov_421">
		<text>Agreed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sak_military_stalker_dialog_0">
		<text>Stalker, we need to talk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sak_military_stalker_dialog_1">
		<text>It is possible I have a pair of offers that would be Favorable to both parties...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sak_military_stalker_dialog_2">
		<text>This is interesting I'm listening...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sherstyk_1_dialog_0">
		<text>Do you Know where the documents are located on the third floor?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sherstyk_1_dialog_1">
		<text>And that! We hardly sleep with this case in embrace... In any way an opportunity will not wait what to send all this shit to the center... On hearings there that that with Burner a brain is connected... Or with a way brains zombie...\nAnd you that what advantage of them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sherstyk_1_dialog_2">
		<text>There is an interest, time is asked...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sherstyk_1_dialog_3">
		<text>Interest is? And in what you estimate this interest?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sherstyk_1_dialog_4">
		<text>Well not in gold reserves in Russia... And there are variants?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sherstyk_1_dialog_5">
		<text>Has got us here to sit... You of binge, neither women, nor entertainments... I to you so will tell - for good binge all can be got... got it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sherstyk_1_dialog_6">
		<text>Well very good binge I do not promise, but vodka it is possible to adjust... Not of burning...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sherstyk_1_dialog_7">
		<text>Appears so... A box of vodka - and the case is yours... That's a bargain yes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sherstyk_1_dialog_8">
		<text>A bargain! there Will be a box of vodka for you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sherstyk_1_dialog_9">
		<text>Eh of the fighter! The native land for vodka will sell... Itself I will extract...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_agroprom_vodka">
		<text>\nEnsign Sherstjuk for twenty bottles of vodka agrees to bring a case with documents...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_borov_11">
		<text>Borov has sent me to survey the site of a helicopter crash which is located behind a bog, just south of the lab, in the Dark Valley. All that is valuable - we must drag to Borov...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_bandit_krisyk">
		<text>\nThe Bandit known by the nickname 'Rat' has written down many secrets in his PDA. Borov wants the return of this PDA. In any way. A mark in a map where the Rat disappeared, it is possible that the Associate from the 100*Rads bar Can pinpoint his location.</text>	<!-- Changed 'Senior Lecturer' to 'Associate'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="sherstyk_12_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello, the Vodka has arrived!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sherstyk_12_dialog_1">
		<text>Ah, your a good fellow! Let's take a look...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sherstyk_12_dialog_2">
		<text>Have you brought the documents?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sherstyk_12_dialog_3">
		<text>The Word of a military man is not to be doubted! Here are your documents!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sherstyk_12_dialog_4">
		<text>Here's your vodka...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sherstyk_12_dialog_5">
		<text>Hold this suitcase, do not strain yourself now...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_price">
		<text>Trader offers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="price_sidor_text">
		<text>Sidorovich's offers:\n \n1. 12x70 buckshot - three packs for a Medusa\n2. RG-5 grenades - two for a Quirk\n3. 5.45x39mm cartridges - three packs for a Droplet\n4. 7.62x39mm cartridges - two packs for a Stone Blood\n \n1. A TOZ-34 for a Flash\n2. A Saiga-12k for a Meat Chunk\n \n1. Eight medkits for a Stone Flower\n2. Three bottles of vodka for a Quirk\n \n1. Three Armor repair kits for a Gravi\n2. Three Weapon repair kits for a Stone Flower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="price_barman_text">
		<text>Barkeep's offers:\n \n1. 5.45x39mm cartridges: five packs of standard, or three packs of armor-piercing for a Flash\n2. Three RGD-5 grenades for a Stone Flower\n3. 5.56x39mm cartridges: five packs of standard, or three packs of armor-piercing for a Slime\n4. 9x39mm cartridges: five packs of standard, or three packs of armor-piercing for a Gravi\n \n1. One AS Val for two Fireballs\n2. One OC-14 Groza for a Night Star\n \n1. Five standard medkits for a Sparkler\n2. Three bottles of vodka for a Stone Blood\n \n1. Three Armor repair kits for a Meat Chunk\n2. Three Weapon repair kits for a Fireball</text>
	</string>
	<string id="price_petrenko_text">
		<text>Petrenko's offers:\n \n1. 7.62x54mm cartridges: two packs of standard sniper rounds, or a pack of armor-piercing for a Droplet\n2. Four VOG-25 grenades, or three VOG-25A for a Stone Blood\n3. 7.62x39mm cartridges: five packs of standard, or three packs of armor-piercing for a Medusa\n4. A Duty PSZ-9Md Universal for two Micas, or a Duty Exoskeleton for three Micas\n \n1. A Vintora Dragunova (SVD) sniper rifle for an Urchin\n2. A truncated SVU Expert automatic sniper rifle for a Soul\n \n1. Three Military medkits for a Stone Flower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="price_scraga_text">
		<text>Miser's offers:\n \n1. 5.56mm cartridges: five packs of standard, or three packs of armor-piercing for a Slime\n2. Two F-1 grenades for a Thorn\n3. PKM machine gun cartridges - two boxes for a Crystal Thorn\n4. 5.7x39mm cartridges for the Belgian FN P90 - four packs for a Gravi\n \n1. A Belgian FN P90 for a Goldfish\n2. An FN2000 for three Souls\n \n1. Five standard medkits for a Jellyfish\n2. Five Antirads for a Quirk\n \n1. Three Weapon repair kits for a Stone Flower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="price_sak_text">
		<text>Syak's offers:\n \n1. Sniper cartridges: two packs of standard, or one pack of armor-piercing for a Meat Chunk\n2. 9x39 cartridges: five packs of standard, four packs of sniper, or three packs of armor-piercing for a Gravi\n3. Gauss rifle charges for a Fireball\n4. A Military SKAT10 for three Urchins.\n \n1. A BCC Vintorez Pro for a Crystal\n \n1. Three Military medkits for a Crystal Thorn\n \n1. Three Armor repair kits for a Flash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="price_doktor_text">
		<text>The Doctor's offers:\n \n1. Shotgun cartridges - five packs for a Thorn\n2. Five RGD-5 grenades for a Slime\n3. 5.56x39mm cartridges - three packs for a Droplet\n4. 7.62x39mm cartridges - three packs for a Flash\n \n1. An SiG sniper rifle for three Micas\n2. An AK-47 for a Soul\n \n1. Three Scientific medkits for a Slug\n2. Five Antirads for a Stone Flower\n \n1. Three Weapon repair kits for a Gravi</text>
	</string>
	<string id="price_jila_text">
		<text>Vein's offers:\n \nAmmunition:\n1. Five fresh sandwiches will get you one box of 5.45x39mm cartridges\n2. Two bars of chocolate will get you one RGD-5 grenade\n3. Two 100*Rads gets you one box of 9x19mm +P+ Cartridges\n4. Five loaves of bread will get you one F1 grenade\n \nWeapons? Well, choose:\n1. An AN-94 'Abakan' will cost you ten tins of canned food\n2. An HK MP5 will cost you five sausages\n \nMedical Supplies:\n1. Two flasks of water will get you one medkit\n2. Five sandwiches will get you one Cossacks vodka\n \nRepair kits:\n1. Three 'Zone' beers will get you one Armor repair kit\n2. Three Cuban cigars will get you one Weapon repair kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="price_kuznezov_text">
		<text>Kuznetsov's offers:\n \n1. 5.45x39mm cartridges for the AK-74: three bottles for five standard packs, or three armor-piercing packs\n2. RGD5 grenades - two for a bottle\n3. 7.62x39mm AK-47 cartridges - five bottles for three packs\n4. Sniper rounds - three bottles for a pack\n \n1. An AN-94 'Abakan' for 5 litres\n2. An AK-47 for 4 litres\n \n1. Two medkits for a bottle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="price_sherstuk_text">
		<text>Sherstjuk's offers:\n \n1. Cartridges 5.45x39mm for the AK-74 - three bottles for five packs of standard, or three packs of armor-piercing\n2. An F-1 Grenade for one bottle\n3. 7.62 PKM machine gun cartridges\n 3a. - One box of 100 rounds for seven bottles\n 3b. - One box of 250 rounds for twelve bottles\n4. Military SKAT9-M for fifteen bottles\n5. Military SKAT10-M for twenty five bottles\n \n1. Abakan sniper rifle - fifteen bottles\n2. PKM machine gun for a 'twenty' case of vodka\n \n1. Standard medkits - two for a bottle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="price_sakharov_text">
		<text>Sakharov's offers:\n \n1. 9mm charges for the M72-M Gauss rifle - ten rounds for a Night Star\n2. 9mm charges for the M72-M SuperGauss - three rounds for a Spring\n3. An SSP-99M Vega suit for a Crystal\n4. Shotgun shells 12x70 mm: five packs of Buckshot, three packs of Darts, or two packs of Slugs for a Sparkler\n \n1. A smooth-bore SPAS 12 shotgun for a Slug\n2. An M72-M Gauss-rifle for three Glassbeads\n \n1. Four scientific medkits for a Thorn\n2. Five Antirads for a Slime\n \n1. Three Armor repair sets for a Gravi</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_repair_box_dialog_0">
		<text>Can you supply me with another Toolbox?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_repair_box_dialog_1">
		<text>Did you go and lose yours or something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_repair_box_dialog_2">
		<text>Just answer the question...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_repair_box_dialog_3">
		<text>Yeah, I can provide you with another one... but...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_repair_box_dialog_4">
		<text>But, what?...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_repair_box_dialog_5">
		<text>But these things aren't cheap. It will cost you ten Medusa artefacts...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_repair_box_dialog_61">
		<text>Okay, fine... it's not like I have a choice... here you go...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_repair_box_dialog_62">
		<text>That's a bit steep, don't you think?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_repair_box_dialog_71">
		<text>That's what I like about you, Marked One... you never haggle...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_repair_box_dialog_72">
		<text>You drive a hard bargain... Okay, fine, make it seven...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_repair_box_dialog_81">
		<text>You want to make something of it?... Go ahead!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_repair_box_dialog_82">
		<text>Thanks. I'll be back for it when I have the artefacts...</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
