<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 something, removed "string_table" - aleks1970 -->
<!-- Translated and corrected by Steve90k for fluency and ease of reading. Edited and proofed by Sword2012 for clarity, brevity, and consistency. 13 Mar 16 -->


	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_0">
		<text>I need answers to several questions...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_1">
		<text>Ask away. I'll try to help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_11">
		<text>Firstly, where are my things?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_111">
		<text>The leader usually keeps all the confiscated stuff. His room's on the top floor. My belongings were taken there when they caught me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_1111">
		<text>Thanks!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_12">
		<text>How can I get out of here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_121">
		<text>When they were leading me around, I noticed a sewer grate under the stairs on the first floor. If you managed to open the cell, it should be possible to get out of here using that sewer...\nThen go West, and use the tunnel to get to Freedom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_1211">
		<text>Thanks for the information</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_14">
		<text>Who captured us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_141">
		<text>We're being held by the Mercs. Nobody really knows who they are, but there are rumours that they work with foreign intelligence services. The location of this base is top secret - no one knows how to get into the Dead City. There are many people who'd be very interested in this information - especially Freedom and Duty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_1411">
		<text>Go on...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_14111">
		<text>If you manage to get a map of the Dead City, a successful assault will be possible. The Mercs or the Bandits will probably have one. You should try to get it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_141111">
		<text>Thanks for your info</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_15">
		<text>What do you know about this place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_151">
		<text>The city is split into two sections. We're on the Merc side. To the South, beyond the square, is where the Bandits are. They're holed up in the school building, southwest of the city. In between the bases, there's a run-down five storey building, and a few relatively intact ones. If the shit hits the fan, you can sit it out in one of those. There are also some garages, and a couple of small houses around that area. There are two five storey buildings and a dozen garages on the Bandits' side also. On the other side of the square is the former city council building</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_1511">
		<text>Thanks for the information</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_16">
		<text>Who's in charge here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_161">
		<text>A truly nasty guy named Dushman. I've seen him carrying around a folder full of documents a few times. I reckon there's something interesting inside...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_1611">
		<text>Thanks</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_17">
		<text>Nope, nothing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_hello_dialog_11">
		<text>Strelok! Where the hell have you been? I haven't seen you or the guys since the last raid! I was getting worried!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_hello_dialog_21">
		<text>So, you feeling better? You thinking clearly?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_0">
		<text>Strelok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_1">
		<text>Yeah, you're Strelok! Who else would you be? I'm Doc, don't you recognize me? What happened to you, my friend? You don't look well. We were in the Zone together for two years. You really don't remember me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_11">
		<text>No I'm sorry, I don't...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_2">
		<text>You don't? Strelok, what the...? You're not joking around, are you? Man... what about the team? Fang? Ghost? You remember them, don't you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_21">
		<text>I don't remember Fang, and Ghost is dead - I found his body in Yantar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_3">
		<text>Ghost? Dead? Dammit, how could that happen? They... they were the best. What happened to you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_31">
		<text>I don't... I don't know what happened. I don't remember...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_4">
		<text>Wait, I need to calm down. That's some really shitty news, man. I think it's all linked with your last trip into the Zone. When we saw each other last, you left me the key to the stash at Pripyat and the map of how to find it. I've managed to keep it hidden from the Mercs. Here, take it. Hide it well. Perhaps you'll find something there. You were saying that there's some kind of trick with the Monolith - but I don't understand what it was about, and you didn't either...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_41">
		<text>I see. Where are we? I don't remember how I got here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_5">
		<text>We're in the Dead City! In the Merc camp...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_6">
		<text>We're in the Dead City! In the Merc camp...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_cit_reward_0">
		<text>By the way, I have information on the Mercs. Interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_cit_reward_1">
		<text>Depends on what it is...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_cit_reward_11">
		<text>I have a map which details the location of their base - the guard posts, ways to get in and out without being noticed, and a lot more...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_cit_reward_111">
		<text>Sounds valuable. I'll give you 3,000 for it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_cit_reward_1111">
		<text>Deal. Here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_cit_reward_11111">
		<text>Great! Here's your reward. Soon Stalkers will be arguing about whether Mercs even existed at all!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_cit_reward_1112">
		<text>No, that's not enough...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_cit_reward_11121">
		<text>As you wish. I'm not giving you any more...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_cit_reward_13">
		<text>Nothing worthwhile. Just the usual gossip, sorry</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_cit_reward_131">
		<text>If you find out something more specific, come back. I'll pay you...</text>
	</string>
