<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 -->
<!-- Translated and corrected by Steve90k for fluency and ease of reading. Edited and proofed by Sword2012 for clarity, brevity, and consistency. 21 Jan 16 -->
	<string id="bun_code">
		<text>A closed door, and a number haunt me, as if from a previous life. I knew them both then, when I didn't believe. Now I remember - 342089 - but I no longer remember the way to the door...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bun_monolith_pda">
		<text>Monolith soldier's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_code_door_info">
		<text>The dead scientist had a map with a door marked on it. The code is 1287975</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_code_door_info_name">
		<text>Coded door</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_get_to_aes_desc">
		<text>Barkeep: Everyone went crazy when they found out! They all started pushing towards the center of the Zone - Loners, Freedom, Duty, even Mercs. The first ones there will get everything! The Wish Granter, the klondike of artifacts, and devil knows what else. You need to hurry, 'cos if the Wish Granter is indeed in the sarcophagus, the first person who gets there will have everything he ever wanted! Right now, there's a detachment of veterans gathering at Radar, just before Pripyat. If you're quick, you might be able to join them. Another gun is always useful...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_sleep_info">
		<text>I turned off the Brain Scorcher. I lost conciousness just as I did it. I had a vision - I saw the Chernobyl power plant and the sarcophagus above me. Then a flash. Then the huge irridescent Monolith standing inside the sarcophagus. It was the Wish Granter! They're the same thing! Then a stalker, ragged and exhausted, tries to reach out his arm to it. Then another bright flash, and I see a fragment of my first dream - A man stands with his back to me, shooting like crazy, as if at an invisible horde of mutants. Someone shouts, "Strelok!". The man stops shooting, shudders for a moment, and then starts to turn around slowly... but then pictures slide past, as if a film was being played backwards, and I see that he's shooting at the rats to force them back into the plant. I realize that I was there. I need to go to the Monolith...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_sleep_info1">
		<text>The Scorcher is no longer a threat to anyone...</text>
	</string>
