<!--1.1.0.0.0.4 -->
<!-- Translated and corrected by Steve90k for fluency and ease of reading. Edited and proofed by Sword2012 for clarity, brevity, and consistency. 08 Oct 16 -->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->
	<string id="bar_darklab_documents_txt">
		<text>Barkeep: According to the documents you brought from Agroprom, things are starting to become clear, although some data is missing. There's evidence to suggest the presence of a 'Brain Scorcher' that blocks the road to the North, but no one knows exactly what it is. There's also mention of a Lab X-18, and its description matches the abandoned underground structures in the Dark Valley. However, its current status is unknown, and bandits have now set up a base in that area.\n Several Duty scouts went there recently, but there's been no news from them so far.\n To get inside the lab, you'll need two electronic keys - I'll give you one, but the other you'll need to get from Borov, the bandit leader, one way or another\n \nThat seems to be the only way to get at the documents...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_darklab_documents2_txt">
		<text>Find the documents relating to previous research in Lab X-18. They should shed some light on the 'Brain Scorcher'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_codedoor_1_txt">
		<text>A combination lock is blocking the way into the lab. You'll need to find someone who knows the combination</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_codedoor_2_txt">
		<text>There's another door, with something definitely behind it. You just need to find the code</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_document1">
		<text>The first stage of the experiment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_document2">
		<text>The second stage of the experiment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_document3">
		<text>Security report</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_document4">
		<text>Attack on personnel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_document5">
		<text>The third and final stage of the experiment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="documents_1">
		<text>A week ago, we decided to increase the radiation dosage of the test subjects. No changes were detected in the first three days. After that, however, strange metamorphoses started to occur, most notably hair loss and heightened aggressiveness. Several subjects were literally trampled over by their peers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="documents_2">
		<text>The subjects' condition has stabilized. Hair loss has stopped, leaving them with approximately 10% of their original follicles. Their claws and teeth have grown considerably. They exhibit seemingly random behaviour, with no sense of purpose or goal. Bursts of aggressive activity are no longer directed at their peers. Senior lab technician A.N. Burnov speculated that this may indicate an increase in the subjects' awareness. We have decided to test the new modulation algorithm of Psi-emissions on the subjects</text>
	</string>
	<string id="documents_3">
		<text>Chief of Security: Yesterday, security guard G.P. Glebov tossed a piece of meat to the subjects, out of 'scientific curiosity'. To his surprise, every one of them sprang to life, tore it apart, and devoured it in seconds, while Glebov was lucky to escape with his life. Subsequently, several individuals have tried to break out of their cells. Because of this, our lab technicians have been unable to obtain the regular test samples. Although Glebov's actions were foolhardy, warranting disciplinary action, I propose that all maintenance personnel be equipped with defensive weapons from here on, for adequate protection in the event of an emergency</text>
	</string>
	<string id="documents_4">
		<text>Chief of Security: Yesterday the experiment almost got out of control. Nearly two dozen test subjects broke out of their cells and vandalised two laboratory rooms. Fortunately, the research personnel were able to lock themselves in an upstairs room. Security was ordered to clear the main laboratory room. In the course of their duties, three guards suffered bites to their bodies. Hopefully, they'll be okay but, for the sake of my men, I hope the experiment will be concluded soon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="documents_5">
		<text>Yesterday, we exposed the test subjects to the new modulation algorithm. While further conclusive examinations are necessary, early diagnoses suggest that their brains have been roasted. I can hardly imagine how this type of emission would affect humans. We have tested every type of emission using various modulation algorithms, and the results match those obtained in the other laboratories. This stage of the experiment can now be considered complete, and we should be ready to conduct it on larger creatures within a week</text>
	</string>
	<string id="LabX18 first key">
		<text>2nd Level access code</text>
	</string>
	<string id="LabX18 second key">
		<text>1st Level access code</text>
	</string>
	<string id="LabX18_information">
		<text>Information from X-18</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pass_to_1st_door">
		<text>Excellent. I'm glad you've received 2nd Level access. Now I can tell you what goes on in our laboratory. Your access code is 1243. Chief of Laboratory X-18, Piotr Ilyitch Kalugin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pass_to_2nd_door">
		<text>Starting tomorrow, your job will be attending to the container in the central laboratory room. The containers must be inspected every two hours. Report everything directly to me. The code to the central laboratory room is 9524. Chief of Laboratory X-18, Piotr Ilyitch Kalugin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_x18_dream_name">
		<text>A strange dream</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_x18_dream_text">
		<text>I had a strange dream. The colossal Chernobyl nuclear power plant emerges in the twilight. Everything is peaceful. A lone man appears, and I watch him from behind, against a background of trees. The wind starts to blow. Suddenly, hordes of rats begin to skitter away from the NPP in all directions. The man, his back still turned to me, starts shooting at the rats. There's an abrupt scream, "Strelok!". The man shudders, and freezes for a moment, before turning slowly in my direction. But an instant before I see his face, I wake up. What does this dream mean? I don't know, but I think it's something I've seen before...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_captive_help_txt">
		<text>The Duty member, Bullet, wants me to rescue his partner who was captured by the bandits. They'll soon be escorting him to the deserted factory</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_help_art_txt">
		<text>Dutyer: They have another one of ours - Serega! They're keeping him in the cellar... There's a large building there, still under construction... Help him out for us, will you? Or they'll finish him too...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_x18_conclusion">
		<text>Lab X-18</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_x18_conclusion_txt">
		<text>Lab X-18 wasn't fun, and neither were its current residents. I didn't think things like that even existed...\nI found some documents. I didn't understand much of what was written in them, except that they contained technical specs for parts of the Kaymanov emitters.\nWhat's interesting is that those parts were destined for another lab with the codename X-16. Chances are it's a secret one, also...</text>
	</string>
