<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4, line 290 Russian char., removed "string_table" - aleks1970 -->
<!-- Translated and corrected by Steve90k for fluency and ease of reading. Edited and proofed by Sword2012 for clarity, brevity, and consistency. 07 Oct 16 -->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->

	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_0">
		<text>Thanks for your help, Stalker! If you hadn't shown up, I wouldn't be alive to thank you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_10001">
		<text>I'm looking for information on a guy named Strelok. Do you know anything?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_10002">
		<text>How do I get into the tunnels?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_15001">
		<text>What about Strelok's secret stash?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_15002">
		<text>Thanks for the information</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_1501">
		<text>Yes, I heard about that. I heard he used to work these areas, and used the local tunnels as a bolthole. His group probably had a base down there, too...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_1502">
		<text>This is one of many openings that'll lead you to the tunnels. Once you're in there, you're on your own. It's like a bloody rabbit warren, and there's no map, sorry...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_2">
		<text>I'm looking for info on a guy named Strelok. Seriy told me you might know something about him</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_30001">
		<text>Thank you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_3001">
		<text>Yeah, we looked for it too, but couldn't find it. I'll send you everything we've got on it, though</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_stalker_about_0">
		<text>What's going on here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_stalker_about_1">
		<text>What does it look like? We're getting fucking hammered! Talk to Mole, if you're both still alive after this shitstorm... Now shut the fuck up and start shooting back!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_stalker_start_0">
		<text>Shit, man, that was a fight and a half. I wouldn't have wished that on a group of Bandits. What the fuck are they looking for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_about_agroprom_0">
		<text>I'm looking for the Agroprom Research Institute</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_about_agroprom_10">
		<text>It's not far from here. Follow the road to the west. It'll lead you straight to the gates</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_about_agroprom_100">
		<text>I hear the Military have set up a base there...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_about_agroprom_120">
		<text>Thanks for the information</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_about_agroprom_20">
		<text>Yeah, there's a military base. Not sure exactly how many soldiers there are, but it's gotta be a platoon, minimum. They're well-armed, and you've got no chance of breaking through - they'll take you down before you even open your mouth.\nThe best way in is during the night - there's too many guards during the day, and they've got checkpoints everywhere.\nOh, I heard a deserter from that base is hiding somewhere in the marshes. He's probably scared shitless so, if you can find him, you may be able to get something useful out of him</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_0">
		<text>What's going on?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_100">
		<text>Me and my boys found a little hidden area full of artefacts, then those Military bastards attacked us for no reason. I don't know what the hell they wanted...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_200">
		<text>Yeah, I've heard about him. I think he used to, you know, 'make a living' from this area. He left a long time ago, though. I don't know when exactly, and I've no idea where he was headed. Sorry...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_2000">
		<text>There's a reason you were waiting here, isn't there? Otherwise, why would Spetsnaz show up?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_250">
		<text>Yeah, I know a little about Strelok...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_2500">
		<text>I'd really appreciate you telling me, please</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_3500">
		<text>Look, if you're lying to me, I'll come back and finish what the soldiers couldn't!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_400">
		<text>I'm not lying! But look - no one really trusts anyone here, so you don't really have much choice...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_met_seriy_100">
		<text>Seriy you say? Well, okay. They say Strelok used to get up to things around here - and probably hid his stuff underground. I heard his group had its main base here, too. We tried looking for it, but we found jack shit. I'll give you everything we have on it though. Maybe you'll have more luck</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_met_seriy_2000">
		<text>What else do you know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_met_seriy_250">
		<text>That's all I know. You'll have to figure the rest out yourself. Good luck</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_help_0">
		<text>Help me, Stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_help_10">
		<text>Okay...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_ratcatcher_start_0">
		<text>Don't shoot, man!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_esc_0">
		<text>What are you doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_esc_20">
		<text>I'm coming back from the factory, just down the road from here. I don't know how, but the Military found out about our group. I didn't wait around for them - I just ran. I hope the others got out of there, 'cos no one'll survive that kind of offensive. That was some serious shit there. Did you see those choppers going in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_esc_300">
		<text>I see. Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_esc_400">
		<text>I see. Thank you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_0">
		<text>I've a couple of questions...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_10">
		<text>What do you want to know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_1000">
		<text>Anything interesting going on in this area?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_120">
		<text>How much do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_130">
		<text>Here's your money. Now where is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_131">
		<text>You can fuck off!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_140">
		<text>Thank you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_20">
		<text>Yeah, there are a couple of places, but it's gotta to be worth something, eh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_21">
		<text>It used to be pretty quiet around here, but recently the Military seem to have got worked up about something. They're all over the bloody place, and they'll waste anyone in their way. They smoked all the Bandits recently, although I hear some of them escaped into the tunnels</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_30">
		<text>Thirty. Deal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_40">
		<text>The exit from the railway tunnel's nearby. The far end's closed off, so it's fairly safe, and no one's been mutilated there whilst asleep - yet. Also, northwest of the factory there's a marsh with a wagon dumped in it. There's a shitload of radiation around it, so you're best approaching it from the western side. A soldier's been spotted there, and he's likely to be from the military base at the Institute. The poor bastard's probably terrified. He can't get out and he can't go back, but he's been there two days and I doubt he'll survive much longer by himself...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_9999">
		<text>Bye...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_0">
		<text>Anything interesting happening here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_1">
		<text>Do you want to know about Ratcatcher? It'll cost you thirty, though...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_11">
		<text>Deal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_111">
		<text>We have a local hero around here we call Ratcatcher. He lives in the marshes. This guy's bred so many rats in the sewage collectors, they could eat through every one of those Military bastards!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_1111">
		<text>Great. Thanks</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_1112">
		<text>Can you tell me more about those collectors?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_11121">
		<text>Collectors are your standard shit-stink sewers. They take waste from the Institute, and dump it into the water reservoir...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_111211">
		<text>Great. Take care of yourself</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_12">
		<text>I do know that already. But thanks</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_121">
		<text>Nothing else to tell you, sorry</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_13">
		<text>Sorry, not enough cash...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_14">
		<text>Thanks, but I'm not interested</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_3">
		<text>Anything interesting happening here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_31">
		<text>Sod all. Absolutely nothing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_311">
		<text>I see. Bye...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_0">
		<text>What can you tell me about this place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_1">
		<text>This is the area around the Agroprom Research Institute. The Institute itself is to the southwest. The factory, that's the Institute's technical production facility, is to the north. The buildings have all been abandoned for ages, and everything that wasn't bolted down, plus most of what was, has been looted. But the Military have been going over that place a lot recently...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_2">
		<text>Tell me more about the Institute...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_21">
		<text>There are so many rumours about the Institute! Before the accident in '86, the only thing there was the Institute of Crop Selection and Genetics. The area where the factory is was used for experimental crop fields.\nAfter the accident, they closed down the Institute and burned all the fields. Then they came back, whitewashed the building, put a fence around it, and built army barracks.\nI've no idea what they used to do there, but they certainly weren't short of funding, that's for sure!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_3">
		<text>Tell me more about the factory...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_31">
		<text>The factory was built in the late '80s. They said it was going to be for building and testing machines that could treat irradiated soil. But as far as I know, no one's ever seen a single machine come out of the place.\nIt's totally empty now, which makes it popular with Stalkers. I hear it's pretty safe, as long as you avoid the dark corners...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_4">
		<text>Thanks</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_0">
		<text>What are you doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_10">
		<text>Hey, I'm just hiding here! I don't want any trouble!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_100">
		<text>Hiding from what, or whom?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_120">
		<text>Catacombs? Underground?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_130">
		<text>Do you know where they keep documents at the Institute?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_140">
		<text>What are you going to do now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_141">
		<text>What are you going to do now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_20">
		<text>I'm from the recon unit. They sent us into the Underground to see what's going on under the base. Christ, it's scary as hell down there! I was the only one to get out! Everyone else is probably dead... I'm not going back there! Not again! The bastards are always using us to plug up holes in the Zone. They tell rookies that the Zone's a top secret area, so there's never a shortage of new guys wanting a piece of the action, but they never say how many are killed here! Fuck! Fuck! Fuck! I wish I'd never signed up for this! I just want to go home!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_30">
		<text>Underground tunnels, from the Institute to the area around it. I'll show you the entrances, but I don't have a map of the catacombs down there...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_40">
		<text>At the HQ. It's on the third floor of the Institute. That's where they keep those damn papers.\nIt's a bitch getting in there, though. By day, the area's teeming with patrols, but not so much at night. Believe me, if you wanna get inside you'll need to go through the catacombs - the soldiers don't like going down there - but you won't stand a chance in hell at the gate...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_50">
		<text>I don't know what to do. Officially I'm a deserter, but I need to get out of here...\nWhen we first arrived there was a Zaporozhets in the garage. I know a bit about cars, but it still took me an hour to get it working. Then the bloody captain just took it for himself, saying it wasn't right that I should have it because he outranked me. But he didn't know how to look after it, and when it stopped on him he just dumped it by the gate.\nIf I could just get that car, getting out of here would be much safer!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_0">
		<text>Hello</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_01">
		<text>What's up?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_011">
		<text>Can you tell me about the collector? How do I get inside? Where are the openings?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_0111">
		<text>It's dangerous inside the collector. There are six openings, and two of them are in the area around the Institute, where the Military have their base. That area is patrolled regularly, and the captain keeps the patrol schedule safe inside his armory</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_01111">
		<text>How do you know all this?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_011111">
		<text>The rats told me. They tell me everything...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_0111111">
		<text>I... see. Well, goodbye, and good luck to you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_012">
		<text>Nothing. See you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_013">
		<text>Who the hell are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_0134">
		<text>I live here. It's a life of my own choosing. I breed rats in the collector, just to annoy the military at the Institute...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_0135">
		<text>I'm known as Ratcatcher</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_01351">
		<text>What are you doing in this pile of shit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_123">
		<text>Well, some say I'm from another story...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_story_0">
		<text>Any more news?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_story_1">
		<text>Well, I was walking through the Dark Valley one night. There was no moon, and I could barely see my hand in front of me. Then I spotted a campfire in the distance. "Thank goodness!" I thought, "Company!"\nJust as I was passing some bushes, though, I saw something move. I thought it was a bandit stalking me, so he could report to his boss, and we'd all be killed in our sleep tonight. So I decided to turn the tables on the bastard and scare the hell out him.\nI moved very quietly, so as not to alert him, then grabbed him and got him in a neck lock. Christ, the guy smelled like a one hundred year old zombie. But my heart was thumping, I was pumped, and I didn't want to lose the advantage. So I put my mouth close to his ear, and whispered, "What the fuck are you doing here, dogmeat?"\nThe guy just snarled, so I eased my grip a bit and said, "Look, the next time I catch you following me, my friends are going to hold you down while I scrape your brain out through your eye sockets. Do you understand?"\nThen suddenly this thing stands up, towers over me, and growls, "You've got balls, so we'll call it quits this time - but next time you come across a bloodsucker having a shit, you'd better leave him in peace...\nDo you understand?..."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_story_2">
		<text>Heh, yeah, that's good...</text>
	</string>
