<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.6, removed "string_table" - aleks1970  -->
<!-- Both Steve and I had problems deciphering this dialogue, even using the original Russian, because it was so poorly written, and neither of us knew the context. We've turned each line into understandable English dialogue that follows some sort of pattern, but we don't know if it's correct in context. Hopefully, once it's in the game, and readable, the forum members will comment on contextual errors, and what the lines should say - Sword2012. 08 Apr 16-->
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_1">
		<text>Can I help you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_11">
		<text>That depends on what you're doing here. Or what you're looking for. Or maybe you've already found it? The Zone is full of surprises...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_111">
		<text>Sorry, I'm not at liberty to say</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_1111">
		<text>Well, I can see you're eager to get away. So did you find what you were looking for? I'm also looking for something</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_11111">
		<text>Well, if I had found anything, it'd be my business...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_11112">
		<text>Yes, I found the missing documents from X-18. The Barkeep promised to pay well for them</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_112">
		<text>Sorry, I didn't find anything</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_2">
		<text>I don't really know why I bothered coming here. I just want to get out...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_21">
		<text>And you're sure you didn't find anything of interest? I've heard that you can find documented evidence on experiments that were carried out here. And get paid handsomely for it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_211">
		<text>No, I didn't find anything</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_2111">
		<text>Are you sure? You're not hiding anything from me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_21111">
		<text>No</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_21112">
		<text>Why so many questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_21113">
		<text>Are you threatening me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_212">
		<text>Fuck whatever's in there! I barely made it out alive!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_2121">
		<text>Well, leave if you want. But I won't be far behind you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_25">
		<text>Listen, buddy, I'm a bounty hunter of the Zone. I've survived radiation, mutants, anomalies, and people constantly trying to kill me - and I always get who or what I'm looking for! I came for the documents here, and I'm not leaving without them. If you have them, then I advise you to hand them over, otherwise you'll stay in this hole forever! Am I making myself clear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_251">
		<text>Yes, very clear</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_2511">
		<text>If you're lying to me - you'll wish you hadn't. I'll ask you again - did you find any documents?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_2521">
		<text>That's good, so next time think carefully before answering. Now go. I can always find you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_253">
		<text>Our conversation's over. Just get out of my way</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_26">
		<text>I don't have any documents</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_271">
		<text>That's better. Now give me everything you found. All the documents. And if you try to hide anything, it'll be the last thing you do...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_51">
		<text>Wait, I'll tell you! I just want to get out of here. Yes, I found them. I'll share them with you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_511">
		<text>I've nothing to share</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_5111">
		<text>That's good... but don't play games with me, okay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_512">
		<text>Are you threatening me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_5121">
		<text>Hey! Calm down... You're the one holding the gun! No more questions. I'm just advising you to be careful, that's all</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_61">
		<text>I only want the documents. Tell me where they are, and I'll let you go. Do you understand me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_6111">
		<text>Come on, say something</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_6121">
		<text>Listen, buddy, stop messing me about and let's get this over with. I could kill you, but that wouldn't help either of us. I just want those documents. Then you're free to go. But I can't let you go until I have them...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_6131">
		<text>Listen, I really need these documents. Can we come to an agreement?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_8011">
		<text>There's nothing here, except fucking Burers. I wish I'd never come here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_8021">
		<text>Feel free to leave, Stalker. Go your own way</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_8031">
		<text>Look, I came here for those documents. If you found something, then tell me. Otherwise we're just going to carry on like this. If you didn't find them, then stop wasting my time!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_8041">
		<text>Look, just give me the papers, unless you want to stay here forever!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_9">
		<text>I'll think about it...</text>
	</string>
