<?xml version="1.0" encoding = "windows-1251"?>
<!-- TB3D 1.0.9.9.9.8, removed "string_table" - aleks1970 -->
<!-- MAJOR REWRITE - Translated and corrected by Steve90k for fluency and ease of reading. Edited and proofed by Sword2012 for clarity, brevity, and consistency. 17 Jan 16 -->
<!-- Added further explanations to two paragraphs - Sword2012 - 21 Mar 16 -->
<!-- Rewriting as commented below - Sword2012 - 18 Oct 16 and 12 Dec 16 -->
 <!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->

	<string id="oso_chernobyl_crush_0">
		<text>Was the explosion of '86 your work, too?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_chernobyl_crush_1">
		<text>Absolutely not! We had nothing to do with that! Most of us were only starting out in science back then. The Exclusion Zone was not even considered as an experimental test site until 1989...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_death_truck_0">
		<text>What are the 'Death Trucks'?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_death_truck_1">
		<text>They're the transport we use to send our marked agents into the Zone. Nobody dares come near them, and our agents can be dropped off discretely. Since the life expectency of a Stalker is relatively short, nobody recognises these agents, so they can infiltrate local Stalker communities with ease. Since they have no recollection of their previous life, they carry out our instructions without realizing it. Unfortunately, the Zone is very unstable, and at least half our agents die during their transportation...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_no_0">
		<text>This isn't right. Killing people to cover your mistakes! Taking over people's minds! I want nothing to do with this kind of deception!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_osoznanie_start_11">
		<text>Hello, Strelok. I see you have many questions. Go ahead and ask them, then we can decide where to go from here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_osoznanie_start_21">
		<text>The choice is yours, Strelok...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_stalker_0">
		<text>The tattoo 'S.T.A.L.K.E.R.' What does it mean?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_stalker_1">
		<text>S.T.A.L.K.E.R. is a coded acronym. We've spread disinformation that it stands for 'Scavenger. Trespasser. Adventurer. Loner. Killer. Explorer. Robber' to make it acceptable in the Zone. A mark of respect, if you will, considering that those who bear it have totally forgotten their background - so it helps avoid unnecessary attention from other Stalkers.\nIn reality, we use it to mark and identify our agents that we've programmed for certain missions. In order to recruit agents, we created a network of psi-fields on the way to the Zone's center. You know one of these areas by the name of the 'Brain Scorcher'. When a Stalker reaches the center of the Zone, he will inevitably be drawn to the powerful mind-altering anomaly known as the 'Wish Granter'. It is with this that we acquire control over the Stalker's consciousness, and programme him for a specific mission</text><!-- Added explanation of S.T.A.L.K.E.R. acronym - Sword2012 - 20 Mar 16 --><!-- Added explanation for the 'Wish Granter' - Sword2012 - 18 Oct 16 -->
	</string>
	<string id="oso_what_about_me_0">
		<text>What happened to me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_what_about_me_1">
		<text>I'm afraid you're just a bolt that fell out of the machine - one which did not come to our attention for a long time. From the moment the Zone was created many people, not just Stalkers, have tried to get to its center. We cannot let that happen because humanity is not yet ready for the truth. This is why we recruit lone Stalkers, by promising them the fulfillment of their deepest desires. Only the strongest and most resourceful make it through, which makes them perfect for our needs. Once recruited, they are programmed and sent out to protect the Zone's privacy. Guardians of the Zone, if you will... You are one of our agents, programmed to kill a man named Strelok and his group after they came too close to finding out things they shouldn't, and wanting to go public. Unfortunately, due to Strelok's security measures, an administrative error was made, we were unaware that we already had you, and you were sent out to kill yourself...</text><!-- Added Strelok's identity - Sword2012 - 20 Mar 16 -->
	</string>
	<string id="oso_what_is_the_zone_0">
		<text>What exactly is the Zone? How did it come about?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_what_is_the_zone_1">
		<text>What you see all around you is the result of our early intervention in the Earth's noosphere. We've learned that every nuclear release or test creates small cracks between dimensions, although they usually heal with time. Unfortunately, we had not allowed for this when we went exploring the noosphere, and our first incursions there turned multiple cracks into a sizeable fracture. The Zone is the visible manifestation of that fracture as our dimensions continue to bleed into others. But this is just a simple analogy - the underlying reality of the fissure we created is far beyond what you can imagine, or I can explain...</text><!-- Small rewrite - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->
	</string>
	<string id="oso_what_next_0">
		<text>So what next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_what_next_1">
		<text>That depends entirely on you. The fracture, the Zone, is growing, and we're desperately trying to limit it, but humanity seems to be intent on hindering our efforts to do so. Our resources are not limitless, and the volunteers connected to the C-Consciousness will eventually die. We need people like you to join us, so that we can restrict the Zone's growth and repair it, but if you decide otherwise... well, we cannot make a credible prognosis of the outcome...</text><!-- Small rewrite - Sword2012 - 18 Oct 16 -->
	</string>
	<string id="oso_who_are_you_0">
		<text>Who are you? All of you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_who_are_you_1">
		<text>We are the result of an experiment aimed at creating an advanced awareness called the 'C-Consciousness'. The minds of seven volunteers, all good people, were connected during the experiment, leading to the creation of the collective consciousness, or superconsciousness that we became. We immediately subordinated those conducting the experiment, and reassigned them to the tasks we needed fulfilled. According to our observations, our planet Earth is surrounded by an informational field called the 'noosphere', the total collective consciousness of all its cognitive inhabitants, living and deceased. This consciousness influences every individual, while each individual affects the collective. Few individuals are able to influence the noosphere significantly, but the C-Consciousness could. Our goal was to make small adjustments to the field, allowing us to remove negative thoughts like apathy, cruelty, selfishness, and other destructive factors from the planet's 'aura', and make people more positively aware of others. Unfortunately we made a serious mistake, which caused the phenomenon you know as the Zone. We've been trying to repair it ever since...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_why_chernobyl_0">
		<text>Why did you choose here, Chernobyl, of all places? That just feels wrong...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_why_chernobyl_1">
		<text>On the contrary, it was the ideal place. After the disaster of 1986 there were very few people left in the area, and we could work without fear of discovery or hindrance. In addition, there were many powerful antennae here, which are vital for our experiments in recalibrating the collective consciousness of mankind</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_yes_0">
		<text>I understand what you're doing, for the greater good of humanity. I'm honoured to accept your offer - to become a part of the C-Consciousness</text>
	</string>