	<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 -->
<!-- Translated and corrected by Steve90k for fluency and ease of reading. Edited and proofed by Sword2012 for clarity, brevity, and consistency. 22 Jan 16 -->
	 <string id="esc_direction_fire">
		 <text>Wait! Hold steady. We attack only on my command...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="esc_fanat_victory">
		 <text>We've won! Well done, brothers. Now loot the bodies, and restock your supplies.\nMarked One, come here, we need to have a word in private...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="esc_return_dv">
		 <text>Marked One! Glad to see you're alive! Have you come to see us? Drop by, and we'll chat. We have some private business to discuss...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="esc_tutorial_end">
		 <text>Excellent! The job is complete. You will always be welcome here, Marked One...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="esc_wolf_thanks">
		 <text>Marked One, now that the Trader's given you the all-clear, we can do business together. Come here, I'd like to talk with you...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="escape_fox_quest">
		 <text>Marked One! About Strelok. There's a Stalker named Fox who's just returned from a raid deep into the Zone. He's trapped by a pack of hungry dogs, and needs help urgently. He won't be able to hold out for long, and he may have useful information about Strelok. Please go and help him. I've given you his co-ordinates...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="escape_stalker_death">
		 <text>Fuck you, Marked One. I'm sorry, I know it's not your fault, but some innocent Rookies have just been slaughtered... Look, after you've been cleared by the Trader, come back and see me. We'll talk then...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="escape_stalker_helped">
		 <text>Good work, Marked One. If you continue like this, you'll make many friends here in the Zone. Come over here. Let's talk...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="escape_stalker_killed">
		 <text>Wow, you're quite an arrogant bastard, aren't you, Marked One? Anyhow, you've passed the Trader's test, so Wolf's interested in doing some business with you...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="info_esc_give_agroprom_task">
		 <text>The Military has dug up something interesting near the Scientific Research Institute at Agroprom. I want to find out what it is, and you probably should too. Find this information, and deliver it to the Barkeep at the 100 Rads. That's in Rostok, the old factory town in the north</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="tips_esc_trader_about_anomalies">
		 <text>There are bolts lying everywhere around this shithole, so use them to identify anomalies ahead of you. Believe me, this old Stalker trick has saved many lives...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="tips_esc_trader_about_pda">
		 <text>Open your PDA and press the 'Contacts' button. Anyone with a PDA within a 250 meter radius will show up on your mini-map.\nBe careful though, because most Bandits don't carry a PDA, in order to keep undetected.</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="tips_esc_trader_activate_map">
		 <text>'$$ACTION_MAP$$'</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="tips_esc_trader_activate_pda">
		 <text>'$$ACTION_ACTIVE_JOBS$$'</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="tips_esc_trader_how_to_talk">
		 <text>'$$ACTION_USE$$'</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="tips_esc_trader_quest_1">
		 <text>Find the artefact located on your map, and bring it to the Trader</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="tutorial_flash_anomaly_alarm">
		 <text>Marked One, be very careful out there. Next time it could be you...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="tutorial_trader_give_medikit">
		 <text>Go and give a first aid kit to this moron...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="tutorial_trader_look_vagon">
		 <text>Marked One! Forget the artefact - you can bring it to me later. Some fucking idiots opened fire on a helicopter! Get to the carriage in the middle of the road, and help my men! I've sent you the co-ordinates...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="tutorial_trader_search_corpses">
		 <text>Search every corpse thoroughly, regardless of its state. There may be something useful left on them...</text>
	 </string>
