<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 186char sms limit-->
<!-- Translated and corrected by Steve90k for fluency and ease of reading. Edited and proofed by Sword2012 for clarity, brevity, and consistency. 22 Jan 16 -->
	<string id="gar_actor_looser">
		<text>Well, you're a fucking wimp, aren't you, Marked One! You're of no bloody use whatsoever. You'll not be welcome here again. Just fuck off!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_actor_normal">
		<text>Not bad, Stalker. Shot a few mutants, did you? Covered your own ass, more like... No big deal. If you still want to go through, you'll still have to pay...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_actor_winner">
		<text>Excellent, Marked One, you really helped us tremendously. You've paid for your pass, forever! Please carry on to Rostock, with our compliments...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_direction_fire">
		<text>Allow them to get closer, so no one is left behind. I shoot first, then you follow me, okay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_warning">
		<text>Stalker! You are in Duty-controlled territory. Be aware that any act of aggression from you will be dealt with swiftly and severely...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_monster_rush">
		<text>Everyone! Come to the Duty outpost at the Garbage. There's a herd of mutants attacking us from the Dark Valley. Anyone who manages to take one down is guaranteed our thanks...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_warning">
		<text>Don't mess around here, Stalker. Cause any kind of ruckus, and Duty'll make sure you don't live to see another day. Don't say you've not been warned!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_victory">
		<text>Well done, men! We overcame them. Everyone regroup, then loot the corpses. You, Stalker - come here, and let's have a chat...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tips_gar_hellcar_alarm">
		<text>This is the commander of the Loner group! We've driven the Bandits out of the Carpark, but there'll be another wave of them soon. Please come and give us some backup. We need help! Please!</text>
	</string>
