<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 -->
<!-- Translated and corrected by Steve90k for fluency and ease of reading. Edited and proofed by Sword2012 for clarity, brevity, and consistency. 08 Oct 16 -->
	<string id="bar_arena_actor_afraid">
		<text>The fight has been cancelled. Our challenger was too scared to enter the ring...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_10">
		<text>10 seconds so far!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_20">
		<text>20 seconds so far!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_30">
		<text>30 seconds!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_40">
		<text>40 seconds!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_50">
		<text>50 seconds!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_60">
		<text>One minute!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_70">
		<text>One minute and ten seconds!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_80">
		<text>One minute, twenty seconds!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_90">
		<text>One and a half minutes!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_begin">
		<text>The fight has begun!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_bloodsucker">
		<text>Attention! Attention! A new fight will soon start! At the left end of the arena - an invisible, ravenous Bloodsucker! And at the right end of the Arena... I don't believe this! Is it a man? Yes, it's the Stalker known as Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_burer">
		<text>Attention! Attention! A new fight will soon start! At the left end of the arena - he can bend the elements! He can overpower your mind! It's - a burer! And at the right end of the Arena - the local hero whose search may end here tonight - Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_dead">
		<text>So! Our challenger has lost to his opponent within the time limit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_lose">
		<text>So! Our challenger has killed his opponent, but exceeded the allotted time, and so forfeits the match!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_pseudodog">
		<text>Attention! Attention! A new fight will soon start! At the left end of the arena - a white, furry, but extremely vicious pseudodog! And at the right end of the Arena - he comes from nowhere - he could end up as a dog's dinner. It's Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_savage">
		<text>Attention! Attention! A new fight will soon start! At the left end of the arena - you know you love to hate it! And it hates you! It's the Animal! And at the right end of the Arena - still alive - Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_snork">
		<text>Attention! Attention! A new fight will soon start! At the left end of the arena - an expert in unarmed combat, martial arts, and eutrophy - a snork! And at the right end of the Arena - the man without a past - without even a name - the fighter known as - Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_timeout">
		<text>Time's up! Our challenger has lost the match to his opponent, but still fights for his life!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_victory">
		<text>So! Our challenger has bested his opponent within the time limit. He's won!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_attack">
		<text>As you wish...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_attract_actor">
		<text>Stalker! Friend! I beg you, please don't leave. Help us! Anarchists have brought down our protection detail, and are trying to kill us. We have so few armed, but many wounded. Please help us!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_heli_down">
		<text>Ha! There goes your chopper! You're next, you amoral government robotniks!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_start_heli">
		<text>Well, Wolfhound, you really have got yourself into a mess. That's a military helicopter up there. And they've spotted you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_escape">
		<text>The professor's run away! Everyone, after Kruglov! He can't have got far!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_hit">
		<text>Marked One! Help me! I'm hit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_spam_1">
		<text>You've always been a scumbag, Wolfhound. Even at school, everyone knew you as a bastard!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_spam_2">
		<text>I'd rather destroy this data before I give it to you. At least my work will die with me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_spam_3">
		<text>Unless you want to be the one responsible for destroying years of research - stay clear!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_spam_4">
		<text>Wolfhound! Withdraw your dogs while you still have a chance!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_attack">
		<text>No more talk. It's time for action...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_attack_attract_actor">
		<text>This is our job. Ridding the world of governmental lab rats...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_attack_spy">
		<text>Marked One. You'll pay for this...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_chase">
		<text>They're still following us! Marked One, stop them!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_spam_1">
		<text>To me, you're nothing more than a scientific prick. Give me those results. Now. Or you'll leave here in one of your test sample bags...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_spam_2">
		<text>Kruglov, I don't know biochemistry, like you, but I do know 'batshit crazy'. Do you want to find out, or are you gonna give me that data?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_spam_3">
		<text>Kruglov, you're supposed to be a smart guy. It's very simple. You give me the drive, and I'll leave you and your friends undamaged</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_spam_4">
		<text>Kruglov, don't you understand? We've brought down your fucking helicopter. There's nobody left to protect you. All we want is that flash drive in your pocket. Nothing else. Just hand it over, and you can all leave. You're of no other interest to us. Otherwise, we kill you and take the drive anyway. I trust it's impervious to water, and other fluids...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_psih_come">
		<text>Come here, quickly! My men have caught the mad stalker near Radar. We're about to interrogate him...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_dolg_1_hit">
		<text>Marked One, are you crazy? Stop shooting, now! This is an order!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_dolg_2_hit">
		<text>Marked One, stop shooting immediately! Fire one more shot, and you're dead!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_dolg_3_hit">
		<text>Marked One. For infringement of the code of Duty, you are now outside of our protection. You are now our enemy...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_dolg_kill">
		<text>Marked One, you have disobeyed our direct order! You're a dead man! Duty does not tolerate defiance!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_nodolg_1_hit">
		<text>Stop shooting! You're in Duty-protected territory! Violation of any kind will be punished!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_nodolg_2_hit">
		<text>Attention, everyone! For infringement of the law, the wilful use of weapons within Duty territory, this Marked One is hereby declared a criminal outlaw...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_nodolg_kill">
		<text>Attention! The murderer has been spotted inside Duty territory! Prevent him from escaping! Kill him!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rostok_kruglov_spam_1">
		<text>Stalker, help! We were attacked by mercenaries, and we've lost half our men. Please help us. We'll find a way of helping you in return...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rostok_kruglov_spam_2">
		<text>Please help us make our way through an ambush, near the factory, I've sent you our co-ordinates. Be careful, friend. Wolfhound is here with his mercs, near the helicopter...</text>
	</string>