<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 Trans 100%, Literal editing 0%, The Doctor, something -->
<!-- ATP MISSIONS -->
<!-- MEETING WHALE -->
<!-- Names changed as commented below. 9 lines edited to make 'accumulators ' into 'accumulator cells' - Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16 -->
<!-- Changed all 'Mother's Beads' to 'Glassbeads' - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->
<string_table>
	<string id="atp_vstrecha_0">
		<text>That was a close call, you mind telling me what's going on here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_vstrecha_1">
		<text>My name is Keith. I'm a scout for Kalinin. Who might you be?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_vstrecha_2">
		<text>That's not important. Who is this Kalinin anyway?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_vstrecha_3">
		<text>Kalinin was the first stalker to visit this part of the Zone. For the longest time, we were the only ones to know about this place at all. Once people found a way to get here though, that all changed, and for the worse. Bandits moved into the area soon thereafter, and wiped out many of our people. The survivors of that raid now live in the Camp, which is where I am headed now. You should go there too, before the Bandits catch wind that you are here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_vstrecha_4">
		<text>I think I should meet Kalinin, and find out more about this place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_vstrecha_5">
		<text>Perhaps you can do me a favor then, I need someone to drive that van over there to the Camp. It belonged to the last person that wandered into this area. They wound up getting killed and eaten by one of those Boars you saw. One of the big grey bastards. Very dangerous. It should work fine, still a little gas in the tank. What do you say, can you help me out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_vstrecha_6">
		<text>I'll have a look at the Van, If I can't get it running then I'll make it to the camp on foot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_vstrecha_7">
		<text>Thanks for the information, I'll probably see you over at the Camp</text>
	</string>
	<!-- KALININ MISSIONS -->
	<string id="kalinin_zadan_vzyt_0">
		<text>I've heard that you are the one that discovered this place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_zadan_vzyt_1">
		<text>That would be correct. I came here a long time ago to get away from the troubles, and complications that pollute the rest of the Zone. Unfortunately, they have managed to find me here as well. Those Bandit bastards seem to come out of the woodwork, and make life a living Hell for everyone they encounter! And, who might you be? Why are you here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_zadan_vzyt_2">
		<text>It's alright, those Bandits are no friends of mine either, bloodsucker crap the lot!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_zadan_vzyt_3">
		<text>I'm glad to hear that! Listen up, we're in trouble here. The Bandits have taken control over our old encampment in the center of this territory. They regularly stage attacks on us from there. They are trying to wipe us out completely so that they will have absolute, and total control over this area. We need some help, and we need it now!! My scout Keith tells me that they are advancing on us as we speak! We can talk more later, but for now, help us, please?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_zadan_vzyt_4">
		<text>What exactly is our defensive situation here?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_zadan_vzyt_5">
		<text>YOUR THE MAN!!! Alright, they will attack us in two waves, advancing from the center. We need to fend off both of these attacks, and then you must infiltrate their base. That's their stronghold. They are led by a man named Shynra, a real piece of work. A sadist, they say he likes to torture animals and such. I want you to take him, and the rest of his sordid kind out of the picture. Kill everyone. All of them. Return to me when the job is done</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_zadan_vzyt_6">
		<text>And such?!!! Don't wanna know! The exterminator at your service! Wait here until I return</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_zadan_vzyt_7">
		<text>This is a bit too extreme for me right now, Sorry, maybe later, see ya</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_otvet_0">
		<text>Well, Shynra is toast along with all his men, tisk, tisk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_otvet_1">
		<text>Marked One, you're one tough son of a psuedodog! You have truly done the World a favor!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_otvet_2">
		<text>It would not be wise to move back into the Carpark tho. There will most likely be more Bandits on their way here, its like rabbits! They had the means to call for reinforcements!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_otvet_3">
		<text>Thank you for the information. As payment, all I can give you is information on a transition from the Dark Valley to the Forgotten Forest. Nobody else besides me knows about it. Take this Serum as well, it's great for sores and hang-overs. Listen, Marked One I have another job for you as well</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gonets_spasti_0">
		<text>Oh, and what might that be?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gonets_spasti_1">
		<text>I'm expecting a Courier that is carrying some very important information. I need you to meet up with him, and get that information from him. Then I want you to escort him back to camp safely, as there are a lot of mutants in this territory. He will be coming in via the same road you came in on, but from the opposite end. Here, I'll send the coordinates to your PDA. Oh, and one more thing, he will be dressed as a Rookie</text>
	</string>
	<!-- KALININ MISSION (Messenger) -->
	<string id="gonets_talk_0">
		<text>You must be the Courier that Kalinin spoke of</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gonets_talk_1">
		<text>That would be me, yes. I've never been to this part of the Zone before, really sucks!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gonets_talk_2">
		<text>Seen worse!, ever seen Recife?, no, ah, never mind! Anyway, if you've never been here before, how did you expect to find Kalinin's camp?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gonets_talk_3">
		<text>Kalinin sends a homing signal to my PDA. I just follow that all the way to the camp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gonets_talk_4">
		<text>Yeh right!, take a bee-line right to him eh? Good thing I've been sent here to meet up with you before you end up feeding the wildlife! I've been sent to collect the Flash-Drive and escort you to the camp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gonets_talk_5">
		<text>Place that nice? Well ok, I just received same message from Kalinin. I also have been instructed to give you an artefact once we reach the camp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gonets_talk_6">
		<text>Sounds good, now tho we've gotta get moving, not a good place for socials!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gonets_talk_7">
		<text>Sorry man, but you're on your own from here, later dude</text>
	</string>
	<!-- KALININ MISSION (Messenger) complete -->
	<string id="gonets_vse_ok_0">
		<text>Here's your Flash-Drive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gonets_vse_ok_1">
		<text>This is Excellent!! It contains the specific radio frequencies that the Bandits use to communicate throughout the Zone. Now I will know their every move before it even happens! This could be our chance to win back that which is rightfully ours! Thank you!! Here, take this RPG as payment for your efforts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gonets_vse_ok_2">
		<text>I can see myself putting this to good use</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gonets_vse_ok_3">
		<text>Stay in touch! We will likely need your help again soon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_btr_vzyt_0">
		<text>That Flash-Card I brought you, were there by any chance Military radio frequencies on it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_btr_vzyt_1">
		<text>Well, let's see here, yes, I've gotten something. It's picking something up now, DAMN!! The Army is planning an excursion into this area, They are massing their troops as we speak!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_btr_vzyt_2">
		<text>When will they get here!!?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_btr_vzyt_3">
		<text>They are awaiting the order to advance. It could happen at any time. We will not survive a Military attack, and you know it!! That RPG I gave you should take care of the armor, but we need you to get us a special Sniper Rifle, an Iglomet, that will take care of the Infantry!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_btr_vzyt_4">
		<text>Damn! Always something! Stalker get THIS, Marked One get THAT, WHEN IS IT EVER GOING TO END?!!!! HUH? Oh sorry, bad day! Okay, I will find the 'Iglomet', and return as soon as I can</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_btr_vzyt_5">
		<text>This isn't my fight! Best of luck to you, and your men tho, really</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_btr_unichtoz_0">
		<text>I found the Iglomet, here it is, pretty cool!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_btr_unichtoz_1">
		<text>Perfect!! Here's what we'll do, you take out the armor, and their Commander with the RPG. We'll cover you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_btr_unichtoz_2">
		<text>Figures! Where are they now?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_btr_unichtoz_3">
		<text>I'm waiting for word from my Scouts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="btr_ataka_0">
		<text>Have they arrived or are they simply passing us by?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="btr_ataka_1">
		<text>My scouts have reported two Troop Carriers and regular infantry are arriving now. There is a third armored Car on the way. You need to take out those Troop Carriers!!! Go now, HURRY!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_btr_nagrada_0">
		<text>It was a brutal, but necessary battle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_btr_nagrada_1">
		<text>Yes, let's hope that they leave us alone now</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_btr_nagrada_2">
		<text>I didn't expect this place to be such a bloody War-Zone!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalinin_btr_nagrada_3">
		<text>Here, take this. It comes from the heart</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_dialog_0">
		<text>Judging by your appearance you'r a former miner</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_dialog_1">
		<text>Yes I am, you scared me. I thought it was those fanatics coming for me. How can you tell?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_dialog_2">
		<text>The odor, but thats not important. You've been a bandit?, and now the monolith, what kind of filth does that?!?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_dialog_3">
		<text>My hands are most certainly dirty. Before the failure in Chernobyl, I was a bandit with allegiance to Shahry. There was a collapse in the cave one month ago that opened a tunnel. I went through the tunnel thinking I could join up with Bandits but never imagined I would find a base of Monolithians! The Miner warned me about going into the tunnel but I didnt listen. They have decided to turn me into a believer. There was another Stalker also held prisoner with me but he escaped while the Monolithians meditated. I was too weak to go with him. Now they have strengthened the gaurd so nobody can run away anymore</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_dialog_4">
		<text>The Miner has sent me to find you and bring you back</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_dialog_5">
		<text>Thank you, I will have a little rest and then I will return on my own. The transition to get out is at the bottom level, a short ways into another cave. It is full of starving rats and danger. Beware of the leader of the Monolithians, he is is immortal. Some kind of mutant zombie bullshit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_dialog_6">
		<text>Immortal Zombie Monolith! What the hell next? Tell the Miner what's going on here and I will see the both of you later</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_dialog1_0">
		<text>Immortal Zombie Monolith! What the hell next? Are you able to get out on your own? look like crap to me! I AM supposed to escort you back</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_dialog1_1">
		<text>It's ok, really. I just need a little rest, my head is dizzy. I will return to the Miner soon. Thanks for the help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_plennik_nayti_0">
		<text>What has happened? You look so sad?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_plennik_nayti_1">
		<text>Yes I am very troubled. I hear you are a very experienced stalker in the Zone, some kind of legend it seems</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_plennik_nayti_2">
		<text>Legend of the 'Marked one', not bad, sorta like it! So, whats keeping you up at night these days?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_plennik_nayti_3">
		<text>Approximately one year ago there was a collapse in the cave. On the bottom level there is a steep wall that can be easily climbed tho hard to see. This leads to a small new tunnel opened up by the collapse. This tunnel leads to a base of fanatics. Recently one of my men went through this tunnel, after argueing with everyone here, and saying he was leaving to become a bandit. I dont know why he was acting so stupid, but he left through the new transition that has opened down there. I Sent some men to look for him but they came back with more bad news, he is now being held prisoner by the fanatics</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_plennik_nayti_4">
		<text>Monolithians, most likely. This is the first Ive heard about an underground base</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_plennik_nayti_5">
		<text>He is being held in the great chamber of the Labyrinth. According to a stalker who recently escaped from there, the Sentry carries a codebook for the cell door. If you are able to obtain it, dont lose this notebook. The prisoner knows where the exit is. Ive been told the Monolith leader in the Labyrinth is immortal, so avoid him. At the bottom of the great hall is another cave that I've been told is full of artefacts and of course danger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_plennik_nayti_6">
		<text>I will try. I will not forget about the notebook, and will try not to lose it. If I find him, I will set him free</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_plennik_nayti_7">
		<text>Thats a big no Miner. I am still young, I want to live</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_plennik_prines_0">
		<text>Your man has been set free, he promised to come after me. He gave me the info on how to find the exit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_plennik_prines_1">
		<text>Thank you Marked One. Here take this recipe to make an artefact. By the way the recipe is from that man you rescued</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_plennik_prines_2">
		<text>Thanks. And how useful was the disk?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_plennik_prines_3">
		<text>Pogodi. My person will return, to find out truth, and you I will tell...\nYes the notebook which you have brought, I esteem, the blessing of small lamps now. You can learn from it yourself, but I do not think that while it will tell much, goodness knows. And, here the 'prodigal son' has returned!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fima_mulo_nayti_0">
		<text>Greetings, Im glad you made it back alive. I want to ask you in detail about the person who was in captivity with you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fima_mulo_nayti_1">
		<text>There's little that I can tell. I can say only that he was an unusual stalker with a beard, and a speech problem. I dont know why, maybe he had a lisp, burrs, or missing teeth</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fima_mulo_nayti_2">
		<text>Burrs? And what was he doing in the Labyrinth?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fima_mulo_nayti_3">
		<text>I dont know exactly, but it was obvious that he had been there before. Possibly, searching for something. Very vaguely I remember, he talked about a cassette and a safe. On the cassette is the code for the bottom door of the bunker of Fanatics, and this code he obviously knew. Where this cassette with the code is now is not known. Where the safe he searched for is and whats in it, no clue. But I know he came planned to leave the Labyrinth to Yantar, he said it was closer to his dealer on Agroprom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fima_mulo_nayti_4">
		<text>From the Labyrinth there is an exit to Yantar?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fima_mulo_nayti_5">
		<text>Yes, I know the coordinates, here. There is another transition, but before I give you the coordinates you need to bring me some things. If you want the transition then bring me ten scientific first-aid sets, ten bandages, a Soul and two bars of soap. I have not washed for a long time. The soap is located in one of the cellars in a house in the rookie village in Cordon. I know because I stayed in this village before the accident at Chernobyl. Also, you need to go to the Agropom and talk to the dealer and see what he knows of my companion in captivity</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fima_mulo_nayti_6">
		<text>I will bring all you asked for. Transitions never come easy, and thanks for the info</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fima_mulo_nayti_7">
		<text>No way Fima! you want soap??? Here the destiny of mankind hangs in the balance and you want soap! You ARE a bit ripe tho!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fima_mulo_prines_0">
		<text>Ive brought everything that you asked for. Judging by all the boar meat on the table you won't starve here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fima_mulo_prines_1">
		<text>The Miner has been generous to me with his food and medicine. Here as promised, I will tell you where the transition is. It is at the top level of the Labyrinth, travel through the great room, past the big anomaly and into the hall that leads to mid-level and you will find the transition to not yet Reconnoitered Earth. But there is one discrepancy, I cannot give the coordinates to you, the Miner asked me not to speak yet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fima_mulo_prines_2">
		<text>Wait a minute! I save your butt, then bring you all these medkits, bandages, an artefact, and not to mention Soap!! and this is how you show gratitude!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fima_mulo_prines_3">
		<text>Dont get angry, the Miner said that it was for your own good. In exploration we are going to do, we are going on an already proven and tested path. In the meantime, here's a recipe. Throw into a Tornado: one sausage and one rudiment of the sternum of a female zombie. This rudiment increases in size, and accordingly is much more valuable to merchants. But, obviously, this is not the whole recipe. The rest of it I dont know. But don't try this transmutation with the auxiliary device, this recipe is an exception and transmutation can only be done by hand. Yes, and the probability of a successful outcome is rather small</text>
	</string>
	<string id="adr_shkatulka_dost_0">
		<text>Adrenalin, I wanted to ask you something. Did a man with a beard and a speech problem come here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="adr_shkatulka_dost_1">
		<text>I deal with lots of people, but such a person I don't remember. There was a rookie, but without a beard and without a speech problem. Why I mention this, his request was strange</text>
	</string>
	<string id="adr_shkatulka_dost_2">
		<text>Oh. What did he ask for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="adr_shkatulka_dost_3">
		<text>Spoke about an underground bunker, which was the first time I had heard of the place. He asked me to bring a safe and a cassette out of there, promised to pay well. I didnt really believe him. After all, where does a rookie get information like that? He told me about one of the transitions into this bunker from Yantar. He also told me where in the bunker the cassette and safe lie. More shortly, I refused this dark business. Why, what do you care?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="adr_shkatulka_dost_4">
		<text>I too have heard about this bunker. In fact I've not only heard about it, I've been there. I'm interested in finding this cassette, will you share your information with me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="adr_shkatulka_dost_5">
		<text>I will share the information with you if you agree to bring me the cassette and the safe. That rookie, or whoever he was, might come back. Here's what I know:\nthe cassette lies on the second level of this cave or labyrinth, and to get on this level is only possible from somewhere else in the labyrinth which is located at the lower-most level, a teleport. Still I know at the bottom of the Labyrinth, it's possible to get through a narrow tunnel. And the safe, I do not know. Yes here, take the transition coordinates to this Labyrinth from Yantar teleport. It's on your map. A reward for this info I don't ask, you will bring the cassette and the safe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="adr_shkatulka_dost_6">
		<text>Alright, I will bring them and we will share info. For the new transition, thanks</text>
	</string>
	<string id="adr_shkatulka_dost_7">
		<text>No thanks, I can't be bothered with vaults</text>
	</string>
	<string id="adr_shkatulka_prines_0">
		<text>Well, did that rookie come back?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="adr_shkatulka_prines_1">
		<text>Nope. Have you brought the safe and cassette?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="adr_shkatulka_prines_2">
		<text>Here's the cassette, but the safe was not found. I Will go to the the Miner and see if he knows something. I will keep you informed of any breakthroughs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="adr_shkatulka_prines_3">
		<text>Good luck, Marked One</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tretiy_kod_dost_0">
		<text>Hello Miner, have you been able to learn anything?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tretiy_kod_dost_1">
		<text>Yes, Ive been able to de-cipher some of this scribbling</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tretiy_kod_dost_2">
		<text>I was in the Labyrinth, and found the cassette Fima Coal was talking about. There were two codes for bunker doors, but I could only open one. I couldn't find the safe</text>	<!-- Changed 'Fima' to 'Fima Coal'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="tretiy_kod_dost_3">
		<text>Yes, there are three doors, one, an entrance at the bottom level, second, between the top and bottom bunker floors, third, an exit from the top floor of the bunker. The code to one of the doors is only kept by a Fanatic who goes by the nickname of The Monolith Shade. I have been told that he is immortal!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tretiy_kod_dost_4">
		<text>Looks like it's impossible to get that safe!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tretiy_kod_dost_5">
		<text>There is one option, though you're probably not going to like the sound of it. You can join the Monolith and then you can find out the code. I Heard that one dealer in the Cordon can take care of such business. But remember, when in the Monolith rank here you will be declared an enemy. You will receive the first bullet from me more than likely! And Fanatic, judging by records, collects artefacts. Bring him a Plasma Caterpillar and the Rattle (I have given the recipe to you). You will find the safe, bring it here, but not until you have divorced yourself from those Monolith scum! I Hope you've still got those codes! Don't you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tretiy_kod_dost_6">
		<text>Lets see, Ummm, Yeah, Join the fanatics, that means I will be enemies with EVERYONE! But I must speak with This Monolith, Shades. So I must go to Sidorovich and get help with fixing this</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tretiy_kod_dost_7">
		<text>I would kill myself before joining the Monolith!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tretiy_kod_nayden_0">
		<text>I've seen enough Horror films! I got the safe, sure was glad to see it was a small!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tretiy_kod_nayden_1">
		<text>Im glad your alive and no longer a Fanatic!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tretiy_kod_nayden_2">
		<text>Yes, what now? The safe looks strong and there's no code to open it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tretiy_kod_nayden_3">
		<text>Leave it here with me and finish your investigation. I know you're look for the killer of a stalker. Finish that business, then return here and we will work on opening the safe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_amulet_vzyt_0">
		<text>Sidorovich, I need to talk to you about something</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_amulet_vzyt_1">
		<text>Well hello there! What's the matter? You look awfull!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_amulet_vzyt_2">
		<text>I have a strange request. I need to infiltrate the Monolith Faction!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_amulet_vzyt_3">
		<text>I don't have contacts within the Monolith, so I don't think I can help you there. There is, however, another way. An Amulet, only Leaders within their faction are given one of these! Don't ask how I got hold of it, or where it came from. Fact is, it might be the only way you can gain entry into their ranks. I can let you use it, but only if you agree to do a small job for me first. Well, what do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_amulet_vzyt_4">
		<text>What sort of job are we talking about here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_amulet_vzyt_5">
		<text>Listen here, Marked One. Before you put on this Amulet, keep in mind that ANYONE and EVERYONE will be your sworn enemy. You cannot remove the Amulet once you have put it on. Only I can remove it for you, which is where my fee comes into to play!! These Monolith freaks might be fanatics and all, but they are well equipped. Bring me two of thier boxed Repair Kits, and I will remove the Amulet for you. Do we have a deal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_amulet_vzyt_6">
		<text>I will bring these boxes to you, black hearted bastard, now give me the Amulet!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_amulet_vzyt_7">
		<text>I don't think I'm ready for this, I'm sorta a nice guy really, just misunderstood, thats all, really</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_amulet_prines_0">
		<text>Here are the boxed Repair Kits you asked for, now help me remove this Amulet, will you? I'm starting to want to read Nostradamus, strange...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_amulet_prines_1">
		<text>So tell me what it was like, the Monolith, what is their secret? What the hell do they want? why have they come here to this God Forsaken place?! Spill it man!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_amulet_prines_2">
		<text>Take the Amulet off me Sid!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_amulet_prines_3">
		<text>Ok, relax, I'm only curious! Give me the Repair Kits, and I'll relieve you of the Amulet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ten_monolita_talk_0">
		<text>Greetings, Im a newcomer here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ten_monolita_talk_1">
		<text>Eee??</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ten_monolita_talk_2">
		<text>What the hell? Im a newcomer can you understand? I need the code to a door in the top part of the bunker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ten_monolita_talk_3">
		<text>Eeeee??????!!!!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ten_monolita_talk_4">
		<text>O, K, look, read my lips, I-NEED-THE-CODE. I have brought gifts to you. Two rare artefacts, a Plasma Caterpillar and a Rattle! Look, see, WHAT-CLASS!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ten_monolita_talk_5">
		<text>Eeee, About!!!! Code is 4241, You can get gear there but find somewhere else to sleep. Hail the force of the Monolith!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ten_monolita_talk_6">
		<text>Well and beautiful! Epsel-mopsel, yada-yada... And if the safe is not there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_land_perehod_talk_0">
		<text>Greetings, you said to come back when I finish the investigation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_land_perehod_talk_1">
		<text>Greetings. Well, have you found out what happened to your friend?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_land_perehod_talk_2">
		<text>My friend is dead, and the people who killed him have been found and dealt with. What news do you have?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_land_perehod_talk_3">
		<text>I have two bits of news: the first, the safe I have not opened, too difficult of a lock. It requires an electronic key. Autogenous cutting! Didnt try, if in the safe there is something in the form of documents, they'll burn! But there is also better news! My men investigated the transition, about which Fima Coal spoke. On investigation of the not yet Reconnoitered Earth territory, they found a specialist who can open the safe. When you arrive there it will be necessary to find an Infirmary or something similar to a clinic</text>	<!-- Changed 'Fima' to 'Fima Coal'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="shax_land_perehod_talk_4">
		<text>And whats in this territory, anything exciting?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_land_perehod_talk_5">
		<text>Its a Wood. I've known it since childhood, there I had many friends. When hunting there I would stay at a good friends hut. The Old Man we all called him. When you see him transfer my greetings. Take away the safe and try your luck on not yet Reconnoitered Earth. in the Labyrinth's top level. I have noted the transition in your PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_land_perehod_talk_6">
		<text>Thanks. I will go to this not yet Reconnoitered Earth and find the infirmary. I will see you again Miner</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zvezdochet_aver_talk_0">
		<text>Hello! I didn't expect to run into you, the rain seems endless here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zvezdochet_aver_talk_1">
		<text>Greetings. I sometimes travel this path. I see you have discovered it. Yes, it gets a little wet here. Well, more truly, like living in a bog, or maybe Seatle, or so I've heard. And what are you here for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zvezdochet_aver_talk_2">
		<text>look, I drug this safe here and have been told that somewhere in this soggy territory there is an Infirmary. And its there that I've been told I can find an expert on locks. Can you just direct me to the Infirmary, PLEASE!?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zvezdochet_aver_talk_3">
		<text>Whats in the safe? Listen, do you want to sell it to me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zvezdochet_aver_talk_4">
		<text>I dont know whats in it, but I will find out. What good is this safe to you anyway? Also where is this Infirmary?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zvezdochet_aver_talk_5">
		<text>All you will learn in time, but not now. The Infirmary, take a left and go past a ravine and a hill. There you will see a camp, talk to the Commander and he'll tell you more. Look, avoid using the paths, the Avengers are notorious for ambushing travellers on them. Towards the center, on a hill, is a group of peaceful hunters. I've got to go, need to get to the dump</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zvezdochet_aver_talk_6">
		<text>Well thanks, I will go and find this camp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otshelnik_yzik_nayti_0">
		<text>Hello, nice camp you have here. What's going on with the helicopter, is there going to be an attack?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otshelnik_yzik_nayti_1">
		<text>Greetings!, Hey, check this out, a comedian stalker! Well, you just don't worry about that helicopter. We have a mutual understanding with the military. Recently we rescued a Major from the snipers. He made an agreement with us, now we get to use his helicopter once a month to bring in supplies from outside the zone. The military gets a payoff, so everybody's happy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otshelnik_yzik_nayti_2">
		<text>Let me get this clear. This helicopter could take me out of the zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otshelnik_yzik_nayti_3">
		<text>The chopper only flies to the perimeter, not any further. There, my people pick up our supplies, and arrange the sale of our artefacts for TEN TIMES what the local traders pay. We have a weapons shipment coming in, but there's been a problem. One of the crates has fallen out of the chopper. If you find it I will give you one of the weapons</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otshelnik_yzik_nayti_4">
		<text>So, now I'm dragging a stupid crate around! Well, crap! Look this territory is new to me, I wanted to ask if you have an Infirmary? And is it nearby?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otshelnik_yzik_nayti_5">
		<text>So we have an agreement then? Walk towards the edge of the clearing and meet the helicopter, my men will brief you. The Infirmary is right next to our camp. As you leave this hut, go at once to the left and you will find a cave. There, the Gynecologist. He treats our sick brothers, but doesnt have the right medicines. He needs medical supplies delivered. But first meet with my men and locate my missing crate</text>	<!-- Changed 'Shura' to 'Gynecologist '- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="otshelnik_yzik_nayti_6">
		<text>Ok, Ok, and thanks for the information</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otshelnik_yzik_nayti_7">
		<text>Listen, I have changed my mind. You have the people to search for it yourself</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otshelnik_yzik_prines_0">
		<text>Heres your crate, it fell into a bog, surprise, surprise! It's wet but nothing's broken</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otshelnik_yzik_prines_1">
		<text>For the box, thanks. Take this weapon and some cartridges. Take care in your travels here, snipers are everywhere. What purpose of these ambushes are, I don't know. They have a camp somewhere in this region</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otshelnik_yzik_prines_2">
		<text>Thanks for the info and the weapon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otshelnik_yzik_prines_3">
		<text>By the way, I buy artefacts. Truth though, I dont pay much. Come back and chat sometime, I might have a job for you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="master_aver_talk_0">
		<text>Hello! Tell me, how it's possible to drop a box from a chopper anyway?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="master_aver_talk_1">
		<text>Greetings, we are lucky to be alive. Did you see how that pilot was flying?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="master_aver_talk_2">
		<text>Yes, looked like a Kamikaze was in control</text>
	</string>
	<string id="master_aver_talk_3">
		<text>The pilot was drinking vodka while we were loading up the chopper at the perimeter, He was flying crazy and it made me sick to my stomach! I opened the hatch to vomit and that's when he made a sharp twisting turn causing the crate to fall out</text>
	</string>
	<string id="master_aver_talk_4">
		<text>Hmmm, And the crate, fell where?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="master_aver_talk_5">
		<text>It landed in a small bog. The path from our camp leads in that direction</text>
	</string>
	<string id="master_aver_talk_6">
		<text>Its good that it fell in this area and not over in Chernobyl somewhere!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starik_aver_talk_0">
		<text>Hello, is this the infirmary? Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starik_aver_talk_1">
		<text>Hello, they call me the Old Man. I have lived in this wood for a long time. Yes, the Infirmary is in this cave. With that swine, Chimera! Terrorizing this wood, we have to be on guard at all times. Thanks to the Gynecologist our wounded can get some basic treatment. But he needs better medicines to treat some of the patients</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starik_aver_talk_2">
		<text>The camp leader had asked me to transfer a parcel to the Physician, and I have come looking for help also. Oh, almost forgot! Greetings to you from the Miner. He said that he knew you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starik_aver_talk_3">
		<text>The Miner? Ah, I remember. So he lives? Too many years have passed. And what is it you need help with?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starik_aver_talk_4">
		<text>I have been told that among the patients is an expert who can open this safe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starik_aver_talk_5">
		<text>Well, there is one such expert, though he is a bit unusual</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starik_aver_talk_6">
		<text>Thanks for the info</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_aver_talk_0">
		<text>What happened to you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_aver_talk_1">
		<text>Hello stranger, this is what happenes when you get too much PSI exposure. But strangly my mind is intact, but I became a walking corpse, even the psuedodogs dont want to eat me. I got caught in a blowout and when I regained consciousness and was surrounded by Monolithians. They accepted me as one of theirs! I escaped from them as soon as possible and found my way to The Doctor. He advised me to come here and to travel at night so no Stalkers mistook me for a zombie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_aver_talk_2">
		<text>How is this possible? However, I did see a Monolithian who looked similar to you. However, he became immortal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_aver_talk_3">
		<text>I am not immortal, but I did aquire abilities which are not ordinary. Telepathy, I sometimes have visions of other people's secrets</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_aver_talk_4">
		<text>Do you think you will recover? Ive never seen anything like this before</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_aver_talk_5">
		<text>I have hope that a cure can be found. In the Zone everything is possible. I am safe here, but outside I would be hunted down like a mutant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_aver_talk_6">
		<text>Well, good luck with your treatment. Perhaps we will be able to help each other</text>
	</string>
	<string id="golograma_aver_talk_0">
		<text>Greetings. Its quite an odd gathering here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="golograma_aver_talk_1">
		<text>Greetings, Im Vitja, here they call me the Hologram. I am a former Ecologist, but I was not always this strange looking</text>
	</string>
	<string id="golograma_aver_talk_2">
		<text>What anomaly did this to you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="golograma_aver_talk_3">
		<text>Not an anomaly. It happened in one of the laboratories, its still active as far as I know and a place you should explore. I was wroking with a companion on an experiment for an influential client. We were extracting a special chemical compound from the artefact Gold Chunk. After one of the experiments we had an accident. The contents of a tub of Reagent splashed directly onto us. My companion was killed but my protective suit saved my life. But as a result of the accident I became sorta translucent</text>
	</string>
	<string id="golograma_aver_talk_4">
		<text>What happened next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="golograma_aver_talk_5">
		<text>I was thrown out of the laboratory. Discarded like a piece of garbage, they did nothing to help me. Close to this Infirmary I discovered snipers similar to me in appearance. But it seems the Hologram affect for them is changeable, they can switch it on and off at will. For me this is a permanent condition. Someone has completed our experiment and found the formula for the cloaking effect. Perhaps I could make a cure, I can make any medicine if I have the right components</text>
	</string>
	<string id="golograma_aver_talk_6">
		<text>Well, I hope you can find a cure. If I can help you solve this problem, let me know</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jora_aver_talk_0">
		<text>Greetings. You look like the shadow of death, I can see only darkness</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jora_aver_talk_1">
		<text>Greetings. I am known as Jora-Anomaly. I used to be a bandit here in the zone, but since the explosion I dont reflect light any more...</text>	<!-- Changed 'Zhorik' to 'Jora-Anomaly'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="jora_aver_talk_2">
		<text>Where did this happen to you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jora_aver_talk_3">
		<text>On a territory not far from the Chernobyl NPP. There they have established huge generators. We went to this region to investigate. All went well at first, but then one of the generators blew up. When I regained consciousness, I discovered that the blast had thrown me 300 metres, maybe more. All my comrades were killed, but I survived with this strange condition. I had heard of an Infimary here, so I came here for help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jora_aver_talk_4">
		<text>Generators? Where are they?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jora_aver_talk_5">
		<text>After the explosion, all the paths were changed. I was earlier a bear hunter, I know of trails that to others are undiscovered</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jora_aver_talk_6">
		<text>Your skills sound necessary. Now I will talk to your doctor and for you I have a job</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginekolog_lekarstvo_nayti_0">
		<text>Greetings, I was asked to transfer a bag to you. Truth is I'm here on business, I think your patient will be able to help me. By the way, why do they call you Gynecologist?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginekolog_lekarstvo_nayti_1">
		<text>Greetings, they call me the Gynecologist because thats what I once was. But now my knowledge of medicine is applied to help people in the Zone. Thanks for the bag, what kind of help are you looking for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginekolog_lekarstvo_nayti_2">
		<text>I have a safe I need opened. I'm searching for its owner, I think the information inside will lead me to him. It's not a normal lock, it will take an expert to open it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginekolog_lekarstvo_nayti_3">
		<text>I will ask Jora-Anomaly to begin trying to open it. But something from you is required in exchange. We are in need of medicines and tools. The Ecologist can make any medicine but the ingredients are not present. The Cyclops is in bad need of treatment, we need to do something quickly</text>	<!-- Changed 'Zhorik' to 'Jora-Anomaly'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="ginekolog_lekarstvo_nayti_4">
		<text>Where is it possible to get them. Should I go to The Doctor?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginekolog_lekarstvo_nayti_5">
		<text>The Doctor doesn't have what we need. Ask the Cyclops, he can use telepathy to help you. There is one condition to this task. Wherever you find these medicines, as a doctor I must ask you to not kill or injure anybody</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginekolog_lekarstvo_nayti_6">
		<text>I will ask the Cyclops where to look. So, NOBODY can die while I take the medicine, GREAT, I understand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginekolog_lekarstvo_nayti_7">
		<text>Well, how can I do it without a little carnage? Rambo style is all I know, I can't do it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginekolog_lekarstvo_prines_0">
		<text>I have found the medicine. I hope, this is what you need. All went as planned and I think nobody got hurt</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginekolog_lekarstvo_prines_1">
		<text>Here, thank you. Jora-Anomaly was able to make some progress on the safe. You should speak with him</text>	<!-- Changed 'Zhorik' to 'Jora-Anomaly'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="ginekolog_lekarstvo_prines_2">
		<text>Thats good news, is there anything else you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginekolog_lekarstvo_prines_3">
		<text>There is some business. But since your wanted as a theif, I can't speak with you about it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_lekarstvo_nayti_0">
		<text>You said that you can use telepathy. Ive been asked to find medicine, can you tell me where to look?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_lekarstvo_nayti_1">
		<text>Yes, we are in bad need of medicine. Listen to my vision:\n \nI see buildings\nIn them are soldiers\nthey drink Vodka and smoke\nthey gaurd the Entrance to the Zone\nIn these Buildings much you will find\nIn them the goods you will take.\n \nSearch this place, of the soldiers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_lekarstvo_nayti_2">
		<text>Whoh, slow down! Allow me to write this down, so I dont forget</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_lekarstvo_nayti_3">
		<text>I think you will find this place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_lekarstvo_nayti_4">
		<text>Yes, but which route should I choose. And how do I take away medicine from the enemy without shooting?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_lekarstvo_nayti_5">
		<text>Steal in a silent way. And here to you still more council: Try to do it without being detected, the Gynecologist will be angry if you fail. But I really need this medicine so if your discovered and he is angry, come speak to me. The code for the safe is important to you and for me the medicine is important! But nevertheless, try to do it with stealth, differently and you will lose much. Here, take these transition coordinates to the garbage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_lekarstvo_nayti_6">
		<text>I understand, thanks for the information and this new transition will save me a lot of travel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_lekar_proval_0">
		<text>I couldnt do it the silent way, and the Gynecologist has taken offence</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_lekar_proval_1">
		<text>A person who can use stealth is much respected in the zone. It's much easier to just take what you want by force but people like the Gynecologist don't respect that. Anyway, were you able to get the medicine?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_lekar_proval_2">
		<text>Yes, here they are</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_lekar_proval_3">
		<text>Give them here while the Gynecologist does not see. I will try to straighten out this situation later</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_lekar_proval_4">
		<text>What about the safe? Has the code been cracked?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_lekar_proval_5">
		<text>Talk to Jora-Anomaly. He was able to make some progress</text>	<!-- Changed 'Zhorik' to 'Jora-Anomaly'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_lekar_proval_6">
		<text>This is good news. I hope you can put in a good word for me with the Gynecologist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jora_accumul_0">
		<text>Greetings, Jora-Anomaly. Have you been able to open the safe?</text>	<!-- Changed 'Zhorik' to 'Jora-Anomaly'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="jora_accumul_1">
		<text>This is no normal safe, it has two doors. The first I managed to open, inside was a code with a heap of figures and a word or a name 'Fang'. More time is necessary to open the second door, and not only time. An electronic key is needed or a device which can create an impulse of a certain frequency. I can make the device, but I need a powerful accumulator cell to do it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jora_accumul_2">
		<text>Fang? So this means it's his safe! This stalker is no longer alive. And what kind of accumulator do you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jora_accumul_3">
		<text>Something similar to that used for generating large installations like X-16 which are capable of producing an electric impulse of high frequency</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jora_accumul_4">
		<text>Where is it possible to get such a device?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jora_accumul_5">
		<text>Talk to the Old Man at the entrance to this cave. He's a long time resident of these regions and should know where such accumulator cells were used...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jora_accumul_6">
		<text>I will go speak to the Old Man</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jora_accumul_prines_0">
		<text>Jora-Anomaly, I have found three accumulators, fully charged</text>	<!-- Changed 'Zhorik' to 'Jora-Anomaly'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="jora_accumul_prines_1">
		<text>That's wonderful. I only need two. You can keep the other one</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jora_accumul_prines_2">
		<text>How long till there is a result?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jora_accumul_prines_3">
		<text>Do not rush a sick person. If there is progress you will know</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starik_zadanie_vzyt_0">
		<text>Hello, old timer. Jora-Anomaly tells me you have lived around here all your life. Do you know where I can find any working accumulator cells?</text>	<!-- Changed 'Zhorik' to 'Jora-Anomaly'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="starik_zadanie_vzyt_1">
		<text>Greetings, and yes I know where accumulators can be found. Not far from here but practically impossible to get to</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starik_zadanie_vzyt_2">
		<text>Please tell me where this location is and why you think its impossible?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starik_zadanie_vzyt_3">
		<text>There is another cave not too far from here. Its nicknamed the Fiery Cave, as one of its entrances is closed by fire. To pass through you would need a special fire resistant suit, or an extreme amount of medkits. The second entrance is safe, but...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starik_zadanie_vzyt_4">
		<text>Well, come on, do not drag out!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starik_zadanie_vzyt_5">
		<text>Recently some Stalker has moved in, setting up teleports to protect the entrances. He is a Neutral as far as I know, and sometimes he comes and speaks to the Hermit. I dont know his name, but you can ask him. This cave has been around for a long time, well before the accident at Chernobyl. It had a fresh air system powered by accumulator cells similar to what you're looking for. I once tried to go in through the first entrance, but the fire stopped me. My gold watch became unbearably hot and I had to throw it off me, and then I couldnt retrieve it! When you go to the cave can you please look for my watch? I'll reward you for your troubles. I just hope someone hasn't already found and kept it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starik_zadanie_vzyt_6">
		<text>I will ask the Hermit about the stalker. I will look for your watch but something that valuable would have probably been picked up by now</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starik_zadanie_vzyt_7">
		<text>Im not into finding watches, I can't help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starik_zadanie_prines_0">
		<text>I managed to find the cave, but couldn't enter. I did find your watch and I get the accumulators</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starik_zadanie_prines_1">
		<text>Thats great! But if you couldn't enter, then how did you get the accumulators and my watch</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starik_zadanie_prines_2">
		<text>The stalker gaurding the entrance was a decent fellow. For a small task I was able to get what we needed</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starik_zadanie_prines_3">
		<text>Well I hope you are able to find a way inside. As a reward for finding my watch I'm giving you the info on transitions from the Army Warehouses and the Dark Valley. To you these will obviously be useful</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otshel_uznat_0">
		<text>Hello hermit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otshel_uznat_1">
		<text>Greetings, have you come to play billiards?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otshel_uznat_2">
		<text>I've come to find out what you know about the Fiery Cave and its inhabitants?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otshel_uznat_3">
		<text>Ah yes, the Fiery Cave. I know of one entrance underwater, in the middle of the big pond. I've been told there is another entrance in a ravine, but its well hidden by trees and folliage. Search for both entrances to the cave. I'm not sure who lives there, I've met one nuetral who stays there but he didn't say much</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otshel_uznat_4">
		<text>Here, take a look at this photo in my PDA. Have you seen this face before, is it him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otshel_uznat_5">
		<text>Nope, never seen that guy. The Astrologer comes by sometimes and the odd traveler now and then</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otshel_uznat_6">
		<text>Thanks for the info about the cave</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim_britva_nayti_0">
		<text>Hello, can you tell me who lives here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim_britva_nayti_1">
		<text>Greetings stalker, all I can tell you is there are no murderers or bandits that stay in this cave. Teleports are active on the entrances for protection from mutants and other uninvited visitors. You can never be too safe in the Zone. I can't let you inside. Anyway you wouldn't be able to deactivate the teleports</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim_britva_nayti_2">
		<text>I understand. I have a question to ask: One elderly man, who has lived in this territory all his life, has lost a gold watch in this cave, and I've also been told that once this installation used accumulators for air processing, I need these items desperately, could I have them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim_britva_nayti_3">
		<text>I did find a watch during my first inspection of this cave. If it belongs to an expert in this territory, then Im ready to return it. And, for the accumulators, we have replaced the device that used them with a generator that supplies us with both light and air</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim_britva_nayti_4">
		<text>Were they thrown out as scrap? Tell me where and I can find them</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim_britva_nayti_5">
		<text>I have kept them here, but I'm not sure if they work. You can have them if you will do me a service. When I first came to this place, I set up camp in an abandoned trailer. I went exploring and when I returned the next day a group of snipers had taken over my camp. My backpack, my gear, all hidden behind the trailer. The most important thing I need is my shaving machine tool. If you bring it to me you can have the watch and the accumulators. Only there is a condition, the backpack should be dragged off with stealth. You can't alert the snipers, I dont want them retaliating. Be prepared, the backpack contains seventy or more pieces! We stop talking if you fail to bring me all the contents, got it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim_britva_nayti_6">
		<text>Take away the backpack in a silent way? Im skilled in stealth, yeah I'll do it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim_britva_nayti_7">
		<text>I will not go!!!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim_britva_prines_0">
		<text>I got the backpack without being spotted</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim_britva_prines_1">
		<text>That's great news! Here, take the watch. You'll have to return for the accumulators, though, as will take some time to charge them up with the generator. Oh, and I'll need recompensing for the generator fuel. 70,000Ru, okay? Sorry, but it's one hell of a job getting it delivered here. But thanks for finding my stuff - I'm going to have my first shave in months!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim_britva_prines_2">
		<text>I will take the watch to the old expert and then return</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim_britva_prines_3">
		<text>It will take about an hour and a half to charge them</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim1_britva1_prines_0">
		<text>I got the backpack, but I was caught and had to shoot my way out</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim1_britva1_prines_1">
		<text>Now I will have visitors! Prepare for defense, here take the watch and return for the accumulators. I will charge them with the generator, and at the same time maybe I'll get to shave</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim1_britva1_prines_2">
		<text>I will take the watch to the old expert and then return</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim1_britva1_prines_3">
		<text>It will take about an hour and a half to charge them</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pilig_akkum_0">
		<text>Have you finished charging the accumulators?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pilig_akkum_1">
		<text>HUH? Hey, look! I have shaved, do I look cool or what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pilig_akkum_2">
		<text>Well, you do look younger. To be honest you looked a lot tougher with the beard. But I'm not the one to ask, I don't work in a barber shop or whatever they call them nowadays</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pilig_akkum_3">
		<text>The accumulator cells are fully charged up. Here you go. Tomorrow, we leave on a mission</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pilig_akkum_4">
		<text>Are you talkin' to me? You MUST be talkin' to me! Who is this we? I see only YOU</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pilig_akkum_5">
		<text>I Can only say we are few but have more people in other areas. It seems my chief knows you, he told me to put in a good word with the Hermit for you when you first arrived</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pilig_akkum_6">
		<text>Chief? He knows me? If I find a key to these teleports, dont get offended because I will come without an invitation. I need to unlock my past and this cave has answers I need</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otsh_pda_nayti_0">
		<text>Were you looking for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otsh_pda_nayti_1">
		<text>Adrenalin has an order for a couple of Ultra Detectors which see all anomalies. These detectors were made by the Ecologist that is now being treated in the Infirmary. I had a couple samples, one I have already sent to Adrenalin, but the second I have to keep</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otsh_pda_nayti_2">
		<text>What do you need from me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otsh_pda_nayti_3">
		<text>Your in the Infirmary quite often and carry out tasks for the Physician. This means you have good contacts. Can you help me get one more detector?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otsh_pda_nayti_4">
		<text>I don't know, I've got a big workload already</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otsh_pda_nayti_5">
		<text>This piece of equipment is extremely useful, and you'll be able to get one too. Once you aquire the Ultra Detector take it straight to Adrenalin. You also have other business with him, he said people had come to retreive the casket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otsh_pda_nayti_6">
		<text>I Will try to get another Ultra Detector as well as one for myself. I Will go to the Hologram and see what he requires</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otsh_pda_nayti_7">
		<text>I have no time to fetch detectors</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otsh_pda_prines_0">
		<text>Greetings Adrenalin, I have brought you the second detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otsh_pda_prines_1">
		<text>Thanks Marked One, these are rare and in great demand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otsh_pda_prines_2">
		<text>A very advanced device indeed. Tell me about the people who came for the casket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otsh_pda_prines_3">
		<text>There were two of them, obviously skilled stalkers. The younger of the two was named the Astrologer. The second was thickset and I couldn't get a good look at his face as he wore a hood, but looked very experienced</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otsh_pda_prines_4">
		<text>The Astrologer. What kind of questions did he ask?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otsh_pda_prines_5">
		<text>Well, he knew that you had the safe. Asked me if I could get you to sell it. I see that you're gonna dissagree, so I won't bother. The Astrologer said that it belongs to his workmate. Think about it and dont make any bad choices. Here take this weapon as a reward, a class piece, rare in the Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otsh_pda_prines_6">
		<text>Thanks for the information. I will go check on the the safe. NICE PIECE! If the Astrologer comes back, tell him we will talk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jora_vopros_0">
		<text>Jora-Anomaly, did you manage to get it open?</text>	<!-- Changed 'Zhorik' to 'Jora-Anomaly'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="jora_vopros_1">
		<text>It's not so simple, these things take time</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jora_vopros_2">
		<text>I'm tired of waiting, hurry up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jora_vopros_3">
		<text>Don't get upset, I will finish soon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="golo_detektor_nayti_0">
		<text>Greetings Hologram. I need your help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="golo_detektor_nayti_1">
		<text>Hello Strelok. What do you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="golo_detektor_nayti_2">
		<text>I heard you make Unique Detectors. I need one, two if possible. I'm ready to trade or buy them from you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="golo_detektor_nayti_3">
		<text>I had a pair of them but they were stolen recently. I know who did it, a former patient here. The Cyclops used his telepathy and saw they were in a stash so he has not sold them yet. He will be able to help you find the location</text>
	</string>
	<string id="golo_detektor_nayti_4">
		<text>What is it you want from me in trade?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="golo_detektor_nayti_5">
		<text>I will trade you the two Ultra Detectors if you can bring me two Elite Detectors and the Plasma Caterpillar artefact. I need those items to replace the two you will keep. Bring me what I ask for and Cyclops will help you find the stash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="golo_detektor_nayti_6">
		<text>Yes, its a fair deal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="golo_detektor_nayti_7">
		<text>I don't need an Ultra Detector, no deal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="golo_detektor_prines_0">
		<text>I've got the artefact and detectors</text>
	</string>
	<string id="golo_detektor_prines_1">
		<text>Thanks, now I can make a couple more detectors</text>
	</string>
	<string id="golo_detektor_prines_2">
		<text>And what about the info on the hiding place, you have not forgotten?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="golo_detektor_prines_3">
		<text>Ask the Cyclops, he will tell you where the stash is</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_stix2_0">
		<text>Greetings Cyclops, the Hologram has sent me to you for help finding his stolen detectors</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_stix2_1">
		<text>Hello Strelok. I will tell you what I see.\n \nIn the roots of a faded giant\nThe back pack is hidden with care\nThere the blind creatures scurry about their business\nBetween a radioactive pile and a hill\nThat is the closest to the lawless Valley\n \nStrelok, I am sure that you perfectly know this place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_stix2_2">
		<text>Still necessary to write this down in my PDA. Thank you for the clues to this location</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_stix2_3">
		<text>Yes, write it down so you dont forget. Good luck</text>
	</string>
	<string id="medik_pribor_1_nayti_0">
		<text>Have you really managed to crack it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="medik_pribor_1_nayti_1">
		<text>Yes, it's opened. There was only a folder with some old maps of the Chernobyl area. These maps were made by the Germans during the Second World War. I have shown them to the old Man, he says that the many territories represented on it no longer have paths. But judging by the marks on the map, seems this man has found some new trails. The folder with the map is on the table, take it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="medik_pribor_1_nayti_2">
		<text>I have a strange feeling that I have seen this map already. The Astrologer has looked very hard for this map, I had better draw a copy of it for him</text>
	</string>
	<string id="medik_pribor_1_nayti_3">
		<text>We have helped you and now we must ask for your help. The Hologram says he can make some advanced medicine with a proper device</text>
	</string>
	<string id="medik_pribor_1_nayti_4">
		<text>What kind of device?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="medik_pribor_1_nayti_5">
		<text>Its a special device for mixing doses of medicine. What we need are the schematics to make this device. When the Hologram worked in the laboratory experimenting with artefacts, he says that the schematics for such a device were on a diskette. We need you to find the disk. Ask the Cyclops, he will be able to help you find it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="medik_pribor_1_nayti_6">
		<text>Ok, I will try to find it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="medik_pribor_1_nayti_7">
		<text>Im too busy for this, I need to search for the Astrologer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="medik_pribor_1_prines_0">
		<text>I have found the diskette. It was in one of the caves in the Labyrinth on a wounded Mercenary</text>
	</string>
	<string id="medik_pribor_1_prines_1">
		<text>Thats great, but the Hologram still needs some more components</text>
	</string>
	<string id="medik_pribor_1_prines_2">
		<text>I know the Hologram needs special flasks and reagents to complete his work. I know where the flasks are, they are in the Radar. I know who has Reagents, its someone who looks similar to the Hologram. The leader for the snipers, but how to get them from him I don't know</text>
	</string>
	<string id="medik_pribor_1_prines_3">
		<text>Yes, we need to get the flasks. Talk to Cyclops he will be able to help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_stix3_0">
		<text>Greetings Cyclops. Im helping Hologram make a device for producing medicine. Can you help me locate the diskette with the schematics he needs?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_stix3_1">
		<text>Hello Strelok, of course now listen:\n \nIn the deserted lower cave of the Labyrinth\nWhere packs of rats scurry in the dark\nthere lies a half-dead body\nAnd the secret is stored on it\n \nStrelok, search for a wounded man, and nearby you will find your diskette</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_stix3_2">
		<text>Thanks, I think I can guess where it is</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_stix3_3">
		<text>In the corner of our cave is a transition you can use, it will save you time</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ded_dialog_0">
		<text>How did you manage to climb in this hole?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ded_dialog_1">
		<text>Give me a first-aid set please, dont look at me as the enemy. I was just doing this work for pay</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ded_dialog_2">
		<text>And why should I help you? I should take the diskette and let the rats complete this business</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ded_dialog_3">
		<text>You have come for the diskette? I can give you further information. Even for a genius the schematics are not enough. Without special flasks and Reagents the schematics are worthless. Glass for these flasks are made from the artefact Mica. I can tell you where the flasks are located</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ded_dialog_4">
		<text>Tell me what you know about these flasks, and where are they?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ded_dialog_5">
		<text>The Reagents were made by two scientists, but there was an accident at the end of the experiment and the result was one dead man, and the other became almost invisible. We didn't have time to use what they created as snipers as bandits attacked and carried away all the Reagents. I was able to take away the flasks and hid them in the attic of a house in the Radar. The flasks have strong radiation so take protection. Now please give me a first-aid set</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ded_dialog_6">
		<text>Since you have told me what you know, here take the first-aid set</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_stix4_0">
		<text>Greetings Cyclops, you have some information for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_stix4_1">
		<text>The Merc you cured has deceived you. The flasks are highly radiocative and he did hide them, but not in the Radar. Listen:\n \nThe strange cache lies beneath,\nThe tower that helped deliver power to the world.\non territory Where the spirit of Anarchy soars highly\nthe soldiers of fortune\nAre close by.\nBut the trick here is -\n- over a fence you must climb.\n \nSearch for the flasks</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_stix4_2">
		<text>Thanks, but it's not an easy riddle. This will take some thought, maybe a few beers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_stix4_3">
		<text>You ponder upon my words, these pieces are on a hill under a tower. The flasks might have rolled away so look around the area if you don't find them all</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akkum_and_mikposx_nayti_0">
		<text>I have brought flasks, all three pieces</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akkum_and_mikposx_nayti_1">
		<text>Thanks Strelok, it's still necessary to get two batteries and a microcircuit with recordings from a Freedom Exoskeleton. I think this will be an easier job for you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akkum_and_mikposx_nayti_2">
		<text>Tell me what I need to do</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akkum_and_mikposx_nayti_3">
		<text>You don't have to go far. I have found out about a key. It was Hologram that made the manual teleporter. These are rare devices but I know precisely where a key is located</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akkum_and_mikposx_nayti_4">
		<text>And what do I need this key for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akkum_and_mikposx_nayti_5">
		<text>It will remove the teleport from one of the entrances to the Fiery Cave. You after all wanted to explore there. Look for the microcircuits and batteries. An explorer recently bought a teleport deactivation key from the Hologram. There is a huge meteorite crater in this area. The hunters, with a camp nearby, have reported seeing his body in the crater but they didn't approach it because of anomalies and mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akkum_and_mikposx_nayti_6">
		<text>For a long time I have been wanting to explore this cave. I have a request, while Im looking for this key could you make a copy of the map from the safe. But don't put the added marks on it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akkum_and_mikposx_nayti_7">
		<text>I will not go, this place sounds too dangerous</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akkum_and_mikposx_prines_0">
		<text>You were right, I found the batteries and the microcircuit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akkum_and_mikposx_prines_1">
		<text>Hologram will now be able to get the info he needs from the microcircuit recordings</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akkum_and_mikposx_prines_2">
		<text>Have you made a copy of the map yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akkum_and_mikposx_prines_3">
		<text>Not yet, I'm trying to do the best job I can, more time is required. I will work on it while you get the Reagents from the snipers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim_3_0">
		<text>Greetings Pilgrim, I thought you said you were going on a mission</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim_3_1">
		<text>So you managed to disconnect the teleport. What did you come here for? To steal? You need to explain yourself!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim_3_2">
		<text>I'm not a thief, you said the owner of this cave knew me. So I came to find out who lives here, where are they?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim_3_3">
		<text>He has not returned yet. And my mission was cancelled. Is that the only reason you are here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim_3_4">
		<text>I'm helping the patients at the Infirmary. I need two batteries and a microcircuit with recordings from a Freedom Exoskeleton. Also, I need to find a way to peacefully approach the snipers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim_3_5">
		<text>There are batteries somewhere around here, you can look. I don't know about the microcircuit, there is only a broken tape recorder. Maybe you can salvage something from it. I can help with approaching the snipers. I have the PDA of a Mercenary we eliminated in our last mission. I can send a message to the leader of the snipers. I can say you are looking for work and you want to offer your services. As far as I know, snipers and Mercenaries are on friendly terms</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piligrim_3_6">
		<text>Sounds like a good idea, send the SMS. Meanwhile I will look for the batteries and microcircuit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chimaera_zadan_nayti_0">
		<text>Greetings, I've come looking for work. I want to build up my reputation as a Mercenary. I want your endorsement</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chimaera_zadan_nayti_1">
		<text>An ambitious rookie Mercenary, I do have one task I need take care of. There's a trader in the Cordon that I need eliminated</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chimaera_zadan_nayti_2">
		<text>You mean the local dealer Sidorovich?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chimaera_zadan_nayti_3">
		<text>Yes, that's who. He's become a pain in the rump. He pays more for artefacts than other dealers, so he gets all the good ones. Soon we will eliminate ALL the competition and it starts with him. Do you have a problem with that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chimaera_zadan_nayti_4">
		<text>Eh, no, it's not a problem. How can I get camouflage like your faction?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chimaera_zadan_nayti_5">
		<text>You kill Sidorovich, and as proof bring me his head. As a reward I will give you some of our camouflage formula. Just mix the two Regeants together and you are ta-da, invisible!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chimaera_zadan_nayti_6">
		<text>Wow, Alright, I will go and think of a way to carry out this contract</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chimaera_zadan_nayti_7">
		<text>I cant cut off a head. Im not cut out to be a Mercenary, maybe I will be an artist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chimaera_zadan_prines_0">
		<text>I have brought you the head, now can I get your recommendation and receive your means for invisibility</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chimaera_zadan_prines_1">
		<text>First, we will have a look at the goods. Mmm, yes, he really was an ugly bastard. Alright, I will give it to my men and let them use it for a football. Now about your reward, I will send the recommendation. I don't store the Reagents here, it's too valuable. It's not because I'm bothered by danger as I'm invincible. Don't take offence, I can't tell you where the hiding place is. But I will answer any other question you ask</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chimaera_zadan_prines_2">
		<text>I really wanted the Regeants, but I must accept the endorsment as payment. Though, question is, why do you kill in this area, there's not much loot here that I can see</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chimaera_zadan_prines_3">
		<text>Experience, that's why. My men train here then go on to more important missions. We have teams all over the zone. There's another piece of business I will tell you about. We're searching for the daughter of one of the Big Boss's, she has gone missing in the Zone. Don't look so surprised, I did say a woman. If you can bring her to me, I will pay a big bounty. Now here take this rare artefact for your troubles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginek_vlip_0">
		<text>I Have managed to communicate with the boss of the snipers, Chimera. He wants me to bring him the head of Sidorovich! Then he will give me the Regeants, Merks have no sole. Eh!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginek_vlip_1">
		<text>Wow, I hope you don't intend to really kill Sidorovich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginek_vlip_2">
		<text>I'm not a murderer! I need another way to do this!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginek_vlip_3">
		<text>Nearby there is a camp of hunters. One of them is an expert at making stuffed animals. His name is Eagle owl. I will send Sidorovich an SMS and tell him to send a photo of himself to your PDA. Go and speak with the hunters and see if they can help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginek_vlip_4">
		<text>I Will try, only it seems to me that it's impossible to make a stuffed animal into the head of Sidorovich. Chimera is not a fool, he would notice if it was not real</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginek_vlip_5">
		<text>We must try, I will give you a few parts of mutants that you can use to barter with.\nYES, Hologram has already assembled the DEVICE, look how it turned out, there, ON THE FLOOR, TO THE RIGHT</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginek_vlip_6">
		<text>I will go and talk to Eagle owl and see what he says</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginek_vlip_raschet_0">
		<text>I have bgought the flasks with Reagents. Here, take them away</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginek_vlip_raschet_1">
		<text>Great work! Now there is hope that my patients will recover</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginek_vlip_raschet_2">
		<text>By the way, Chimera spoke about a woman being missing. Have you heard anything?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ginek_vlip_raschet_3">
		<text>I've heard nothing. Here, take this reward for your good work. Torn from my heart. Look, dont sell it. My Great-Grandfather brought it back from the war. You are always welcome here and come check on how the patients are healing. Also Cyclops has the location of another cache for you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="land_oxot_nayti_0">
		<text>Hello hunter. I have some business that requires your help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="land_oxot_nayti_1">
		<text>Greetings, what is it you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="land_oxot_nayti_2">
		<text>Strange business, Ive been told you stuff animals. I need you to make me a head to look like the dealer from the Cordon, Sidorovich. Here are his photos</text>
	</string>
	<string id="land_oxot_nayti_3">
		<text>The person in this picture has a huge head, an unusual request but we can try. The Most important thing I need is the best material for this work. The skull of an experienced controller, the whole head to be exact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="land_oxot_nayti_4">
		<text>What??? A controller???? Your joking??</text>
	</string>
	<string id="land_oxot_nayti_5">
		<text>Why would I joke. The Body needs to be extracted after it has been dead for two to three days, then the material will be more like plastic and easier to shape. A couple of days ago one of my men killed a controller in the woods in the Radar. He was not able to carry it away because Monolithians arrived so he had to flee. Its located next to a rock wall and a tree. It's heavy so don't bring much in your backpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="land_oxot_nayti_6">
		<text>Ok, I will go and retreive this carcass, but it's hard to imagine you can make it look like Sidorovich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="land_oxot_nayti_7">
		<text>No way I'm carrying a rotten controller</text>
	</string>
	<string id="land_oxot_prines_0">
		<text>I have brought the controller, the stink is unbearable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="land_oxot_prines_1">
		<text>Throw the smelly hulk down by the firewood. For this work I require from you ten Chimera claws and 100,000ru, I hope it's not too much</text>
	</string>
	<string id="land_oxot_prines_2">
		<text>Alright, I will bring what is necessary for payment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="land_oxot_prines_3">
		<text>Screw this, ten Chimera claws AND a fortune!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="land_oxot_raschet_0">
		<text>Here is the payment. Is the head ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="land_oxot_raschet_1">
		<text>Yes, it's been completed. You can find it by the saw horse next to the fire wood. It was not easy work, I should have charged more</text>
	</string>
	<string id="land_oxot_raschet_2">
		<text>I brought what you asked, it's more than enough. Though I have to say I am impressed with your work</text>
	</string>
	<string id="land_oxot_raschet_3">
		<text>If you ever need a stuffed girlfriend, I can prepare one from s controller for you, HA, HA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_stix5_0">
		<text>Hello Cyclops, I need your help finding the Reagents. Chimera has deceived me and given me nothing. He has only told me that the Regeants are in a hiding place somewhere. But he could have lied</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_stix5_1">
		<text>Don't be upset, the main thing is that he has told you about a hiding place. Now I can make a connection with my telepathy. You will now be able to take everything from his hiding place. He has hidden it well so listen attentively:\n \nWhere five towers\naspire in a height. Go down from the heavens in human life\nThe doll lost by the mistress it is forgotten,\nyou will find it In one of rooms\nAnd near to a doll in the house\nYou will find a backpack with plunder\n \n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_stix5_2">
		<text>Im not sure where that is, can I have another clue?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_stix5_3">
		<text>I can only see an approximate place. I See only vague outlines of the subjects nearest to a hiding place and objects and I can express it only in the form of riddles, Good luck</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_stix6_0">
		<text>Hello Cyclops, I have brought you the Reagents for your treatment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_stix6_1">
		<text>Thanks Strelok, the treatment will take some time. In my case, a long time. I know of one more cache, take it as a gift from me. The Rhyme is short, it's a place you will find without problems.\n \nWhere the bloodsuckers call home\nWearily sleeps the Iron Horse\n \n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_stix6_2">
		<text>Thanks, I think I know this place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ziklop_stix6_3">
		<text>Well, this is excellent. Look, the Hologram has already charged the device!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vuxod_atp_0">
		<text>How is it possible to get out of this territory?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vuxod_atp_1">
		<text>It's quite a dilemma you have, you got here but you cant leave</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vuxod_atp_2">
		<text>I've looked around and can't find an exit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vuxod_atp_3">
		<text>You didn't think to ask the person who sent you? I can show you a path to the Dump, but there will not be further conversation till you bring me three artefacts: a Glassbeads, Moonlight, and a Flash. All of them can be found on this territory. You bring them to me and I will show you the path</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vuxod_atp1_0">
		<text>Here's your artefacts, now could you show me the path</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vuxod_atp1_1">
		<text>The path to the Dump is at the end of the road on the opposite side of this territory, I have sent the info to your PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vuxod_atp1_2">
		<text>That's easy enough to find</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstrecha_0">
		<text>Fang??? Is it really you??? I thought you had been killed</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstrecha_1">
		<text>Greetings Strelok, I've not seen you for a very long time. No, as you can see, they have not killed me. I was able to slip away. I was able to fool the Mercenaries into thinking they got me. You were gone, and Ghost went missing</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstrecha_2">
		<text>Ghost was lost on a mission inside X-16 but it's rumored that the body of his double lies there. He is capable of such a thing. Why didn't you leave me a message?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstrecha_3">
		<text>I had to keep a low profile. You were gone somewhere in Chernobyl and it was rumored that you had entered the O-consciousness and became their assassin. So it was necessary to observe you. Now I know that the rumors were false. I met the Astrologer who told me he pulled you out of the death truck. I'm a little suspicious of him, it's too much of a coincidence and he asked a lot of questions. He knew about my map with the noted transitions. Therefore, I told you to make a copy, without my marks. I will take the map from you for awhile. Dont say anything about us meeting to the Astrologer yet. All I can say about the Pilgrim, he is a simple and honest friend who can be trusted</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstrecha_4">
		<text>I'm glad that you are alive. I really did talk to the man from O-consciousness, but I refused to join them. After that everything is covered by a gloom, I remembered nothing. Cordon, the Astrologer, the Cave, the Doctor. I've been through so much in a short period of time. What will we do next, do you have any plans? Let's have a drink to our reunion</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstrecha_5">
		<text>Eh, that's good Vodka! Now about our plans, you already know about the decoder in Pripyat but there's no need to hurry with that. There is something else more important. I have information that the daughter of a boss from O-consciousness has arrived to visit daddy. She has gone missing, it's more likely she was abducted. The last time she was spotted was in the Radar, around the Aerials. All the Monolith are searching for her, and not only the Monolith. I'm searching for her also and I need your help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstrecha_6">
		<text>Of course I will help. But why are we searching for her?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstrecha_7">
		<text>We need to find out why there is so much intrest in this girl, there is something big going on here. Also if Ghost is alive he needs to be found, if he is dead then we need proof. I also need you to check out a new territory. It's a former Military Laboratory called Warlab. It is undergound near to Chernobyl, but the only entrance I know of is from the Radar, I will mark it in your PDA. I don't know who is there or what they're up to, but you need to find out. There is data that suggests the girl is there. The return path from the location is also known, I will also give you these coordinates. Possibly, the laboratories of the zone have been connected by underground tunnels. The transition to the exit is through a tunnel to X-16. The Pilgrim and I will be engaged in exploring the transitions on my map and determining if they work. I will stay in touch with you by SMS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstrecha_8">
		<text>I understand, we have much work to do</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstr_after_prizrak_0">
		<text>Fang??? Is it really you??? I thought you had been killed</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstr_after_prizrak_1">
		<text>Greetings Strelok, I've not seen you for a very long time. No, as you can see, they have not killed me. I was able to slip away. I was able to fool the Mercenaries into thinking they got me. You were gone, and Ghost went missing</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstr_after_prizrak_2">
		<text>Ghost is alive and now in the Radar territory. He is just as sly as you. He left a body double in X-16 and even left an audio message. He was not easy to find. Why didn't you leave me a message?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstr_after_prizrak_3">
		<text>I had to keep a low profile. You were gone somewhere in Chernobyl and it was rumored that you had entered the O-consciousness and became their assassin. So it was necessary to observe you. Now I know that the rumors were false. I met the Astrologer who told me he pulled you out of the death truck. I'm a little suspicious of him, it's too much of a coincidence and he asked a lot of questions. He knew about my map with the noted transitions. Therefore, I told you to make a copy, without my marks. I will take the map from you for awhile. Don't say anything about us meeting to the Astrologer yet. What I will say about the Pilgrim, he is a simple and honest friend who can be trusted</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstr_after_prizrak_4">
		<text>Im glad that you are alive. I really did talk to the man from O-consciousness, but I refused to join them. After that everything is covered by a gloom, I remembered nothing, Cordon, the Astrologer, the Cave, the Doctor. I've been through so much in a short period of time. What will we do next, do you have any plans? Lets have a drink to our reunion</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstr_after_prizrak_5">
		<text>Eh, thats good Vodka! Now about our plans, you already know about the decoder in Pripyat but there's no need to hurry with that. There is something else more important. I have information that the daughter of a boss from O-consciousness has arrived to visit daddy. She's gone missing, it's more likely she was abducted. The last time she was spotted was in the Radar, around the Aerials. All the Monolith are searching for her, and not only the Monolith. I'm searching for her as well and I need your help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstr_after_prizrak_6">
		<text>Of course I will help. But why are we searching for her?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstr_after_prizrak_7">
		<text>We need to find out why there is so much intrest in this girl, there is something big going on here. I need you to check out a new territory. It's a former Military Laboratory called Warlab. It's undergound near Chernobyl, but the only entrance I know of is from the Radar, I will mark it in your PDA. I don't know who is there or what they are up to, but you need to find out. There is data that suggests the girl is there. The return path from the location is also known, I will also give you these coordinates. Possibly, the Laboratories of the zone have been connected by underground tunnels. The transition to the exit is through a tunnel to X-16. The Pilgrim and I will be engaged in exploring the transitions on my map and determine if they work. I will stay in touch with you by SMS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstr_after_prizrak_8">
		<text>I understand, we have much work to do</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstrecha_otchet_0">
		<text>Greetings. Seems I arrived at Warlab at an inappropriate moment. The Monolith attacked the mercenary base. Or on the contrary. But the Monolithians destroyed Mrcenaries, and then I finished off the Monolithians. The lab has been cleaned out. The entrance into one of the parts of the laboratory is closed off by a teleport. To pass through there is impossible. The girl was no where to be found, but a search of one of the leaders of the group has produced an interesting document. It's not difficult to guess to whom it belonged</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstrecha_otchet_1">
		<text>This means the Astrologer is in communication with the Mercenaries. The guy needs to be checked up on to see if he really is double dealing here. Mercenaries, apparently, know about the girl, and know where she's at. Perhaps he too tries to find out it? We must find a way into this confidential part of Warlab</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstrecha_otchet_2">
		<text>Yes, but how will I remove the teleport in Warlab if I dont have a key??</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstrecha_otchet_3">
		<text>To get the key to the teleport I think you must gain the trust of the Mercenaries. Talk to Lukash and tell him Fang told you he could help you with this mission. I have known him for a long time and he was a former Merc himself. Get him to loan you his Signet ring that will get you accepted as one of the Mercs. I must warn you, once you put on the ring you will be an enemy to all stalkers. Also recent data reports show that a large force of Mercs has returned to Warlab. Onto other matters, we have checked up on only one territory so far. The so-called Generators, these were spare generators that were established for Chernobyl. When there was a second more powerful explosion the path was lost but we should be able to find it later. Now we need to check out the transition to Limansk, you must have heard of it. But that task will come a bit later. For now Pilgrim and I will remain in the Bar territory</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_vstrecha_otchet_4">
		<text>Well, I will go and speak with the Freedom boss</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_pechatka_nayti_0">
		<text>Lukash, greetings. Fang has hinted that you could help me with some business</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_pechatka_nayti_1">
		<text>Fang has been dead for a long time. I already know you were searching for his killers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_pechatka_nayti_2">
		<text>Fortunately for me, and for you, he is alive. He told me you could help me join the Mercs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_pechatka_nayti_3">
		<text>Ssshhhhh!!!! Not so loud, this is for our ears only</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_pechatka_nayti_4">
		<text>You have a Signet ring that I need to borrow, when my task is finished I will return it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_pechatka_nayti_5">
		<text>About the Signet ring, I dont have it anymore. A Monolithian called Spider most likely has it. A long time ago, just after I first joined Freedom as a recruit, we were on a mission in Pripyat. I shot a Merc boss in a firefight and took the ring as a trophy. Later that day, I was badly wounded and taken prisoner. This Spider took away the Signet ring. They were feeding our wounded to the mutants in the football stadium for entertainment. I was able to escape, but that's another story. It is said that Spider is still alive and in the Radar. He is based at the end of a road, next to a tunnel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_pechatka_nayti_6">
		<text>Is this ring the only way for me to gain there trust?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_pechatka_nayti_7">
		<text>There is no other way. This signet ring belonged to the former boss of the Mercenaries. You will extract it and use it. After your mission it will be of no further use to you and you will return it to me. The ring is very valuable and you will receive a reward</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_pechatka_nayti_8">
		<text>I have understood, and we will settle later. I will try to 'squash' this Spider and take away the Signet ring, then go to Warlab</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_pechatka_vernul_0">
		<text>I Have returned. I found the Signet ring and little 'iti-biti' Spider has been eliminated. Now about that reward</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_pechatka_vernul_1">
		<text>There is one more task for you to execute before you receive the reward</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_pechatka_vernul_2">
		<text>Well, Lukash, why do you want to treat me like a rookie?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_pechatka_vernul_3">
		<text>You will get your reward and a bonus, but first listen. Freedom is expanding its borders of influence. We want to organise one more base in the former Laboratory, Warlab. You know this place and your help is essential. I sent a group of masters there under the command of Vitamin. Help secure the lab and Vitamin will give you the award and bonus when the task is completed. By the way, acquaint yourself, he's here now. He will give you further instructions</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitamin_reyd_zadan_0">
		<text>Greetings, are you Vitamin?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitamin_reyd_zadan_1">
		<text>Hello stalker, yes I am. I hope Lukash has briefed you on our forthcoming operation. Your knowledge of the Lab and the route to get there is very important</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitamin_reyd_zadan_2">
		<text>Yes, he has briefed me. The Mercs have already been dealt with but now blind dogs have made a den there</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitamin_reyd_zadan_3">
		<text>So, little Doggies, this clears up the situation a little. We need you to guide us to the entrance of the Laboratory</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitamin_reyd_zadan_4">
		<text>I can do that. What is your plan and what is the bonus Lukash mentioned?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitamin_reyd_zadan_5">
		<text>The Bonus? Yes, yes, I have a key which will disconnect any teleport in Warlab. For your help, it will be yours. And from Lukash, you will get another gift. I will meet you with my group of fighters at the entrance to the Radar territory. You lead the group and we will clear the road and gather at the entrance to the Lab. When we get to the entrance I will wait for the second group of fighters to arrive. I just hope that when this is over there's not too much dog crap to clean up</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitamin_reyd_zadan_6">
		<text>Mmm, yes, The Plan sounds simple enough. Well, we will meet in the Radar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitamin_reyd_zadan_7">
		<text>Screw this, I'm no dog catcher! You dont need my help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitamin_radar_0">
		<text>You got here quickly. Well, are you ready to go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitamin_radar_1">
		<text>On the way we kill everything that moves. You will lead the group. Choose the safest possibile route. When we reach the entrance to the lab, we will take a smoke break, a chug, then discuss our next move</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitamin_radar_2">
		<text>Lets move out men, lock and load!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitamin_radar_3">
		<text>We are right behind you, move out men!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitamin_reyd_okonchen_0">
		<text>We made it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitamin_reyd_okonchen_1">
		<text>I will wait for the next group of fighters and then we will follow you into the laboratory. You go ahead and check the lab</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitamin_reyd_okonchen_2">
		<text>And where is my compensation?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitamin_reyd_okonchen_3">
		<text>Dont worry, when the lab is clear of all dogs you will be rewarded</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitamin_warl_talk_0">
		<text>Well, thats all the dogs killed! No doubt your men will eat well tonight, Eh</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitamin_warl_talk_1">
		<text>Yes, this has all turned out well. Now freedom has another base, and its an extremely important location</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitamin_warl_talk_2">
		<text>Dont expect me to help your men clean up the dog crap, now how about my reward</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitamin_warl_talk_3">
		<text>Here, take your well earned rewards, a key for a teleport and a gift from Lukash. The gift is a small Gold Ingot. Its owner has a number of important advantages in our faction: when it is in your backpack, you are one of us. When you enter a territory with it in your pack, you will be rcognized as a member of Freedom. Taking it out of your pack won't make you nuetral until you leave the territory</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
