<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 -->
<!-- Translated and corrected by Steve90k for fluency and ease of reading. Edited and proofed by Sword2012 for clarity, brevity, and consistency. 08 Oct 16 -->

	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_agroprom_large">
		<text>An eerie place. The silent building conceals its own share of secrets, but Stalkers are drawn to the numerous artefacts that can be found in the area, despite the danger everywhere. Here, strategic preparation and accurate shots will make you Lady Luck's favorite Stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_agroprom_short">
		<text>The silent building conceals its own share of secrets, but Stalkers are drawn to the numerous artefacts that can be found in the area, despite the danger everywhere</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_atp_large">
		<text>This bus and trolley park is the Zone's lobby, where abandoned tractors, buses and trucks have stopped in their tracks forever. No artefacts have ever been reported here, but the place is popular with experienced Stalkers who hunt down rookies and grab what they can. Take cover in buildings and behind equipment, and watch out for enemies on the roofs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_atp_short">
		<text>This bus and trolley park is the Zone's lobby, where abandoned tractors, buses and lorries have stopped in their tracks forever</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_bath_large">
		<text>This mysterious, echoing place holds a strange attraction. Who built that experimental pool, and why? That will forever remain a secret. No artefacts are to be found here. Only the remnants of strange machines and devices attract Stalkers here. Keep your eyes on roofs, and remember that the radiation level is extremely high in this area</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_bath_short">
		<text>This mysterious, echoing place holds a strange attraction. Who built that experimental pool, and why? That will forever remain a secret</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_factory_large">
		<text>A gloomy run-down factory. There's no telling how many Stalkers have met their end within these walls. All kinds of anomalies abound, but Stalkers are drawn in like a magnet since valuable artefacts can be found here. Watch out for the radiation levels!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_factory_short">
		<text>A gloomy run-down factory. There's no telling how many Stalkers have met their end within these walls</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_garbage_large">
		<text>This is a region of the vast dump where mountains of radioactive rubbish were brought after the disaster in '86. Dilapidated cranes, motors, hardware, and so on - anything made of metal. You'll find a huge hangar, and remnants of many old facilities here. All this close to the entrance to the Zone, with many artefacts being generated constantly. That's what brings in Stalkers looking for easy pickings</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_garbage_short">
		<text>This is a region of the vast dump where mountains of radioactive rubbish were brought after the disaster in '86. Dilapidated cranes, motors, hardware, and so on - anything made of metal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_lost_village_large">
		<text>A deserted, decrepit village deep inside the Zone. The shallow, rust-coloured lake filled with forsaken cars breeds a primeval fear in the hearts of the Zone's explorers. Beware of snipers, but keep in mind that the Zone usually favours the brave</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_lost_village_short">
		<text>A deserted, decrepit village deep inside the Zone. The shallow, rust-coloured lake filled with forsaken cars breeds a primeval fear in the hearts of the Zone's explorers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_military_1_large">
		<text>A disaffected army base with mildewed barracks, a decaying command centre, and a fleet of broken-down trucks and APCs left to rust. But it's not what it seems. The base is rich in artefacts, and death hides behind every corner. Prove your mettle and collect the reward!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_military_1_short">
		<text>A disaffected army base with mildewed barracks, a ruined command centre, and a fleet of broken-down trucks and APCs left to rust</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_military_2_large">
		<text>This derelict old village is an eerie and sinister place, full of death-traps. Even if you've come this far, despite all the risks, be prepared for sudden death - because nowhere is safe here. May your scope, silencer and instincts keep you in one piece</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_military_2_short">
		<text>This derelict old village is an eerie and sinister place, full of death-traps. Even if you've come this far, despite all the risks, be prepared for sudden death - because nowhere is safe here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_prypiat_large">
		<text>The infamous city of Pripyat was once home to all the workers at the Chernobyl NPP, or what's left of it now. The ruins of this industrial skeleton now house clear and present danger. You truly need to fear for your life here - just as they once did</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_prypiat_short">
		<text>The infamous city of Pripyat is the forsaken heirloom of the Chernobyl catastrophe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_railraod_short">
		<text>A small railroad station at the Rostok factory</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_railroad_large">
		<text>A small railroad station at the Rostok factory. The ruined engines and rolling stock now stand rusting at an eternal terminus. The many artefacts found here lure in desperate Stalkers from all over the Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_rostok_large">
		<text>Last century, national evangelism booming from its loudspeakers, this factory bustled with the activity of workers hurrying to, and through, their shifts each day. Now abandoned, neglected, and forgotten, it has done its share of work. Beneath its heaps of metal, behind its walls of concrete, it holds a spectral silence for those it is about to permanently retire</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_rostok_short">
		<text>Beneath its heaps of metal, behind its walls of concrete, this abandoned, neglected, and forgotten factory holds a spectral silence for those it is about to permanently retire</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_workshop_large">
		<text>The outskirts of the Rostok factory before Duty's arrival, this crumbling, decaying area is nonetheless rich in artefacts. Empty hangars and warehouses teem with dangers every step of the way. Be extremely careful, and keep a close watch on the white tower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_workshop_short">
		<text>The outskirts of the Rostok factory before Duty's arrival, this crumbling, decaying area is nonetheless rich in artefacts</text>
	</string>
