<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 new Collector, more dav updates, val_zapis_9, dav update 16Apr14, hunt_part2_message, 27_2, hunt_doc_jupu, minor edits, \n\n to \n.\n-->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->
<string_table>
#include "text\eng\stable_bio_name.xml"
#include "text\eng\string_table_arts_desc.xml"
	<string id="val_zap">
		<text>Collector's Notebook</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_1">
		<text>Somewhere in the Cordon, above a tunnel. No rail tracks there...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_2">
		<text>Stalker... once you read this... it means that I may already be dead. This all started when I was on a job near the Radar for the Initiative. They wanted me to find a couple of 'rare' artefacts that can only be found up there. I found myself hiding for my life from those Monolith freaks. I ducked down behind some bushes, and found myself enveloped in a thick dense fog that seemed to suddenly form out of nothing. It only enveloped me for a few seconds, my Geiger counter and anomaly detector went wild, and I felt very strange...\n the rest... well, I lost consciousness... I woke up feeling fine, and somewhat rejuvenated. Some time later, I began to notice something... I could sense nearby artefacts. And then it started... I found the Artefracts for each order with ease. I made it to the Chernobyl NPP but I could not find the Sarcophagus. I did manage to gather a lot of rare unknown artefacts and unusual mutations of mushrooms.\nThe Mushrooms are very interesting as these have very high levels of Caesium-137, strontium-90, barium-137, Iodine-131, tellurium and rubidium isotopes, plutonium and other heavy elements - all naturally absorbed, a characteristic of mushrooms.\n.\n Each time I came back to the Cordon, I left well concealed caches in the areas I traveled through as well as notes with hints of other locations. With my fading health and memory I knew these cryptic clues would be needed. With each passing day, the cumulative affects of CS-134 and other radioactive isotopes are quickly bringing me to my demise. Each time I look at my reflection I am significantly older. Only a few months after that incident at the Radar, my life is at an end.\nBut lucky for you... you found my last note. Good luck to you Stalker, in pursuit of my treasures. I moved my stashes between 3 locations so it will be in one of them...\n• In the Cordon:\n In a tree south of the Military outpost...\n• Check under the Railroad cars...\n• Amongst some stones East of the place of Guide...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_3">
		<text>At the Dump\n• Between a heap of pipes and the transition to Agroprom, try looking up...\n• A body on a chopper...\n• In a pipe on a hill 50m behind the bus...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_4">
		<text>At Agroprom\n• A pipe in the Swamp...\n• A nother P ossible C ache...\n• Nearby four large containers and a wall...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_5">
		<text>At the Dump\n• Inside next to a pillar of the Northern side of the Hanger...\n• Up high in a ruined Building near the Duty checkpoint - difficult climb...\n• On the radioactive hill closest to the Duty checkpoint...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_6">
		<text>In the Dark Valley\n• On a two Story red Brick Electrical building...\n• A high tree near the X-18 Lab...\n• Main Base, high and near a Crane...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_7">
		<text>At the BAR\n• Roof near Southern Duty outpost - behind the fence...\n• On the second level...4 water collector stacks...\n• Beyond the Iron gates...Wild Territory transition...rubbish dumpster</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_8">
		<text>In the Wild Territory\n• In an unfinished 3 story building...\n• Room at the transition to the Bar, need jump on rail for this one...\n• Fence near the snipers - But how to get there? and how to get out?...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_9">
		<text>In Yantar\n• Beam of a hanger with some roof missing...\n• 3 pipes near 4 corpses and a backpack...\n• A=1...4,9,7,7,5,18...Z=26...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_10">
		<text>In the Wild Territory\n• Two utility sheds near the rail track\n• higher than 4 snipers nearest the Bar transition, a sight from a tower...\n• Beside the grave marked with a cross...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_11">
		<text>At the Army Warehouses\n• near a crashed helicopter - under the concrete channels...\n• metal pipes near concrete slabs...\n• amongst 3 stones, behind the barbed wire fence near the APC, not an obvious climb...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_12">
		<text>At the Radar\n• next to the twin transmission towers above the X-10 Lab, look for a ladder...\n• the tank aims too low ??...\n• In rocks, just behind a fence, behind an Armored Troop Carrier by the cliffs...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_13">
		<text>In Pripyat\n• In the nine-story with the collapsed corner...\n• broken Gondola...\n• Helmet of the Statue...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_14">
		<text>At Chernobyl\n• a far away Red Truck...\n• Under the fallen trees...\n• Under the railroad bridge...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_15">
		<text>In the Radar forest\n• Near the crashed helicopter I ran towards the cliffs in total darkness - chased by snorks and Zombies.\n A monster with huge claws appeared in front of me, I thought this was the end but the beast was a tree.\n Jumping and climbing the tree Beast I found refuge and left my stash...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_16">
		<text>In the forest of the Radar, I happened upon a pack of Chernobyl Psi-Dogs, I also encountered a group of Snorks. All I could do was climb up a tree, firing, as I climbed from branch to branch... and then there it was... a teleport... I woke up on the ground on one of the low hills in the forest. As I began to investigate the area, I discovered that all the hills are connected by the same source. Roaming those hills, I have found my fortune in artefacts, including some very 'rare' and expensive ones. I carried what I could, and left the rest inside a Cache; the properties of which are very specific... very specific indeed!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_17">
		<text>Stalker, well done - you have found my main stash. These unique and rare artefacts will be of great help to you. Watch their negative properties though!.\n.\n Live long and Prosper.\n.\nPS...I passed some of my unusual finds to a good friend of mine nicknamed Caesier. He's a very smart Scientist who thinks he can develop an antidote for Cs-134 poisoning. Find him or his clues and you'll be very happy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_18">
		<text>I haven't seen the Collector for a while now. Maybe he finally succumbed to the Zone, some say he was enveloped by a bright light and he ascended to the sky.\nHe passed information onto me about rare arteacts, how to modify weapons with special artefacts and how to breed unique flora and plants, including his favorite Mushrooms.\nLike the Collector, I have left my stashes over the Zone - in the New Territories. Some of these stashes contain very special weapons or artefacts. They will be very difficult to find as these items are far too powerful for the inexperienced. I wish you luck in finding my stashes...\nAt the Base nearby there is a broken round pipe on top of some concrete slabs. Beware, the Base may be well defended\n.\nCaesier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_19">
		<text>RECON\n.\n• In a pool under a lake...\n• Under a large rock in a crater, in Mr Bones NE view...\n• In large rocks near the trail to the Army Warehouses...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_20">
		<text>\nSwamp\n• On the CS Main Base roof - but it may wash off...\n• On the top of a high water Tower...\n• A Train carriage near a Cave...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_21">
		<text>\nOld Village\n• Old Tractor taken by the trees...\n• In a house Chimney...\n• An attic of a high up house...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_22">
		<text>\nHospital\n• Under a Star...\n• The Dome is Holographic...\n• On the Digger Track...\n• On the Digger Scoop</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_23">
		<text>\nLimansk\n• Tactpohom...\n• Tunnel under Antenna array...\n...Take a leap of faith\n• Suspended up high...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_24">
		<text>\nGenerators\n• Epicenter...\n• Spiked tree in front of the Truck...\n• Solitary power building roof</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_25">
		<text>\nWarlab\n• down, R1, down, under steps...\n• Pool room Sofa...\n• On top of 1 of 6 tanks...\n• Top of first level power cabinets...\n.\n.\ngenerated in the mirror 65409152</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_26">
		<text>\n Red Forest\n• Three rocks down by river\n• Under the floorboards across the river...\n• River Truck...\n• 1 of 3 pipes near Truck...\n• Overlooking the Boiler Anamoly...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_27">
		<text>\nDead City\n• Crashed helicopter...\n• Under a Transition Bridge...\n• Photo board...\n• Follow 2 power lines near an antenna...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_28">
		<text>\nBackwater\n• Overlooking the Electric Chopper...\n• A rock overlooking 2 Cranes...\n• Waste Processing station - In 1 of 3 overhead Pipes...\n• Waste Processing station water reservoir...\n.\nThe end of a chopper blade will give you a nice surprise</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_29">
		<text>\nJupiter\n.\nAt the end of the Rail lines there is a a room with a door and a Transition to Caesier's Lookout\n.\n• Stair Platform you can't get to...\n• Factory roof tree...\n• Factory roof overlooking the Chopper...\n• Storm drain behind the Factory...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_30">
		<text>\nEast Pripyat\nAt the River port, there is a Teleport Booth that leads to my safe area.\nFind my photo document and your search for my Stash will be easier. Look for the X that marks the spot and risk the jump...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_31">
		<text>\nAt the River Port Pier there is transport to Jupiter. Find the elevator in the old Jupiter Factory and make your way underground.\nJupiter underground\n.\nClimb through the Tunnel bars - a Teleport awaits you.\nMake your next choice wisely - your life depends on it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_zapis_32">
		<text>\nCaesier's last Secret Note</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tayniki_coll_0">
		<text>Listen Sid... I have heard rumors about some very rare artefacts that are very hard to find. It is said that someone had found some of them deep inside the Zone, and that they had sold some of them to you here in the Cordon...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tayniki_coll_1">
		<text>Well, yes... that much is true. Most of the orders I received were for one particular artefact, but... I have since had several orders for a particular type in a certain quantity - the payment, as you know... will suit the job. Roughly speaking though... it would be twice as profitable as the total value if the artefacts were sought out individually...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tayniki_coll_2">
		<text>Sounds good to me... Let us talk business, then...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tayniki_coll_3">
		<text>That's exactly all it is at this point... Talk!! I'm at a loss as to what to do. The Stalker who took these orders has disappeared without a trace... and with him... the mystery of it all as well... By the way... have you heard tell of this Collector fellow at all?!... well, that's his nickname around these parts, anyways...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tayniki_coll_4">
		<text>No, this is the first I've heard tell of him... please go on...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tayniki_coll_5">
		<text>That's understandable. The Old-Timers that knew him only tend to spend a day or two in the Zone and they don't like to talk about him much. From what they have revealed the 'Collector' was a seasoned Stalker that took orders for rare artefacts, plants and fauna from some Zone factions and loners.  Some of these 'rare' artefacts can only be found near the Radar. The level of anomalous activity and concentration of heavy metals and Radioactive substances are ideal for the creation of all forms of unique items. I remember one job the Collector took and he was probably gone more than a month, I thought that the Zone took him... like so many others before. And then suddenly one day he shows up... and, with the ordered artefacts as well!! None of us had ever seen such artefacts... such treasures!! But, he had changed very much since he left. He seemed older, somehow...\n A week later he was back again - this time to sell me two very rare artefacts - he looked awful... as if he had aged five years...\n Later I asked 'Wolf' about him, and he said that an 'old' man fitting his description wandered into the village, but didn't speak to anyone... not even him. He only stayed overnight, sleeping near the fire in the center of the village, and then he left early the next morning. No-one has seen or heard from him since...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tayniki_coll_6">
		<text>So what are you proposing then?...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tayniki_coll_7">
		<text>Well, nothing really... don't get too excited... it could all just be a bunch of campfire talk...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tayniki_coll_8">
		<text>Well, I suppose so... but, it might be worth looking into all the same...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tayniki_coll_9">
		<text>Well, I'll tell you one thing... this 'Collector' fellow was no dummy. How could he possibly spend a few days here in the Cordon and find such rare artefacts that can only be found near the center of the Zone!? My guess is that he had them hidden away somewhere in secret caches that only he knew about. There may still be some of these 'Caches' still out there. If you are the curious type that I think you are, then have a good, close look around here in the Rookie Village. This is the last place he was seen, after all...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tayniki_coll_10">
		<text>Food for thought... I may check into that. Talk to you later...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_hand_name_c1">
		<text>Rubberized Gloves</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-hand_c1">
		<text>Capable of blocking up to 30 percent of the harmful effects of the selected artefact. Essentially, a simple pair of Fighting Gloves that have been re-enforced heavily with a thick rubberized compound...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_hand_name_c2">
		<text>Improved Gloves</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-hand_c2">
		<text>Capable of blocking up to 50 percent of the harmful effects of the selected artefact. These gloves were treated by throwing them into the WEB anomaly. Abnormal filaments have been implanted into the fibers of the gloves themselves, thereby increasing their protective characteristics...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_hand_name_c3">
		<text>Upgraded Gloves</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-hand_c3">
		<text>Capable of blocking up to 70 percent of the harmful effects of the selected artefact. Advanced pair of Gloves taken from an Exoskeleton which was enhanced somehow by means of the venerable 'Burr' artefact...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_hand_name_c4">
		<text>'Unique' Gloves</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-hand_c4">
		<text>These Gloves completely block 100 percent of the harmful effects of the selected artefact and seem to amplify the users striking energy, making them excellent fighting gloves as well. Taken off of a rare Exoskeleton, and by means of many unsafe experiments... using a combination of two artefacts - the 'Burr' and the 'Igla', which managed somehow to completely negate the harmful effects of the artefacts without harming the person wearing them. The 'Igla' is very rare artefact, so these gloves are literally worth their weight in Gold...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_1">
		<text>…Somewhere very close to a blocked tunnel …</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_2_1">
		<text>...I was high on Mushrooms, South of the the Military outpost, check the trees...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_2_2">
		<text>...check the Railroad cars carefully...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_2_3">
		<text>...Buried amongst some stones East of the place of Guide...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_3_1">
		<text>...between a heap of pipes and the transition to Agroprom...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_3_2">
		<text>...on a hill between a hangar and a Duty outpost, a piped box...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_3_3">
		<text>...on a hill between a hangar and a parking yard, on the side closest to the central road...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_4_1">
		<text>...in a swamp pipe...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_4_2">
		<text>...A nother P ossible C ache...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_4_3">
		<text>...nearby four large containers...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_5_1">
		<text>...inside the Hanger... Northern wall...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_5_2">
		<text>...in the rubble near the Duty checkpoint...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_5_3">
		<text>...on the radioactive hill near the Duty checkpoint...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_6_1">
		<text>...red brick electrical switch building...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_6_2">
		<text>...tree near lab...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_6_3">
		<text>...701 bin...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_7_1">
		<text>...near the Duty outpost close to the Dump...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_7_2">
		<text>...on the second level... 4 water collector stacks...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_7_3">
		<text>...iron gates...Wild Territory transition...rubbish dumpster...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_8_1">
		<text>...in an unfinished 3 story building...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_8_2">
		<text>...at the transition to the Bar there's a room in another dimension, no soldiers, no people anywhere...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_8_3">
		<text>...collapsed train platform...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_9_1">
		<text>...the barbed-wire fence...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_9_2">
		<text>...3 pipes near 4 corpses and a backpack...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_9_3">
		<text>...4, 9, 7, 7, 5, 18...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_10_1">
		<text>...Two utility sheds near the rail track...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_10_2">
		<text>...higher than 4 snipers and seen from the Bar transition...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_10_3">
		<text>...beside the grave marked with a cross...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_11_1">
		<text>...near the crashed helicopter - under the concrete channels...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_11_2">
		<text>...metal pipes near concrete slabs...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_11_3">
		<text>...amongst 3 stones, behind the barbed wire fence near the Mercenary Outpost...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_12_1">
		<text>...next to the transmission towers above X-10...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_12_2">
		<text>...the tank barrel points the way - up...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_12_3">
		<text>...amongst some stones nearby an armored troop-carrier...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_13_1">
		<text>...in the collapsed corner of a nine-storey building...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_13_2">
		<text>...broken Gondola...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_13_3">
		<text>...in the kindergarten...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_14_1">
		<text>...outside the fence, next to the locomotive...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_14_2">
		<text>...under the fallen trees...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_14_3">
		<text>...under the rail bridge...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_15">
		<text>...there where the BEAUTY is embraced by the BEAST...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_16">
		<text>...in the hills surrounding the Radar...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_17">
		<text>...dAVROs has a hidden message...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_18">
		<text>...ATP Bandit Base...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_19_1">
		<text>...pool under lake...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_19_2">
		<text>...crater rock, in Mr Bones NE view...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_19_3">
		<text>...rocks near AW transition...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_20_1">
		<text>...Base watertank...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_20_2">
		<text>...top of high water tower...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_20_3">
		<text>...train carrage near cave...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_21_1">
		<text>...old tractor...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_21_2">
		<text>...Chimney...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_21_3">
		<text>...attic...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_22_1">
		<text>...under the star...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_22_2">
		<text>...Holographic Dome...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_22_3">
		<text>...Digger track...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_22_4">
		<text>...Digger scoop...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_23_1">
		<text>...Tactpohom...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_23_2">
		<text>...Tunnel under Antenna array...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_23_3">
		<text>...Chimney near sniper tower...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_24_1">
		<text>...Epicenter...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_24_2">
		<text>...Spiked tree in front of Truck...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_24_3">
		<text>...down, R1, down under 4 steps...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_25_1">
		<text>...Pool room sofa...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_25_2">
		<text>...top of 1 of 6 tanks...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_25_3">
		<text>...top of power cabinets...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_26_1">
		<text>...3 rocks down by river...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_26_2">
		<text>...under the floorboards on the otherside...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_26_3">
		<text>...river truck...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_26_4">
		<text>...1 of 3 pipes near truck...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_26_5">
		<text>...overlooking the boiler...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_27_1">
		<text>...Chopper...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_27_2">
		<text>...so much rubble...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_28_1">
		<text>...overlooking the electric chopper...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_28_2">
		<text>...rock overlooking 2 cranes...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_28_3">
		<text>...in 1 of 3 overhead pipes...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_28_4">
		<text>...near the 3 pipes high up pillar...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_29_1">
		<text>...Jupiter factory inaccesible stairs...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_29_2">
		<text>...Jupiter factory roof tree...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_29_3">
		<text>...Jupiter factory roof overlooking the chopper...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_29_4">
		<text>...Behind Jupiter factory strom drain...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_30_1">
		<text>...round and round a prominent figure...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_30_2">
		<text>...prominent figure...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_30_3">
		<text>...good reception...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_30_4">
		<text>...roof...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="collector_clue_31">
		<text>...Secret room stash...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunt_part2_message">
		<text>...Marked One, I overheard a conversation about Caesier. He was last seen in the ATP, far to the northwest...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunt_ldk_warning">
		<text>ATTENTION: LDK have been seen infiltrating the underground facilities in the North, use extreme caution!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunt_bkwtr_warning">
		<text>ATTENTION: Reported confrontation with LDK in Backwater. Military troops are to withdraw from that area immediately!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunt_doc_jupu">
		<text>This is my last hideout.\nI left small stashes of weapons throughout the Zone for my use.\nYou are welcome to them as I no longer need them, hopefully I will make it to Moscow as a stowaway in the LDK evacuation.\nYou can escape by jumping onto the ledge below the opening and sliding through the window.\nI have also left my hand teleporter to Limansk which may come in handy at times!\nGood luck and stay cautious!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunt_doc_j">
		<text>To he who finds this</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
