<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
	<string_table>
<!-- 12/70 a?iau -->
		<string id="ammo-12x70-buck">
			<text>12x70 Schrotladung</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-12x70-buck_s">
			<text>12x70 Schrot</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-12x70-buck_descr">
			<text>Standardgeschosse Kaliber 12 gefüllt mit 6mm-Schrot. Tödlich auf kurze Distanz. Geeignet für Jagdgewehre und Schrotflinten sowie für die halbautomatischen Schrotflinten SPSA14 und Chaser 13.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 12/76 ioey -->
		<string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan">
			<text>12x76 Gewehrladung</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan_s">
			<text>12x76 slug rounds</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan_descr">
			<text>Diese schweren 12 Kaliber Massivgeschosse werden normalerweise auf der Jagd nach ganz großer Beute eingesetzt, können aber auch in anderen Bereichen sinnvoll sein. Die schwere Munition bohrt sich nicht wie üblich durch die Panzerung, sondern durchschlägt sie einfach mit einer immensen Wucht.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 12/76 a?ioee -->
		<string id="ammo-12x76-dart">
			<text>12x76 Spitzgeschosse</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-12x76-dart_s">
			<text>12x76 Spitz</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-12x76-dart_descr">
			<text>Spitzgeschosse. Die Lamellen erhöhen die Stabilität und damit die Schussgenauigkeit. Der massive Stahlkern der Munition kann jede Panzerung durchdringen. Geeignet für Jagdgewehre und Schrotflinten sowie für die halbautomatischen Schrotflinten SPSA14 und Chaser 13.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 9o18 -->
		<string id="ammo-9x18-fmj">
			<text>9x18 mm Patronen</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-9x18-fmj_s">
			<text>9x18</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-9x18-fmj_descr">
			<text>Die Patrone 9?18 mm (oder auch als "9mm Makarow" oder " 9x18 PM" bekannt) war die Standard-Pistolenmunition der Sowjetarmee und der übrigen Streitkräfte des Warschauer Paktes. In den Nachfolgestaaten der Sowjetunion ist die Patrone nach wie vor weit verbreitet.\n \nEntwicklung:\nGegen Ende des Zweiten Weltkrieges suchte die Führung der Sowjetarmee nach Ersatz für die betagte Pistole Tokarew TT-33. Bei der Neuentwicklung der Pistole orientierte man sich an der deutschen Walther PP, die mit einfachem Masseverschluss (unverriegelter Rückstoßlader) auskam. Dementsprechend wurde auch keine starke Patrone erforderlich; dies hätte den Verschlussmechanismus überfordert.\n \nDie Tokarew-Munition hatte eine deutlich höhere Geschossenergie und eine gestrecktere Flugbahn, denn sie war auch für den Einsatz in Maschinenpistolen vorgesehen. Mit der Ausmusterung der MPis und der Umstellung der Bewaffnung auf Sturmgewehre bestand dafür jedoch keine Notwendigkeit mehr. Die neue Patrone sollte bei geringerem Rückstoß eine größere Aufhaltekraft entfalten, die Reichweite war nachrangig. In jüngerer Vergangenheit erachtete das russische Militär die Energie der Geschosse jedoch als zu schwach und führte im Jahr 2003 mit der Jarygin PJa eine Pistole im Kaliber 9?19 mm ein.
</text>
		</string>
<!-- 9o18 IAI -->
		<string id="ammo-9x18-pmm">
			<text>9õ18 mm +PBM+</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-9x18-pmm_s">
			<text>9õ18mm +PBM+</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-9x18-pmm_descr">
			<text>Hergestellt ande der 90er von der "Federal State Unitary Enterprise", kurz FSUE. Deutsch: "Föderales Staatliches Unitarunternehmen"\nDiese Patrone besitzt ein Teilmantelgeschoss mit einem freiliegenden Stahlkern in Aluminiumummantelung. Dank der leichten Kugel entsteht auch bei ihrer Mündungsgeschwindigkeit von praktisch 500 m/s ein Rückstoss vergleichbar mit der normalen Makarov Munition. Sie durchschlägt die russische Standardschutzweste der Armee bis auf 30 Meter Entfernung.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 9o19 -->
		<string id="ammo-9x19-fmj">
			<text>9x19mm</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-9x19-fmj_s">
			<text>9x19mm</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-9x19-fmj_descr">
			<text>Die Patrone 9?19 mm, auch "9mm Parabellum" oder "9mm Luger" genannt, ist eine der weltweit am weitesten verbreiteten Patronen für Selbstladepistolen. Sie findet auch in Maschinenpistolen Verwendung.\n \nGeschichte:\nDie Patrone 9x19 mm ist keine US-amerikanische Erfindung, wie so manches Gerücht über ihre Entstehung besagt. Der Ursprung dieser mittlerweile weltweit verbreiteten "Großkaliberpatrone" liegt ein knappes Jahrhundert zurück, im Deutschen Kaiserreich. Die Entstehung der Patrone ist eng mit der Entwicklungsgeschichte der Pistole 04/08 verbunden.\n \nUm 1900 hat Georg Luger mit Hugo Borchhardt gemeinsam als Konstrukteur bei DWM (Deutsche Waffen- und Munitionsfabriken) in Berlin gearbeitet, wo Luger auch die nach ihm benannte "Luger"-Pistole entwickelte. Für seine Luger-Pistole änderte er die 7,63 mm Mauser um indem er die Mauser-Hülse um 3mm kürzte, ein anderes Geschoss einsetzte und fertig war seine 7,65 mm Luger bzw. 7,65 mm Parabellum. Diese Waffe, die zu jener Zeit hauptsächlich unter dem Namen "Parabellum-Pistole, System Luger/Borchhardt" bekannt wurde, wurde 1901 der preußischen Gewehr-Prüfungs-Kommission vorgelegt (diese Abteilung prüfte alle Waffen, die für eine militärische Verwendung geprüft werden sollten). Die Kommission befand die Waffe als durchaus militärtauglich, allerdings wurde die Munition als zu schwach gewertet, da aufgrund der fehlenden 'Mannstopp'-Wirkung eines solch kleinen Kalibers, die nach den Erfahrungen in bereits vorangegangen Gefechten dringend benötigt wurde, nicht die vom Militär gewünschten Verletzungen hervorgerufen wurden.\n \n1902 erweiterte Luger den Hülsenmund seiner 7,65 mm Parabellum auf 9 mm um keine großen Veränderungen an seiner Pistole vornehmen zu müssen und kürzte die Hülse von 21,5 mm auf 19 mm; So mußte lediglich der Lauf ausgetauscht werden, da der Bodendurchmesser der gleiche wie bei der 7,65 mm Luger ist, alle anderen Teile blieben erhalten.\n \n1904 wurde die Pistole samt dem neuen Kaliber bei der kaiserlichen Marine unter der Bezeichnung "Selbstladepistole 04" eingeführt und mit der ersten fabrikgefertigten Munition, einem bei DWM gefertigten abgeflachten Stahlmantelgeschoss (auch Kegelstumpfgeschoss) und einer speziell für die Luger Pistole abgestimmten Ladung, versehen.\n \n1908 führte das kaiserliche Heer die Pistole mit verkürztem Lauf samt Munition als "Pistole 08" (P08) ein.\n \n1915 ersetzte DWM das Kegelstumpfgeschoss durch ein Vollmantelrundkopfgeschoss.

Der Name Parabellum leitet sich aus der Kurzform des lateinischen Feldherren Spruchs 'qui desiderat pacem praeparat bellum' (wer Frieden wünscht, bereitet den Krieg vor) 'Si vis pacem, para bellum' (wenn du den Frieden willst, bereite den Krieg vor) ab. Heute ist sie ein weltweit eingesetztes Geschoss, verwendet von Sportschützen wie auch von Polizeikräften und dem Militär. Die Patrone 9x19 mm ist NATO-Standard-Patrone für Pistolen und Maschinenpistolen.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 9o19 +?+ -->
		<string id="ammo-9x19-pbp">
			<text>9x19mm +P+</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-9x19-pbp_s">
			<text>9x19mm +P+</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-9x19-pbp_descr">
			<text>9x19mm In einer verbesserten Spezialversion mit panzerbrechendem Geschoss und eigentümlicher Konstruktion, die seit etwa 1994 erzeugt wird. Die sehr starke Treibladung dieser als 7N21 bezeichneten Patrone ergibt Spitzendrücke von 2.800 bar. Das panzerbrechende Geschoss hat einen gehärteten Stahlkern, der in einem Bimetall-Geschossmantel eingeschlossen ist. Der Raum zwischen Kern und Mantel, der üblicherweise von einem Bleihemd ausgefüllt wird, ist hier mit Polyäthylen verfüllt. Die Spitze des Kerns ist an der Geschossspitze freigestellt, also sichtbar. Dies soll eine bessere Durchschlagsleistung erbringen. </text>
		</string>
<!-- 5,7x28 SS190 -->
		<string id="ammo-5.7x28-fmj">
			<text>5.7x28mm SS190</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-5.7x28-fmj_s">
			<text>5.7x28mm SS190</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-5.7x28-fmj_descr">
			<text>Die Patrone 5.7?28mm it ein Vollmantelgeschoss (FMJ, englisch full metal jacket) und ist eine von der belgischen FN Herstal SA hergestellte Munition für Handfeuerwaffen. Diese ab etwa 1985 entwickelte Munition entspricht neuen taktischen Erfordernissen von Militär und Polizei und soll auf Entfernungen unter 200m die Vorteile von Pistolen- und Gewehrmunition vereinen. Das sind vor allem geringer Rückstoß, hohe Magazinkapazität, hohe Durchschlagskraft gegen Schutzwesten und geringe Umfeldgefährdung.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 5.7x28 AP -->
		<string id="ammo-5.7x28-ap">
			<text>5.7x28mm AP</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-5.7x28-ap_s">
			<text>5.7x28mm AP</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-5.7x28-ap_descr">
			<text>Die Patrone 5.7?28mm, SS190-Munition mit armor piercing (AP, deutsch „panzerbrechend“) bezeichnet und ist entwickelt worden, um Schutzwesten zu durchschlagen. Das Geschoss der SS190 hat einen Aluminiumkern, vor dem sich ein Penetrator aus Stahl befindet. Damit ist der Aufbau fast identisch mit der SS109-FMJ-Munition für Gewehre im Kaliber 5.56?45 mm, bei der lediglich ein anderes Material für den Kern benutzt wird. Dabei befindet sich unter dem Stahlmantel des Geschosses, hinter einem kleinen Hohlraum, ein 55 Brinell harter Stahlkern. Hinter diesem wiederum befindet sich ein leichtes Aluminiumstück, das den Geschossmantel ausfüllt. Dadurch ist der Schwerpunkt, gegenüber anderen Geschosskonstruktionen, verschoben. Als Ergebnis durchdringt die spitze Form auch Kevlarpanzerungen und Fahrzeugteile. Querschläger an Wänden und Böden werden vermieden, da das Geschoss auch beim Auftreffen im flachen Winkel in das Material eindringt und hier seine Energie abgibt. In weichen Zielen wird das Geschoss oft instabil und überschlägt sich durch den verlagerten Schwerpunkt. Hierdurch wird viel Energie abgegeben und ein Durchschuss - auf Kosten eines größeren Wundkanals - vermieden.</text>
		</string>
<!-- .50 Action Express -->
		<string id="ammo-50-ae">
			<text>.50 Action Express</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-50-ae_s">
			<text>.50 AE</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-50-ae_descr">
			<text>.50 Action Express ist eine Patrone mit dem Kaliber 12.7mm (0,5 Zoll). Sie wurde für die Verwendung in Faustfeuerwaffen entwickelt, die bekannteste Waffe in .50 Action Express ist die Selbstladepistole Desert Eagle.\n \nGeschichte:\nDie Patrone wurde im Jahre 1988 von Evan Whildren von der Firma Action Arms für die Desert Eagle entwickelt. Der Verkauf begann im Jahre 1991. Die .50 Action Express wurde für die Jagd und für das Scheibenschießen entwickelt.\n \nTechnik:\nDer Boden der Patrone ist mit dem der .44 Magnum identisch. Das ermöglicht es, die Patrone nur durch Austausch des Laufes aus einer für .44 Magnum eingerichteten Desert Eagle zu verschießen. Der Durchmesser der Patronenhülse beträgt 13,9 mm (0,547 Zoll). Diese Munition wird vorwiegend in Kurzwaffen, aber auch in einigen Langwaffen verwendet.\n \nLeistungsbetrachtung:\nVerschossen aus einer Desert Eagle mit 152-mm-Lauf liegt die Mündungsgeschwindigkeit der knapp 20 g (300 Grains) schweren Geschosse bei 400 m·s?1 bei einer Mündungsenergie von etwa 1700 Joule. Werden die Patronen wiedergeladen, lassen sich diese Werte durch eine stärkere Treibladung noch übertreffen. Die .50 Action Express ist somit die stärkste Patrone für Selbstladepistolen auf dem Markt. Ihre Leistungen hinsichtlich der Ballistik werden im Bereich der Munition für Faustfeuerwaffen nur von einigen Revolverpatronen wie .454 Casull oder .500 S&W übertroffen.</text>
		</string>
<!-- .357 Magnum -->
		<string id="ammo-357">
			<text>.357 Magnum</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-357_s">
			<text>.357 Magnum</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-357_descr">
			<text>Die Patrone .357 Magnum wurde von der Firma Smith & Wesson 1934 für Revolver auf den Markt gebracht (s. Bild: Colt Python). Heute gibt es eine Vielzahl von Lang- und Kurzwaffen, die in diesem Kaliber hergestellt werden.\n \n.357 Magnum-Munition ist doppelt so stark geladen wie .38 Special-Munition (ähnliches Kaliber). Beim Abschuss aus einem .38 Special-Revolver könnte der entsprechend höhere Gasdruck die dafür nicht ausgelegte Waffe sprengen und somit den Schützen gefährden. Um diese Abschussmöglichkeit zu verhindern, ist die Hülse der .357 Magnum um ca. 3,4 mm länger als die der .38 Special. Umgekehrt ist es jedoch gefahrlos möglich, die kürzere .38 Special-Munition mit .357 Magnum-Revolvern zu verschießen.</text>
		</string>
<!-- .45ACP -->
		<string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj">
			<text>.45ACP Patronen</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj_s">
			<text>.45ACP</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj_descr">
			<text>Der Munitionstyp .45 ACP ("0.45 inch Automatic Colt Pistol“) wurde erstmals bei der US-amerikanischen Pistole Colt M1911 verwendet. Sein Kaliber (Geschossdurchmesser) beträgt 0,45 Zoll oder umgerechnet 11.43 mm. Die Patrone wurde von John Moses Browning im Jahre 1905 entwickelt.\n \nEntwicklung:\nIn den frühen 1900er-Jahren zeigte sich in der Kavallerie der US-Streitkräfte, dass die neu eingeführte .38er-Kaliber-Munition im Gefecht nicht die alte .45er-Kaliber-Munition ersetzen konnte. Die Mannstoppwirkung der .38er lag zu niedrig, und die Kavallerie verlangte eine Munition, deren Mannstopp-Leistung auf dem Niveau der alten .45er Colt lag.\nColt und Browning arbeiteten im Jahre 1904 an einer .41er Patrone. Als die Kavallerie im Jahre 1905 nach einer .45er verlangte, wurde der .41er Prototyp vergrößert. Das Originalprojektil hatte ein Gewicht von 13 g (200 grain) und eine Mündungsgeschwindigkeit von 275 m/s. Später wurde sie auf ein Gewicht von 15 g (230 grain) mit einer Mündungsgeschwindigkeit von 260 m/s modifiziert.\nDie .45er ACP liegt somit in der Leistung mit der .40 S&W gleichauf und leicht unter der der .45 Colt.\n \n:Lesitung:\nDiese Patrone ist sehr effektiv zur Selbstverteidigung, da sie eine starke Mannstopp-Wirkung hat. Der Rückstoß und das Mündungsfeuer der Munition sind vergleichsweise gering. Wegen ihrer geringen Durchschlagswirkung eignet sie sich aber nur bedingt zur Bekämpfung von Gegnern, die Schutzkleidung tragen. Das Gewicht und die Materialkosten sind im Vergleich zur 9-mm-Patrone höher. Als Dienstkaliber in den US-amerikanischen Streitkräften sowie bei den Polizeien der Kommunen und der Bundesstaaten sowie der US-Regierung wurde die .45 ACP größtenteils durch das Kaliber 9x19 mm ersetzt, außer bei einigen Spezialeinheiten, die modifizierte 1911A1-Pistolen, HK-SOCOM-Mk. 23 und die HK P12 verwenden. Dies führte aber insbesondere bei Einsätzen der Polizeien gegen Straftäter, die unter Drogeneinfluss stehen, dazu, dass Polizisten häufig ihr ganzes Magazin leerschießen, um den Straftäter zu Boden zu bringen.</text>
		</string>
<!-- .45ACP HS -->
		<string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro">
			<text>.45ACP Hydra-Shock</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro_s">
			<text>.45ACP HS</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro_descr">
			<text>Premiumhohlspitzgeschoss mit Zentralalpin im Zentrum der Hohlspitze. Höchste Präzision, kontrollierte Expansion durch effiziente Energieabgabe. Eingekerbter Geschossmantel, vernickelte Hülse. Weltweit im Einsatz bewährt und FBI-zertifiziert.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 5.45o39 -->
		<string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj">
			<text>5.45x39mm (7N10)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj_s">
			<text>5.45x39 (7N10)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj_descr">
			<text>Die Patrone 5.45x39 mm, auch als Modell M74 bezeichnet, wurde eigens für das Sturmgewehr AK-74 entwickelt, nicht zuletzt unter dem Eindruck des US-amerikanischen Einsatzes der Patrone .223 Remington (5.56x45mm NATO) im Vietnamkrieg. Die 5,45x39mm folgte einer internationalen Tendenz zu kleineren Kalibern bei Schützenwaffen.\nDie Vorteile eines gegenüber dem früheren Standardkaliber (7.62mm) kleineren Kalibers liegen in der gestreckteren Flugbahn (bessere Rasanz), im geringeren Rückstoß, was die Treffgenauigkeit bei Feuerstößen erhöht und im geringeren Gewicht der Patrone, wodurch ein Schütze eine höhere Anzahl an Patronen mitführen kann.\nAnders als z. B. bei der 5.56x45 Nato deformiert bzw. fragmentiert das Geschoss beim Eindringen in ein weiches Ziel nicht zuverlässig. Eher neigt das Geschoss dazu, im Ziel zu taumeln, was durch die hohle Spitze begünstigt wird. Die Wundwirkung ist geringer als bei vergleichbarer fragmentierender Munition, da die permanente Wundhöhle kleiner ist.\nDie Patrone 5.45?39 mm wird fast ausschließlich für den militärischen Bedarf früherer Mitgliedsstaaten des Warschauer Pakts hergestellt oder für Staaten, die mit diesen kooperierten. Nur wenige Hersteller vermarkten diese Patrone (ohne Stahlkern) für zivile Zwecke, im Gegensatz etwa zur .223 Remington, die in zahlreichen Match- und Jagdlaborierungen angeboten wird. In Deutschland kommt hinzu, dass der Besitz von Hartkernmunition laut Waffengesetz (Anlage 2, Abschnitt 1, Punkt 5, Unterpunkt 4) verboten ist.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 5.45o39 AI-->
		<string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap">
			<text>5.45x39mm (7N22)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap_s">
			<text>5.45x39mm (7N22)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap_descr">
			<text>Die 5.45x39mm (7N22) ist die Panzerbrechende version. Eingeführt  1998, verfügt über einen 1,75 g scharfen Stahlpenetrator und einen weichen Bleipolster in der Ummantelung.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 5.56o45 -->
		<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190">
			<text>5.56x45mm (SS109)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190_s">
			<text>5.56x45mm (SS109)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190_descr">
			<text>Die Patrone 5.56x45mm NATO ist eine bei den Armeen der NATO weit verbreitete Munition für Sturmgewehre. Im zivilen Bereich wird die Patrone als .223 Remington bezeichnet und für Jagd oder Sport verwendet.\n \nEnticklung:\nNach dem Zweiten Weltkrieg entstand bei den Militärs das Bedürfnis nach neuen, leichten Waffen, unter anderem dem Karabiner M1 Carbine oder der Thompson-Maschinenpistole, deren verwendete Munition .30 Carbine und .45 ACP sich nur im Nahbereich als besonders wirksam erwies. Also ging die Entwicklung neuer Waffen – zum Beispiel nach dem Prinzip des deutschen Sturmgewehres 44, dessen Name ein Synonym für die neue Generation von Waffen wurde – mit der Entwicklung neuer Munition einher. Die Forderungen dafür waren typischerweise geringeres Gewicht, hinreichend gestreckte Flugbahn für etwa 300 m effektive Reichweite, kontrollierbare Feuerstöße und geringere Produktionskosten. In Deutschland entstand noch während des Kriegs das mittlere Sturmgewehrkaliber 7.92x33mm, das weltweite Nachkriegsentwicklungen beeinflusste. Während auf sowjetischer Seite 1943 ein ähnliches Kaliber (7.62x39mm) geschaffen wurde, entstanden in Europa bereits verschiedene dem späteren Kaliber 5.56mm ähnliche Versuchspatronen.\nDie Patrone SS109 wurde mit einem 3,95 g schweren Geschoss für eine geänderte Zuglänge im Lauf entwickelt. Die Verwendung in der Bundeswehr ist aus der Liste von Bundeswehrmunition ersichtlich.\nDie Patrone wurde zum Vorbild für das Kaliber 5.56x45mm NATO, dem neuen Standardkaliber in den NATO-Armeen seit den frühen 1980er-Jahren. Es wird in den meisten aktuellen Sturmgewehren (Colt M4, Heckler & Koch G36, Steyr AUG, FAMAS, AK-101) verwendet. Für das SIG 550 verwendet die Schweizer Armee die Ordonnanzpatrone Gw Pat 90. Da die Patrone Gw Pat 90 jedoch weitgehend kompatibel zur Patrone 5,56x45mm NATO ist, findet diese Patrone vor allem auch bei Exportwaffen Verwendung. Auch einige Maschinengewehre (wie das M249 oder das MG4) sowie einige wenige (zumeist polizeiliche) Scharfschützengewehre verschießen dieses Kaliber.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 5.56o45 AP -->
		<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap">
			<text>5.56x45mm (P112)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap_s">
			<text>5.56x45mm (P112)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap_descr">
			<text>Die  5.56x45mm NATO in der +P+ version ist bekannt als P112. Weit verbreitet von Westlichen Sicherheitsdiensten und Spezialeinheiten. Effektiv gegen Panzerung.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 9o39 NI-5 -->
		<string id="ammo-9x39-sp5">
			<text>9x39mm SP-5</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-9x39-sp5_s">
			<text>9x39 SP-5</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-9x39-sp5_descr">
			<text>Die 9x39mm ist eine sowjetische Unterschall-Mittelpatrone, die in schallgedämpften Spezialwaffen wie dem Wintores-Scharfschützengewehr und dem Sturmgewehr AS Wal verwendet wird.\n \nEntwicklung:\nDie Patrone wurde aus der 7.62x39-mm-Patrone M43 entwickelt. Dazu wurde die Hülse der M43 auf 9mm aufgeweitet, die übrigen Dimensionen blieben unverändert.\n \nEigenschaften:\nDie Patrone wurde gezielt auf Unterschallgeschwindigkeit des Projektils hin entwickelt, um den Überschallknall zu vermeiden. Der verbleibende Mündungsknall lässt sich mit einem Schalldämpfer stark vermindern.\n \nSP-5 (GRAU-Index 7N8, russisch ÑÏ-5): Spezialnij Patron, "Spezialpatrone“. Präzisionsmunition mit Bleikern-Vollmantelgeschoß.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 9o39 IAA9-->
		<string id="ammo-9x39-pab9">
			<text>9x39mm PAB-9</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-9x39-pab9_s">
			<text>9x39mm PAB-9</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-9x39-pab9_descr">
			<text>Die 9x39mm ist eine sowjetische Unterschall-Mittelpatrone, die in schallgedämpften Spezialwaffen wie dem Wintores-Scharfschützengewehr und dem Sturmgewehr AS Wal verwendet wird.\n \nEntwicklung:\nDie Patrone wurde aus der 7.62x9-mm-Patrone M43 entwickelt. Dazu wurde die Hülse der M43 auf 9mm aufgeweitet, die übrigen Dimensionen blieben unverändert.\n \nEigenschaften:\nDie Patrone wurde gezielt auf Unterschallgeschwindigkeit des Projektils hin entwickelt, um den Überschallknall zu vermeiden. Der verbleibende Mündungsknall lässt sich mit einem Schalldämpfer stark vermindern.\n \nPAB-9 (GRAU-Index 7N12, russisch ÏÀÁ-9): Vereinfachte kostengünstige Variante der SP-6, die aufgrund der damit verbundenen Nachteile wie verringerte Präzision und erhöhter Rohrverschleiß nicht mehr produziert wird.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 9o39 NI-6 -->
		<string id="ammo-9x39-ap">
			<text>9x39mm SP-6</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-9x39-ap_s">
			<text>9x39mm SP-6</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-9x39-ap_descr">
			<text>Die 9x39mm ist eine sowjetische Unterschall-Mittelpatrone, die in schallgedämpften Spezialwaffen wie dem Wintores-Scharfschützengewehr und dem Sturmgewehr AS Wal verwendet wird.\n \nEntwicklung:\nDie Patrone wurde aus der 7.62x39-mm-Patrone M43 entwickelt. Dazu wurde die Hülse der M43 auf 9mm aufgeweitet, die übrigen Dimensionen blieben unverändert.\n \nEigenschaften:\nDie Patrone wurde gezielt auf Unterschallgeschwindigkeit des Projektils hin entwickelt, um den Überschallknall zu vermeiden. Der verbleibende Mündungsknall lässt sich mit einem Schalldämpfer stark vermindern.\n \SP-6 (GRAU-Index 7N9, russisch ÑÏ-6): Panzerbrechende Patrone mit Stahlkern. Durchschlagsleistung 6 mm Stahl oder 2,8 mm Titan bzw. 30 Lagen Kevlar auf 200 Meter.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 7.62x25 I -->
		<string id="ammo-7.62x25-p">
			<text>7.62x25mm P</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x25-p_s">
			<text>7.62x25mm</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x25-p_descr">
			<text>Die 7.62x25mm Tokarev Patrone ist ein russischer Flaschenhalspistolenpatrone weit verbreitet in der ehemaligen sowjetischen Satellitenstaaten, China und Pakistan unter anderen Ländern verwendet. Die Patrone hat da in den meisten Kapazitäten durch die 9 ? 18 mm Makarov in russischen Diensten ersetzt.\n \nGeschihcte:\nVor dem Ersten Weltkrieg, die 7.63x25mm Mauser Kaliber Mauser C-96 Pistole weltweit an Popularität gewonnen. Im Jahr 1908 legte der zaristischen Armee, die C-96 auf einer Liste der zugelassenen Handfeuerwaffen, die Offiziere konnten auf eigene Kosten statt der Durchführung der Nagant M1895 Revolver kaufen. Zwischen 1914 und 1917 wurden mehr Mauser Pistolen und Munition erfasst Waffen aus deutschen und türkischen Streitkräfte erhalten. Die Mauser und seine Patrone wurden an allen Fronten des russischen Bürgerkrieg und in den 1920er Jahren über einen Zeitraum von relativ enge Zusammenarbeit zwischen der Sowjetunion und der Weimarer Republik verwendet, kaufte der Roten Armee Chargen des kleineren Bolo-Version sowie Munition für Verwendung durch seine Offiziere. Obwohl eine Kopie der Kassette wurde am Podolsky Munitionsfabrik hergestellt, die Sowjets schließlich kaufte eine Lizenz und Fertigungseinrichtungen von DWM in Deutschland, um die Patrone zu erzeugen. Im Jahr 1929 machte die sowjetische Artillerie Ausschuss den Vorschlag, eine inländische Pistole für die Mauser Patrone Kammern zu entwickeln. Nach erheblichen Forschung und Entwicklung, wurde beschlossen, dass das "Modell 1930 7.62mm Pistolenpatrone" im Wesentlichen die Mauser Rund mit geringfügigen Änderungen, war es, die Standard-Kaliber für sowjetische Pistolen und Maschinenpistolen zu werden. Frühe Versionen des Vasily Degtyaryov gestaltete PPD-40 Maschinenpistole wurden mit der Aufschrift "Für Mauser Patrone Kaliber 7.62mm".\n \nEntwicklung:\nDie Patrone ist im Prinzip eine erweiterte russische Version des 7.63x25mm Mauser. Die Russen produziert eine breite Palette von Belastungen für diese Patrone für die Verwendung in Maschinenpistolen. Dazu gehören panzerbrechenden, Tracer, und Brand Runden. Diese Patrone hat hervorragende Penetration und kann leicht zu besiegen leichter Schutzwesten sowie einige Kevlar-Helme, wie die American PASGT Helm. Obwohl die meisten Waffen in diesem Kaliber Kammern wurden obsolet erklärt und vom Militärbestände entfernt, können einige Polizei und Spezialeinheiten in Russland, Pakistan und in China immer noch sie wegen der großen Menge der gespeicherten Munition zur Verfügung.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 7.62x25 IN -->
		<string id="ammo-7.62x25-ps">
			<text>7.62x25mm PS</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x25-ps_s">
			<text>7.62x25mm PS</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x25-ps_descr">
			<text>Sowjetische Pistole Patrone, Kaliber 7.62mm mit Stahlkern. Bietet verbesserte Treffsicherheit gegenüber die Standard 7.62x25mm P.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 7.62o39 -->
		<string id="ammo-7.62x39-fmj">
			<text>7.62x39mm</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x39-fmj_s">
			<text>7.62x39mm</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x39-fmj_descr">
			<text>Die Patrone 7.62x39 mm (häufig auch unter der militärischen Bezeichnung Kurzpatrone M 43 geführt) gehörte als Munition zur Ausrüstung der Roten Armee, der Armeen des Warschauer Pakts und der Volksbefreiungsarmee Chinas. Sie wird noch bei den finnischen Streitkräften und den Streitkräften vieler anderer Staaten verwendet.\n \nGeschichte:\nBereits zu Beginn des 20. Jahrhunderts begann in Russland die Entwicklung von Selbstladegewehren, wie zum Beispiel des Fjodorow-Gewehres. Nach dem Ersten Weltkrieg wurde verfügt, dass alle automatischen Waffen die Armeepatrone 7.62x54 R Mosin zu verwenden hatten, die schon während der Regentschaft des Zaren Nikolaus II eingeführt wurde. Dies brachte zahlreiche konstruktionstechnische Probleme mit sich, denn durch ihren markanten Rand war die Patrone für diesen Zweck ungeeignet. Bis zum Beginn und noch während des Zweiten Weltkrieges versuchten sich viele sowjetische Konstrukteure an der Aufgabe, eine zuverlässige selbstladende Waffe auf der Grundlage der vorgegebenen Munition zu entwickeln. Das beste Resultat dieser Bemühungen war wohl das Gewehr SWT-40, das aber auch nicht völlig überzeugen konnte, was jedoch zu einem großen Teil auf die Eigenart der Munition zurückzuführen war. Während des Krieges wurde der Armeeführung bewusst, dass die Mosin-Patrone für den Gebrauch in Infanteriegewehren überdimensioniert war, jedoch Maschinenpistolen wie die Schpagin PPSch-41 eine zu geringe Reichweite hatten. Den Weg, wie diese Lücke zu füllen war, zeigte eine deutsche Entwicklung: die Kurzpatrone 7.92x33 mm, wie sie im Sturmgewehr 44 verwendet wurde.\n \nEntwicklung:\nSchon im Jahr 1943 wurde die neue Patrone vorgestellt: sie war randlos (was ihre Verwendung in automatischen Waffen begünstigte) und stark konisch (was das Einführen in die Patronenkammer bzw. das Herausziehen aus der Kammer erleichterte). Die erste Waffe auf Grundlage der neuen M 43 erschien bereits ein Jahr darauf mit dem Gewehr Simonow SKS-45 des Konstrukteurs Sergej Gawrilowitsch Simonow. Die Patrone wurde daraufhin in Waffenprototypen von Michail Timofejewitsch Kalaschnikow verwendet, aus denen später das Sturmgewehr AK-47 entstand. Es gibt eine Vielzahl von stärkeren Gewehrpatronen als die M 43 und zweifellos präzisere und weiter reichende Waffen als die AK 47. Was der Kombination aus beiden eine so große Verbreitung verschaffte, war die Art und Weise, wie hierbei mehreren Anforderungen gleichermaßen Rechnung getragen wurde:\n
Hohe Zuverlässigkeit der AK 47, auch unter widrigen Gefechtsfeldbedingungen\nHohe Feuerrate\nAusreichende Reichweite und Genauigkeit auf mittlere Entfernungen\nSchützen können durch das geringere Gewicht der Patrone eine größere Menge an Munition mitführen\nIm Vergleich zu herkömmlichen Infanteriepatronen geringere Schützenbelastung durch geringeren Mündungsknall und Rückstoß.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 7.62o39 AI-->
		<string id="ammo-7.62x39-ap">
			<text>7.62x39mm (7N23)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x39-ap_s">
			<text>7.62x39mm (7N23)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x39-ap_descr">
			<text>Etnwicket von Barnaul-Werkzeugmaschinenfabrik D. Veronese und V. Zaharyaschevym, 7.62x39mm Panzerbrechend (Index 7N23). Es ist die Antwort auf die zunehmende Verwendung von kugelsicheren Westen, die innerhalb der militärischen Kräfte auf der ganzen Welt getragen werden. Die neue Patrone wurde 2002 verabschiedet und entworfen worden, um Ziele in Schutzwesten, geöffneten Schutzräumen und normale Fahrzeugen zu agieren.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 7.62x51 IAOI -->
		<string id="ammo-7.62x51-fmj">
			<text>7.62x51mm NATO</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x51-fmj_s">
			<text>7.62x51mm</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x51-fmj_descr">
			<text>Die Patrone 7.62x51mm NATO ist eine Gewehrpatrone mit großer Verbreitung im Militär- und Jagdbereich. Die Zentralfeuerpatrone ist auch als 7.62x51mm CETME/NATO und .308 Winchester bekannt.\nIm Jahre 1957 wurde die Patrone – als erste Patrone für Handfeuerwaffen – als NATO-Standard 2310 standardisiert. Bis in die 1980er-Jahre war sie damit eine der am meisten verwendeten Patronen in der westlichen Welt.\n \n:Entwicklung:\nDie Patrone 7.62x51mm wurde als Ablösung der Patrone .30-06 Springfield von Frankford Arsenal aus der .300 Savage entwickelt. Im Dezember 1953 wurde sie als Standardpatrone der NATO eingeführt. Die Firma Winchester bot diese Patrone erstmals 1951 unter der zivilen Bezeichnung .308 Winchester an. In Deutschland wird die Patrone vor allem im Sturmgewehr Heckler & Koch G3 und dem Maschinengewehr MG3 verwendet.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 7.62x51 IAOI AI -->
		<string id="ammo-7.62x51-ap">
			<text>7.62x51mm AP</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x51-ap_s">
			<text>7.62x51mm AP</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x51-ap_descr">
			<text>Eine Panzerbrechnede version der 7.62x51mm NATO-Patrone aus  den USA. Verwendet einen gehärteten Stahlkern, der mit einer schwarzen Spitze gemalt ist.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 7.62o54 7I1 -->
		<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h1">
			<text>7.62x54mm</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h1_s">
			<text>7.62x54mm</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h1_descr">
			<text>Die 7.62x54R PP (7N13) ist eine Varianten der 7.62x54R. Hergestellt für PKM Machinengewehre. Hat einen gehärteten Stahlkern und ist entworfen, um 10mm Rüstung auf 200m zu druchdringen.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 7.62o54 7I14 -->
		<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14">
			<text>7.62x54mm 7N14</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14_s">
			<text>7.62x54mm 7N14</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14_descr">
			<text>7.62x54mm SNB (Index 7N14,) Is a sniper round for the SVD and other Russian sniper rifles. It provides improved accuracy and range, and has moderate armor penetration capabilities. The cartridge has a bimetallic case.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 7.62o54 7I26 -->
		<string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap">
			<text>7.62x54mm PS</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap_s">
			<text>7.62x54mm PS</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap_descr">
			<text>Armor piercing variant of 7.62x54mm cartridge. Uses a steel core for the penetration of armor. Like many Russian rounds it uses a bimetallic or lacquered steel case instead of a brass case, for cost effectiveness and ease of manufacture.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 8.6x70 -->
		<string id="ammo-8,6x70-fmj">
			<text>.338 Lapua Magnum</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-8,6x70-fmj_s">
			<text>.338 Lapua Magnum</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-8,6x70-fmj_descr">
			<text>338 Lapua Magum (8.6x70mm) is a cartridge developed specifically for long range sniper rifles with a maximum range of approximately 1500m. The Afghanistan War and Iraq War made it a combat-proven round with ready and substantial ammunition availability. The .338 Lapua is a dual-purpose, anti-personnel and anti-materiel round, but its anti-materiel potential is limited, due to the bullet's lower kinetic energy compared with that of the .50 BMG's 35.64-to-55.08-gram (550.0 to 850.0 gr) projectiles.</text>
		</string>
<!-- GAUSS -->
		<string id="ammo-gauss">
			<text>2mm Flash rounds</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-gauss_s">
			<text>2mm Flash</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-gauss_descr">
			<text>Energy cells prepared with lethal elements in a Gauss rifle magazine. The energy source is an encapsulated piece of the Flash Artifact.</text>
		</string>
<!-- miniGAUSS -->
		<string id="ammo-gauss_cardan">
			<text>2mm Flash Cardan</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-gauss_cardan_s">
			<text>2mm Flash Cardan</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-gauss_cardan_descr">
			<text>Energy cells prepared with lethal elements in a Gauss rifle magazine. The energy source is an encapsulated piece of the Flash Artifact.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 7.62o54 IEI -->
		<string id="ammo-7.62x54-pkm">
			<text>7.62x54mm 7N26</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x54-pkm_s">
			<text>7.62x54mm 7N26</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x54-pkm_descr">
			<text>Armor piercing round developed in 2002 at the Novosibirsk cartridge plant. Designed to engage manpower behind light armored cover, at ranges up to 500 metres.</text>
		</string>
<!-- IA-7A -->
		<string id="ammo-og-7b">
			<text>OG-7V "Êàðàíäàø"</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-og-7b_s">
			<text>OG-7V</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-og-7b_descr">
			<text>A highly-explosive 40mm fragmentation warhead for the RPG-7. Equally effective against troops and light armored vehicles.</text>
		</string>
<!-- a?aiaoa O1 -->
		<string id="st_grenade_f1">
			<text>F1 Grenade</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_grenade_f1_descr">
			<text>A defensive hand grenade with a large radius of shrapnel damage. It is recommended to throw it only from behind cover.</text>
		</string>
<!-- a?aiaoa ?AA-5 -->
		<string id="st_grenade_rgd5">
			<text>RGD-5 Grenade</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_grenade_rgd5_descr">
			<text>>An offensive hand grenade with a small radius of shrapnel damage.</text>
		</string>
<!-- a?aiaoa AA-5 -->
		<string id="st_grenade_smoke">
			<text>GD-05 Smoke</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_grenade_smoke_descr">
			<text>A smoke grenade. Creates a smoke screen for cover. Lasts for 10 seconds.</text>
		</string>
<!-- a?aiaoa GL-1 -->
		<string id="st_grenade_light_descr">
			<text>Chemical flare grenade. Designed to illuminate areas during night fights, and to dazzle and disorient the enemy. Lasts less than a minute.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_grenade_light">
			<text>GL-1</text>
		</string>
<!-- AIA-25 -->
		<string id="ammo-vog-25">
			<text>VOG-25 Grenade</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-vog-25_s">
			<text>VOG-25</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-vog-25_descr">
			<text>A 40mm grenade for the GP-25 grenade launcher, the OC-14 "Groza"'s integrated grenade launcher, and the RG-6 revolver grenade launcher.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AIA-25I -->
		<string id="ammo-vog-25p">
			<text>VOG-25P Grenade</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-vog-25p_s">
			<text>VOG-25P</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-vog-25p_descr">
			<text>A 40mm grenade for the GP-25 grenade launcher, the OC-14 "Groza"'s integrated grenade launcher, and the RG-6 revolver grenade launcher. Prior to explosion, the grenade leaps in to the air about one meter, increasing its kill effectiveness.</text>
		</string>
<!-- M209 -->
		<string id="ammo-m209">
			<text>M209 Grenade</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-m209_s">
			<text>M209 Grenade</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-m209_descr">
			<text>A 40mm grenade for the M203 grenade launcher (for the LR-300, G36, SIG-550, and L85A2 rifles) and the integrated grenade launcher of the FN F2000.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae aey Galil -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_galil">
			<text>Galil sight</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_galil_descr">
			<text>Optical sight for the Israeli IMI Galil machinegun.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae iioe?aneee II 4x34 -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_4x34">
			<text>PO 4x34</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_4x34_descr">
			<text>Optical sight featuring variable magnification. Used on hunting rifles and are designed for precise focusing when shooting. The weapon sights are mounted using special brackets.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae ONI-1 "O?euiai" -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_1p29">
			<text>1P29</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_1p29_descr">
			<text>The USP-1 sight (index 1P29) has an optical arrangement with a prism-erecting system. Sighting angles are set mechanically by turning the sight body relative to the weapon mounting bracket. The sight requires no batteries as it is tritium illuminated . The ranging scale at the edge of the sight field off view provides a means to find visually the range of up to 1200 m of a target 1.5 m high.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae 1II93 -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_1pn93">
			<text>1PN93-4</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_1pn93_descr">
			<text>Russian night sights designed to monitor the battlefield and assit aimed shooting in conditions of bad visibility.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae «Eia?a» YEI-1N-03 -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_kobra-ekp-1s-03">
			<text>EKP 1S-03 Kobra</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae «Eia?a» YEI-8-02 -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_kobra-ekp-8-02">
			<text>EKP-8-02 Kobra</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_kobra_descr">
			<text>The Kobra sight is an open collimator combat optic using a laser generated HUD to superimpose a reticle pattern onto a filtered lens. It is designed for engaging fast moving targets and targets appearing for a short period of time in close quarters and urban combat situations in various light conditions. It provides clear targeting from 104 lx to 10-2 lx (daylight, twilight and moonlight), one- or two-eye targeting, is very effective when shooting from moving vehicles, and allows for perfect kill shots on fast-moving, small and spontaneously appearing targets.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae EOTech -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_eotech">
			<text>EO-Tech Sight</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_eotech_descr">
			<text>Holographic sight for NATO assault rifles and sub-machine guns.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae C-more Railway Tactical -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_c-more">
			<text>C-MORE Tactical Sight</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_c-more_descr">
			<text>High performance red dot sight that provides an unlimited field of view, while eliminating obstruction and tunnel vision common to tube style scopes.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae DOCTER Sight  -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_docter_sight">
			<text>DOCTER Sight</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_docter_sight_descr">
			<text>Due to its light weight as well as compact pipeless design, these sights see wide spread applications both in hunting and for sport. Reliable performance, high optical power, attractive design and trouble-free operation even in extreme weather conditions make the sight DOCTER sight irreplaceable.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae IE-A -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_pk-a">
			<text>PK-A</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_pk-a_descr">
			<text>The PK-A red dot sight is a reflex sight produced by BelOMO in Minsk, Belarus. The sight is compatible with side-mounted systems commonly found on AK, SKS, and SVD-type rifles. The sight uses a single red dot within a nitrogen-filled lens setup and has eight brightness levels.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae ACOG -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_acog">
			<text>Trijicon ACOG</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_acog_descr">
			<text>Advanced Combat Optical Gunsights are a series of telescopic sights manufactured by Trijicon. Can be mounted on NATO assault rifles and sub-machine guns as well as the AK-12.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae Barska RED DOT 2o30ii. AC11090 -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_ac11090">
			<text>AC11090 Red Dot Sight</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_ac11090_descr">
			<text>Cheap 2x magnification red dot sight for NATO assault rifles and sub-machine guns.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addons_box">
			<text>Multi-Tool</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addons_box_descr">
			<text>Compact multi tool with numerous hex bits and punch tools used to unmount optical sights.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae INI-1 -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope">
			<text>PSO-1</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_descr">
			<text>A common Soviet-made 5.0x fixed zoom optical scope with a range scale. Attached to weapons by means of a dovetail mount, which is standard in Warsaw Pact countries.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae INI-1I2-01 -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_pso-1m2-01">
			<text>PSO-1M2-01</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_pso-1m2-01_descr">
			<text>TThe PSO-1M2-O1 features an extremely effective and useful height-based rangefinder for dual use, with graduated scales for both standing and prone figure estimation. The 400 meter Simonov height based gradient (choke style) rangefinder has a chevron for use with the 9x39 caliber rifles.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae INO-1 -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_x2.7">
			<text>PSO-1</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_x2.7_descr">
			<text>Optical sight with a fixed multiplicity (2.7). Optimized for combat at medium distances, and also for use in urban areas. For mounting fastening type "dovetail"</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae ii?iie 1II58 (INIOI-2) -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_night_vision">
			<text>NSPU-3 scope</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_night_vision_descr">
			<text>An image intensifier night vision 5.0x fixed zoom scope for combat in darkness. Attached to weapons by means of a dovetail mount.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae 1I21) -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_detector">
			<text>>PSS-2x scope</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_detector_descr">
			<text>A 5.0x fixed zoom optical scope with a built-in heat visor used to identify heat sources typical of the human body. Designed for use by special forces. Attached to weapons by means of a dovetail mount.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae SUSAT) -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_susat">
			<text>SUSAT</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_descr">
			<text>Optical sight SUSAT L9A1 - Sight Unit Small Arms, Trilux. Most often used for aimed fire from small arms and light weapons at medium and long distances. Mounted on Picatinny rail.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae SUSAT) -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_x1.6">
			<text>ACOG 1.6x</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_x1.6_descr">
			<text>Optical sight ACOG. Most often used for aimed fire from small arms and light weapons in small and medium distances. Mounted on Picatinny rail.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae SUSAT-D) -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_dusk">
			<text>ACOG-D</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_dusk_descr">
			<text>Optical sight ACOG-D. Designed for close combat in low light conditions. Mounted on Picatinny rail.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae SUSAT-N) -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_night_vision">
			<text>ACOG-N</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_night_vision_descr">
			<text>Optical sight ACOG-N - Trilux, Night sighting device for small arms with lights "TRILUX" with integrated night vision device). Designed for combat in the absence of light sources. Mounted on Picatinny rail.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?eoae SUSAT-RF) -->
		<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_custom">
			<text>ACOG-RF</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_custom_descr">
			<text>Optical sight ACOG-RF - Trilux, RangeFinder (sighting device for small arms with lights "TRILUX" with custom rangefinder magnification). You can adjust the magnification to improve accuracy of fire. Mounted on Picatinny rail.</text>
		</string>
<!-- IAN -->
		<string id="st_addon_silencer">
			<text>9mm Suppressor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_silencer_descr">
			<text>Suppressor for 9mm pistols and sub-machine guns.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 6I9 -->
		<string id="st_addon_sil_6p9">
			<text>6P9 Suppressor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_sil_6p9_descr">
			<text>Suppressor for use on the PB pistol.</text>
		</string>
<!-- 57 -->
		<string id="st_addon_sil_57">
			<text>5.7x28mm Suppressor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_sil_57_descr">
			<text>Suppressor for use on the FN P90 PDW.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Aeooae aey 9A-91 -->
		<string id="st_addon_sil_9a91">
			<text>9A-91 Suppressor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_sil_9a91_descr">
			<text>Suppressor for the 9A-91 carbine.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Aeooae aey AIN (IO-33) -->
		<string id="st_addon_sil_aps">
			<text>OTs-33 Suppressor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_sil_aps_descr">
			<text>Suppressor for the OTs-33 carbine.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Aeooeoaeu GemTech -->
		<string id="st_addon_sil_gemtech">
			<text>GemTech Suppressor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_sil_gemtech_descr">
			<text>Suppressor for the Glock and the FN FNP.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Aeooae aey Aeo?y -->
		<string id="st_addon_sil_vihr">
			<text>SR-3M Suppressor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_sil_vihr_descr">
			<text>Suppressor for the SR-3M.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Aeooeoaeu 45-ai eaeea?a. -->
		<string id="st_addon_sil_45">
			<text>.45 ACP Suppressor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_sil_45_descr">
			<text>Suppressor for .45 ACP pistols and sub-machine guns</text>
		</string>
<!-- AOA -->
		<string id="st_addon_sil_atg">
			<text>ATG Suppressor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_sil_atg_descr">
			<text>Suppressor for the 5.56 mm AK102 and 7.62 mm AK 103 and AK 104 Kalashnikov rifles.</text>
		</string>
<!-- OAI-A -->
		<string id="st_addon_sil_tgp-a">
			<text>TGP-A Suppressor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_sil_tgp-a_descr">
			<text>Suppressor for 5.45 mm machine guns.</text>
		</string>
<!-- IAN-1 -->
		<string id="st_addon_sil_pbs-1">
			<text>PBS-1 Suppressor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_sil_pbs-1_descr">
			<text>Kalashnikov Suppressor.</text>
		</string>
<!-- IAN-4 -->
		<string id="st_addon_sil_pbs-4">
			<text>PBS-4</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_sil_pbs-4_descr">
			<text>Suppressor for the shortened 5.45mm kalashnikov (AKS-74U).</text>
		</string>
<!-- EC?CI -->
		<string id="st_addon_sil_kzrzp">
			<text>KZRZP Suppressor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_sil_kzrzp_descr">
			<text>Suppressor for the SVD sniper rifle</text>
		</string>
<!-- I5.56-A -->
		<string id="st_addon_sil_nato">
			<text>NATO Suppressor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_sil_nato_descr">
			<text>Suppressor for the standard NATO 5.56x45 caliber, as well as for 11.43x23 pistols and submachine guns</text>
		</string>
<!-- G&P SR-25 Silencer -->
		<string id="st_addon_sil_sr25">
			<text>G&P SR-25 Suppressor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_addon_sil_sr25_descr">
			<text>Suppressor for the SR-25.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AI-25 -->
		<string id="st_grenade_launcher">
			<text>GP-25 Kostyor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_grenade_launcher_descr">
			<text>A single shot, front loaded, rifled underbarrel grenade launcher for assault rifles made in Warsaw Pact countries. The firing mechanism is self-cocking, with a manual safety catch and automatic shot prevention if incorrectly installed onto a rifle. Uses VOG-25 grenades.</text>
		</string>
<!-- M203 -->
		<string id="st_grenade_launcher_m203">
			<text>M203</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_grenade_launcher_m203_descr">
			<text>A modified M203 grenade launcher that has been shortened by three inches, attached to weapons by means of a Picatinny Rail. Thanks to a changed mount, this grenade launcher is widely used around the world.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AG36 -->
		<string id="st_grenade_launcher_ag36">
			<text>H&K AG36</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_grenade_launcher_ag36_descr">
			<text>The AG36 is a single-shot 40 mm grenade launcher that operates on the High-Low System and was designed primarily for installation on the G36 assault rifle, designed by the German weapons manufacturing company Heckler and Koch.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Ii? -->
		<string id="st_knife">
			<text>knife</text>
		</string>
<!-- 9A-91 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_9a91">
			<text>9A-91</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_9a91_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]EKP 1S-03 Kobra, EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1M2-01, 9A-91 Suppressor\n\nThe 9A-91 is a carbine assault rifle currently in use with Russian police forces. It is a gas operated, rotating bolt weapon, which utilizes a long stroke gas piston, located above the barrel, and a rotating bolt with 4 lugs. The receiver is made from steel stampings; the forend and pistol grip are made from polymer. The steel buttstock folds up and above the receiver when not in use. The charging handle is welded to the right side of bolt carrier. The safety / fire selector lever is located at the left side of the receiver, above the trigger guard, and allows for semi- and full-automatic fire. The flip-up rear sight has settings for 100 and 200 meters range, but the relatively short sight base and steep trajectory of the subsonic bullet effectively restricts the 9A91 to ranges of about 100 meters.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AIN -->
		<string id="st_wpn_aps">
			<text>APS</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_aps_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x18mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]E9mm Suppressor\n\nThe Stechkin APS is a Russian selective fire machine pistol. It bears the name of its developer, Igor Stechkin. The Stechkin automatic pistol was originally chambered for 7.62?25mm Tokarev. Stechkin changed the pistol to the 9 mm caliber used in the new Makarov pistol, as it became clear that this cartridge was set to become the new service ammunition for handguns of the Soviet Army. In 1951, both the Makarov and Stechkin were introduced into the Soviet military arsenal, replacing the aging TT-33.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AI-94 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_abakan">
			<text>AN-94 Abakan</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_abakan_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.45x39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]PSO scope, GP-25 grenade launcher, 5.45 suppressor\n\nThe AN-94 "Abakan" is an advanced Russian assault rifle. The Russian Government formally declared the AN-94 to be the successor & replacement to the legendary Kalashnikov series of rifles following the Project Abakan advanced assault rifle trials in the USSR throughout the 1980s. Gennadiy Nikonov's system reportedly outperformed its many remarkable rivals significantly, proving better than the AEK-971 and the AKB-1. The Nikonov AN-94 was commissioned for general issue to the Soviet armed forces, with mass production to be carried out by the historic Izhmash state factories. At present the AN-94 is only issused in limited quantities to the elite forces of the Russian Army, police and Internal Affairs Ministry due to its rather complicated design, production cost and the cost related to training in achiving its effective use in combat. The AN-94 offers a unique two-shot burst function at a stated 1800 rounds per minute rate of fire. The Nikonov mechanism fires the second shot in the burst quickly enough to allow it to escape before the recoil of the first shot is felt, thus potentially allowing the two shots to hit extremely close together, for example to aid in piercing body armor.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AAE-971 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_aek971">
			<text>AEK-971</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_aek971_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.45x39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]EKP 1S-03 Kobra, EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1, GP-25 grenade launcher, TGP-A Suppressor\n\nThe AEK-971 assault rifle was developed at Kovrov Machinebuilding Plant (formerly known as Kovrov Machineguns Plant) by chief designer S.I. Koksharov. Originally designed and tested during the 'Abakan' trials of the late 1980s, it failed in the trials, but its development was continued in hopes to sell the gun to police forces and for export. During the early 2000s small batches of AEK-971 rifles in 5.45x39 caliber were manufactured for Russian MVD troops, but has since then seen extremely limited production. Based on previous AK rifles in internal design and layout, the AEK-971 is also equipped with a recoil-balancing mechanism by way of a counter-weight that negates the impulse of the gas piston and bolt carrier, resulting in more controllable automatic fire.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AE-12 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_ak12">
			<text>AK-12</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_ak12_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.45x39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]Trijicon ACOG, AC11090 Red Dot Sight, C-MORE Tactical Sight, EO-Tech Sight, GP-25 grenade launcher, PBS-1 Suppressor\n\nThe Kalashnikov AK-12 assault rifle is the newest creation of the IZMASH factory. It is intended to replace in production older Kalashnikov AK-74M and AK-100-series rifles for domestic use, as well as for export. The AK-12 assault rifle is a gas operated, selective fire weapon using traditional “Kalashnikov type” action with long stroke gas piston and rotary bolt locking. The Bolt group is noticeably lightened to decrease recol and improve accuracy in full-automatic fire. Barrel has improved rifling for better accuracy, and a revised muzzle brake. The receiver is redesigned, key modification being new top cover of more rigid design. Elongated top cover is removably attached to the receiver using two dovetails plus a captive cross-pin at the rear. The rifle comes standard with pictanny rails and an adjustable telescoping stock.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AE -->
		<string id="st_wpn_ak">
			<text>AK</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_ak_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]7.62?39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]GP-25 grenade launcher, PBS-1 Suppressor\n\nThe AK is best described as a hybrid of previous rifle technology innovations. Kalashnikov decided to design an automatic rifle combining the best features of the American M1 and the German StG44. The Kalashnikov assault rifle, also known to the West as the AK-47, and its derivatives, also known under the common name of AK, is a selective-fire, gas-operated 7.62?39 assault rifle and by far the most prolific small arm of the 2nd half of the XX century. It had been and still is (in more or less modified form) manufactured in dozens of countries, and has been used in hundreds of conflicts since its introduction.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AEN -->
		<string id="st_wpn_aks">
			<text>AKS</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_aks_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]7.62?39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]GP-25 grenade launcher, PBS-1 Suppressor\n\nThe main variant of the AK-47 was the AKS-47, which was equipped with an under folding metal shoulder stock in place of the fixed wooden stock. It was designed for use inside armored vehicles and by paratroopers.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AE-74 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_ak74">
			<text>AK-74</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_ak74_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.45?39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]EKP 1S-03 Kobra, EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1, GP-25 grenade launcher, TGP-A Suppressor\n\nThe AK-74 is a 5.45mm assault rifle adapted in the early 1970s in the Soviet Union by Mikhail Kalashnikov from the earlier AKM. It was introduced in 1974 and first saw service with Soviet forces engaged in the Afghanistan conflict. Basically, it was the same old AKM rifle, adapted to the smaller 5.45mm cartridge and fitted with a relatively large muzzle brake.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_ak74_without_rail_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.45?39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]GP-25 grenade launcher, TGP-A Suppressor\n\nThe AK-74 is a 5.45mm assault rifle adapted in the early 1970s in the Soviet Union by Mikhail Kalashnikov from the earlier AKM. It was introduced in 1974 and first saw service with Soviet forces engaged in the Afghanistan conflict. Basically, it was the same old AKM rifle, adapted to the smaller 5.45mm cartridge and fitted with a relatively large muzzle brake.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_ak74_up_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.45?39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]GP-25 grenade launcher, TGP-A Suppressor\n\nThe AK-74 is a 5.45mm assault rifle adapted in the early 1970s in the Soviet Union by Mikhail Kalashnikov from the earlier AKM. It was introduced in 1974 and first saw service with Soviet forces engaged in the Afghanistan conflict. Basically, it was the same old AKM rifle, adapted to the smaller 5.45mm cartridge and fitted with a relatively large muzzle brake.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_ak74_up2_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.45?39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]GP-25 grenade launcher, TGP-A Suppressor\n\nThe AK-74 is a 5.45mm assault rifle adapted in the early 1970s in the Soviet Union by Mikhail Kalashnikov from the earlier AKM. It was introduced in 1974 and first saw service with Soviet forces engaged in the Afghanistan conflict. Basically, it was the same old AKM rifle, adapted to the smaller 5.45mm cartridge and fitted with a relatively large muzzle brake.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AE-74I -->
		<string id="st_wpn_ak74m">
			<text>AK-74M</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_ak74m_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.45?39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]EKP 1S-03 Kobra, EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1, GP-25 grenade launcher, TGP-A Suppressor\n\nIn 1991 the Izhmash factory in the city of Izhevsk began production of an improved variant of the AK-74 - the AK-74M assault rifle. Apart from several minor production improvements the rifle also features a new synthetic stock made from a black, glass-filled polyamide that is shaped like the AK-74 fixed stock, but also folds like in the AKS-74. Additionally the AK-74M uses a reinforced muzzle device and dust cover. Each AK-74M is fitted with a side-rail bracket for mounting optics. The AK-74M has been accepted as the new service rifle of the Russian Federation.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AE-74I Camo -->
		<string id="st_wpn_ak74m_camo">
			<text>AK-74M (camouflage)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_ak74m_camo_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.45?39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]EKP 1S-03 Kobra, EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1, GP-25 grenade launcher, TGP-A Suppressor\n\nCamouflaged variant of the AK-74M featuring an MTK-83 mount and a PK-A red dot sight.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AE-101 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_ak101">
			<text>AK-101</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_ak101_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]Trijicon ACOG, AC11090 Red Dot Sight, C-MORE Tactical Sight, EO-Tech Sight, GP-25 grenade launcher, ATG Suppressor\n\nThe AK-101 is an assault rifle of the Kalashnikov series designed for the world export market, using 5.56?45mm NATO cartridges, which is the standard of most NATO armies. The AK-101 is marketed at those looking for a weapon that combines the logistical compatibility and familiarity of the 5.56?45mm NATO round with the reliability of a Kalashnikov. It is designed with modern and composite materials, including plastics that reduce weight and improve accuracy. Many of the improvements found in the AK-101 are also present in the AK-103 and the rest of the AK-10x series of rifles.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AE-102 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_ak102">
			<text>AK-102</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_ak102_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]Trijicon ACOG, AC11090 Red Dot Sight, C-MORE Tactical Sight, EO-Tech Sight, ATG Suppressor\n\nThe AK-102 is a 5.56x45 shortened carbine version of the AK-101 rifle. It features a shortened barrel that makes it a middle ground between a full rifle and the more compact AKS-74U. The rifle's receiver is made of stamped steel. The magazine is made out of reinforced fiberglass. The butt stock is made of hollow plastic, making it lighter, more durable, and allowing a field kit to be stored in side of it.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AE-103 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_ak103">
			<text>AK-103</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_ak103_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]7.62x39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]EKP 1S-03 Kobra, EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1, GP-25, ATG Suppressor\n\nThe AK-103 assault rifle is a derivative of the AK-74M chambered for 7.62?39, same as the AKM and AK-47. The AK-103 can be fitted with a variety of sights, including laser, night vision, and telescopic sights, plus a suppressor and the GP-25 grenade launcher. It uses plastic components whenever possible instead of wood or metal in order to reduce weight.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AE-104 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_ak104">
			<text>AK-104</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_ak104_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]7.62x39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]EKP 1S-03 Kobra, EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1, ATG Suppressor\n\nThe AK-104 is a 7.62x39 shortened carbine version of the AK-103 rifle. It features a shortened barrel that makes it a middle ground between a full rifle and the more compact AKS-74U. The rifle's receiver is made of stamped steel. The magazine is made out of reinforced fiberglass. The butt stock is made of hollow plastic, making it lighter, more durable, and allowing a field kit to be stored in side of it.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AE-105 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_ak105">
			<text>AK-105</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_ak105_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.45x39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]EKP 1S-03 Kobra, EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1, TGP-A Suppressor\n\nThe AK-105 is a 5.45x39 shortened carbine version of the AK-74M rifle. It features a shortened barrel that makes it a middle ground between a full rifle and the more compact AKS-74U. The rifle's receiver is made of stamped steel. The magazine is made out of reinforced fiberglass. The butt stock is made of hollow plastic, making it lighter, more durable, and allowing a field kit to be stored in side of it.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AEI -->
		<string id="st_wpn_akm">
			<text>AKM</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_akm_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]7.62x39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]EKP 1S-03 Kobra, EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1, GP-25, PBS-1 Suppressor\n\nThe AKM is a 7.62mm assault rifle designed by Mikhail Kalashnikov. It is an upgraded version of the AK-47 rifle and was developed in the 1950's. Introduced into service with the Red Army in 1959, the AKM is the most ubiquitous variant of the entire AK series of firearms and it has found widespread use with most member states of the former Warsaw Pact and its many African and Asian allies. The production of Soviet rifles was carried out at both the Tula Arsenal and Izhevsk Mechanical Works.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AEIN -->
		<string id="st_wpn_akms">
			<text>AKMS</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_akms_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]7.62x39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]EKP 1S-03 Kobra, EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1, GP-25, PBS-1 Suppressor\n\nThe main variant of the AKM is the AKMS, which was equipped with an under-folding metal shoulder stock in place of the fixed wooden stock. The metal stock of the AKMS is somewhat different from the folding stock of the previous AK-47 model as it has a modified locking mechanism, which locks both support arms of the AKMS stock instead of just one (left arm) as in the AK-47 folding model.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AEN-74 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_aks74">
			<text>AKS-74</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_aks74_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.45x39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]EKP 1S-03 Kobra, EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1, GP-25, TGP-A Suppressor\n\nUnlike the AKMS, the AKS-74 stock has a triangular shape and lacks the folding shoulder pad of the AKMS (which increases the stock's rigidity) and is folded to the left side of the receiver. The hinged stock is securely locked in place in its extended position by a latch mechanism at the rear of the receiver. The latch release button is located on the left side of the receiver. When folded, the stock is held by a spring-loaded capture in the forward barrel trunnion. A rear sling swivel is also provided and placed on the right side of the lower stock frame.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AEN-74O -->
		<string id="st_wpn_ak74u">
			<text>AKS-74U</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.45x39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]EKP 1S-03 Kobra, EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1, PBS-4 Suppressor\n\nIn 1979 a shortened variant of the AKS-74 was adopted into service – the AKS-74U carbine, which in terms of tactical deployment, bridges the gap between a submachine gun and assault rifle. It is intended for use mainly with special forces, airborne infantry, rear-echelon support units and armored vehicle crews. The weapon's compact dimensions, compared to the AKS-74, were achieved by using a short, 210 mm (8.3 in) barrel (this forced designers to simultaneously reduce the gas piston operating rod to an appropriate length). A new gas block was installed at the muzzle end of the barrel and a new conical flash hider was used. The AKS-74U is significantly more maneuverable in tight quarters than the AKS-74, however the steep decline in muzzle velocity from 900 m/s (2,953 ft/s) to 735 m/s (2,411 ft/s) resulted in a decrease in effective aimed range.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_without_rail_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.45x39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]PBS-4 Suppressor\n\nIn 1979 a shortened variant of the AKS-74 was adopted into service – the AKS-74U carbine, which in terms of tactical deployment, bridges the gap between a submachine gun and assault rifle. It is intended for use mainly with special forces, airborne infantry, rear-echelon support units and armored vehicle crews. The weapon's compact dimensions, compared to the AKS-74, were achieved by using a short, 210 mm (8.3 in) barrel (this forced designers to simultaneously reduce the gas piston operating rod to an appropriate length). In order to effectively stabilize projectiles, the barrel's twist rate was reduced from 200 mm (7.9 in) to 160 mm (6.3 in). A new gas block was installed at the muzzle end of the barrel and a new conical flash hider was used, which features an internal expansion chamber that alleviates gas pressure generated during firing. The flash suppressor locks into the gas block with a latch placed on the right side. The forward sling loop was relocated to the left side. The weapon's front sight is integrated into the gas block base.\n\n The AKS-74U also has a different sight system setup with a U-shaped flip sight instead of the standard sliding notch sight. The rear sight has two settings: "P" (fixed for firing at 350 m) and "4-5" (used for firing at distances up to 400-500 m). The rear sight is housed in a semi-hooded shroud that is riveted to the receiver top cover. This top cover is connected with the gas tube cover and is hinged, pivoting forward when opened. Both the gas tube and hand-guard are also of a new type and are shorter than analogous parts in the AKS-74.\n\n The AKS-74U is significantly more maneuverable in tight quarters than the AKS-74, however the steep decline in muzzle velocity from 900 m/s (2,953 ft/s) to 735 m/s (2,411 ft/s) resulted in a decrease in effective aimed range (the effective hitting distance for a "running"-type silhouette was reduced from 625 to 350 m). The carbine cannot mount a bayonet or standard under-barrel grenade launcher. However, a suppressed 30 mm BS-1 grenade launcher was developed for this weapon that fires high-explosive dual purpose (HEDP) grenades. The grenades from the BS-1 are launched by blank cartridges and the weapon is cycled manually in this mode of operation. The majority of AKS-74U's were manufactured at the Tula Arms Factory rather than Izhmash.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AEN-74O -->
		<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_snag">
			<text>AKS-74U Snag</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_snag_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.45x39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]EKP-1S-03 kobra sight and PBS-4 Suppressor\nA modernized version of the AKS-74U rifle with a EKP-1S-03 kobra sight and a PBS-4 suppressor.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Steyr AUG A1 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_aug">
			<text>Steyr AUG A1</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_aug_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]NATO Suppressor\n\nThe Steyr AUG (Armee Universal Gewehr - Universal Army Rifle) had been in development since the late 1960s, as a replacement for venerable but obsolete Stg.58 (FN FAL). It was developed by the Austrian Steyr-Daimler-Puch company in close conjunction with Austrian Army. The major design is attributed to the three men - Horst Wesp, Karl Wagner and Karl Moser, who developed most of the rifle features. The new rifle has been adopted by the Austrian Army in 1977, as the Stg.77 (Assault rifle, model of 1977), and production began in 1978. Since then, the AUG gained serious popularity, being adopted by the armed forces of Australia, Austria, New Zealand, Oman, Malaysia, Saudi Arabia, Ireland and some others. It also was widely purchased by various security and law enforcement agencies worldwide, including the US Coastal Guard. The Steyr AUG can be considered as the most commercially successful bullpup assault rifle to date.</text>
		</string>
<!-- L96A1 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_l96a1">
			<text>L96A1</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_l96a1_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]7.62x51mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]None\n\nIn early 1980-ies British Army started the search forthe replacement ofthe aging L42 Enfield sniper rifles. Main compettitors were Parker-Hale with their Model 82 bolt action rifle, and Accuracy International, with their PM rifle. Eventually, the PM rifle won the competition and was accepted by the British Army under the designation of L96. One of the most notorious features of the PM rifle was the design of the stock. Instead of the solid polymer or wooden stock, PM/L96 rifle used a hollow polymer stock, made from two halves and assembled aroundaluminium bedding block, that extends through entire stock lenght. This line of rifles is among the best in the World of sniper rifles today.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Barrett M98B -->
		<string id="st_wpn_m98b">
			<text>Barrett M98B</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_m98b_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default].338 Lapua Mag\n\nThe Barrett M98B is a bolt-action long-range tactical rifle chambered in .338 Lapua Mag. Rather than modifying a hunting rifle, Barrett modified its original tactical design to create the M98B. The M98B features an adjustable butt stock and cheek pad for personalized comfort. Also, an adjustable trigger for preferable trigger control. A rear monopod on the stock and a front bi-pod for stability. Shooters can further personalize the rifle by attaching sights, lights and grips to its rail system. The M98B has a simple design making it easier for shooters to disassemble and clean.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Cz-75 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_cz75">
			<text>Cz-75</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_cz75_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default].40 S&amp;W\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]10mm Suppressor\n\nThe CZ-75 was developed in the Czech Republic by the Koucky brothers. This full-size semiautomatic pistol first appeared in 1975, and the production began circa 1976. The CZ-75 was intended for the export market. The CZ-75 accumulated best features from many preceding designs. The resulting pistol was aesthetically attractive, comfortable to handle and shoot, quite accurate and reliable in operation. Made by CZ in various versions and modifications, CZ-75 was also widely copied and cloned.</text>
		</string>
<!-- IMI Galil -->
		<string id="st_wpn_galil">
			<text>IMI Galil</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_galil_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]7.62x39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]PBS-1 Suppressor\n\nThe Galil is an Israeli assault rifle, designed by Yisrael Galili under Israeli Military Industries in 1969. Its design is based on that of the Finnish RK 62 rifle, which in turn is derived from the Russian AK-47. It was adopted by the Israeli Defence Forces (IDF) in 1972, beating out several other rifles and replacing the unreliable FN FAL. The Galil is noted for its reliability in combat conditions, and ease of maintenance.</text>
		</string>
<!-- HK G3 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_g3">
			<text>HK G3</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_g3_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]7.62x51mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]NATO Suppressor\n\nThe G3 is a battle rifle developed in the 1950s by the German armament manufacturer Heckler & Koch GmbH (H&K) in collaboration with the Spanish state-owned design and development agency CETME (Centro de Estudios Técnicos de Materiales Especiales). It is designed to use the 7.62x51 NATO round, and uses a Roller-delayed blowback action. The rifle owes its design to the CETME mod. A, which was designed by the german engineer Dr. Ludwig Vorgrimler. In 1957 Heckler & Koch bought the license to manufacture the rifle, where small modifications were made to the CETME design, and it was officially adopted into service in 1959, by the Bundeswehr as the G3, where it remained as the main service rifle until 1995 where it was replaced by the G36. Despite having been officially replaced by the German army, it is still in limited use. The G3 is also widely popular rifle among militaries all over the world, among a few nations that use it are Greece, Angola, Denmark, Iceland, Gabon, Lebanon, Iran, Mexico, Morocco, Norway, Phillipines, Turkey, Turkey, and Sweden.</text>
		</string>
<!-- HK G3SG1 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_g3sg1">
			<text>HK G3SG1</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_g3sg1_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]7.62x51mm\n\nAn accurized variant of the G3. The "SG" stands for Scharfschutzengewehr, or "sharpshooting rifle". The rifles were individually selected from the production line for their accuracy and then modified. A Zeiss 1.5-6x variable power telescopic sight was added using a HK claw mount attached to the receiver. The stock was extended slightly compared to the standard G3 fixed stock and comes with a heavy, dual-stage buffer and adjustable cheek rest. A special set trigger group was added for a crisp trigger pull of 1 lb. Automatic fire was retained.</text>
		</string>
<!-- FN Five-seveN -->
		<string id="st_wpn_fn57">
			<text>FN-57</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_fn57_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.7x28mm\n\nThe Five-seveN is a delayed blowback operated, semi-automatic firearm. It was designed by FN company (Belgium) as a complimentary sidearm for the P90 submachine-gun. The P90 and Five-seveN share the same ammunition, the 5.7x28mm SS190 cartridge. The key idea behind that ammunition and weapons is to provide good penetration against personnel, protected by modern body armour, while keeping weapons' weight, dimensions and recoil at the reasonable levels.</text>
		</string>
<!-- FN FNP -->
		<string id="st_wpn_fnp45">
			<text>FN FNP-45</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_fnp45_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default].45 ACP\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]GemTech Suppressor\n		\nThe FN FNP pistol is a series of semi-automatic, polymer-framed pistols manufactured in Columbia, SC, by FNH USA, a division of Fabrique Nationale de Herstal. The pistol debuted in early 2006. The FNP series weapons are hammer fired weapons utilizing a Browning cam system with an external extractor. The trigger module is housed inside the polymer frame as an individual unit connected to the hammer. The magazine release button is held in place by a retention pin which can be removed to allow the magazine release button to be reversed.</text>
		</string>
<!-- FN FNX -->
		<string id="st_wpn_fnx45">
			<text>FN FNX-45</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_fnx45_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default].45 ACP\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]SilencerCo .45 Osprey\n\nThe FNX line of pistols were introduced in 2009 by FNH USA, a US-based subsidiary of the famous Belgian gun making company FN Herstal. Originally developed to the requirements of the US Joint Combat Pistol Program, these pistols are manufactured in the USA and intended for military, law enforcement and civilian use. All FNX handguns are semi-automatic pistols with double/single action trigger and external hammer. FNX pistols use modified Browning-type locking system with short recoiling barrel that tips down to unlock from the slide, using cam-shaped cut below the breech. Frame of the every FNX pistol is made from impact-resistant polymer,  with removable backstraps of different sizes. Barrel and slide are made from stainless steel. FNX pistols feature fully ambidextrous controls, including frame-mounted manual safety/decocker and slide release levers, as well as magazine release buttons. Ammunition is fed from double stack, single feed box magazines. FNX-45 Tactical is a specialized variant of the basic FNX-45, that features extended threaded barrel and raised sights, to be used with detachable sound suppressor.</text>
		</string>
<!-- II-443 «A?a?» -->
		<string id="st_wpn_mp443">
			<text>MP-443 Grach</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_mp443_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x19mm\n\nThe MP-443 is a short recoil operated, locked breech pistol that was developed for the Russian Army trials, codenamed "Grach" (rook). These trials were started by issuing initial requirements for a new military pistol in 1993. Several designs were submitted to the trials, but the eventual winner was the pistol designed at the state Izhevsk Mechanical Plant by Vladimir Yarygin. This pistol, initially known as the 6P35 (military index during trials) or the MP-443 "Grach" (manufacturer's designation), is now officially adopted by the Russian Government for Military and Law Enforcement use under the PYa designation, and already issued to some Russian Army units.</text>
		</string>
<!-- OO-33 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_tt33">
			<text>TT-33</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_tt33_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]7.62x25mm\n\nThe TT-33 is a Russian 7.62x25 pistol. It was developed in the early 1930s by Fedor Tokarev as a service pistol for the Soviet military to replace the Nagant M1895 revolver. At one time or another most communist or Soviet bloc countries made a variation of the TT-33 pistol, until it was eventually replaced for use by first-line troops by the 8 round, 9x18mm Makarov PM in 1952. Production of the TT-33 in the USSR ended in 1954.</text>
		</string>
<!-- IO-33 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_oc33">
			<text>OTs-33 Pernach</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_oc33_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x18mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9mm Supressor\n\nOTs-33 "Pernach" (multivaned mace) is a recent entry into the small and very special class of automatic (machine) pistols, and is intended to replace obsolete Stechkin APS pistols in the hands of various special units in Russian police and other paramilitary units. Developed circa 1995-96 by the Igor Stechkin at the TSKIB SOO (central design bureau for sporting and hunting arms, Tula, Russia), the same designer who developed the APS, the OTs-33 is now in limited production by the KBP design bureau. OTs-33 has simplified "squared" shape and is much easier (and less expensive) to manufacture, as well as simpler in design. It is capable of fully automatic and semi-automatic fire, and can be fitted with a detachable folding shoulder stock, made of steel. It is in limited use with some OMON units in the Russian police force. Fixed sights have white inserts for improved visibility.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AO-18 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_gsh18">
			<text>Gsh-18</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_gsh18_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x19mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9mm Supressor\n\nThe GSh-18 is a 9 mm semi-automatic pistol developed in the early 1990s at the KBP Instrument Design Bureau in Tula. The pistol's name is derived from its designers - Gryazev and Shipunow, and the number 18 denotes the magazine capacity. The GSh-18 is a recoil-operated, locked breech pistol. The weapon has an unusual cam-rotated barrel with 10 locking lugs. The GSh-18 is striker-fired and features a pre-set trigger that pre-cocks the pistol when the slide recoils after firing a shot. The striker firing pin is then fully cocked by pulling the trigger back to the rear.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Glock 17 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_glock17">
			<text>Glock 17</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_glock17_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x19mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9mm Supressor\n\nInstead of adopting an existing design to meet the requirements, Gaston Glock, owner of a relatively small company Glock GmbH, called for the best designers and experts and asked them to create an ideal pistol. It was clear that the Austrian Army wanted a defensive pistol – simple, reliable, lightweight and inexpensive. The Glock team accordingly created what would be called the most utilitarian pistol of recent decades. The low weight was achieved by using a polymer frame – a solution probably borrowed from the Austrian Stg.77 (Steyr AUG) assault rifle, adopted in 1978. Simplicity of operation combined with a minimum number of parts were achieved by using patented “safe action” trigger system, which has no manual safeties.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Glock 19-->
		<string id="st_wpn_glock19">
			<text>Glock 19</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_glock19_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x19mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9mm Supressor\n\nThe Glock 19 is a smaller pistol (defined as "compact") based on teh original Glock 17 with the new gun made easier to conceal for use by military and police forces. The pistol was debuted by Glock GbmH of Austria in 1988. When compared to the Glock 17, the Glock 19 retaind the wieght ot its slide to keep the short recoil operation in check while at teh same time shortening the grip and barrel. Many of the components of the Glock 19 were made interchangeable with the Glock 17 and this included teh magazine. Essentially, the Glock 19 was teh same design, just made more compact.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Naeaa-12E -->
		<string id="st_wpn_saiga">
			<text>Saiga-12K</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_saiga_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]12x70, 12x76\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]EKP 1S-03 Kobra, EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1, 12 Gauge Suppressor\n\n]The Saiga-12 is a Kalashnikov-pattern 12 gauge combat shotgun available in a wide range of configurations. Like the Kalashnikov rifle variants, it is a rotating bolt, gas-operated gun that feeds from a box magazine. All Saiga-12 configurations are recognizable as Kalashnikov-pattern guns by the large lever-safety on the right side of the receiver, the optic mounting rail on the left side of the receiver and the large top-mounted dust cover held in place by the rear of the recoil spring assembly. The rumored inaccuracy of Kalashnikov type guns is not an important shortcoming in a shotgun, a weapon rarely used beyond 50 yards. However, the loose and reliable design is an enormous boon on a semi-automatic shotgun, as this class of weapon had previously tended towards unreliability. The gun is also readily affordable and easy to maintain, made almost entirely from sheet-metal stampings.The Saiga-12 is manufactured by the arms division of Izhmash, in Russia. It was previously imported into the US by European American Armories, although their agreement expired in 2005 and Izhmash is now exporting through the Russian-American Armory Company.</text>
		</string>
<!-- ?IE -->
		<string id="st_wpn_rpk">
			<text>RPK</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_rpk_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]7.62x39mm\n\nThe RPK is a Soviet light machine gun, developed by Mikhail Kalashnikov in 1961 based on the design of the Kalashnikov assault rifle. Created as part of Soviet efforts to standardize the armoury of the Red Army, the RPK replaced the RPD in service and is still in use to present day.</text>
		</string>
<!-- ?IE-74 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_rpk74">
			<text>RPK-74</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_rpk74_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.45x39mm\n\nThe RPK-74 is a 5.45x39mm light machine gun of Soviet design, developed by Mikhail Kalashnikov in the late 1950s, parallel with the AKM assault rifle. It was created as part of a program designed to standardize the small arms inventory of the Red Army, where it replaced the 7.62x39mm RPD light machine gun. The RPK continues to be used by the armed forces of countries of the former Soviet Union and certain African and Asian nations.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Beretta M92 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_beretta">
			<text>Beretta 92</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_beretta_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x19mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9mm Suppressor\n\nAdopted by the American army and police, as well as many military and police units all over the world. It is especially popular among criminals for its high-powered rounds and high-capacity magazine.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AI-16 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_bm16">
			<text>TOZ-66 Sawn-off</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_bm16_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]12x70, 12x76\n\nA double-barreled shotgun with shortened barrels. Lighter and more compact, but is only effective at close range.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Colt M1911A1 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_colt1911">
			<text>Colt M1911A1</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_colt1911_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default].45 ACP\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default].45 Suppressor\n\nBetween 1906-1907, the U.S. Army announced trials to replace its service revolvers with a new, semi-automatic pistol. The Army required the new pistol to have the caliber of .45 inch, so Browning designed its own cartridge that fired a 230 grains (14.9 gram) bullet, and then, designed a new pistol. In 1911, after extensive testings, the new pistol and its cartridge, designed by Browning and manufactured by Colt, were adopted for U.S. military service as the M1911. Prior to and during World War One, more than one million of these pistols were manufactured, mostly by Colt and Springfield Armoury, as well as by Remington-UMC, Burroughs, Savage and some other companies. The rights to manufacture Colt/Browning design were also sold to some foreign countries, such as Norway or Argentine.In 1926, original design was improved, following the recommendations of the US Army Ordnanve Dept. These changes incorporate: a wider front sight, longer hammer spur, Shorter trigger, Curved spring housing, simplified grip panels checkering, index finger reliefs behind the trigger, and a longer grip-safety spur. The improved design was adopted by US Military as M1911A1 pistol, and served with distinction until the mid-1980-ies.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Kimber Desert Warrior -->
		<string id="st_wpn_colt1911_kimber">
			<text>Kimber Desert Warrior</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_colt1911_kimber_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default].45 ACP\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default].45 Suppressor\n\nAn advanced variant of the Colt M1911A1 developed by Kimber Manufacturing.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Desert Eagle -->
		<string id="st_wpn_eagle">
			<text>Desert Eagle</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_eagle_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default].50 AE\n\nThe Desert Eagle Pistol was conceived in 1979, when three people with an idea for creating a gas-operated, semi-automatic, magnum-caliber pistol founded Magnum Research, Inc. in St. Paul, Minnesota (USA). Magnum Research, Inc. patented the basic design of the Desert Eagle in 1980, but the final refinements to the pistol were made by Israel Military Industries (IMI), under contract to Magnum Research, Inc. In around 1996, Magnum Research, Inc. successfully introduced the .50 Action Express Desert Eagle Pistol to fill an unmet need in the sporting/hunting market. Today Desert eagle pistols are used for competitive shooting as well as for hunting and general plinking.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_eagle_nimble_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default].50 AE\n\nA variant of the Desert Eagle pistol featuring a unique color scheme, a DOCTER red dot sight, and a compensator to reduce recoil.</text>
		</string>
<!-- FAMAS -->
		<string id="st_wpn_famas">
			<text>FAMAS F1</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_famas_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]Trijicon ACOG, AC11090 Red Dot Sight, C-MORE Tactical Sight, EO-Tech Sight, NATO Suppressor\n\nFAMAS stands for Fusil d'Assaut de la Manufacture d'Armes de St-Etienne (Assault Rifle by St-Etienne Arms Factory - a member of the French govt. owned GIAT Industries concern). Development of this rifle began in 1967, under the leadership of the Paul Tellie, a French arms designer. This new rifle was intended to replace in service the MAS Mle.49/56 semi-automatic rifles, MAT-49 submachine guns and some MAC Mle.1929 light machine guns. The first FAMAS prototype had been built in 1971. French military began to test this rifle in 1972-73, but, in the meantime, France adopted a Swiss-designed SIG SG-540 5.56mm assault rifle as an intermediate solution. The FAMAS rifle was adopted by the French in 1978 and since then became a standard French Army shoulder fired small arm, known among the French soldiers as "Le Clairon"(the bulge).</text>
		</string>
<!-- FN-2000 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_fn2000">
			<text>FN F2000</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_fn2000_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]NATO Suppressor\n\nDuring the late 1980-ies and early 1990-ies famous Belgian company FN Herstal began the search for its next entry into the assault rifle world. The aim this time was to produce a modern, modular weapon, and this ultimately resulted in the FN F2000 rifle, which was first displayed in public in 2001. The F2000 offers all of the most popular features of the modern assault rifle, such as a compact bullpup layout, completely ambidextrous handling, and a modular design with plenty of options and add-ons already available, which allow the rifle to be “tailored” for any particular mission or tactical situation. So far the FN F2000 rifle found only a few buyers, including the Armed forces of Slovenia and Belgian Special operations forces. Nevertheless, it is one of most promising assault rifles on the market.</text>
		</string>
<!-- II-19 «Aecii» -->
		<string id="st_wpn_bizon">
			<text>PP-19 Bizon</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_bizon_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x18mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]PBS-1 Suppressor\n\nThis interesting submachine gun had been developed in Izhevsk at the famous IZHMASH state arms factory during the early 1990s, and first appeared on public circa 1993. Obviously influenced by the somewhat unsuccessful Calico submachine guns, Bizon (Bison) SMG combined high capacity "helical"magazine with more conventional appearance and layout. Bizon submachine guns are built on shortened AKS-74 receivers, made from stamped steel. It featured a simple blowback action, hammer fired from closed bolt. Feed is from "helical" magazines, made mostly of plastic and mounted under the barrel. The design of those cylindrically shaped magazines are loosely based on American Calico designs. The Bizon is capable of semi-automatic and full automatic fire, with typical AK-typesafety - selector lever at the right side of the receiver. Sturdy skeletonized buttstock is made from stamped steel and folds to the left side when not needed.Sights are similar to ones found on the AKS-74U, with hooded front post and flip-up rear.</text>
		</string>
<!-- FN P90 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_p90">
			<text>FN P90</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_p90_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.7x28mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]Trijicon ACOG, AC11090 Red Dot Sight, C-MORE Tactical Sight, EO-Tech Sight, 5.7mm Suppressor\n\nThe FN P90 submachine gun (SMG) was developed in the late 1980s as a personal defense weapon for the troops whose primary activities does not include small arms, such as vehicle and tank crew members, artillery crews etc. Standard pistols and submachine guns chambered for pistol rounds were proved ineffective against enemy soldiers, wearing body armor; Therefore FN designers first developed a new round with enhanced penetration, initially known as SS90. To achieve necessary high penetration while keeping recoil impulse low, FN used a small-bore approach, creating a round that looked much like the scaled down 5.56 NATO round. Resulting weapon appeared in around 1990 as FN P90 personal defense weapon, along with improved 5.7x28 SS190 ammunition, which replaced polymer-cored bullets with heavier dual-core (steel / aluminum) bullets with better penetration against body armor. Several other types of ammunition were developed for this weapon, including tracer, subsonic ball and soft-core training ball.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Oi?o-12 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_fort">
			<text>Fort-12</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_fort_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x18mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9mm Suppressor\n\nThe Fort 12 pistol is an attempt of the independent Ukraine (one of the former USSR republics) to develop its own police pistol to replace Soviet era, aging Makarov PM pistols. To accomplish this task, Ukrainian state-owned FORT factory purchased Czech machinery from CZ-Uhersky Brod factory, and by the late 1990s developed its first pistol, the Fort 12. Currently, this gun is issued to the Ukrainian police and security forces and also sold on civilian market chambered for non-lethal rubber ammunition or tear gas ammunition. Early production Fort 12 pistols were reported as only marginally reliable, but at the present time most of the teething problems are gone, and Fort 12 pistol provides some improvements over the older Makarov PM in the ergonomics, accuracy and magazine capacity.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Oi?o-17 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_fort17">
			<text>Fort-17</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_fort17_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x18mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9mm Suppressor\n\nThe Fort 17 pistol is the latest development of the Ukrainian state-owned FORT factory. Basically, it is a polymer-framed modification of the earlier Fort 12 pistol, and all the mechanisms and properties are almost the same between these two pistols. However, the Fort 17 is lighter than its predecessor, and features a removable grip backstrap, which can be had in various sizes, to adopt the pistol for a particular shooter.</text>
		</string>
<!-- HK G36 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_g36">
			<text>HK G36</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_g36_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\nThe Heckler und Koch G-36 assault rifle had been born as the HK-50 project in early 1990s. The reason behind that project was that the Bundeswehr (the German army), after the cancellation of the G11 and G41 projects, was left with outdated G3 rifles. Therefore the famous company Heckler & Koch was set to develop a new assault rifle for both the German army and for export. The new 5.56mm assault rifle was adopted by the Bundeswehr in the 1995. The G36 also found its way into the hands of various law enforcement agencies worldwide, including British police and some US police departments. So far, there have been very few complaints about this rifle. The more common ones being the overheating of the handguards during sustained fire, and the loose of zero on the built in scope of some G36KE rifles. Some German soldiers also complained about the position of the dual optical sights and those sights being easily fogged in bad weather. Otherwise it is a good rifle, accurate, reliable, simple in operations and maintenance</text>
		</string>
<!-- HK G36C -->
		<string id="st_wpn_g36c">
			<text>HK G36C</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_g36c_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]Trijicon ACOG, AC11090 Red Dot Sight, C-MORE Tactical Sight, EO-Tech Sight, NATO Suppressor\n\nFor those soldiers who need to work in tight spaces, the standard G36 setup was less than ideal. In order to give those special forces soldiers something truly special, H&K designed a shorter version of the G36 they dubbed the "C" or carbine version. The main changes are a drastically shortened barrel and a re-positioned gas block to keep the gun cycling even despite the shorter dwell time in the barrel. The gun is noticeably lighter by almost a full pound. The interiors of the gun are all steel, but the chassis is made out of a high strength polymer. This makes for a sleek looking firearm that is very light weight. The magazine sports a set of nubs on the exterior that are designed to slot into one another, and allow the shooter to tie multiple magazines together.</text>
		</string>
<!-- HK G36K -->
		<string id="st_wpn_g36k">
			<text>HK G36K</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_g36k_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]NATO Suppressor\n\nA shortened variant of the G36 rifle with a shorter barrel (fitted with an open-type flash suppressor) and a shorter forend, which includes a bottom rail that can be used to attach tactical accessories, such as a UTL flashlight from the USP pistol. The carbine's barrel lacks the ability to launch rifle grenades and it will not support a bayonet. The weapon retained the ability to be used with the AG36 grenade launcher. G36Ks in service with German special forces are issued with a 100-round C-Mag drum. There are two variants of the G36K. The first and most commonly known has x3 scope/carry handle attached to the top, while the second is the one with the iron sights and rail.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Aaonn -->
		<string id="st_wpn_gauss">
			<text>Gauss Rifle</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_gauss_descr">
			<text>\nA super-accurate weapon made by Agroprom Research Institute scientists. Gunfire is nearly inaudible, due to its use of energy obtained "Flash" artifacts instead of gunpowder. In spite of the Gauss Rifle’s tremendous firepower, the recoil is insignificant. The accuracy and power of this gun exceeds those of all other small arms.</text>
		</string>
<!-- IO-14 «A?ica» -->
		<string id="st_wpn_groza">
			<text>OTs-14 Groza</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_groza_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x39mm\n\nThe OTs-14 “Groza” (“thunder”) modular assault rifle was developed during the early 1990s at the TSKIB SOO. It was intended for various Special Forces in the Russian army and Internal Affairs Ministry as an dedicated CQB/Urban warfare weapon. It was briefly manufactured in small numbers at the Tula Arms factory during the mid-1990s. OTs-14 rifles saw some action during the first anti-terrorist campaign in Chechnya in 1999, but soon felt out of favor and are no longer made. The OTs-14 is based on the familiar AKS-74U receiver and action, modified for the larger 9 x 39 subsonic ammunition favored by various SpetsNaz troops. It is fitted into a bullpup layout, with removable trigger/pistol grip unit which could be replaced with an alternative unit integral with 40 mm grenade launcher. In the grenade-launching configuration, a single trigger controls both the 40 mm GL and the rifle itself, with a separate barrel selector. The safety/fire mode selector of AK pattern is retained and in bullpup configuration is especially uncomfortable to operate. The barrel can be fitted with a quick-detachable silencer. Standard open sights are built into the carrying handle, which results in relatively short sight base. The carrying handle also has mounting points for telescope, red dot or night sights.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Browning HP-SA -->
		<string id="st_wpn_hpsa">
			<text>Browning HP-SA</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_hpsa_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x19mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9mm Suppressor\n\nThe Browning Hi-Power is a single-action, 9 mm semi-automatic pistol. It is based on ideas conceived and patented in 1922 by American firearms inventor John Browning, and later patented by Fabrique Nationale (FN) of Herstal, Belgium. Browning died in 1926, before he had finished developing a production version. The design was fully developed and realized by Belgian arms designer Dieudonne Saive, working at FN.\n\n The Hi-Power pistol was named for its 13-round magazine capacity, which was almost twice that of contemporary designs such as the Luger or Mauser 1910. The Hi-Power had the first functional double-column magazine of 9 mm rounds, and was capable of holding 13 cartridges, with a 14th loaded in the chamber. Flush-fit 15 round magazines are now available, as well as higher capacity magazines which extend past the end of the butt.The pistol is often referred to as an HP (for "Hi-Power" or "High-Power") or as a GP (for the French term, "Grande Puissance"). The term P-35 is also used, based on the introduction of the pistol in 1935. Another common nickname is the "King of Nines." It is most often called the "Hi-Power", even in Belgium. This modified variant of the Browning HP pistol, despite its venerable age, retains a very high popularity around the world.</text>
		</string>
<!-- HK-416 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_hk416">
			<text>HK-416</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_hk416_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]Trijicon ACOG, AC11090 Red Dot Sight, C-MORE Tactical Sight, EO-Tech Sight, NATO Suppressor\n\nThe HK416 is an assault rifle designed and manufactured by Heckler & Koch to be an improved version of the M4 Carbine pattern firearm. It is available as a complete firearm, or as an upper receiver kit that fits on any AR-15 type lower receiver. The US Army’s Delta Force collaborated with the German arms makers to develop the new carbine. It replaced its M4s with the H&K 416 in 2004 after tests revealed that the piston operating system significantly reduces malfunctions while increasing the life of parts. The project was originally called the HKM4, but this was changed in response to a trademark infringement suit filed by Colt Defense. It is speculated that "416" is a reference to the M4 and M16 it's designed to succeed. So far the weapon has reportedly been tested by the United States military as well as some law enforcement agencies. It is only available to government and military organizations currently.</text>
		</string>
<!-- L85A2 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_l85">
			<text>L85A2</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_l85_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]NATO Suppressor\n\nThe development of the SA80 system, which included two weapons - the SA80 IW assault rifle and SA80 LSW light machine gun, began in the late 1960s when Britisharmy decided to develop a new rifle, which will eventually replace the venerable 7.62mm L1 SLR (British-made FNFAL rifle) in the 1980s. When NATO trials were announced in 1977 to select a new cartridge, British state-owned Enfield Small Arms Factory developed its own small-caliber, high velocity round, which was more or less representing the US .223/5.56mm case necked down to accept 4.85mm (0.19 inch) bullet. When the cartridge came out, Royal Small Arms Factory at Enfield developed a new weapon around it, initially designated as SA80-IW or XL65. Original SA80 weapons (both L85 and L86) were plagued with many problems, some being very serious. In general, the L85 was quite unreliable and troublesome to handle and maintain, so, finally, in the year 1997, after years of constant complaints from the troops, it had been decided to upgrade most L85 rifles then in service.  The current L85A2 rifles are recognized as reliable and very accurate, especially when using standard issue SUSAT telescope sights.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Z-M LR-300ML -->
		<string id="st_wpn_lr300">
			<text>LR-300ML</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_lr300_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]M203, NATO Suppressor\n\nThe LR-300 rifle was manufactured by the small US-based company Z-M Weapons between 2000 and 2007, when all rights for the design were sold to the Para USA, the US-based subsidiary of the Canadian pistol maker Para-Ordnance Ltd. The original LR-300 rifles were designed by Alan Zitta as an upgrade to the well known and popular M16/AR-15 rifles. In fact, LR-300 and Para TTR both use standard AR-15-typelower receivers; only upper receivers are different and contain patented modified gas system. The key reason for tha modification was to prowide AR-15-type weapon with capability to mount side-folding stock rather than partially collapsible M4 carbine-typestock. Z-M Weapons intended its rifles mostly for military and law enforcement personnel, by offering LR-300-ML weapons with short barrels and select-fire capability. Great ergonomics and lightweight, this weapon is highly accurate.  However, it is sensitive to dirt and is not ideal for difficult field conditions.</text>
		</string>
<!-- M590A1 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_m590a1">
			<text>Mossberg M590A1</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_m590a1_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]12x70, 12x76\n\nMossberg 590 was developed by O.F.Mossberg & sons company (USA) in the mid-1970s as a "military specifications" (adopted for USMilitary) modification of the Mossberg model 500 shotgun. "Militarization"included strenghtening of the receiver and other parts, installation ofthe vented heatshield around the barrel,bayonet lug and extended magazine, as well as an aluminum trigger guard instead of plastic one.Standard finish is Parkerizing, and the gun is usually provided with replacement pistol grip, which allows easy converion to 'Cruiser' modification and back. Since 1987 this shotgun is a standard equipmentof US Armed forces; while it was officially replaced in US Army with Benelli M1014 semi-automatic shotgun, Mossberg 590 shotguns are still widely used by US Navy and US Marine Corps.</text>
		</string>
<!-- I?-133 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_mp133">
			<text>MP-133</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_mp133_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]12x70, 12x76\n\nThe MP-133 is a product of the Izhevsk Mechanical plant. This shotgun is an evolution of the earlier IZh-81 pump action shotgun, and is intended primary for civilian and security markets. It is produced in two basic versions (standard MP-133 with tubular magazine andMP-133K with detachable box magazine), and either version can be had in a variety of barrel lengths and styles, as well as in wooden or polymer furniture, with traditional fixed buttstock, side-folding (AK-74M type)polymer folding buttstock, or pistol grip and no buttstock. The MP-133 shotgun uses traditional pump action with sliding forend that has dual action bars. Locking is achieved by a tilting locking piece, which is installed in the bolt and engages the notch in the barrel extension when in battery. Feed is from tubular underbarrel magazine which holds 4 rounds (capacity can be enhanced byinstalling magazine extension tubes). The receiver of the MP-133 is made from aluminum alloy. Barrels can be easily removed, and available in a variety of lengths and styles (with ventilated ribs or with no rib and rifle-type sights). Barrels are equipped with interchangeable choke system. </text>
		</string>
<!-- I?-153 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_mp153">
			<text>MP-153</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_mp153_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]12x70, 12x76\n\nThe MP-153 self-loading shotgun was the first semi-automatic shotgun designed and manufactured by Izhevsk Mechanical Plant. It was developed simultaneously with the pump-action MP-133 shotgun and shares many parts and assemblies with it. The MP-153 is one of the most popular semi-automatic shotguns of Russian origin, and is widely used to hunting various game across the Russia. It is also sold for export, and in the USA it is known as Remington "Spartan" SPR453 autoloader. MP-153 shotguns are known for solid (although some what heavy) construction, and reliability.</text>
		</string>
<!-- M4 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_m4">
			<text>M4</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_m4_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]Trijicon ACOG, AC11090 Red Dot Sight, C-MORE Tactical Sight, EO-Tech Sight, NATO Suppressor\n\nThe M4 Carbine descends from a family of firearms tracing its lineage back to earlier carbine versions of the M16, all based on the original AR-15 made by ArmaLite. It is a shorter and lighter version of the M16 style assault rifle, sharing 80% of its parts. The M4 and variants fire 5.56x45mm NATO ammunition and are gas-operated, air-cooled, magazine-fed, selective fire firearms with a 4-position telescoping stock.As with many carbines, the M4 is handy and more convenient to carry than a full-length rifle. It has been adopted by United States Special Operations Command (USSOCOM) and is the preferred weapon of the U.S. Army Special Forces and Navy SEALs. The M4 is similar to much earlier compact M16 versions, such as the 1960s-era XM177 family.</text>
		</string>
<!-- M4A1 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_m4a1">
			<text>M4A1</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_m4a1_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]Trijicon ACOG, AC11090 Red Dot Sight, C-MORE Tactical Sight, EO-Tech Sight, NATO Suppressor\n\nThe M4A1 is a modified variant of the M4 carbine able to fire full-auto.</text>
		</string>
<!-- M16 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_m16">
			<text>M16</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_m16_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]Trijicon ACOG, AC11090 Red Dot Sight, C-MORE Tactical Sight, EO-Tech Sight, NATO Suppressor\n\nM16 (more formally Rifle, Caliber 5.56 mm, M16) is the U.S. military designation for a family of rifles derived from the ArmaLite AR-15 and further developed by Colt starting in the mid-20th century.The M16 rifle family including the M16/A1/A2/A3/A4 has been the primary infantry rifle of the United States military since the 1960s. With its variants, it has been in use by 15 NATO countries, and is the most produced firearm in its caliber. The M16 entered Army service in 1964.The M16 is a lightweight, 5.56 mm caliber, air-cooled, gas-operated, magazine-fed assault rifle, with a rotating bolt, actuated by direct impingement gas operation. The rifle is made of steel, aluminum, and composite plastics.</text>
		</string>
<!-- M16A1 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_m16a1">
			<text>M16A1</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_m16a1_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]Trijicon ACOG, AC11090 Red Dot Sight, C-MORE Tactical Sight, EO-Tech Sight, NATO Suppressor\n\nAn M16 with a forward assist feature requested by the Army. All of the early versions were chambered to fire the M193/M196 cartridge in the semi-automatic and the automatic firing modes. This occurred in the early 1960s, with the Army issuing it in late 1964. Commercial AR-15s were first issued to Special Forces troops in spring of 1964.</text>
		</string>
<!-- M16A2 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_m16a2">
			<text>M16A2</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_m16a2_descr">
			<text>]\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]Trijicon ACOG, AC11090 Red Dot Sight, C-MORE Tactical Sight, EO-Tech Sight, NATO Suppressor\n\nThe M16A2 rifle entered service in the 1980s, chambered to fire the standard NATO cartridge, the Belgian-designed M855/M856 cartridge. The M16A2 is a select-fire rifle (semi-automatic fire, three-round-burst fire) incorporating design elements requested by the Marine Corps: an adjustable, windage rear-sight; a stock 5/8-inch longer; heavier barrel; case deflector for left-hand shooters; and cylindrical hand guards.The fire mode selector is on the receiver's left side. The M16 rifle is principally manufactured by the Colt and the Fabrique Nationale de Herstal arms companies, with the variant rifles made elsewhere in the world.</text>
		</string>
<!-- M16A3 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_m16a3">
			<text>M16A3</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_m16a3_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\nBy 1996, the two newest versions of the M16 appeared, the M16A3. This rifle differs from the M16A2 by having a removable carrying handle, with the upper receiver being fitted with a Picatinny-type accessory rail. The M16A3 also replaced the infamous three-round burst mode with a full auto mode. The key advantage of both the M16A3 rifle is the ability to quickly mount and re-mount a wide variety of optical, red dot or night vision / IR sights with MIL-STD 1913 (Picatinny-type) compatible mounts. </text>
		</string>
<!-- M16A4 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_m16a4">
			<text>M16A4</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_m16a4_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\nDeveloped along side the M16A3, the M16A4 differ from the M16A2 by having a removable carrying handle, with the upper receiver being fitted with a Picatinny-type accessory rail. Otherwise the M16A4 is similar to the M16A2. The key advantage of the A4 rifle is the ability to quickly mount and re-mount a wide variety of optical, red dot or night vision / IR sights with MIL-STD 1913 (Picatinny-type) compatible mounts.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_m16a4_camo">
			<text>M16A4 (camouflage)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_m16a4_camo_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\nA variant of the M16A4 rifle with a desert camo and Leupold Mark 4 sight.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_m16a4_camo">
			<text>M16A4 (camouflage)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_m16a4_camo_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\nA variant of the M16A4 rifle with a desert camo and Leupold Mark 4 sight.</text>
		</string>
<!-- HK MP5 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_mp5">
			<text>MP5</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_mp5_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x19mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]Trijicon ACOG, AC11090 Red Dot Sight, C-MORE Tactical Sight, EO-Tech Sight, 9mm Suppressor\n\nThe MP-5, is one of the most famous and wide-spread firearms of its class. Its development began circa 1964 under the company designation HK MP-54, or simply the HK 54. In 1966, German police and Border Guard adopted the HK 54 as the MP-5. Over the years the MP-5 was adopted by the huge numbers of police, security and military forces around the world. T MP-5 is still manufactured in Germany by HK itself, and also licensed to Greece,Iran, Pakistan and Mexico. The only real rival to the MP-5 in the terms of proliferation across the world is the famous Israeli UZI submachine gun. The MP-5, basically, is no more than the scaled-down version of the Heckler-Koch G3 battle rifle. It shares the same basic design with stamped steel receiver and the same roller-delayed Modern MP-5 submachine guns are equipped with three-lug quick detachable silencer mounts on the barrel. Sights consists of front hooded post sight and adjustable drum-type diopter rear sight. Special quick-detachable clamp mounts allows for installation of night, optical and red-dot sights if required.</text>
		</string>
<!-- HK UMP -->
		<string id="st_wpn_ump45">
			<text>UMP45</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_ump45_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default].45 ACP\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]Trijicon ACOG, AC11090 Red Dot Sight, C-MORE Tactical Sight, EO-Tech Sight, NATO Suppressor\n\nThe UMP was developed by the Heckler & Koch company of Germany in the mid- to late- 1990-ies and first appeared on the market in 1999. The key idea behind the UMP was to ceate lightweight and powerful submachine gun, that was also cheaper than the MP-5. The UMP, being targeted primary for USA law enforcement market, first appeared in .45ACP and .40SW chamberings, and later - in 9mm. The UMP is a blowback-operated select-fire submachine gun, being fired from the closed bolt. The receiver is made from the polymer, the controls are fully ambidextrous. UMP can be fired in full-auto, in single shots, and in 2 or 3 round bursts (optional). UMP also has bolt hold-open device, which traps the bolt in the open position when the last round from magazine had been fired. UMP has side-folding buttstock and two set of picatinny rails - one on the top of the receiver, and the other - on the forend. These rails can accept wide variety of sighting and other equipment, such as red-dot sights, laser pointers, tactical grips and flashlights.The barrel has quick mount for snap-on silencer.</text>
		</string>
<!-- HK MP5SD -->
		<string id="st_wpn_mp5sd">
			<text>MP5SD</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_mp5sd_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x19mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]Trijicon ACOG, AC11090 Red Dot Sight, C-MORE Tactical Sight, EO-Tech Sight\n\nA variant of the MP5 with an integrated suppressor.</text>
		</string>
<!-- II-2000 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_pp2000">
			<text>PP-2000</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_pp2000_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x19mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]Trijicon ACOG, AC11090 Red Dot Sight, C-MORE Tactical Sight, EO-Tech Sight, 9mm Suppressor\n\nThe PP-2000 is the latest development of the famous Instrument Design Bureau (KBP) from Tula, Russia. It has been first displayed to the public in 2004, although the patent for its layout has been filed since 2001 and issued in 2003. Today it is already in use with some Law Enforcement (police and state security) units of the Russian Federation. The main "niche" for the PP-2000 is as a personal defense weapon for non-infantry military personnel, as well as close combat weapon for special forces and special law enforcement teams. As such, it is a compact weapon with as few parts as possible for enhanced reliability, simplified maintenance and low cost. The PP2000 is fitted with fixed open sights, and a Picatinny-type acessory rail is provided on the top of the receiver cover. This weapon is most often encountered with various types of red-dot sights, best suitable for close combat.</text>
		</string>
<!-- IA -->
		<string id="st_wpn_pb">
			<text>PB</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_pb_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x18mm\n\nThe PB (Pistolet Besshumnyj - Silenced Pistol), also known for Soviet/Russian army as 6P9, has been developed by 1967 for Spetsnaz elements of the Soviet army, as well as for operatives of KGB. The pistol is based on significantly modified Makarov PM pistol, and features an unique integral two-part silencer. The rear part of the silencer is fixed around the barrel, which is drilled to decrease the muzzle velocity below the speed of sound. The front part of the silencer is quickly detachable, so pistol can be broken down into two parts for more convenient carry. Unlike many other integrally silenced pistols the PB can be safely fired with the front part of the silencer removed, but this will greatly increase the sound signature. Still, it is an useful emergency feature. Because the front part of the barrel is enclosed into the silencer, the slide is made very short and cannot contain the return spring. Instead, the return spring is located in the grip, under the right panel, and linked to the slide via the rocking lever. The double-action firing unit with external hammer and slide-mounted safety/decocker, as well as the magazine, are borrowed from the Makarov PM pistol with no modification. The PB has fixed sights.</text>
		</string>
<!-- II -->
		<string id="st_wpn_pm">
			<text>Makarov PM</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_pm_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x18mm\n\nThe Makarov PM is a semi-automatic pistol designed in the late 1940s, by Nikolai Fyodorovich Makarov, and was the Soviet Union's standard military side arm from 1951-1991. The Makarov pistol resulted from a design competition for replacing the Tokarev TT-33 semi-automatic pistol. Rather than building a pistol to an existing cartridge, Nikolai Makarov designed a new cartridge, the 9x18mm Makarov. For simplicity and economy, the Makarov pistol was of straight blowback operation, with the 9x18mm cartridge being the most powerful cartridge that its design could safely fire; although the nominal calibre was 9mm, the actual bullet was 9.3mm in diameter - shorter and wider and thus incompatible with pistols chambered for 9x19mm Parabellum cartridges. Consequently, Soviet ammunition was unusable in NATO firearms, hence, in war, NATO would be unable to use ammunition from killed or captured Soviet soldiers or from Soviet ammunition dumps. In 1951, the Pistol Makarova (PM) was selected because of its simplicity (few moving parts), economy, easy manufacturing, accuracy, and reasonable killing power. It remained in service with Soviet military and police until the end of the U.S.S.R. in 1991. Today, the Makarov is a popular handgun for concealed carry in the U.S.; variants of the Makarov remain in production in Russia and Bulgaria.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Iaa?aaiie II -->
		<string id="st_wpn_pm_actor">
			<text>Ceremonial Makarov PM</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_pm_actor_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x18mm\n\nAn ancient PM received by Degtyarev as a reward for "Succesful execution of highly dangerous state orders, as well as valor and courage shown in the line of duty."</text>
		</string>
<!-- III -->
		<string id="st_wpn_pmm">
			<text>PMM</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_pmm_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x18mm\n\nThe most widely known variant, the Makarov PMM, was a redesign of the original gun. In 1990, a group of engineers reworked the original Makarov, primarily by increasing the load for the cartridge. The result is a significant increase in muzzle velocity and generation of 25% more gas pressure. The PMM magazine holds 12 rounds, compared to the PM's 8 rounds.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Protecta -->
		<string id="st_wpn_protecta">
			<text>Striker</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_protecta_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]12x70, 12x76\n\nThe Striker shotgun was originally designed in the early 1980s by Hilton Walker from Rhodesia. After the fall of Rhodesia he moved to the South African Republic, where he continued the development of his counter-insurgency, high capacity combat shotgun. First production models of his shotgun, named "Striker", were made during the mid-1980s, and found its way from the South Africa and into the USA, and other countries. The key advantages of the Striker shotgun were its large magazine capacity, which is doubled the traditional shotguns magazine capacity of that time, and rapid-fire capability.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Remington 870 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_remington870">
			<text>Remington 870</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_remington870_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]12x70, 12x76\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]AC11090 Red Dot Sight, C-MORE Tactical Sight, EO-Tech Sight\n\nThe Remington 870 is a pump-action shotgun developed by Remington Arms Company in 1951 in competition with Winchester to produce a rugged, streamlined and relatively inexpensive shotgun. It is widely used by sporting shooters, hunters, law enforcement and military personnel, and has enjoyed steady popularity among all markets since its release.</text>
		</string>
<!-- ?A-6 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_rg6">
			<text>RG-6</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_rg6_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]VOG-25 Grenades\n\nThe RG-6 (index 6G30) was in development between 1993 and 1994 by the TSKIB SOO. The new stand-alone, rapid firing multi-shot launcher was required to increase the firepower of the infantry during the urban combat, specifically for recent small-scale conflicts, such as the Chechen wars. The RG-6 entered limited production by mid-1990 and is now in use by various elements of the Russian Army and special forces, as well as by special forces in MVD (Internal Affairs Ministry). The RG-6 is designed to fire all standard 40mm "caseless" grenades, available for general issue underbarrel launchers, such as GP-25 and GP-30. These rounds include VOG-25 fragmentation grenade, VOG-25P bouncing fragmentation grenade and "Gvozd" (Nail) less-lethal tear gas grenade for riot control. The design of the RG-6 is, apparently, heavily influenced by the South African Milkor MGL grenade launcher.</text>
		</string>
<!-- IEI -->
		<string id="st_wpn_pkm">
			<text>PKM</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_pkm_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]7.62x54mm\n\nThe PK General Purpose Machine Gun is a highly respected weapon that was added to the Soviet Army arsenal to replace the aging RP46 system. The PK was chambered to fire the same 7.62mm round that was and continues to be common throughout Russian supply depots and in former Soviet-supported states and clients. As a squad support weapn, the PK compliments the existing array of assault rifels that fire a middle-range version of the same round. A bipod is fitted to the underside of the barrel system for stabalized support and can be folded up and into the design when portability is required. Additionally, a carrying handle is added atop the barrel towards the middle of the weapon to make transit a snap. The weapon feeds into a feed system similar to that as found on the AK systems before it, and ca nfire from a 100, 200 or 250 round belt (either fired as a free-fed belt or held in a box). For overheating concerns, the barrel is designed to be replaceable and most necessary when sustained fire of upwards of 650 rounds per minute is reached. A true general purpose machine gun that is light and reliable, the PK family continues to serve throughout the world in the mods deadly-effictive of roles.</text>
		</string>
<!-- ?IA-7 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_rpg7">
			<text>RPG-7</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_rpg7_descr">
			<text>\nThe RPG-7 is a further development of the previous RPG-2 antitank grenadelauncher. The RPG-7, in its first version, known as RPG-7V, has been adopted by the Soviet army in 1961, and is still widely fielded in Russia and at least 50 more countries. By far, RPG-7 can be considered as one of the most successful antitank grenade launchers ever made.Initially thought of as an anti-armor weapon, it was later adopted for other fire-support missions by the introduction of various types of grenades, such as anti-infantry HE-FRAG, multi-purpose Thermobaric / FAE, etc. The RPG-7 is a shoulder fired, single-shot, smoothbore recoilless launcher. Grenades are loaded from the front, and the rear of the barrel is fitted with venturi nozzle. Because of the recoilless design, there is a dangerous backblast zone, more than 20 meters/60ft long. The RPG-7 is usually issued with 2.7X fixed magnification optical sight, designated PGO-7. The RPG-7 is a simple and inexpensive weapon, yet it possess a high threat to most modern tanks, and can also serve in a number of other roles, making it a true one-man artillery.</text>
		</string>
<!-- SIG-P220 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_sig220">
			<text>SIG-Sauer P220</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_sig220_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default].45 ACP\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default].45 Suppressor\n\nThe SIG-Sauer P220, manufactured in the late 1970-ies by J.P. Sauer & Son Copmany, is often considered the best “out of the box” .45 caliber double action pistol. An instant and continuous success, the P220 was adopted by the Swiss and Japanese armies, and by a large number of European police organizations. This pistol also rapidly found its way into the USA, first thorough the Browning Arms Company of Utah, and, since the mid-1980s, through the SIGARMS Company of New Hampshire.</text>
		</string>
<!-- SIG SG-550 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_sig550">
			<text>SIG SG-550</text>
		</string>
<!-- SIG "No?aeie" -->
		<string id="st_wpn_sig550_strelok">
			<text>SIG "Strelok"</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_sig550_strelok_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]7.62x39mm\n\nA Swiss-made SIG SG762 assault rifle chambered for the more common 7.62x39 round. Although it is hardly new, it is clear that the previous owner took good care of it: the weapon has been taken apart and put back together, with every component fine-tuned for optimum performance, increasing stopping power. The letter "S" has been carved into the stock, along with 16 small notches.</text>
		</string>
<!-- SIG SG-551 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_sig551">
			<text>SIG SG-551 LB</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_sig550-551_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]Trijicon ACOG, AC11090 Red Dot Sight, C-MORE Tactical Sight, EO-Tech Sight, M203, NATO Suppressor\n\nThe SG-551 LB became a shortened pattern carbine form of the the full-sized SG-550 copmlete with a 18-inch barrel and applicably shortened gas cylinder and pistol. This version, unlike the standard SG 551, retaind the capability to fire rifle grenades and mount a bayonet.</text>
		</string>
<!-- SIG SG-552 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_sig552">
			<text>SIG SG-552</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_sig552_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]5.56x45mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]Trijicon ACOG, AC11090 Red Dot Sight, C-MORE Tactical Sight, EO-Tech Sight\n\nIn 1998, the SG-550 family was further developed into a more compact version as the SG-552 "Commando". This form included a 9-inch barrel and reworked internals due to its reduced overall size. </text>
		</string>
<!-- FN SCAR-L -->
		<string id="st_wpn_scar_light">
			<text>FN SCAR-L</text>
		</string>
<!-- FN SCAR-H -->
		<string id="st_wpn_scar_heavy">
			<text>FN SCAR-H</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_scar_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]7.62x51mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]Trijicon ACOG, AC11090 Red Dot Sight, C-MORE Tactical Sight, EO-Tech Sight, M203, NATO Suppressor\n\nThe Special Operations Forces Combat Assault Rifle (SCAR) is a modular rifle made by FN Herstal for SOCOM to satisfy the requirements of the SCAR competition. This family of rifles consist of two main types. This is the SCAR-L, for "light", is chambered in the 5.56x45mm NATO cartridge.</text>
		</string>
<!-- SPAS-12 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_spas12">
			<text>SPAS-12</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_spas12_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]12x70, 12x76\n\nThe SPAS-12 was designed in the late 1970s by the Italian company Luigi FranchiSpa as a special purpose, military and police close combat weapon. The SPAS-12 can be used as a gas operated semi-automatic repeater or as a manually operated pump action repeater, depending on the mission and ammunition used. Since its introduction the SPAS-12 became a very popular police and specialforces weapon, being versatile, reliable and with good firepower. On the other hand, it is heavier than most other similar shotguns and quite complicated, which results in relatively high prices.</text>
		</string>
<!-- SR-25 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_sr25">
			<text>SR-25</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_sr25_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]7.62x51mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]M203, SR-25 Suppressor\n\nThe SR 25 rifle (Stoner Rifle, model 25) was developed by Reed Knight (owner of Knights Armament Co) and Eugene Stoner (designer of the M16 and Stoner 63 rifles among other things) during the early 1990s. In essence, the SR 25 was the AR-15 rifle scaled up to shoot 7.62x51/.308 Win ammunition, with up to 60% of parts of new rifle being interchangeable with standard AR-15 components. This rifle sold well among civilian shooters who needed an accurate semi-automatic rifle in 7.62/.308 caliber for hunting or target shooting. This rifle also found a favor among US Military. All rifles built on the SR-25 platform share the same basic action, which is based on AR-15/M16 system. Because of AR-15-style recoil buffer, which extends rearwards fro the receiver, SR-15 cannot be fitted with folding buttstock; most rifles are fitted with fixed butt, while SR-25 carbines are fitted with telescoping buttstock. Trigger is also of match grade, fully adjustable.</text>
		</string>
<!-- NA-98 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_sv98">
			<text>SV-98</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_sv98_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]7.62x54mm\n\nThis sniper rifle was developed by IZHMASH (Izhevsk Machinebuilding Plant) and based on proven sporting rifle desighn.The SV-98 features backup iron sights and a scope mount. Standard scope is a Russian-made PKS-07 7X fixed magnification scope. The trigger is of "sport-style" and adjustable. The wooden stock features an adjustable buttplate and cheek pad; the folding bipods are integral. The manually operated bolt action has a rotating bolt with three frontal lugs. The cold hammer-forged barrel is free-floating, and has a threaded muzzle which can accept sound moderator(special type of silencer intended for supersonic ammunition). A special plastic magazine holds 10 rounds. The SV-98 is in production at IZHMASH and used by various Russian law enforcementand counter-terrorist forces. With match-grade ammunition the SV-98 can  shoot 5cmgroups at upwards of 300 meters, which accounts for sub-MOA accuracy.</text>
		</string>
<!-- NAA -->
		<string id="st_wpn_svd">
			<text>SVD</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_svd_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]7.62x54mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]KZRZP Suppressor\n\nThe SVD "Dragunov sniper rifle", is a 7.62 mm semi-automatic sniper rifle, developed in the former Soviet Union. It was selected as the winner of a contest that included three competing designs: the first was a rifle designed by Sergei Simonov (known as the SSV-58), the second – by Alexander Konstantinov (prototype designated 2B-W10) and the third rifle, the SVD-137 was a design by Evgeny Dragunov. Extensive testing of the rifles in variable environmental conditions resulted in E. F. Dragunov’s design being accepted into service in 1963. At the same time an initial pre-production batch of 200 rifles was assembled, and from 1964 serial production was carried out at Izhmash. Since then, the SVD has become the standard squad support weapon of several countries, including those of the former Warsaw Pact, among them Poland (since 1966). Licensed production of the rifle was established in China (Type 79 and Type 85) and Iraq (as the Al Kadesiah).</text>
		</string>
<!-- NAO -->
		<string id="st_wpn_svu">
			<text>SVU</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_svu_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]7.62x54mm\n\nThe SVU project (Snaiperskaya Vintovka Ukorochennaya- shortened sniper rifle) traces its roots back to the 1970-ies, when it was decided to develop a compact sniper rifle for Soviet airborne (VDV) troops. Such a rifle was designed using the standard Dragunov SVD action converted to a bullpup layout. Back then this project never went past its development stage, but in around 1991 it was resurrected in Tulaand and offered to the Russian Internal Affairs Ministry (MVD) as a possible weapon for urban operations.</text>
		</string>
<!-- OIC-194 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_toz194">
			<text>TOZ-194</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_toz194_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]12x70, 12x76\n\nThe TOZ-194 is a 12 Gauge, pump-action shotgun manufactured by the Tula Arms Plant. Designed during the last years of the Soviet Union, the manufacture of this firearm has started after its collapse, and since then it has gained a certain popularity within civilian shooters in Russia itself and in Europe, and is reported to be in use with some Russian Security forces.</text>
		</string>
<!-- OIC-34 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_toz34">
			<text>TOZ-34</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_toz34_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]12x70, 12x76\n\nIntended for professional and amateur hunting the TOZ-34 is a lightweight and compact shotgun. It compares well with high-grade shotguns as it has perfect balance and high accuracy of hits. This shotguns’ design is original, simple and inimitable.</text>
		</string>
<!-- OIC-34 ia?ac -->
		<string id="st_wpn_toz34_obrez">
			<text>TOZ-34 Obrez</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_toz34_obrez_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]12x70, 12x76\n\nIntended for professional and amateur hunting the TOZ-34 is a lightweight and compact shotgun. It compares well with high-grade shotguns as it has perfect balance and high accuracy of hits. This shotguns’ design is original, simple and inimitable.</text>
		</string>
<!-- OIC-66 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_toz66">
			<text>TOZ-66 Obrez</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_toz66_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]12x70, 12x76\n\nThe Tula Arsenal Model TOZ-66 is a popular side-by-side shotgun used for hunting game. It is a double-hammer shotgun, and its popularity and ease of procurement outside the Zone has led to it becoming one of the most common weapons smuggled into it, either in the hands of trespassers, or sold by traders either in its standard form, or sawn-off for use in close range encounters. Being a familiar weapon to most stalkers, many of them keep it and continue to use it for defense against many types of threats.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_toz66_full">
			<text>TOZ-66</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_toz66_full_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]12x70, 12x76\n\nThe Tula Arsenal Model TOZ-66 is a popular side-by-side shotgun used for hunting game. It is a double-hammer shotgun, and its popularity and ease of procurement outside the Zone has led to it becoming one of the most common weapons smuggled into it, either in the hands of trespassers, or sold by traders either in its standard form, or sawn-off for use in close range encounters. Being a familiar weapon to most stalkers, many of them keep it and continue to use it for defense against many types of threats.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Iaecaanoiia i?o?ea -->
		<string id="st_wpn_umirotvoritel">
			<text>Unidentified weapon</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_umirotvoritel_descr">
			<text>An unknown weapon, the firing mechanism of which has not been established. The weapon appears faulty - squeezing the trigger doesn't do anything.</text>
		</string>
<!-- HK USP -->
		<string id="st_wpn_usp">
			<text>HK USP</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_usp_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default].45 ACP\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default].45 Suppressor\n\nOriginally designed for the American market, the USP (Universal Self-loading Pistol) has found international acceptance as an accurate and ultra-reliable handgun. Features favored by U.S. law enforcement and military users provided much of the design criteria for the USP. The controls are uniquely American, influenced by such famous designs as the Government Model 1911 pistol. All USPs use a fiber-reinforced polymer frame stiffened by stainless steel inserts at areas subject to stress and friction. The USP control lever, a combination safety and decocking lever, is frame mounted and quickly accessible. Using a modified Browning-type action with a special patented recoil reduction system, the USP recoil reduction system reduces recoil effects on pistol components and also lowers the recoil forces felt by the shooter. This same recoil reduction system has been tested and proven in the HK Mark 23 pistol developed for the U.S. Special Operations Command. The modular design of the USP’s internal components allows the control lever function to be switched from the left to the right side of the pistol for left-handed shooters. The USP can also be converted from one type oaf trigger firing mode to another. This includes combination double-action and single-action (DA/SA) modes and double action only (DAO) modes. </text>
		</string>
<!-- HK USP Match -->
		<string id="st_wpn_usp_match">
			<text>HK USP Match</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_usp_match_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default].45 ACP\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default].45 Suppressor\n\nThe first offering by HK of an enhanced USP with distinct characteristics that make it more attractive to the target shooter. With the O-Ring barrel first seen in the Mark 23, the Match includes compensator that helps reduce the relatively mild kick of the .45. The Match also features polygonal rifling, a trigger stop, and fully adjustable rear sight.</text>
		</string>
<!-- AN «Aae» -->
		<string id="st_wpn_val">
			<text>AS VAL</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_val_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]EKP 1S-03 Kobra, EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29, PSO-1M2-01\n\nThe AS is widely used by Russian Army recon units, as well as by MVD (Internal Affairs Ministry) and FSB (Federal Security Bureau) Special Forces. The AS is a gas operated, integrally silenced weapon. The receiver is machined from steel forging for improved strength. The AS rifle has a standard side-mounted rail for optical, night vision or red dot scopes. It has no provision for mounting a bayonet or a grenade launcher. The integral silencer could be easily detached for maintenance, repair, or compact storage, but the rifle should not be fired with the silencer removed due to safety and reliability issues.</text>
		</string>
<!-- N?-3 «Aeo?u» -->
		<string id="st_wpn_vihr">
			<text>SR-3M Vikhr</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_vihr_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]SR-3M Suppressor\n\nThe SR-3 "Vikhr" ("Whirlwind") compact assault rifle was developed in TSNIITOCHMASH by A. Borisov and V. Levchenko during the early 1990-ies. Initially known as "MA" (Malogabaritnyj Avtomat = small-size assault rifle), it was based on the silenced 9 mm AS "Val" assault rifle, and intended for concealed carry by special VIP protection teams and State security operatives. The SR-3 is widely used by various FSO (Federal Protection Service, a VIP protection organization, which guard the President and other government officials of the Russian Federation) and FSB (Federal Security Service) operatives, elite Russian counter-terror teams. Following the demand from users, the TSNIITOCHMASH recently developed an improved version of the SR-3, with intent to produce a more versatile weapon for Law Enforcement use. The new SR-3M (Modified) compact assault rifle features more convenient fire controls and charging handle, integral forward grip (folding), and, most important, specially developed quick-detachable silencer (sound moderator) and a standard side rail for mounting day or night optics on the left side of the receiver. Another useful accessory for the SR-3M is a new magazine with enlarged capacity (30 rounds), which also provides more reliable feeding during automatic fire. Open sights consist of a protected front post nd a flip-up rear sight with U-notch, with settings for 100 and 200 meters range.</text>
		</string>
<!-- ANN «Aeioi?ac» -->
		<string id="st_wpn_vintorez">
			<text>VSS Vintorez</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_vintorez_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x39mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]EKP 1S-03 Kobra, EKP-8-02 Kobra, 1P29\n\nDesigned at TSNIITochMash by Peter Serdyukov and his team, the new rifle was intended to replace some AK-47/AKM rifles, fitted with silencers, in the hands of various Special Operations (SpetsNaz) troops of the Soviet Army, KGB and MVD.The VSS is quite popular among its users for its stealthy capabilities and the great lethality of the heavy 9mm bullets. The effective range of the VSS is limited to 300-400 meters. The VSS is a gas operated, selective fire weapon. The silencer is the integral part of the weapon, and while it could be easily removed for storage or maintenance, the VSS shound not be fired with its silencer removed due to safety and reliability issues. Standard sighting equipment consists of side rail on the receiver, which usually accommodates the 4X PSO-1M2-01 scope. Any other scope or night vision sight can be mounted on the appropriate mount. Backup iron sights consist of tangent rear and blade front. The Rear sight is graduated for up to 400 meters. Feeding is achieved from a 10 or 20 round box magazines made from polymer.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Walther P-99 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_walther">
			<text>Walther P-99</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_walther_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9x19mm\n\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Attachments:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]9mm Suppressor\n\nThe P99 pistol was a rather radical step forward for the Walther company, made under new management. The development of a new pistol started in 1994 and the first production pistols were shown to public in 1997. The earliest pistols were made in 9mm, and a .40 S&W version appeared in 1999. By 2004, the Carl Walther company presented the second generation of the P99 pistols. These new guns had even better ergonomics, and new model designations. As the duty pistol for law enforcement agencies in North America, Europe and Asia, the P99 has endured some of the harshest operating conditions a handgun will ever see. The P99 is truly a world class handgun for professionals who must trust their lives to a firearm.</text>
		</string>
<!-- Winchester-1300 -->
		<string id="st_wpn_wincheaster1300">
			<text>Winchester 1300</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_wpn_wincheaster1300_descr">
			<text>\n%c[255,255,255,255]%c[255,255,255,255]Ammunition:\n\n%c[255,1,255,255]%c[default]12x70, 12x76\n\nThe Winchester 1300 shotgun was first introduced in around 1981, when the US Repeating Arms Company (USRAC) took over production of the 'Winchester' brand guns from the Olin/Winchester corporation. In fact, the model 1300 was a slightly modified version of the previous Winchester model 1200 shotgun, which was manufactured by Olin/Winchester between 1964 and 1980. The Winchester1300 shotguns are also known as the 'Speed pump', because of the very fast-cycling pump action, which makes these guns popular among both hunters and sport shooters. These shotguns also work well for home defense and security applications, especially with availability of relatively short-barreled models with long magazines.</text>
		</string>
	</string_table>
