<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 additional items, fixed typos, added 135 items, corrected text and strings aleks1970, det_art_super -->
<!-- Text editing as commented below - Sword2012 - 16 Oct 16 -->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->
<!--;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;
FOOD AND PROVISIONS 
;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;-->
<string_table>
	<string id="medic_overdose">
		<text>Overdose!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="medic_several">
		<text>Unable to use several drugs simultaneously!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="medic_can_overdose">
		<text>You cannot take the drug often, Overdose can happen!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="medic_not_finished">
		<text>The first medical treatment is not yet set, finished!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pivo">
		<text>Chernigov Beer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_pivo">
		<text>It is not known who first brought this beer into the Zone, but it very quickly became a favorite among STALKERs... Now it can be found at practically every Dealer throughout the Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="irp-b">
		<text>Military Rations</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_irp-b">
		<text>Military dry-ration developed specifically for Military personnel serving in the Zone. Like all things however, it has started to become available over the counter at various Dealers. The container is specially soldered in such a way that that the contents remain, and untainted for an extended period of time. Very tasty and nutritious - any STALKERs dream... although expensive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mechta">
		<text>Dream Cigarettes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_mechta">
		<text>Very much like a normal cigarette, although of what they really consist of, it is only possible to judge by the various names given to them by STALKERs: "Fairy Tales from the Viennese Wood", "Grandma`s Mattress", "Lump of Coal". Nevertheless, they are smoked well throughout the Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voda">
		<text>Crystal Mineral Water</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_voda">
		<text>Crystal brand mineral water. Perfectly satisfies thirst, improves overall well being, and restores energy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tuchenka">
		<text>Canned Meat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_tuchenka">
		<text>Canned food from Army Warehouses throughout the Zone which have been raided by STALKERs on a regular basis... The best-before period hasn't expired as of yet, so it should still be safe to eat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sardina">
		<text>Sardines</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_sardina">
		<text>Canned sardines are very popular in almost all parts of the world, whereas, in some regions the fresh form is preferred. There are various methods of canning sardines. Sardines are cleaned and then the heads, gills and viscera are removed. These cleaned pieces of sardines are then cooked by steaming or deep frying. After cooking, these fish pieces are dried and packed in oil (olive or soybean), salt water or sauce (tomato or mustard)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sholad">
		<text>Chocolate</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_sholad">
		<text>Dark chocolate is well known for its health benefits, as it seems to possess a substantial amount of antioxidants that reduce the formation of free radicals in the body. How it came to the Zone in the first place is unknown... but, no-one is complainng</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ogursi">
		<text>Marinated pickles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_ogursi">
		<text>It is recommended to use together with strong Vodka. These exquisite Pickles were liberated from a broken down delivery truck that was on its way to make a delivery to a small grocery chain once located on the outskirts of Pripyat. Brine reduces the effects of a hangover quite nicely</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar">
		<text>Yantar (Amber) processed cheese</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_yantar">
		<text>Yantar (Amber) was actually a low-priced Russian competitor to the processed cheese Viola that was introduced to the Soviet market in the 1950's by Finnish company Valio Ltd. It was created (according to local legend) by the factory's experimental and scientific division to "promote friendship among all peoples of the Soviet Union and the world."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nuts">
		<text>Mixed Nuts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nuts_descr">
		<text>Mixed nuts are a snack food consisting of any mixture of mechanically or manually combined nuts. Peanuts (actually a legume), almonds, walnuts, Brazil nuts, cashews, filberts, hazelnuts, and pecans are common constituents of mixed nuts. They can be salted, roasted, cooked, or blanched. In addition to being eaten directly, these can be used in cooking</text>
	</string>
	<string id="olives">
		<text>Olives</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_olives_descr">
		<text>Olives are high in monounsaturated fat, iron, Vitamin E, and dietary fiber. Naturally ripened purple/black appearing olives contain anthocyanins. Artificially ripened "black olives" are frequently canned and sent to grocery stores. There is an effect that typical processing has on the quantity and type of anthocyanins contained in olives. Can be useful as a quick, nutritious snack and does a good job in quickly satisfying hunger pangs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kolbasadmx">
		<text>"Doctor's" Sausage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_dmx_kolbasa">
		<text>The most gentle taste of the sausage is produced using traditional technology, mainly consisting of high-quality, low-fat, Pork and beef, with the addition of eggs, integral cow`s milk and a simple dash of nutmeg</text>
	</string>
	<string id="absolut_vodka">
		<text>"Absolut" Vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_vodka_absolut">
		<text>Absolut Vodka is a French-owned brand of vodka, produced near Ehus, Skene, in southern Sweden. Since March 2008, the company has been owned by the French firm Pernod Ricard, having been sold by V</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nemiroff_vodka">
		<text>Nemiroff Vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_vodka_nemiroff">
		<text>A stylish, truly masculine vodka with a bright personality and a sense of dignity. Discover the unusual flavour of this vodka, feel its distinctive self-assertive taste, appreciate its complete and bold composition that includes caraway and honey</text>
	</string>
	<string id="smirnoff_vodka">
		<text>Smirnoff Vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_vodka_smirnoff">
		<text>The Smirnoff brand began with a vodka distillery founded in Moscow by Pyotr Arsenievich Smirnov (1831-1898), the son of illiterate Russian peasants. It is now distributed in 130 countries. Smirnoff products include vodka, flavored vodka, and malt beverages. In March 2006, Smirnoff vodka was deemed the best-selling distilled spirit brand in the world</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mineral_water">
		<text>Mineral Water</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_vodka_water">
		<text>water containing minerals or other dissolved substances that alter its taste or give it therapeutic value, generally obtained from a naturally occurring mineral spring or source. Dissolved substances in the water may include various salts and sulfur compounds. Mineral water can be sparkling (with effervescence), or still (without effervescence)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="energy_stalker">
		<text>STALKER Drink</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_energy_st">
		<text>powerful energy drink containing methylxanthines (including caffeine), vitamin B and herbs. Other common ingredients are guarana, acai, and taurine, plus various forms of ginseng, maltodextrin, carbonated water, inositol, carnitine, creatine, glucuronolactone and ginkgo biloba. May contain high levels of sugar. The central ingredient being caffeine, the same stimulant found in coffee or tea</text>
	</string>
	<string id="energy_non_stop">
		<text>Non-Stop Energy Drink</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_energy_stop">
		<text>"Non Stop" contains toning up substances, such as caffeine and other stimulators, as well as a complex of vitamins. Well restores energy after long jogs between anomalies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="energy_ad_rush">
		<text>Adrenaline Rush</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_energy_ad_rush">
		<text>Bold citrus taste enhanced with a unique blend of energizing elements including D-ribose, L-carnitine and taurine. So good. SoBe Adrenaline Rush</text>
	</string>
	<string id="energy_red_bull">
		<text>Red Bull Energy Drink</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_energy_red_bull">
		<text>In 2009, batches of "Red Bull Cola" drinks imported from Austria were found to contain between 0.1 - 0.3 micrograms of cocaine per litre, according to Officials. It was found that this was due to a launch marketing campaign the next day. Importing cocaine to some foreign countries is an offense that is punishable either by death or a life sentence in prison. In Germany, 11 out of 16 states had already banned the drinks by May 25, 2009</text>
	</string>
	<string id="energy_non_stop_lite">
		<text>Non-Stop lite</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_energy_non_stop_lite">
		<text>Essentially the same as regular "Non-Stop", only without the extra sugar added... not as effective</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sok">
		<text>Juice</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_sok">
		<text>Tasty, nutritious juice. On the package it says "multi-fruit", and consequently it contains a full set of vitamins. It both satisfies thirst, and restores energy so that one may continue on with their busy day</text>
	</string>
	<string id="syh_pay_gde_3">
		<text>Military Rations GDE-3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_syh_pay_gde_3">
		<text>Dry army-ration (GDE-3) manufactured in America. tastes better than the Russian equivalent. Also, it weighs less... and is slightly less nutritious</text>
	</string>
	<string id="syh_pay_spp5">
		<text>Military Rations SSP5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_syh_pay_spp5">
		<text>Russian dry-ration (SSP5). This advanced complete meal setup contains a diet specially developed for heavy field conditions. More nutritious than its NATO counterpart</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pivo_baltika">
		<text>Baltic Beer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_pivo_baltika">
		<text>Strength: 8.0 % - Baltika Strong light beer brewed from selected ingredients according to the newest technology, its a unique combination of the strength of the beverage and the lightness of drinking. This beer is brewed for you</text>
	</string>
	<!-- MEDICINE -->
	<string id="antiseptic">
		<text>Antiseptic Bandage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_antiseptic">
		<text>%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Improvement of:%c[255,1,255,1] 5%\n%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Haemorrhage:%c[255,1,255,1] 90%\n%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Number:%c[255,1,255,1] 1\n%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Side effects: mild fatigue\nChemical agent that destroys or inhibits the growth of pathogenic bacteria and other microorganisms, but which is non-toxic to skin and mucous membranes. Helps with bleeding, disinfect the wound and improves the general condition. The drug is fast acting</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zhgut">
		<text>Splint</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_zhgut">
		<text>%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Haemorrhage:%c[255,1,255,1] 100%\n%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Number of applications:%c[255,1,255,1] 5\n%c[default]Myramistin temporarily stop bleeding from large vessels, is a strong, relatively narrow and long strip of - or the material overlaps with the purpose of clamping the vessel to the bony prominences, reducing its lumen, and as a consequence, the termination or significant reduction in bleeding</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pervitin">
		<text>"Pervitin"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_pervitin">
		<text>%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Increased stamina:%c[255,1,255,1] 190%\n%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Reduced appetite:%c[255,1,255,1] 50%\n%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Side effects: a slight deterioration of general condition\n%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Number of tablets:%c[255,1,255,1] 2\n%c[default]Used in the treatment of narcolepsy, psychogenic depression, depressive alcoholic and other diseases associated with drowsiness, lethargy, asthenia. Also used to temporarily eliminate fatigue, improve physical and mental performance. WARNING! Overdose can prvesti to cardiac arrest!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="amfetamin">
		<text>Amphetamine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_amfetamin">
		<text>%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Increased stamina:%c[255,1,255,1] 180%\n%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Reduced appetite:%c[255,1,255,1] 40%\n%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Side effects: a slight deterioration of general condition\n%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Number of tablets:%c[255,1,255,1] 2\n%c[default]This stimulant widely and has long been used as a therapy, as well as with non-medical purposes. The neurotransmitter - units responsible for signal transmission from cell to cell. The influence on the activity of the brain performed on the mechanisms are different for different drugs. The operation stimulates the release of catecholamines (norepinephrine, serotonin, dopamine) and inhibition of reuptake. WARNING! An overdose can lead to heart failure!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="medkit_elite10">
		<text>'Elite' medkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="medkit_elite10_s">
		<text>Medkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="medkit_elite">
		<text>'Elite' medkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="medkit_elite_s">
		<text>Medkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medkit_elite">
		<text>The 'Elite' medkit developed by Zone Scientists specifically for work in the Zone. Kit includes:\n   2 alice clips and all military stencils\n   1 2" x 4.1yrds bandage gauze\n   2 4" x 4" sterile sponges\n   5 1" x 3" bandage strip\n   1 Field dressing\n   3 knuckle bandages\n   2 ammonia inhalant ampoules\n   2 butterfly strips\n   1 first aid instructions\n   1 triple antibiotic 1\n   1" tape\n   4 alcohol wipes\n   3 iodine wipes\n   3 antiseptic wipes\n   3 clean wipes\n   3 after bite wipes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandage_dmx">
		<text>Special Bandage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_bandage_dmx">
		<text>Special dressing injected with an anti-radiation compound. Typically used used by the Military in order to treat wounds whilst on manoeuvres throughout the Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tab">
		<text>Antipohmelin Tablets</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_tab">
		<text>%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Reduce hangover:%c[255,1,255,1] 95%\n%c[default]Tablets, completely relieving effects of alcohol. They enter the bloodstream special substances, which are somewhat reduce the concentration of ethanol. It was noticed that the constant use of data caps, their effectiveness is markedly reduced. No side effects were noted. The drug is fast acting</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radioprotector">
		<text>Radioprotector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_radioprotector">
		<text>%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Duration:%c[255,1,255,1] 60 sec\n%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Protection:%c[255,1,255,1] +150\n%c[default]Radioprotector "Indralin-B190," was part of the personal kits power plant staff. Appeared as a substitute in the Zone too toxic cystamine hydrochloride FC1. Reduces the effects of gamma radiation on the tissues of a living organism. The drug D-190 provides life-saving nine out of ten irradiated in obtaining an absolutely lethal dose of radiation. It is advisable to use pre-emptively, before irradiation, since the drug is not instantaneous. The drug is long-acting</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_anabiotic">
		<text>Anabiotic</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_anabiotic_descr">
		<text>%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Duration:%c[255,1,255,1] 5 minute\n%c[default]An experimental drug designed to research groups operating in the zone. Underlying drug tetradotoksin, known as "zombie powder", causes complete paralysis of the central nervous system, which supposedly can help out the shelter to survive ejection. The drug has not been tested in field conditions and failed clinical trials, which casts doubt on its effectiveness, and raises questions about possible side effects</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_psy_blockade">
		<text>Psi-block</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_psy_blockade_descr">
		<text>%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Duration:%c[255,1,255,1] 60 s\n%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Psi-defense:%c[255,1,255,1] +240\n%c[default]Narcotic drug that blocks nerve impulses to an avalanche. Protects against psychic radiation exposure and the controller for a short time or completely eliminates this effect. An interesting side effect: after treatment there is a total blocking of any emotion. In the Zone is used to counteract abnormal fields of increased psy-activity; application outside the Zone does not exist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_coagulant">
		<text>Vinca</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_coagulant_descr">
		<text>%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Duration:%c[255,1,255,1] 20 s\n%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Healing:%c[255,1,255,1] +30\n%c[default]Vikasol - a synthetic analogue of vitamin C. The main effect is to increase blood clotting. Demand among the stalkers, because it allows the body faster scar lacerations. It has a lasting effect</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_yadulin">
		<text>Yadulin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_yadulin_descr">
		<text>%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Improvement of:%c[255,1,255,1] +45\n%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Reduce hangover:%c[255,1,255,1] 50%\n%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Side effects: severe fatigue and a slight deterioration\n%c[default]The cheapest and widespread in the zone medical preparations for the accelerated healing of minor wounds and withdrawal from the body effects of alcohol. Were found side-effects shortly after taking the drug could dramatically worsen mood, or rolled over severe weakness. The drug is fast acting</text>
	</string>
	<!-- OTHER ITEMS -->
	<string id="wpn_arm_binoc">
		<text>Army Binoculars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_arm_binoc_s">
		<text>Army Binoculars PNV</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_dmx_binocul">
		<text>Portable Army Field-Binoculars with an improved aiming grid. Also equipped with Night-Vision capabilities, which make this particular model well sought after throughout the Zone. Manufactured strictly for Military use oin the late 1980's, extensive field research has proven time, and time again that these Military Binoculars well outmatched their predecessor - the world-famous "Zeiss" Binoculars</text>
	</string>
	<!-- NOT USED -->
	<string id="item_svarog">
		<text>Detector Svarog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_svarog_info">
		<text>Detector artifacts Series "Svarog". This detector is the latest leading research institutes. Thanks to nanotechnology, the sensitivity of the detector is increased up to 1.5 miles. The presence of artifacts displayed markers on the map terrain. In addition to their location, the detector detects the types of artifacts, making this unit the best of all the series of detectors</text>
	</string>
	<!-- AS OF YET UNUSED -->
	<string id="item_razgruzka">
		<text>Tactical Vest</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_razgruzka">
		<text>Convenience: 100\nStrength Class: 1\nWeight: 1kg\nThe 'Unloading Vest' is intended for the quick dispersal of ammunition, as well as individual means of emergency medical-aid. Contains ballistic panels to be used as an over-the-uniform multi-purpose Tactical Carrying Vest for serious incursions deep into the most dangerous parts of the ZONE</text>
	</string>
	<string id="timer">
		<text>Watch</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_timer">
		<text>Digital clock timer. Specially developed for special units of Russian Army. Shockproof and water resistant, can withstand immersion to 300 metres. Equipped with a timer and sundomerom. New Party were repeatedly stolen hours stalkers Scout warehouse database D-3 Special Forces colonel Bibik and sold wholesale traders in the Zone. Scout for these crimes was three times sentenced to death, but thanks to the notorious syndrome "Fear of Death," the stalker managed to survive the enforcement of sentences</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mine_1_name">
		<text>Mine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mine_1_name_s">
		<text>Mine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mine_1_description">
		<text>Blast Radius: 1 metre\n  Capacity: 20\n  Detonation Time: 10 seconds\n A mine used by the Military in order to defend a perimeter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mine_2_name">
		<text>"Enhanced" Mine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mine_2_name_s">
		<text>Mine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mine_2_description">
		<text>Blast Radius: 3 metres\n  Capacity: 35\n  Detonation Time: 10 seconds\n An improved version of the Military mine with a larger blast radius capable of inflicting severe damage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mine_3_name">
		<text>Electric Mine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mine_3_name_s">
		<text>Mine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mine_3_description">
		<text>Blast Radius: 6 metres\n  capacity: 60\n  Detonation Time: 10 seconds\n Developed by Military Scientists, this explosive device inflicts a severe "electric" discharge, causing serious damage to its victim(s)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_guitar_name">
		<text>Acoustic Guitar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_guitar_name_s">
		<text>Guitar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_guitar_descr">
		<text>A typical model, cheaply made in the Czech Republic, and brought into the Zone by an unknown Importer... many STALKERs like to have a little music to go along with their Vodka when relaxing near campfires throughout the Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_harmonica_name">
		<text>Harmonica</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_harmonica_name_s">
		<text>Harmonica</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_harmonica_descr">
		<text>It is believed that these mouth instruments are being brought into the Zone by the same Importer that has managed to smuggle in the vast number of Acoustic Guitars seen all over the place at campfire's throughout the Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_smoking">
		<text>Cigarette</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_wpn_smoking">
		<text>A simple cigarette. The truth is... no-one actually knows where, and who makes these cigarettes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_racya">
		<text>Portable Radio</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_racya_s">
		<text>Radio</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_racya">
		<text>Military issue hand-radio. Reception Radius is limited to 10 kilometres. Useful for communicating with others throughout the Zone, but it is anyone's guess who might be listening</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_fuck">
		<text>The Finger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_wpn_fuck">
		<text>Also known as: the middle finger, the highway salute, the bird (as in flicking, flipping or flying the bird), or to flip someone off, is an obscene hand gesture, often meaning the phrase "fuck you" or "up yours". Not adviseable to go around flipping people the "finger" if you don't want to get shot!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fosfor">
		<text>Phosphorous Stick</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fosfor_descr">
		<text>A small stick made of phosphoric material, which is used as a source of light in darkened spaces. Does not require recharging, but over time the glow weakens</text>
	</string>
	<string id="car_key">
		<text>Car Key</text>
	</string>
	<string id="car_key_s">
		<text>Car Key</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_car_key">
		<text>A car key that seems to have been modified. Supposedly, it may fit some of the vehicles found throughout the Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="car_key_2">
		<text>Strange Key</text>
	</string>
	<string id="car_key_2_s">
		<text>Strange Key</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_car_key_2">
		<text>A key that seems to have many extra facets and a small military symbol on it. Looks like it might fit some of the vehicles found throughout the Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bolt_detector_otclik">
		<text>Response Detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bolt_detector_otclik_s">
		<text>Response</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_bolt_detector_otclik">
		<text>Outdated model of the detector of abnormal activity. Reacts audible signal at the ingress of abnormal particles in a special chamber at the approach to anomalies, in addition, can detect the presence of artifacts and measure the distance to the nearest of them. The distance to the artifact is determined by supply frequency sound. Search mode artifacts include elevated cap antenna on the front panel. Due to simplicity of design is able to find only the most common artifacts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bolt_detector_medved">
		<text>Bear Detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bolt_detector_medved_s">
		<text>The Bear</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_bolt_detector_medved">
		<text>The detector of abnormal activity of last generation. Equipped with radar anomalous formations and LED display for displaying the direction to the artifact, and is able not only to detect artifacts, but also to determine distance. Search mode artifacts include elevated cap antenna on the front side of the device. Unfortunately, some outdated list of artifacts was hard coded into the device</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bolt_detector_veles">
		<text>Veles Detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bolt_detector_veles_s">
		<text>Veles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_bolt_detector_veles">
		<text>Detector scanner a new generation that is used by scientists. With three advanced camera location registration artifacts on the detector is displayed on a special screen. Is able to capture the radiation and the presence of anomalies. Search mode artifacts include elevated indicator-board on the front side of the instrument, in this mode is able to detect all known science artifacts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="helmet_stalker">
		<text>Mask</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_helmet_stalker">
		<text>Radiation protection = +60\nA standard gas mask designed to filter the air of radioactive dust and toxic substances. Widely used by both novices and veterans of all armed groups because of its functional indispensability. Not equipped with protection from bullets, shrapnel and mechanical effects</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radiation_detector">
		<text>Research dosimeter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_radiation_detector">
		<text>The device is accurate measurement of radiation in a unit of Bear. When you turn on full scans of the owner for radiation. Used mostly by scientists, but sometimes you can find the mother of stalkers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="m_dmx_box">
		<text>My stuff</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_m_dmx_box">
		<text>Backpack with my belongings</text>
	</string>
	<string id="silencers_box">
		<text>Bag with silencers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_silencers_box">
		<text>The bag, which contains all types of silencers for weapons</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zombie_antiradiation">
		<text>Antiradin Device</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zombie_antiradiation">
		<text>This device is intended to protect humans from radiation emitted by zombie. Device in a backpack completely absorbs radiation, which subsequently accumulates in a special container made of similar material, which covered stalker's containers for artifacts. "Antiradin" - expensive, but very useful thing in areas of high PSI activity - in fact most often it can run into a zombie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="device_warning_module">
		<text>Decoder Module</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_device_warning_module">
		<text>Decoder Module, connected to the PDA. Catches warnings from stalkers. Allows decoding PDA stalkers and withdraw money from them. After all the money in the Zone - electronic</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mine_detector">
		<text>Mine detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mine_detector">
		<text>Compact self-scanning minesweeper. Warns of finding mines beep. Radius sustainable detect mines seven metres</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_ammo_flame_transfer">
		<text>Generator flame mixture</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_ammo_flame_transfer">
		<text>This device allows you to create a mixture of colloidal gas and gasoline, which can then be used in a flamethrower. To generate the flame mixture must have a gas cylinder, a gas canisters and most flamethrower. After using the generator, Flamethrower is fully charged</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bolt_box">
		<text>Box with screws</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_bolt_box">
		<text>A small box inside of which is ten most common bolts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="device_torch_bad">
		<text>Broken Flashlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_device_torch_bad">
		<text>These lanterns are often out of order. Expiration date not specified. You may need to buy a new one</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_car_repair">
		<text>Automotive repair kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_car_repair">
		<text>Set of tools to almost completely restore the technical condition of the car. Use the set follows directly from the car</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Quest items -->
	<string id="item_doc_x8">
		<text>Aleksandrov's Diary</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_doc_x8">
		<text>Our laboratory work did not stop after the second explosion, also, it is not involved in the creation of a "live" weapons in contrast to other laboratories. We have been tasked so - to create a compact, stand-alone weapon. Whom is the so-called Cube Shadow. The technology was invented by his creation of a single subject, which we found in an expedition near the fourth power unit of Chernobyl NPP. This course consisted of an unknown substance, which was stronger than steel in a few thousand times... And not only that all the interesting properties of matter - there were other.\nFour years later, created the first prototype of Cuba shadows. I will not tell its working principle and features, except to say that the cube can "suck" the life energy of every creature and send it to the owner...\nCube of Shadows is the latest development in the history of the laboratory X-8. In fact because of him and began to create something weird. In the course of the next test in the test room explosion. More precisely it was like a very loud bang... I just was not far from the place. Going into it, I saw the bodies of their colleagues - as white medical gowns... All of them were dead... And standing in the middle of a ghost. Most, if I may say so, the real, the ghost!..\nI slammed the door in terror trial in the hall, knowing that it will not help... After that, give the command to evacuate. At this point, as an evil light was extinguished. Could be heard running, screaming, the new "bangs"...\nAs a result, the lab got a total of nine people, including me, and five soldiers. Others did not have time...\nI had to return to his apartment and wait for the decision of the authorities about the incident...\nAll the same, the fact remains - it was after the trial began, Cuba Shadows are strange things... Perhaps, the phantom was placed in the energy sector in Cuba and testing freed... I have to learn this subject sret...\nI've decided. I will take all necessary and sent to the laboratory</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dmx_military_map">
		<text>Map of Army Warehouses</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dmx_military_map_s">
		<text>Army Warehouses</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_dmx_military_map">
		<text>An old map of the army warehouses. Apparently was made before the second explosion at Chernobyl. On the map, in some places there are a few notes without names.\n \n"To see insert the card into the slot pistol"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fake_cube">
		<text>Cube Shadow</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_fake_cube">
		<text>Qualitatively made mock Cube shadows. Most likely it should look like a real cube</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dmx_pripyat_map">
		<text>Map of eastern Pripyat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dmx_pripyat_map_s">
		<text>Eastern Pripyat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_dmx_pripyat_map">
		<text>Place on the map marked the evacuation of the laboratory personnel X-8. Marker placed on the building of the BWC "Jubilee".\nOn the back of the card can be seen worn in some places record: "... for speed unlock doors before evacuating the code was changed to a very simple, consisting of a single digit - 1."\n \n"To see insert the card into the slot pistol"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mudrec_instruments">
		<text>Repair Tools</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mudrec_instruments">
		<text>A good set of tools. Apparently, the carefully chosen experienced master "for themselves, native." Despite the years, the entire instrument is well preserved</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_doc_x8_2">
		<text>Documents from laboratory X-8</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_doc_x8_2">
		<text>The documents indicate the technical characteristics of an antenna-radiator and how they differ from predicted. Apparently it is in X-8 developed a plan to create a radiator "Rainbow" (aka Brain Burner). On the reverse side is marked - it shows that this documentation is designed in the laboratory X-10</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_certificate">
		<text>Identity soldier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_certificate">
		<text>Document certifying that the holder is on the Zone and is in its legal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bipsizon_ogse">
		<text>"Psihodelin"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_bipsizon">
		<text>Strange chemical concoction made specifically for abnormal conditions within the Zone. Protects from psi-radiation and the incapacitating influence of Controllers for a short duration, and has been known to be able to disable their influence completely. Developed exclusively for Sciuentific Division Leaders conducting field tests inside of Zone's perimeter. Invented by a Dr."Bibik Voenstalov" and given the codename "Xanth-83". Extremely rare</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yod_ogse">
		<text>Preparation A-190</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_yod">
		<text>Preparation A-190 (190-kilodaton) has been identified in several multidrug-resistant (MDR) cell lines that show decreased drug accumulation without expression of P-glycoprotein. It is not clear whether this 190k protein is involved directtly in drug efflux. Recently, a gene for a putative transporter protein, MRP (multidrug resistance-assiciated protein) has been sequenced and localized to chromosome 16. The protein encoded by this gene contains a 7-amino-acid sequence present in the synthetic peptide used to generate the antiserum recognizing the 190k protein.Purpose:The study was undertaken to clarify the relationship of the 190k protein to MRP gene expression in non-P-glycoprotein-containing MDR cells of the large-cell and adenocarcinoma cancer lines</text>
	</string>
	<!-- THE ADDITIONAL DESCRIPTION TO SUBJECT MATTERS OF SALT !TB3D not in 134-->
	<string id="mushroom">
		<text>"Magic" Mushroom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_mushroom">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+10\n%c[default]"Amanita Muscaria" ( commonly known as the "fly agaric" ) is a poisonous and psychoactive basidiomycete fungus, one of many in the genus Amanita. Native throughout the temperate and boreal regions of the Northern Hemisphere. Known for the unpredictability of their effects. Depending on habitat and the amount ingested per body weight, effects can range from nausea and twitching to drowsiness, cholinergic crisis-like effects (low blood pressure, sweating and salivation), auditory and visual distortions, mood changes, euphoria, relaxation, ataxia, and loss of equilibrium. It was referred to as the 'Flesh of the Gods', or 'Food of the Gods' because those who ingested it believed that they were in direct communication with the Earth and the Universe when they consumed this Fungi. The Fly-Agaric was commonly used by the Druids and other "Magic" users. It was considered too powerful for those not trained in the higher levels of the mind</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mushroom2">
		<text>Holucengenic Mushroom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_mushroom2">
		<text>2   Purple A special mushroom that has mutated due to the affects of close proximity to rare artefacts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mushroom3">
		<text>Radiated Mushroom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_mushroom3">
		<text>3    Green A special mushroom that has mutated due to the affects of close proximity to rare artefacts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mushroom4">
		<text>Power Mushroom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_mushroom4">
		<text>4    Red top A special mushroom that has mutated due to the affects of close proximity to rare artefacts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mushroom5">
		<text>Wealth Mushroom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_mushroom5">
		<text>5    Blue fluoro top. A special mushroom that has mutated due to the affects of close proximity to rare artefacts</text>
	</string>
	<!-- !TB3D -->
	<string id="bolt_descr">
		<text>Bolt 32h100. A Stalker's best friend</text>
	</string>
	<!--	Duplicated from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970
	<string id="bolt_descr">
		<text>Bolt 32x100. Stalker's best friend</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="rover_bot_stancion">
		<text>Station for a mobile robot</text>
	</string>
	<!-- !TB3D -->
	<string id="cigara">
		<text>Cuban Cigar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cigara_s">
		<text>Cuban Cigar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_cigara">
		<text>Cuban cigars are rolled from tobacco leaves found throughout the country of Cuba. The filler, binder, and wrapper may come from different portions of the island. All cigar production in Cuba is controlled by the Cuban government, and each brand may be rolled in several different factories in Cuba. Cuban cigar rollers or "torcedores" are claimed by cigar experts to be the most skilled rollers in the world. Torcedores are highly respected in Cuban society and culture and travel worldwide displaying their art of hand rolling cigars. These are a rare find in the Zone... and can be worth a lot of Rubles to the right buyer</text>
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="cigara">
		<text>Cuba Cigar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_cigara">
		<text>This Cuban cigar. In the Zone gets smuggled. According to this, local merchants to sell cigars can be bought and they can not be the same. Tobacco natural, strength and flavor excellent. Complementing the picture beautiful form of cigars, which makes smoking a real pleasure when you consider that we are in the Zone</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="fake_cigara">
		<text>This needs to be fixed</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sandwich">
		<text>Sandwich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sandwich_s">
		<text>Sandwich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_sandwich">
		<text>A very basic sandwich using any available meat, or sausage product. The bread doesn't seem to be too stale to eat... will satisfy hunger for the time being, or until something more nutritious comes along</text>
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="sandwich">
		<text>Sandwich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_sandwich">
		<text>The most common sausage sandwich. Prepared in advance, so that you can eat on the go, without a knife uncovered and not digging in his backpack in search of food ingredients</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="beer_a">
		<text>Zone Beer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="beer_a_s">
		<text>Beer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_beer_a">
		<text>Apparently, this beer is brewed right here in the Zone somewhere. No-one seems to know where, but no-one seems to complain about it either</text>
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="beer_a">
		<text>Beer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_beer_a">
		<text>Beer of local production. Composition of the course has been written. A good way to get drunk to the blue tomato</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="flaska">
		<text>Flask</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flaska_s">
		<text>Flask</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_flaska">
		<text>A flask filled with clean, spring water... possibly just re-filled from the "Crystal" brand water found throughout the Zone</text>
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="flaska">
		<text>Flask</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_flaska">
		<text>Flask, filled to the edge of water from a pure spring. Cleaner water in these places do not find</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="sweetness">
		<text>"Alenka" Chocolate Bar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sweetness_s">
		<text>"Alenka"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_sweetness">
		<text>First produced in 1966 in Moscow's Red October Factory following a Kremlin directive to create a new brand of milk chocolate, "Alenka" became a sign of the good times... and a favorite snack of several generations to follow. Ingredients: sugar, dried whole milk, cocoa oil, ground cocoa, emulsifier lecithin E322</text>
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="sweetness">
		<text>Bar of chocolate</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_sweetness">
		<text>A delicious chocolate bar. Soybeans in excess, the presence of natural cocoa is doubtful. Well satisfies hunger and positive effect on brain activity</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="box_cigara">
		<text>Box of Cigars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="box_cigara_s">
		<text>Box of Cigars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_box_cigara">
		<text>A box of Cuban Cigars... worth a lot of money in a place such as this!</text>
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="box_cigara">
		<text>Cigar Box</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_box_cigara">
		<text>A box with Cuban cigars. Very expensive thing</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="balalaika_a">
		<text>Balalaika</text>
	</string>
	<string id="balalaika_a_s">
		<text>Balalaika</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_balalaika_a">
		<text>A stringed instrument of Russian origin, with a characteristic triangular body and three strings. The balalaika family of instruments includes, from the highest-pitched to the lowest, the prima balalaika, sekunda balalaika, alto balalaika, bass balalaika and contrabass balalaika. The earliest mention of the term balalaika dates back to a 1688 BC Russian document.The term became widely used in Ukrainian language documents from 1717-1732. According to one theory, it is thought that the term was borrowed into Russian where, in literary language, it first appeared in a poem by V. Maikov "Elysei" in 1771</text>
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="balalaika_a">
		<text>Balalaika</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_balalaika_a">
		<text>Normal balalaika. A wonderful Russian folk instrument. In the Zone, too, lacks the masters of playing</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="det_artefact_indy">
		<text>"Response" Artefact Detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="det_art_indy_info">
		<text>The "Response" Detector was developed by the Zone's Scientific Community. It was the first model of Detector to surface within the Zone. Detection radius is limited to 40 metres, and the presence of an Artefact is distinguished only by a simple sound. Further developments of this model have led to far more effective devices, which can be difficult to obtain both inside, and outside the Zone's perimeter</text>
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="det_artefact_indy">
		<text>Detector artifacts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="det_art_indy_info">
		<text>This is the first detector artifacts, designed by local craftsmen. The device is ineffective because it does not reach over and 40 meters, and the presence of an artifact is recognized only an audible signal. But in its time, with the help of this device has been found so many artifacts</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="det_art_ultra_super">
		<text>"Svarog" Artefact Detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="det_art_ultra_super_s">
		<text>"Svarog"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_det_art_ultra_info">
		<text>The last known invention to come out of the Scientific Research Institute. Using advanced "Nanotechnology", this sensitive detector can detect Artefacts from as far away as 1.5 km, and displays such finds on the user's map. Besides their precise location, this excellent detector can distinguish the type of Artefact found. This alone, sets it apart from all other models. "Svarog" - ( Old Slavic mythological God of the sky, the father of the sun and fire )</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Duplicated string id's from "string_table_arhara.xml" and the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" files.
 TB. you should choose only one string id and delete the rest - aleks1970 -->
	<!-- before was "det_art_ultra_info" id(which was also duplicated), but now have new string to match "items.ltx" file - aleks1970 -->
	<!--	<string id="enc_det_art_ultra_info">
		<text>Artifact Detector Series 'ULTRA'. This detector is the latest created by local scientists. Thanks to nanotechnology, the sensitivity of the detector is increased to one hundred meters. The presence of Artifacts displays markers on the map. In addition to their location, the detector detects the types of Artifacts, which makes this unit the best of all the series of detectors to hunt for Artifacts. Activated when in the pistol slot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_det_art_ultra_info">
		<text>This is an improved version of the detector artifacts, past upgrades among scientists. Added map of the area with the output label on it. Range increased to 70 meters. In connection with the reasonable price and improved performance, its use is considered preferable</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="detektor_amorf">
		<text>Isomorphic Detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="detektor_amorf_s">
		<text>Isomorphic Detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="detektor_amorf_info">
		<text>Detector able to detect items containing particles of an Alien power and display these items on the map within a radius of fifty to sixty metres, also beeps. It is also possible to locate Artifacts. Activated when in the pistol slot</text>
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="detektor_amorf">
		<text>The detector is isomorphic</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="detector_elite_john">
		<text>Ultra Detector</text>	<!-- Was 'Hologram Detector' -->
	</string>
	<string id="detector_elite_john_s">
		<text>Ultra Detector</text>	<!-- Was 'Hologram Detector' -->
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="detector_elite_john">
		<text>Detector Holograms</text>
	</string> -->
	<!-- DOCUMENTS AKIM -->
	<string id="doc_garbage">
		<text>Old documents from the Dump</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_garbage_s">
		<text>Old documents</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_doc_garbage">
		<text>Documents found at the Dump. Some sort of Scientific formula.... written in an incomprehensible language. By the looks of it - could quite easily be the senseless scribblings of a lunatic</text>
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="doc_garbage">
		<text>Old paper from the landfill</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_doc_garbage">
		<text>Documents found in the Garbage. Formula, write a foreign language. By type - ravings of a madman</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="doc_agro">
		<text>Old documents from Agroprom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_agro_">
		<text>Old documents</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_doc_agro">
		<text>A stack of documents found in the Catacombs beneath the Agroprom Institute. Some sort of formula written in a language I don't understand. Very strange indeed</text>
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="doc_agro">
		<text>Old paper with agricultural industry</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_doc_agro">
		<text>A stack of documents found in the catacombs of agricultural industry. Formula, write a foreign language. By type - not very much like the previous</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="doc_x18_1">
		<text>Old Document - Part I</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_x18_1_s">
		<text>Part I</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_doc_x18_1">
		<text>Documentation found in the Dark Valley. Appears to be the first part of something more in depth</text>
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="doc_x18_1">
		<text>The old document. Part I</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_doc_x18_1">
		<text>Documents found in Dark Valley. By all appearances this is the first part</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="doc_x18_2">
		<text>Old Document - Part II</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_x18_2_s">
		<text>Part II</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_doc_x18_2">
		<text>The second part of a series of Documents to be found in Laboratory X-18</text>
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="doc_x18_2">
		<text>The old document. Part II</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_doc_x18_2">
		<text>The second part doumentov found in the laboratory X-18</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="doc_x18_3">
		<text>Old Document - Part III</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_x18_3_s">
		<text>Part III</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_doc_x18_3">
		<text>The third part of a series of Documents to be found in Laboratory X-18</text>
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="doc_x18_3">
		<text>The old document. Part III</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_doc_x18_3">
		<text>The third part doumentov found in the laboratory X-18</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="doc_x18_4">
		<text>Old Document - Part IV</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_x18_4_s">
		<text>Part IV</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_doc_x18_4">
		<text>The fourth part of a series of Documents to be found in Laboratory X-18</text>
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="doc_x18_4">
		<text>The old document. Part IV</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_doc_x18_4">
		<text>Last quarter of doumentov found in the laboratory X-18</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="doc_x16">
		<text>Old Document from Laboratory X-16</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_x16_s">
		<text>Old X-16 Document</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_doc_x16">
		<text>Documentation found inside Laboratory X-16. A series of Scientific Formulas written in a language I do not understand. Apparently this is the last portion of a series of Documents which make up some sort of Report on Secretive Experiments throughout the Zone... It is signed by a one 'Benjamin Linus' of the Dharma Initiative... what does this mean?!.... and, who/what is this Dharma Initiative I keep seeing all over the place!?</text>
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="doc_x16">
		<text>Old document from the X-16</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_doc_x16">
		<text>Documents found in the laboratory X-16. Formula, write a foreign language. Apparently this is the last part of the documents found</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="pda_info">
		<text>Broken PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_s">
		<text>PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_pda_info">
		<text>A typical PDA, which in the zone a lot. Besides - a non-working and bruised. It is seen that the former owner was with him, not very thrifty. Activate the PDA can not be due to a broken screen. Flash cards do not. So fuck anything</text>
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="pda_info">
		<text>Broken PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_pda_info">
		<text>A typical PDA, which many in the Zone. Besides - a non-working and bruised. It is evident that the former owner was with him not very frugal. Insert a PDA can not be due to a broken screen. Flash card no. In general, nothing can fuck</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="hand_teleporter_arhara">
		<text>Defective hand teleporter</text>	<!-- Was 'teleportator' -->
	</string>
	<string id="hand_teleporter_arhara_s">
		<text>Defective teleporter</text>	<!-- Was 'teleportator' -->
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="hand_teleporter_arhara">
		<text>Faulty manual teleportator</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="hand_teleporter">
		<text>Hand teleporter</text>	<!-- Was 'teleportator' -->
	</string>
	<string id="hand_teleporter_s">
		<text>Hand teleporter</text>	<!-- Was 'teleportator' -->
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="hand_teleporter">
		<text>Hand teleportator</text>
	</string> -->
	<!-- Documents on the Hood -->
	<string id="bloknot_pantera">
		<text>Panther's Notebook</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bloknot_pantera_s">
		<text>P. Notebook</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_bloknot_pantera">
		<text>Panther's personal notebook. It contains several indecipherable phrases, and the following code: 25190456... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
	</string>
	<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970
	<string id="bloknot_pantera">
		<text>Panthers Notebook</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_bloknot_pantera">
		<text>Personal notebook Panthers. It was written a few sentences and some code: 25,190,456. To view a document, insert in pistol slot</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="dosye_zvez">
		<text>The "Astrologer" file</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dosye_zvez_s">
		<text>Astrologer Profile</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_dosye_zvez">
		<text>A file containing information on the "Astrologer"... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
	</string>
	<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970
	<string id="dosye_zvez">
		<text>Astrologer Profile</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_dosye_zvez">
		<text>Quick profile on Astrologer. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="foto_kukla">
		<text>Photo of a Doll</text>
	</string>
	<string id="foto_kukla_s">
		<text>Photo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_foto_kukla">
		<text>An old photograph of a child's toy doll... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
	</string>
	<!--		Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970
	<string id="foto_kukla">
		<text>Photo Doll</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_foto_kukla">
		<text>Old photo normal infant dolls. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="pilot_zapiska">
		<text>the Pilot's Letter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pilot_zapiska_s">
		<text>Letter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_pilot_zapiska">
		<text>The Helicoptor Pilot's letter... which contains some very important information... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
	</string>
	<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970
	<string id="pilot_zapiska">
		<text>Letter to the pilot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_pilot_zapiska">
		<text>Letter from a helicopter pilot with important information. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="foto_chaes_truba">
		<text>Photo of the Pilot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="foto_chaes_truba_s">
		<text>Photo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_foto_chaes_truba">
		<text>The photograph of the burned helicoptor taken by the Pilot. In it, the large pipe alongside the burned helicopter can be seen clearly... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
	</string>
	<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970
	<string id="foto_chaes_truba">
		<text>Photo Driver</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_foto_chaes_truba">
		<text>Photo taken a helicopter pilot. It is visible to a large pipe with the burning helicopter. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="foto_aver_mono">
		<text>Group Photo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="foto_aver_mono_s">
		<text>Photo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_foto_aver_mono">
		<text>Photograph of the group that burned the helicoptor... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
	</string>
	<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970
	<string id="foto_aver_mono">
		<text>Photo of</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_foto_aver_mono">
		<text>Group photo, fired on the helicopter. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="foto_aver_zvezd">
		<text>Photo of the group "Leader"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="foto_aver_zvezd_s">
		<text>Photo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_foto_aver_zvezd">
		<text>Photograph of the Leader of the group that burned the helicoptor... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
	</string>
	<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970
	<string id="foto_aver_zvezd">
		<text>Photos of the leader</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_foto_aver_zvezd">
		<text>Photos of the leader who fired on the helicopter. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="chaes2_karta_kluk">
		<text>Photo of the NPP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chaes2_karta_kluk_s">
		<text>Chernobyl</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_chaes2_karta_kluk">
		<text>Photograph of the northern side of the Chernobyl NPP. There is a mark on it possibly indicating the way to the southern side of the NPP... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
	</string>
	<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970
	<string id="chaes2_karta_kluk">
		<text>Chernobyl Photo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_chaes2_karta_kluk">
		<text>Photo northern region of Chernobyl. It marked a rough passage on the other - the south side of the Chernobyl NPP. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="kreditka">
		<text>Credit Card</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kreditka_s">
		<text>Credit Card</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_kreditka">
		<text>A Credit Card issued from the Bank of America with a $5000,000 limit on it!... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
	</string>
	<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970
	<string id="kreditka">
		<text>Credit Card</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_kreditka">
		<text>Credit Card Bank of America in denominations 5 mil. USD. To view the credit card insert in pistol slot</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="razved_karta">
		<text>Map Fragments</text>
	</string>
	<string id="razved_karta_s">
		<text>Map Fragments</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_razved_karta">
		<text>Old scraps of a map containing directions, or coordinates of some sort... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
	</string>
	<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970
	<string id="razved_karta">
		<text>Scrap maps</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_razved_karta">
		<text>Old scrap card with the coordinates of the transition. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="karta_peschera">
		<text>Cave Map</text>
	</string>
	<string id="karta_peschera_s">
		<text>Map</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_karta_peschera">
		<text>Old map of the caves... somebody has scribbled some possible directions on it... hard to decipher... maybe the way out of here?!... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
	</string>
	<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970
	<string id="karta_peschera">
		<text>Map of Cave</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_karta_peschera">
		<text>An old map of the Cave. It shows all the moves and tunnels. There's also a label with the outputs of the Cave. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="recipi_bpb">
		<text>STALKERs Note</text>
	</string>
	<string id="recipi_bpb_s">
		<text>STALKERs Note</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_recipi_bpb">
		<text>Unidentified STALKERs' note... there appears to be information here regarding being able to modify certain Artefacts!?... sounds interesting... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
	</string>
	<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970
	<string id="recipi_bpb">
		<text>Note stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_recipi_bpb">
		<text>Note an unknown stalker. There is information on the modification of the artifacts. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="stukach_book">
		<text>Informant's Notebook</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stukach_book_s">
		<text>Notebook</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stukach_book_desc">
		<text>Notebook belonging to the "Freedom" informant. It contains information about modifying Artefacts... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
	</string>
	<!-- from the "string_table_enc_equipment" file - aleks1970
		<string id="stukach_book">
		<text>Notebook informer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stukach_book_s">
		<text>Notebook informer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stukach_book_desc">
		<text>Notebook informer group of Liberty. There is information about the new artmod. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>
	</string> -->
	<!-- from the "sak_strings" file - aleks1970
		<string id="stukach_book_desc">
		<text>To view: insert the Laptop into the first slot.\nPavliks laptop. Besides some boring financial records, it contains a recipe for 'Artpreobrazovaniya'</text>
	</string> -->
</string_table>
