<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 controller vice comptroller -->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->
<string_table>
	<string id="stalker_story_1">
		<text>Climb, then at the hangar. Around pylischa, web - all under the roof, the detectors completely stupid smack, they say, not that anyone around, and we are in nature no. Come take a position on the perimeter : Sanya ahead, we covers... And then - BAM! Balka, a hefty, steel, rust on the ceiling, breaks down - and down! As Sanya dodged, he did not know, but this crap stuck right in the spot where he stood. Well, he is dropped and rolled, did not rise to their feet at all, and so let's lay shmalyat! Others, too frightened, idiots, and myself went to plant a white light. Here Sanya started yelling something about a creature in the corner. I'm looking - there is no creature can not see... In general, went without surgery, but this particular mess... bordelero... We went to these ruins go, but walked five minutes - cautiously, so that under the beams of these no longer come to be. And delirium, delusions full well : that one, then another something prividitsya, they come in bursts polrozhka slash in an empty space. And two of them did not lucky : one was walking on a level floor, and suddenly fell into a pit, the second runaway door across the back pulled. Well, here we all wound up - clearly are in fact, the creature was some fun! Kerf Psi- defense, in all corners of the gas grenade - well, wait, someone will, and the fingers on the descent. We are waiting, waiting... A creature, as it turned out, was a bat or something... While we are all in a heap at the bottom of playing the fool, she thought quietly sitting under the ceiling and the fun, bitch... It came down to us only later, and then almost by accident. This shook the snake a couple of bars - half a roof and welled. Straight at us... four guys in the pellet in place... Here we have it and get it! As Sanya heard sheburshanie above, so on the machine and gave all - useful fucking jerk! Come here and scream! We, too, is clear, jump, given all of the trunks... Creature sypanula top with cries that right ears laid. Well, here already, we took the soul : who is the butt beat, who just walked up and down legs. Sanya, so he took out a knife so that she pobolnee guts spill... Commander, of course, all with difficulty, but dragged, and then the bastard would do this with a spoon scrape the floor had to be...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_1_name">
		<text>The Creature in the Hangar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_10">
		<text>Have you heard about the Explorer? The first of stalkers. First in a zone started to walk. Until now live. It is said to hold at any point. Another thing is that find it difficult - posters with the address did not stick... Yes, and spend far not everyone agrees. Bablosov takes a lot, but if you found him and arranged to be sure - he'll train will take where necessary. But with whom would pereteret. So he, perhaps, saw what was on the radar...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_10_name">
		<text>Superconductor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_11">
		<text>Ponty beat and Salvage to be - are two big differences... Che dumali, then loot the so- given? No shit! For you so just ugly any shavaet or soldiers overwhelm... We must think. There must think, and here is even better. Quite the bulls here long stretch. Do not feed it, without the attic, if... In short, it is there. The three of us with bruises and Tsepoy deceased went through the service yard - road, shorter cut. Look - bandyukov some scratches. Well, we snykalis. And he goes past us - not to notice. such fine and pulls the bag - whether it is healthy. And the machine hangs slyly : just what we nashpiguet olives. Well, Bruise me: " Come let us touch mozglyaka Che him there? " And I told him : "Quiet, woodpecker! better see where he draws his swag. " Well Th... Here the deer as failed somewhere - we do not even understand. Oh, wait. He got about twenty minutes. While shake to him Tsepa back quietly pulled from the trellis and poltykvy demolished. They started with a black body to gut : Bronicas it was cool, and Lopatnic should be... I cast away - my boys will give me always, I living in a share. Here, as heranet!... In short, the suffering that was not simple : it is a tricky four- frills, that exploded when with him Bronicas someone would shoot. I knocked out for a quick - very few people right now on the shot and the explosion to be declared... Came a month later. By flails with bruises and a deer - if only bone. In general the zeros. In short, I figured, where he dived into the ruins, and he climbed up there... Well, took three rooms - Golyakov! Then look in the corner a lot of beds in bulk. What the dick there so many sunbeds? In short, took shovel. Sweeping. Look, my woman, the hatch! Pick up, then cover the candle lantern. E - pH - pe - se -te! I'm in paradise!... Well, why was there - my business... In the loser is left. And his ears would be hanged - would long ago have become blind man's buff, or are still running around barefoot, cormorants... As some...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_11_name">
		<text>Hatch in Paradise</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_12">
		<text>They say there is one group of friends... when they called a shaman, and when the druids. They say even with an electronic equipment are not - to nature, they say, is closer, and so on... Well, they say that the area of electronics... on all sorts of electromagnetic radiation reacts strongly... Yes, and mutants at you inciting. As for their language is obtained, so Zone - a living organism. It is impossible, they say, to get into it with the devices - the right person and without any extra portions cope. True, they are machines, goats, hauling... None would have teeth and claws to try... On the other hand, they die in the zone seems to be not so much. Not more than us, they fins glued... So, perhaps, correctly guessed... They are, however, like more on the Belarusian side to enter the Zone... And then it would be nice to look at them... so check at the same time as they have artefacts in my pocket is found...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_12_name">
		<text>The Story of the Battle Druids</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_13">
		<text>Does anyone know about the secret laboratories deep in the Zone?... Say, still working... Well, yes, yes... It is unclear how there anyway someone could survive... without supplies, energy... That's a question - maybe there are not people work? I'm here with tipkom one spoke... He had not seen the laboratory... No, I do not see, but the scanner caught negotiations strange at Yantar. In them about some laboratories it was. And the other guy that, first, swore that he came across as something on a figure in kombeza type stalkerovskogo, but heaped more... And figure this translucent told him that he was falling away from here. " Do not bother, they say, go away, we're working. " Well, the guy peresral... understandably! Who of us had seen this?... On the other hand, it seems to happen far from the radar... Well, yes. So it is hardly true... But on the other hand... mutation, because they are different, perhaps, are they? Maybe this is not the people, and any entity energy?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_13_name">
		<text>Shadow Ghost</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_14">
		<text>Know what to say? In this part of the zone is almost impossible to sleep... I am a lucky, and so I can not sleep... and the people of such nightmares happen, that happen, and do not wake up in the morning... of heart failure, for example... Who are the horses move, and who exactly tearing the roof... Recently, however, the rumor went, that there is a remedy. If strong itch to get some sleep, it is desirable to find a bucket of old... well, or at least a large pot... evaporation there... The main thing is the whole... Head back tuck - and spins himself as God 's bosom... Well, laugh, laugh. I look at you in a couple of days when the fatigue of the legs start to fall. Geniuses... But tell yourself what, so horseradish warriors here have recently begun to run hither and helmets clever? Well, yes! Previously, two years as much, nor hearing, nor spirit, but lately frequented! Hat they have some new - the boys found the body of one, was told. The grid is inside of a thin copper wire, attached to the liner. Think about it - what a harness, Ladi the hell is she? In general, it is " x -g - g " an ulterior motive, just telling you. Of the anomalies to choose here is nothing special - not the land, at other sites and pobezopasnee and fatter pieces still exist... I think so, the approaches they are scheduled. Bridgehead prepared. The sarcophagus want to break, mark my words. Soon as figanet - nobody will not find it. Mark my words... Most importantly, away from here at that time to be...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_14_name">
		<text>Nightmare Bucket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_15">
		<text>Slyshte, guys, and you're about to "intercept" of anything how to know? It is well, say spetsaki, human warriors! But how they work, eh? How to work! This is not a asshole to the cordon! Not only that, in most zazhope climb, so more and sit in the zone for months! Yes, I do not gonyu! Base with them, several pieces at once, caches up to figischa, and to the perimeter of the turntable to hold on supplies podkidyvayut. Commander they Gromov some... I think the name - bullshit, fake. They did a "major", then "Thunder" name. Do not believe me? So Pahomych interception somehow caught! Caught and his legs barely carried away, but it would shpoknuli for healthy living... Secrecy, so it! Pahomycha something everyone knows? Well, that and it is! Not this bullshit, and a serious team. Fuck knows what they then drew such an interesting, but they work - my mother dear! I would be in a third... not, at least ten percent of the way! Already have a house in Sochah ten floors built to... They say such a thing is... monstrov for two hundred meters intersect. Any creature! Clear horseradish, then walk around the Zone - spit... But then again, they say, there are some figures... Not warriors, but kind of like of our... In general, slipped some to the Zone center. Few that made their way - they say, and know how to tame the beasts! They are generally outside the perimeter, on the mainland, do not go - and for them too, no one... Well, except, perhaps, to whom the sarcophagus destined to get... Already arteacts in them - even wipe! Dolgovtsy some of them are well known... know, you bastards, fight and keep silent! Ask anyone of them policemen, all respond: "Fairy Tales". Well do not females, as well?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_15_name">
		<text>Intercept - inhabitant of depth</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_16">
		<text>Brethren, ye have heard that recently a few not the right of the antennas? Monolith has sent us, and the brothers time to get noticed. One we destroyed immediately. The other two fled. Panties. They are all cowards. Only true faith leaves no room for fear! Two were able to escape, but Monolith is wise and omniscient. Hence, they need him alive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_16_name">
		<text>About probrvavshihsya to antennas</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_17">
		<text>Brothers, Monolith has called me at night. I talked to him. It was beautiful in its grandeur. I'm almost blind, but it's light filled me with great force! I know, I feel that his power remains with us all! He told me that he can only defeat the evil of strong faith. that his strength will fill only the faithful. Still, he showed me that our victory is close!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_17_name">
		<text>About Monolith in a dream</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_18">
		<text>The brothers recently Monolith had my faith, and I almost fell from grace. But I survived! Praise Monoliths! His temper test us! We returned from the dark valley, and I almost fell behind his brothers. The evil took advantage of it and suddenly began to play with me. I... I doubted. True image distorted ; enemy whispered to me that the Monolith is using us as slaves. But then I realized : this is a test. I thought about the strength and radiance of the monolith, and then the will and confidence back to me. Since then, I'm not afraid of any testing and did not know doubts. Praise Monoliths!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_18_name">
		<text>On the test of faith</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_19">
		<text>I was in the Dark Valley. There's a lot wrong, because the power of the Monolith has not yet reached these places. We protected. At night we were attacked. We have fought fiercely with these animals. Merit brothers were great : soon monolith called them to himself. To me, he prepared another test. My weapon is not fired. But here Monolith told me: " You are with me, and my strength - with you. If you will be steadfast in their faith, then my enemies in pieces, and close to me! " Then I became a shadow. I crouched down and walked to the right. Stupid spies did not notice anything. thought it through with us and laughed at the empty bodies of our brothers. But I have seen them back. And then out of my hands hit the power Monolith. So he killed them all. I am happy to serve you, perfect!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_19_name">
		<text>Pro bout in the Dark Valley</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_2">
		<text>We are a partner to one SRI long straight. Painfully lonely place. Nor beast in the county, nor the mutants. But who would not go there either scared vusmert, or with coils moved down back, if any, they are no longer seen. Have decided to quietly scout. They came out dark, and how to get to the places already beginning to dawn. Left the car in raspadochke, went to the forest edge. There stood, partner stayed at the bottom and I climbed up a tree with optics - look around, that 's going around. I see - the body, and not so very much neglected, the whole glass almost everything in the yards of grass a little bit, not like in other places - on the belt... Around it appeared that live here, but the silence was complete, and no movement was not. Suddenly a little on my right turn passed - someone with a machine gun beat short. I optics there. I see on the roof of one of the buildings unknown man, hunted like a rat rushes, shooting indiscriminately in all directions. Who is it so scared - I look and I can not understand : he was there alone. And here... began... I saw it all in full view. Machine gun from his hand by itself has departed... If the glands have grown wings!... A guy opened my mouth can be seen, yelled something, pulled a knife and put it in front of him. And then, tree - winder, and lo and behold in front of him hanging by itself is another. That's a sting in the air to him and hanging, and no one holds it. What happened next - it's not the night to tell... Five minutes to cut the guy. Little by little, so females, their mother 's leg : it cut, then a shot... Poor guy soon had already been covered in blood... Then, as he's in his legs began to totter, it also knocked the knife, then as a man lift into the air as zavernet a couple of times... I like that in my life seen - naturally, like a rag Berthelot... I was wet for three seconds... Then... No, all I will not... In general, as I catch my breath, for another five minutes fumbling gunpoint in the area. Hands trembling, optics has become wet from sweat... Well, at least to a creature! And in the normal range and infakrasnom - no -che st. As I have tears, mate looked at me, and ask his mind. And how have returned to base, I have a week to tear the eyebrows, not dries out... Then, like a bit away, porassprashival our - maybe some of what is heard? Only the people in my oblique glances started - an hour, did not move it? That such things...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_2_name">
		<text>Horror in the SRI</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_20">
		<text>Brothers, we patrolled the outskirts of the Black Forest and ran there for the wrong - alone. He began to turn, so we did not kill him, but he is still half the animal was in its state... I know a wise Monolith did it for us all : he once again showed us the true face of their enemies. Now, our faith became stronger! Nearing, brothers... Nearing victory over the infidels, and then the monolith to fulfill our heart's desire! A true devotee, he will bring to himself and to his glory, his majesty! We will dwell forever in the glory of it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_20_name">
		<text>Transformation in the Black Forest</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_3">
		<text>In general, my friend told me this is what one Shout. Picked it up in the middle of the night boss : " Run to the lab! cargo arrived. " He was drowsy, do not cut one : what load? They told him : "Are you alcohol official government census? Trupak fresh on the table, Bon appetit! " He was at the table. And there is... He, along the way, blind man's buff from the Zone in his lifetime has seen : and you are torn, and fried - varenye and mutants fell more than a dozen, and then once in the stomach dinner walk began. From the first vzglyada, two minutes a person, just head for the normal guys are similar: a healthy pumpkin bumpy. Well, the body - a concentration camp, a pancake. Skin and bones. But he is then disassembled, and at first said, I looked, mash some : everything upside down, slap an orange- red dirty trick, blood type... These munitions have not regretted Honduras. It says, was a cross between a colander and torn pads... In general, they are clearly on it in their jackboots walked well, not the object, and a piece of meat in black rags. rest of the night and half the morning hunchback. Along the way, it turns out, this is the creature, which the local illusionist known for : the black cloth, a vision of stalkerov, chump meter in girth... Funny that his face, who saw, felt that this type temechko. No, a person something he naturally is, only very small : winkers not be opened, and a nose like a pin, though a hefty fall, straight jamb at the door. Walks, shows, and his head on his chest hangs - no forces to keep sharp... Mozglyak... And imagine what these creatures eat for lunch. Fungi! Mushrooms! In short, all seen - in the Zone is full of mushrooms, so "old "tooth imply that these creatures juice from them too tight. Gourmets, Shoot... And you know what he had in the bag was stashed on the side? Well? But where you are! In short, the brains he had the sun dried. And you know whose? Controllers!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_3_name">
		<text>Dinner pathologist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_4">
		<text>Profits came to us here Durikov a hiking deep into the Zone... Cheshem, it means that the tabernacle in the five minutes of rest, and it immediately to the fifth point, and relax. And how to walk, so he was the last ass off the ground tears. Well dorasslablyalsya... Behind, and there it Controller of the brains of the DAC - and ready... So, remember moral of the story. The rustle of a breeze out there, or any suspicious... Let him run through bunny, bunnies though there do not let God... In short, ready every moment should be. To shop, hand grenades and machine were in the continuous. If you already have seen that, once planted polrozhka. If the bushes something - too lupite, and then to ask. Here the course of this young soldier : not hung clothes, but with guts will eat, will not have time to fart! Yes, at the monitors - is another story. Suppose you had shot at rustling and falls immediately in the same second! Though on the back, as though. Controller picks, if he sees you, he needs to concentrate or something. While sunbathing in the shade, listen to both ears - a rustling, is there any stuff to you. You can gently slide pereschelknut, and grenades, too it is useful to prepare... In general, if quietly all count to three and bring down! Bring down to hell! Well that sucked? Eh... take care of myself every second - the only way to survive here and you can...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_4_name">
		<text>Easy prey Controller</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_5">
		<text>I think that... Not even what I think - so pretending to be... And suddenly it all - that's all there is - an experiment some of the people? This is, perhaps, some creatures green... Why? No worse than any other version... It is interesting to me: if it's something like a landfill, then what they run in there? Check for any artefacts we most drool admits? Or is it a general bomb some, eh? Porastaschili them around the world, in laboratories every one that is rich poraskoshelilis... No, well, that's cool!... This is to my pleasure!... Bought under the counter any crap... took away a lot of dough... Like we have all the steeper, envy, sheep... but it... it... ka -ak heranet!... Oh, Class!... Oh, I can not!... Oops... UV -f- r... But in general, of course, FIG knows what really is... Is the one who went for a radar can about this porasskazat... Well, yes, they, can, and know just can not tell - moo and drooling allowed. Maybe it's because both times and let... Eh... That climb all sorts of thoughts... Sadly it at all...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_5_name">
		<text>Pitfalls</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_6">
		<text>So... I remember someone I was yesterday about anything asked, and I forgot... And, he remembered. There is, therefore, curious, why in the Zone only our bigheads crawling, and foreigners, and the nose does not appear, though here the material Nobelevok thousand and three... Hence, corresponding to the points. Firstly, why should there by climbing when you can give to our grant with such conditions, they you all that necessary, you will bring on a silver platter? But if the second, they actually visited here, and over and over. These are the last two years zabugortsy the Zone are afraid to climb... happened to them, one major bummer. Now just buy the materials so the information. Pay in general good, so many single work for them, and looters, too... What, never heard of this story? Well, give! The whole area was on the ears, and you have fallen from the sky. In general, getting to a big one. Some scientists about thirty people from half the world... all the lights, of course, here and there... Preparing seriously: money charges - at least one place you eat, the equipment - the mountains. Taken with a platoon of military experts for the protection of our three guides, the armored shielded plunged and cast off. What's that... Returned a week later... twelve men on armored personnel killed in the trash. By Barb came at Rotten wood, and there they were waiting... looters. Yes... These do not care where people broke... Put almost everyone. For the perimeter, only three have chosen - our two and one egghead. The man from the impressions powerfully moved attic... Well, it quickly by the neck - and treat. He now writes a book about the Zone. Our else did - the experience has helped. Although... also, probably, in their own way moved : one went to the radar and gone, and the second to the mainland served. Well, the other area has. About Campus -32 heard? That's where they hit. At first everything seems quiet it was... Well, within... They're filmed, was measured, samples were collected in the anomalies pointed their instruments... And then they started insanity. Mass. People slowly began to ride the roof. I ours - one that had gone into retirement - told... Who 's throat began to tear his nails, who currently heads against the wall broke, and who simply - the barrel in his mouth, and... And then there was wild beasts flooded. in itself was barricaded in the house. Provided, huh? Outside, the night and all the surrounding creatures, but inside people with coils flies, one after another. In short, the morning ones who have to think he could, somehow escaped. drove back straight, with no roads, and even a couple of anomalies hooked... Reached Rotten wood... And of those who stayed there, one was never found. Guys just say that in those places were added sharply supervisors. Yes... Since then, in town -32 no one agrees, as a foreigner in a zone and a roll and not make me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_6_name">
		<text>The Chronicles of eggheads globalists</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_7">
		<text>So that's what I wanted to say something. When dolg visited that illusion was taken, I was near there! Yes, I happen to do in those places turned out to be! My car flew right front : the bolts were cut on a hummock. And in spare parts complete zero. Pomaterilsya as I should, then let me, I think the plant will go there, pick up the correct. Well, there was kilometer to go, back and forth - a half-hour Delov! Yes, and I have been there before... Suddenly I see " Duty! And not just patrol and pieces of rug! Well, I think, a pancake - compote!... As was so into the bush and rolled over. "If you noticed, and combing will - I think - and here I tryndets. Lay down, in short, in the hole and try not to breathe. And then the shooting! So that such queues shmalyali, I've only heard once in a lifetime... when first base was taken - old men, remember? In general, lying down, listening to both ears... It is currently the Baha'i and then another, and how grohnet!... After five minutes, subsides, and for me like no one is going. Well, I picked up insolence, rose sensitive and looking through binoculars. And they quickly pulled out of the shop... creased such blind man's buff its a bunch of drag and illusions on canvas... lumps are already some of the illusion of left... Utyanulis in the hollow. Then I hear - engines roared and the sound was gone. I have waited - like anyone. I am inside. Well, it is clear that after the " debt " fuck what you find! But it is interesting then! This, I tell you, there was something! The walls are almost through a hole. Beams strewn across the floor, a piece of the roof collapsed. Sleeves on his knee - a natural shooting. Krovischa, lumps of some... Useful, however, found nothing - well, two horns so full automatic wallowed beam pinned down, not pull out... Of bolts, I, naturally, and forgot to think... Returned to the wheelbarrow, he thought for five minutes, took off on the bolt with the other wheels... well, and rode quietly... And I go out there for half an hour earlier... Hmm...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_7_name">
		<text>The illusion of "debt"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_8">
		<text>Yes, because I was already up to the outskirts of Pripyat reached. Well, first of all decided to look around. Found a point higher - there was a large boiler with a pipe. Well, went neatly... like, look, chiki -peaks of all - the dust lies, no traces... Climbed and crawled into the furnace : it inside the tube steps were. Normal climb, even snuff has not spoiled - petrified... Carefully pop out... Beauty! Half of the city in your hand! Pulled out the binoculars and look around... ( slight pause ) And more... already met, then sliding down, and here a thought slips : what 's going on under their very noses, and have not looked! small bend over the edge, look to one side then the other... Oba- na! That's got to! The courtyard dwarf walks! The main thing I'm down there almost useful! And okay, he does not see me. Only the tower, I can not carry him : ACN on the back hangs a tube is narrow at all, do not turn around. From the PM that the armpit, rotten thing - there fifty meters, vertical height and... In short, if not make it right - and yet not make it - then just kerdyk. I sit, thinking. Well, look at the same time, what he was doing there. And he does something funny. First bodrenko so with a twinkle, rummaging in a pile of rubbish - just pieces of right and left scattered. And then suddenly stood and stood. Like listening. Well, there is quite a mess began. Debris in the pile itself began to move. Dwarf quickly sprang, was a column that way, put his hands to his head, hands somehow cleverly twisted... and in his ka -ak fly! From all sides!... Pieces of iron, bricks, roofing material, a branch... His way with head and cover. Well, I think that's all. Kick kitten, more piss will not... Those guys! Two seconds of this rubbish lay, and then exactly the same ka -ak falls upon all sides! There was a piece of pipe, so they are straight into the fence concrete povtykalis. Carl stood still for half a minute, pokumekal yourself something, and then turned around and stomped into the building. I have translated the spirit of the moment. "Well - I think - a good little bit of everything, it's time to throw away." And suddenly the smoke was drawn. And then bake it became. Yes, you go into a stump! Fire someone from below spread out! A minute later there was nothing to breathe already. Somehow has removed the edge of the pipe, there is no playground, sitting, legs hung... Only the smoke is still eating his eyes, the air is not enough... in short, blame must be urgently! Thank God I'm with you always repshnura forty meters dragged to any fireman in case... exactly what the fire... In general, I folded it in half - it was not very thick - more or less fixed on the tube, neck scarf ripped in half, to bespalki wound on top, and climbed up, all the Gods, praying... At the head of one thought: just not for break! No insurance, nothing cuts the cord palm... And, of course, the law of meanness about five meters to the ground, it was not enough. Segal had. What to do? Oh, and I roared! Fortunate, though not broken anything... But right leg ripped off and pulled - be healthy! Then he thought that tore ligaments in general. And then pulled out so that the gold medal in the race, probably would have won...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_8_name">
		<text>Grey in Pripyat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_9">
		<text>And I did not believe his eyes. That would seem to have pretty girls, huh? But this was... She... Perfection. Yes. There. Perfection. Such was the feeling that the world around her black and white and blurry, it is only one in color and sharpness. As she moved! I, too, a never seen before. I've already got a lump in my throat. Well, she gave up the science! What it here in the Zone do?... Well, yes, in the zone. By evening it was... At the bus station, where nine- separate. First, something in the window on the first floor flashed. I machine quickly took off with a fuse and then I saw - out of the house goes... I wanted to rub my eyes - you never know what you can expect from the Zone? And it fits. And I'm like a fool, staring... The machine, however, keep at the ready - the habit has already... Then she noticed me... Smile... Hello... And I listen and hear everything at her watch. She was in blue overalls, this bright... But do not balahonistom and nearly skin-tight... Figure in it - something fantastic! Only then it dawned on me that I was not listening at all, she says, standing and smiling from ear to ear... It appears from the study group was. Asking whether I have the opportunity to help her. Hey! Yes, I would be an anomaly for her helpful!... Said that she is dealing with these as they are... Endemic zones. Well, plants that are found only here. She said that she ran off guard, because with them any freedom of action there, and came here alone. I do not know. I believe it. Agreed to help smuggle her something. After two days came, as agreed. Five times just did not spot until collected. Go, but his one thought in mind : now I see her again! And nothing! I am even at home where she was met, not seen. That's... But what she was! She is right inside the world...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_9_name">
		<text>Men's loneliness</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Stories">
		<text>Local Folklore</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
