<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4, line 308 Russian char., removed "string_table" - aleks1970, Miser -->
<!-- Translated and corrected by Steve90k for fluency and ease of reading. Edited and proofed by Sword2012 for clarity, brevity, and consistency. 21 Mar 16 -->

	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_11">
		<text>Halt, Stalker. Go no further!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_111">
		<text>Why not?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_1111">
		<text>Because it's our territory - Duty territory - and we're very careful who we let through. If you don't have anything important to discuss with our leaders, you're not getting past here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_11111">
		<text>I see...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_111111">
		<text>Those are the rules...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_11112">
		<text>I need to pass. I have urgent business with the Barkeep</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_111121">
		<text>Ah, so it's you. Barkeep told us. You can pass</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_1111211">
		<text>I'd rather pay. Here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_11112111">
		<text>Good! You can pass, but you'd better have some really important business with the Barkeep, you hear? Oh, and be careful - there's lots of anomalies ahead</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_1111212">
		<text>What's the favour?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_11112121">
		<text>Nothing too difficult. There's a herd of Boars wandering nearby that needs to be killed. Take 'em out, and consider your passage paid</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_111121211">
		<text>Deal...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_1111212111">
		<text>Good luck, Stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_111121212">
		<text>I don't have the money</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_1111212121">
		<text>Well, you'd better start looking for it, then!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_111122">
		<text>I don't have the money</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_111123">
		<text>Well, you can't go through to the Bar, then</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_1231">
		<text>Thanks for helping us fight off the Boars. Here's your well-earned reward</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_12311">
		<text>Thanks!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_22">
		<text>So, have you killed those Boars yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_221">
		<text>Not yet...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_2211">
		<text>Pity. When you start cutting them up for chops, bring me one, would you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_222">
		<text>Yeah, I killed them all</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_2221">
		<text>Okay, carry on. And say 'Hi' to the Barkeep for me, will you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_33">
		<text>Say 'Hi' to the Barkeep from me when you see him. Oh, and don't forget - there are many anomalies on the way, so be careful!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dramm_novice_start_0">
		<text>Thanks, man. You really helped me out. I won't forget it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dramm_novice_start_1">
		<text>What's going on here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dramm_novice_start_11">
		<text>Okay</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dramm_novice_start_2">
		<text>We're trying to clear the Garbage of bandits. My colleagues are preparing to ambush a bandit squad nearby. If we don't stop them, they'll take control of the Garbage and nobody will be able to go deeper into the Zone. Talk to our commander. He and his men are near here, at the machinery scrapyard. I'm going there myself. We can go together if you prefer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dramm_novice_start_21">
		<text>Good idea. Let's go</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dramm_novice_start_3">
		<text>Can you tell me anything about the Garbage?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dramm_novice_start_31">
		<text>There ain't much to tell, man. The Garbage is simply... a dump. Duty fighters guard the northern road to the Bar. You might want to avoid them - Duty is full of real nasty types. To the right are the paths into the Dark Valley, but the radiation levels are much higher there. A little closer is the Grimpen Mire - a treacherous marsh full of anomalies. I've heard it's not difficult to find decent artefacts there, but it's much easier to find yourself in deep shit. But at least there's no Hound of the Baskervilles in the Mire - just the occasional chimera or werewolf!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dramm_novice_start_311">
		<text>Go on...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dramm_novice_start_3111">
		<text>To the right, by the marshes, there's a secret hiding place. You'll see a metallic construction overhanging a puddle. My stash is right below it. I put it there a while ago, but you saved my life and could probably make better use of it than me. Please feel free to use it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dramm_novice_start_31111">
		<text>Thanks, man. That's useful info</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dramm_novice_start_312">
		<text>That's interesting. Thanks</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_11">
		<text>Hey, Stalker, you're just in time! Those bandit bastards are trying to take control of the Garbage. We had a shootout here half an hour ago and managed to take down three of the shits. The others escaped, but they're bound to be coming back with reinforcements any minute now. They know there aren't many of us left, and we could really use your help...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_111">
		<text>Go on...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_1111">
		<text>We've set up an ambush for them here. They'll be coming from the West, from the Agroprom Research Institute. Help us destroy their reinforcements, and I promise you won't regret it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_11111">
		<text>Okay, I'll help you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_111111">
		<text>Great!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_11112">
		<text>Sorry, but it's none of my business, and I don't want to get involved</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_111121">
		<text>As you wish. But you'll be cursing yourself every time you pay those boneheads for passage into the Zone in future...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_11113">
		<text>I've killed them all...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_111131">
		<text>You're the man! But I'll play it safe just in case...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_21">
		<text>We have nothing to talk about</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_3111">
		<text>Thanks man, you really helped us out there. Will you accept some cash - a small token of our gratitude?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_31111">
		<text>Sure. Thanks</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_311111">
		<text>Here, this should cover the treatment for your injuries...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_3111111">
		<text>Thank you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_31113">
		<text>Tell me about yourself</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_311131">
		<text>My name's Bes. I came to these parts three years ago. Like many of the guys in the Zone I'm a fugitive, wanted for two murders and GBH. A few years ago a friend of mine got beat up pretty bad - they literally had to stitch him back together at the hospital. So I paid the bastards who did it a little visit. When the cops showed up, I had to shoot one of them and jump out of a third floor window...\nI've been here since. I've done well in this place, but the list of my crimes has got a little longer too. I try to fight the lawless here, too, just as I did on the outside. I also train up rookies, and teach them to survive in the Zone...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_3111311">
		<text>So if you feel that way, why don't you join Duty?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_31113111">
		<text>Duty fights against the Zone. I fight for the people in it. Besides, they're linked a bit too closely with the government and military for my liking, and I don't want to wake up in a cold cell every morning for the rest of my life...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_311131111">
		<text>Well, good luck to you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_31114">
		<text>What is this place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_311141">
		<text>This is the Garbage. We're right at home here. You see those heaps of crap? You don't want to go there, trust me. They're so full of radioactive waste, the Geiger counter needles go straight to the end and stay there... But this is the only decent way into the Zone, and more and more bandits are realizing this. They're shit-scared of going deeper into the Zone - into Duty territory - like any experienced Stalker, so they just stay here, robbing anyone who comes through - especially the rookies. So if nobody else cares, we have to stand our ground and fight them ourselves...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_3111411">
		<text>Go on...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_31114111">
		<text>Everywhere, especially here, you gotta act like a decent human being. Not like some self-centered hungry animal. That's my outlook on life</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_311141112">
		<text>Are there any large buildings in the Garbage?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_31114111211">
		<text>Thank you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_31115">
		<text>Thanks, but I don't need anything from you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_3112">
		<text>I've learned quite a lot. I could share some information with you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_41">
		<text>The job ain't done. Let's finish it and talk later</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_51">
		<text>Hey, Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_start_11">
		<text>Dammit it man, this ain't no time for chit-chat! In a few seconds the only things talking will be guns. Help me fight them off, and we can talk afterwards</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_start_22">
		<text>Thanks for the help. Things got pretty hairy back there. What are you doing here anyway?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_start_221">
		<text>I'm looking for information about Strelok. Fox told me about you, so I came looking for you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_start_2211">
		<text>Okay, you helped me out for free so I'll tell you. One of the guys, a former miner called Mole, is waiting for me. He dug up Strelok's old stash but I don't know if he found anything there. Here are the coordinates of our meeting place. Tell him I sent you. They'll be looking for me now, so I need to disappear for a while. Here's some cash for your help, too</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_start_2212">
		<text>Thanks for the information</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_start_222">
		<text>I'm looking for information about Strelok. Do you know anything?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_start_2221">
		<text>Okay, you helped me out for free, so I'll tell you. One of the guys, a former miner called Mole, is waiting for me. He dug up Strelok's old stash and found some documents that explain a few things. He had some bandits on his tail, so he had to leave the documents - but he remembered the place. They'll be looking for me now so I need to disappear for a while. Here are the coordinates of the meeting place with Mole. Tell him I sent you. I'll upload the info to your PDA. Here's some cash for your help, too</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_start_2222">
		<text>Thanks for the information</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_start_33">
		<text>Hey, man! Things got pretty hairy here a minute ago. Thanks for your help. What are you doing here, anyway?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_start_44">
		<text>A safe path, Stalker. A safe path past the anomalies and straight to the artefacts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_start_441">
		<text>What can one find at the Garbage?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_start_4411">
		<text>You can find a lot of trouble real quick, that's for sure. But you look like you already know your way around, so I'll tell you what I know. To the East is a small forest. Nothing interesting there, and it's always full of dogs, so be careful. This railway track will lead you to a tunnel. There are loads of anomalies there, and maybe something else too, but I've never managed to get to the end. You probably know about the Duty checkpoint in the North. That's basically all I know about this place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_start_44112">
		<text>Thanks for the information</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seryi_about_garbage_0">
		<text>So what can I find at this Garbage?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seryi_about_garbage_1">
		<text>You can find trouble real quick, that's for sure. But you look like you already know your way around, so I'll tell you what I know. To the East is a small forest. Nothing interesting there, and it's always full of dogs, so be careful. This railway track will lead you to a tunnel. There are loads of anomalies there, and maybe something else too, but I've never managed to get to the end. You probably know about the Duty checkpoint in the North. That's basically all I know about this place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seryi_about_garbage_11">
		<text>Thanks for the info. I'll keep it in mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_stalker_about_level_0">
		<text>Can you tell me anything about this place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_stalker_about_level_1">
		<text>Look around you. It's all a big stinking dump. After the accident in '86 they brought all the radioactive waste, cranes, and ruined machinery here. Basically, it's full of useless crap and anomalies. You can find a few artefacts, but they're nothing spectacular, which is why you'll find mostly ookies in this place. Trouble is, lots of rookies means lots of bandits, so it's best not to hang around too long. Once word gets out there's someone here, a whole pack will be onto you, just like the fucking dogs all over here, too. Further to the East are loads of radiation pockets, and you can't go there without protection. Go South and you'll reach the border of the Zone. Go North, and you'll eventually reach Rostok factory and the '100 Rads' - the Stalker bar. To the East is the Dark Valley, a miserable place controlled by Bandits. To the West is the Agroprom Research Institute. I'll mark the safe pathways on your map</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_start_3111411121">
		<text>In the center is a large hangar. It's usually pretty quiet there, other than the odd bandit attack, but the mutants tend to stay clear. Worst comes to worst, you can spend the night there. If you go west, towards Agroprom, there's a bandit camp, and that's where those dirtbags we killed off a while ago were coming from. But I have a feeling there's a lot more of them there...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_story_0">
		<text>Anything new?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_story_1">
		<text>I found a rare artefact yesterday. I was walking around the Army Warehouses, through a village. I was just throwing bolts as usual, watching the detector and smoking a cigarette. You know - throw, thump, puff, throw, thump, puff until something happens. Well, suddenly a bolt I threw didn't go thump. It just stayed above the ground, hanging in the air. I couldn't believe it! I've been in the Zone for nearly a year now, and never seen such a thing! I was so shocked, I did something incredibly stupid - I reached out to touch it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_story_2">
		<text>What happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_story_3">
		<text>It was like my hand went into some sticky mucus... and I couldn't pull it out! So I was just stood there, looking as if I was shaking hands with the Invisible Man! Or maybe some kind of beggar...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_story_4">
		<text>How did you manage to get out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_story_5">
		<text>That's what I'm getting to! I noticed something really weird about thirty centimetres from my hand. Spiral with blue markings, and shining as though it was emitting some kind of energy. So instead of trying to pull away, I pushed, trying really hard to reach that thing, but it kept pushing me back. Like trying to push two large magnets together. It must have taken me half an hour, from every angle, to reach it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_story_6">
		<text>Heh, the zombies around there must have thought it was some kind of entertainment!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_story_7">
		<text>Heh, yeah. And bloodsuckers selling tickets...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_story_8">
		<text>So, what happened next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_story_9">
		<text>Well, as soon as I grabbed that thing, everything stopped. No more mucus, and no pushing. But now I have my own portable matrix</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_story_10">
		<text>Wow, what kind of artefact is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_story_11">
		<text>I showed it to the Barkeep. He didn't know anything about the anomaly, but the artefact is known as 'Glassbeads'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_story_12">
		<text>Cool</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_story_0">
		<text>Anything new around here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_story_1">
		<text>Not much. Hey, have you met the new Spetsnaz soldiers yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_story_2">
		<text>No, have you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_story_3">
		<text>Yep. I was on an expedition to the sector near the underground, looking for a pseudodog for the Scientists. Well, I reached the entrance, hiding near the cars, watching the surroundings with binoculars. Then I heard this growl right behind me. Every hair on my body bristled, and my heart sank, 'cause I knew my rifle was just out of reach. I thought, "You fucking idiot!" So I turned round slowly and saw this massive pseudodog looking straight at me! Fuck, that thing had been quiet! I just knew it was the one that finished off many of our guys recently. I thought it was my turn. You ever faced death like this before? Knowing your entire life is going to end in a split second? And you realise you haven't prepared for it? And will anyone even know what happened to you? Then you realise just how pointless it all was, and that you fucking wasted it. Your whole life goes through your head, and you wonder how much of a difference you made. Then bang! It's all over, and there's a red mist everywhere. Then I'm thinking, "What the fuck's going on? I'm still here. Am I a ghost? The pseudodog's lying on its side, its skull blasted open, its brain everywhere. It's all over me. Fuck, I can taste it! I was so shocked, I just stood there. What the hell had just happened? Then someone walks out from behind a rubbish container. A soldier! There's something special about this one - exoskeleton, Dragunov, the way he moves. He comes right up to me and asks "Who are you? What are you doing here?" but in a computer voice. Well, I was starting to shake, so I told him everything quickly, that the Scientists sent me on a mission to find a pseudodog, but it had found me instead. Then he lowers his rifle and takes off his helmet... and I see it's actually a woman! Bloody attractive one, too! God, if she hadn't outranked me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_story_4">
		<text>Heh, you'd have got her phone number...?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_story_0">
		<text>Doesn't it get boring around here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_story_1">
		<text>Boring? Well, listen to this! Last month I was walking through an abandoned village. I've been there many times. You probably have, too. Anyway, it was getting dark, and I saw light coming from the windows of one of the houses. I was curious about who was in there, especially since it didn't look abandoned any more. I peeked through a window, and it looked bright and occupied - even though I couldn't see anyone. So I went round to the front and knocked on the door. In the Zone, hah! Well, there was no answer, so I turned the knob and it opened, so I walked in. I couldn't believe it - everything was so neat and clean. New furniture, flowers on the window sill, clean carpet on the floor, even the beds were made! I thought this was really weird, and wondered if the old owners had returned - you know, that happens sometimes. I went into another room, and there was a table with plates of food, a tureen of soup, and a decanter with what looked like wine in it. God, that soup smelled so good!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_story_2">
		<text>Come on! If you're going to tell a story, at least make it believable!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_story_3">
		<text>No, listen... I hadn't smelled anything so good in years! So, I thought the owners must be somewhere nearby, and I waited for a while to introduce myself. But there wasn't a sound in the house, and there was nobody outside. I realised that the soup was starting to go cold, I was really hungry, and it smelled delicious, so I started to wonder why there was food here if no one's gonna eat it? I was hoping to be invited anyway, so what if I just helped myself to my share? I hoped they wouldn't be offended, and I could always offer to pay them for it. So I sat down in an armchair - it was really soft and comfortable - put my shotgun nearby and started to eat. Oh my, it was the best meal I'd had since I left home! After that, I just fell asleep and had such wonderful, happy dreams. When I woke up it was already daylight, and the sun was streaming in through the window. Then I realised that there was no glass in it. I looked around me, and I was sitting in a broken wooden box in the the middle of an empty, dirty hovel. I thought, "What the f...!" and grabbed my rucksack. Everything was still inside, and my gun was next to it. I was totally gobsmacked, wondering how the hell I'd got there. I rushed outside and looked around. The house looked similar but was all old and rickety, just like all the others in the village. Everything was quiet as usual, but I couldn't move. I just stood there, trying to get a grip on what was real... What do you think? Why do things like that happen?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_story_4">
		<text>Is it possible you'd already overfilled on vodka that day?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_story_5">
		<text>No! I'm a light drinker, and I've never, ever done drugs or anything. I eat healthily and keep myself fit. So how did that happen?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_story_6">
		<text>I'm sorry, brother. I think the Zone affects all of our minds, in one way or another. I keep having weird dreams about the Chernobyl power plant, as though I've actually been there, and something happened while I was there...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_story2_0">
		<text>Have you heard of the Wish Granter?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_story2_1">
		<text>Of course! Did the Barkeep tell you about it? I nearly found it once...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_story2_2">
		<text>You serious?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_story2_3">
		<text>May the Zone take me if I'm lying! Honestly! It happened here, in the Garbage. I was trying to avoid Piotr Miser - you know, that stupid wanker who's impossible to work with. I'm sick of his babbling, "That's mine, I saw it first!", then shooting in all directions. So while I was hiding I took a swig - well, several swigs - anyway, too much vodka - you know, to protect myself from radiation. Well, I took a wrong path and ended up in a swamp. I would've sank, but Rad Hoosher saved me, and told me that Butcher had found the Wish Granter, and that he - sorry, Rad - now knows the way. He didn't want to go there alone, and offered me the chance to go with him. But although he knew where it was, he'd forgotten to ask about a safe path to it, and a bunch of mutants attacked us before we got there. I ran towards where we were headed, cause' all my stuff had got lost in the swamp, but Rad ran back to the swamp where he'd come from. I haven't seen him since, and he didn't tell me the path to the Wish Granter. Which is a shame. That's the story...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_story2_4">
		<text>That really is a shame - although if you'd made it there, do you think we'd be talking here now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_story2_5">
		<text>Oh, I never thought of it that way. I doubt it very much...</text>
	</string>
