<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?> 
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 Serega, removed "string_table" - aleks1970 -->
<!-- Translated and corrected by Steve90k for fluency and ease of reading. Edited and proofed by Sword2012 for clarity, brevity, and consistency. 07 Oct 16 -->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->

	<string id="val_escort_captive_dialog_11">
		<text>Fucking bandits! Those sons of bitches were taking me to the old factory. I've no idea what they were planning to do with me. I saw them take another guy there, a long time ago, and never saw him again. They've already got Serega, another one of ours. They keep him in the basement of their camp, that large unfinished building over there. Can you help him out? I know they're going to kill him otherwise...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_captive_dialog_2">
		<text>Do you know what they've got there at the factory?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_captive_dialog_21">
		<text>I haven't heard much. All I know is their boss, Borov, has one of the keys to the Underground there. There used to be a lab or something. Borov wants to find out what's inside, but he can't without the second key. If you're thinking of trying to get inside the base, it's shit-full of bandits. More than anywhere else I've seen...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_captive_dialog_211">
		<text>Thanks, I'll keep that in mind</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_captive_dialog_3">
		<text>I'll try to help your guy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_captive_dialog_41">
		<text>It's a real shame about my partner - he was a great guy. But still, I owe you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_captive_dialog_411">
		<text>I'm sorry, but shit happens whatever you try to do...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_captive_dialog_51">
		<text>Thanks for your help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_captive_dialog_511">
		<text>Bye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_captive_dialog_61">
		<text>You don't give a shit about anyone but yourself. Fuck off! I want nothing to do with you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_21">
		<text>Thanks! You got my partner out! Here, please accept this. I wish I had more to offer you other than my gratitude, and my friendship if you ever need help…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_2111">
		<text>Deal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_212">
		<text>I guess you know this area well. Anything interesting around here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_2121">
		<text>To the north there's a Bandit camp. To the east, an old factory. To the southwest, a deserted pig farm. And some kind of gate beyond it. I can't say what's there, I've never been that far</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_21211">
		<text>Can you tell me more about the Bandit camp?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_212111">
		<text>A load of Bandits settled in an unfinished building just north of here. Their leader's called Borov. A real animal, and a total bastard. That's why they sent us - to try and finish him off. Once he's gone, we reckon the rest will disappear fast, without the need for any more bloodshed...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_21212">
		<text>What's happening in the factory?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_212121">
		<text>We found out that there's some kind of vault down there. Only it's guarded like friggin' Fort Knox!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_2121211">
		<text>What kind of vault? What's inside?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_21212111">
		<text>We've no idea, but we were trying to find out. The only thing I know is that Borov has one of the keys to it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_21213">
		<text>A real pig farm? With actual pigs?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_212131">
		<text>Nah, not any more. The farm was abandoned after all the animals died and the soil was ruined. Thinking about pork chops? Have you ever tried the boar meat from around here? I did once. You ever see those 'glow in the dark' toys? Well, after one meal, everyone knew where I'd been for a crap! Funniest thing about it was the poor bastard who thought he'd found a new artefact!\nAnyway, just a few Stalkers hang out there now. I get a bad feeling about them, though, and I usually trust my gut, even though it's been irradiated and everything...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_21214">
		<text>What's this gate you mentioned?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_212141">
		<text>I'm not sure. It's just an old gate, except that it's kept locked and well-guarded. We haven't gone near it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_21215">
		<text>I see. Thanks</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_212151">
		<text>You're welcome! Come back any time!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_213">
		<text>Just the two of you on a scouting raid?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_2131">
		<text>There was another guy, Sergei. I don't know. He disappeared, and I've not heard of him since</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_214">
		<text>Take care, my friend</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_31">
		<text>So, what will happen to me now? Thank you, friend, at least you tried to help. And I do keep my word</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_41">
		<text>Thanks for your help! What else did you want to know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_61">
		<text>If you'd really meant to help when I asked you, someone of your obvious ability would have killed at least ONE of those Bandits...\nI don't know if you intended us to fail, but we have nothing more to discuss. Just fuck off out of here and don't come back. And remember, the Zone's a small place...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_611">
		<text>Bye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_hello_11">
		<text>Hey, buddy! Help me! I'm a Duty scout. Can you help me get out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_hello_111">
		<text>I'll do my best...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_hello_112">
		<text>Sorry, but there's nothing I can do for you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_hello_21">
		<text>Thanks, brother! I owe you one. Here's something that might be of use to you. Borov, the one who calls the shots here, has collected quite a lot of goodies. He's got one of the keys to the lower levels at the old factory. I heard the guards yacking, and they said there used to be some kind of lab there. The thing is, getting close to Borov isn't easy...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_hello_211">
		<text>Thanks for the info</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_hello_2111">
		<text>We need to get back to our guys, but I've a feeling we'll be lucky to get out of here alive...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_hello_21111">
		<text>Good luck...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_hello_31">
		<text>We have to get outta here before the bastards decide to check out this place! If you want something, make it quick!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_hello_311">
		<text>Nope, nothing</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_hello_41">
		<text>Hey! There's a switch over there on the wall. It opens the cell door...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_hello_411">
		<text>Okay, I'll look</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_rob_dialog_11">
		<text>Hey, you want an awesome gun? I found this stash near Yantar - maybe one of those scientists earning a little extra...\nThere was this Gauss rifle inside, amongst other things. I'm telling you, man, this thing fucking rocks! You can take out anyone within a few hundred metres with one hit! Even a mutant! Yours for just 800...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_rob_dialog_111">
		<text>Deal. Here's your money</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_rob_dialog_112">
		<text>Thanks, but no thanks</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_rob_dialog_113">
		<text>Thanks, but keep it. Money's hard to come by</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_rob_dialog_21">
		<text>Got the money? Hurry up, I've got other customers. They'll be here soon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_rob_dialog_3">
		<text>Excellent. I've it hidden it away carefully. Wait here, I'll go get it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_rob_dialog_31">
		<text>I'm still waiting. What's the problem?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_sos_dialog_11">
		<text>Hey, gimme a medkit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_sos_dialog_111">
		<text>Here you are...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_sos_dialog_112">
		<text>Sorry, I don't have one</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_sos_dialog_21">
		<text>Thanks, you really bailed me out! I owe you a big favour, but all I can give you at the moment is a juicy tip. South of here, there's a farm where some Stalkers set up camp. I heard one of them's selling a working Gauss rifle for just 800. I wanted to buy it, but before I could get back with the cash I got knee deep in this shit. If you want an absolute bargain, then it's yours!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_sos_dialog_211">
		<text>Thanks for the tip</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_4111">
		<text>I owe you, and I always repay my debts. Let's go</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_41111">
		<text>Excellent! Now let's tear 'em some new ones...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_4112">
		<text>Sorry, I have other plans</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_41121">
		<text>Well, good luck then</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_412">
		<text>Bye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dark_pulia_talk_story_0">
		<text>Know any interesting stories?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dark_pulia_talk_story_1">
		<text>Have you heard of the 'Stone Blood' artefact? I found one once! I was on my way back from a raid. I needed money desperately, so I went looking for artefacts. It was dark, and I walked straight into a moving anomaly. I was in agony, and couldn't get up. I rolled over and over, trying to get away from the bitch. Then suddenly I was staring at an artefact I'd never seen before.\nI started to crawl back to camp, but by the time I'd got there I was walking fine, and all my wounds had healed! I showed it to everyone, and they all said I should take it to the Scientists, so I did. They were really excited, and gave me a ton of money for it. Seriously, it's true...</text>
	</string>
