<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 edits/cyrillic, line 629, 1505 removed russian char. aleks1970 -->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->
	<string_table>
		<string id="dead_city_secret_1_name">
			<text>Fugitives Stash</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dead_city_secret_1_descr">
			<text>It's time to get out of the last day... Thugs... I'll make a stash, then I'll be on the lam - useful - little things I need badly...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dead_city_secret_2_name">
			<text>Zombie Things</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dead_city_secret_2_descr">
			<text>Something, after yesterday's rendezvous with the controller somehow not on its own... Thoughts stupid and head like a brick... Put it away until their belongings here - as if they are not stupid I've done, while sick...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dead_city_secret_3_name">
			<text>Nychka Obomorok</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dead_city_secret_3_descr">
			<text>Nychka - not nychka, but so far its the same jackals do not profit and not cleaned out - put it away... In this area, even with the authorities attach little importance</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dead_city_secret_4_name">
			<text>Veterans Stash</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dead_city_secret_4_descr">
			<text>I've collected a little. But where to put all this?? Here neither are traders, nor are other areas... The trash would be better to lie here - maybe for a better time, then I'll pick it up</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dead_city_secret_5_name">
			<text>Dedkiny things</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dead_city_secret_5_descr">
			<text>I'm old... The backpack is a burden to carry - not that these young Cheats... Unknown to them and the taste G victory of adrenaline when you go on a mission with one-edged... But must - leave it - can someone, and for the repose of my drink and then when he finds...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="atp_arhara_secret_1_name">
			<text>Hiding place of the experienced scout</text>
		</string>
		<string id="atp_arhara_secret_1_descr">
			<text>Has buried a map with transition co-ordinates. To me it already to what - this path I and so by heart I know...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="atp_arhara_secret_2_name">
			<text>Zanachka Shnyry</text>
		</string>
		<string id="atp_arhara_secret_2_descr">
			<text>Well blah, thieves. Where conscience thieves'? Loot it is insignificant, I would not covet at all, but I will hide. If will be still that valuable - in it I will add. I hope, so it is high so thieves will not get</text>
		</string>
		<string id="atp_arhara_secret_3_name">
			<text>Loot of the Whale</text>
		</string>
		<string id="atp_arhara_secret_3_descr">
			<text>Kalinin-Kalininym, and habarok I am better from its inquisitive an eye I will put by. Trunks now in deficiency. Razhivus money - guns for perimetre I will take. Speak, there now the lawlessness is created</text>
		</string>
		<string id="generators_arhara_secret_1_name">
			<text>Backpack of the Monolithuanian</text>
		</string>
		<string id="generators_arhara_secret_1_descr">
			<text>Lines me has pulled to move to these fanatics. Steal at them habarok - they of type speak - a sin such to store... Feet I will do from here - I will take</text>
		</string>
		<string id="generators_arhara_secret_2_name">
			<text>Hiding place of the Fellow countryman</text>
		</string>
		<string id="generators_arhara_secret_2_descr">
			<text>Has buried from bad and envious eyes the habarok. Let here will stay - a place deserted - nobody will reach</text>
		</string>
		<string id="generators_arhara_secret_3_name">
			<text>Loot of the security guard</text>
		</string>
		<string id="generators_arhara_secret_3_descr">
			<text>Has put by belongings which-what. All the same they any more be not required to their former owners, and to me - can and will fit</text>
		</string>
		<string id="generators_arhara_secret_4_name">
			<text>Tajnik Fritsa</text>
		</string>
		<string id="generators_arhara_secret_4_descr">
			<text>Loot it is not too bad. In its backpack constantly to drag - has not put. I will put by on the future - not for a century I in the Zone have got stuck...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="generators_arhara_secret_5_name">
			<text>Unknown hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="generators_arhara_secret_5_descr">
			<text>Owner of this hiding place is unknown. Probably it has disappeared for a long time already in severe whirlpool of life of the Zone, having left the of loot for stalker who has casually come across a hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="aver_arhara_secret_1_name">
			<text>Arhara's Stash</text>
		</string>
		<string id="aver_arhara_secret_1_descr">
			<text>Zahoval stuff, I hope will not find - to the people here it is a little rummaged. With itself to drag in a regional ohm...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="aver_arhara_secret_2_name">
			<text>Hiding place of the Pilgrim</text>
		</string>
		<string id="aver_arhara_secret_2_descr">
			<text>Loka for me new. Let habarok while will lie down - I will accustom - I will take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="aver_arhara_secret_3_name">
			<text>Hiding place of the Eremite</text>
		</string>
		<string id="aver_arhara_secret_3_descr">
			<text>Have presoaked yesterday some avengers... Have taken away only the weapon - and that - unusual, therefore has put by about the best days</text>
		</string>
		<string id="aver_arhara_secret_4_name">
			<text>Hiding place of the Astrologer</text>
		</string>
		<string id="aver_arhara_secret_4_descr">
			<text>I Will make and in this wood Taynichok useful - all the same often here I happen... It is useful a difficult minute - habarok quite good...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="aver_arhara_secret_5_name">
			<text>Hiding place of the Old man</text>
		</string>
		<string id="aver_arhara_secret_5_descr">
			<text>I Will leave here Ryukzachek with Artami while at the physician I am treated. Papravlyu health - I will take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="warlab_arhara_secret_1_name">
			<text>Hiding place of Panther</text>
		</string>
		<string id="warlab_arhara_secret_1_descr">
			<text>Has put by it is sensitive a loot and a spare favourite trunk. These muzhiks - such thieves, will drag off all, and Taynichok can and not find</text>
		</string>
		<string id="warlab_arhara_secret_2_name">
			<text>Vitamin Hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="warlab_arhara_secret_2_descr">
			<text>Have come. Dogs have done some shooting. Our base. I have put by is sensitive a loot - that in a backpack superfluous not to drag yet. On the task I will go - I will take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="warlab_arhara_secret_3_name">
			<text>Tajnik Kostoloma</text>
		</string>
		<string id="warlab_arhara_secret_3_descr">
			<text>Zatiharil in mine of the lift a backpack. Let the hour waits - can and it is useful. Life of the mercenary is not necessary also a penny - i.e. That will be tomorrow</text>
		</string>
		<string id="village_arhara_secret_1_name">
			<text>Tajnik Mihi</text>
		</string>
		<string id="village_arhara_secret_1_descr">
			<text>Figs knows, how me here has brought, but back all junk that here lumped, I can not drag off. The most unnecessary Zanychu, will be gone, so it is not a pity</text>
		</string>
		<string id="village_arhara_secret_2_name">
			<text>Hiding place local</text>
		</string>
		<string id="village_arhara_secret_2_descr">
			<text>Village has died out... All have imperceptibly dispersed, who-where... before any dead was established, already creep run... Not to good it. That is - I will put by, for now it is necessary to do feet from here</text>
		</string>
		<string id="village_arhara_secret_3_name">
			<text>Backpack of the captain</text>
		</string>
		<string id="village_arhara_secret_3_descr">
			<text>Have smoothed out yesterday the chosen square. Corpses plenty. Have kindly merged to secondhand dealers. That remains - I will put by - suddenly in maps I will be lost - will be, than a duty to give</text>
		</string>
		<string id="village_arhara_secret_4_name">
			<text>Hiding place of the lieutenant</text>
		</string>
		<string id="village_arhara_secret_4_descr">
			<text>Has made secluded. Sometimes it is possible to rest and have a bite and a magazine... To look through. It is necessary to support a tone. And what idiot has told, what the Zone not for women? The impotent man it, it is exact...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="village_ghost_secret_name">
			<text>Hiding place of the Ghost</text>
		</string>
		<string id="village_ghost_secret_descr">
			<text>I will leave here my special outfit with hope, that nobody will find it before I return to the NORTH...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0000_descr">
			<text>our Hiding place while in a tunnel, all good lies in a pipe. There it is good, very few people about a place knows, and anomalies will discourage to climb</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0000_name">
			<text>Seris Hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0001_descr">
			<text>In hemp has hidden, near a tunnel. A hole there the convenient</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0001_name">
			<text>a stub Full of holes</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0002_descr">
			<text>Under a cross, near a bush has dug a loot it is sensitive</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0002_name">
			<text>Grist under a cross</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0003_descr">
			<text>Has thrown off a backpack under the tumbled down tree</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0003_name">
			<text>Backpack under a tree</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0004_descr">
			<text>Backpack thrust in a pipe, near factory. Nobody will find</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0004_name">
			<text>Backpack of the chimney sweep</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0005_descr">
			<text>Box on a factory roof, there nobody will see. Only in the rain will rust</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0005_name">
			<text>Box on a roof</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0006_descr">
			<text>Shot, it was necessary to throw a backpack under the car, behind a wheel. But has left. Then I will take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0006_name">
			<text>Backpack of the drunkard</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0007_descr">
			<text>Under a cross has hidden, behind tanks. Dig a little, only be not fond</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0007_name">
			<text>At three tanks</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0008_descr">
			<text>At factory has put a backpack from above, so from below not visible. Only here precisely I do not remember that in it</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0008_name">
			<text>Backpack in a window</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0009_descr">
			<text>In factory, in a box has hidden it all</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0009_name">
			<text>Radioactive box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0010_descr">
			<text>Under a ladder in a box a hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0010_name">
			<text>Box in flight</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0011_descr">
			<text>In drawer has hidden, all the same anybody will not check</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0011_name">
			<text>Factory box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0012_descr">
			<text>Has thrown off a bag behind a window, I will take away it then</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0012_name">
			<text>Bag on a support</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0013_descr">
			<text>We with Koljanom on Agroprom have not bad taken a walk, miscellaneous stuff, but something could be put by. A box have put in the garbage container</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0013_name">
			<text>a garbage Box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0014_descr">
			<text>Under the tumbled down tree has found the safe while here all I will hide</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0014_name">
			<text>Safe under a tree</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0015_descr">
			<text>In a pipe has thrown things, then I will take away. It was necessary to leave, and that with itself would take away, certainly. If only have not become wet</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0015_name">
			<text>Things in a pipe</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0016_descr">
			<text>Kindly in an old pipe, it will be necessary to boys to tell. I there will not get</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0016_name">
			<text>Radioactive pipe</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0017_descr">
			<text>Has run away from base, well them in a bath, to climb under bullets of stalkers. Has hidden belongings in a pipe, in a blockage. I will overstay, will not depart yet, then I will take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0017_name">
			<text>Blockage</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0018_descr">
			<text>Under a bush the semidug safe, here all I hide</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0018_name">
			<text>Safe under a bush</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0019_descr">
			<text>Box have found out under a support, someone dragged it already from scientific research institute. We will wait for the helicopter then we will take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0019_name">
			<text>Archival boxing</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0020_descr">
			<text>In iron fitting has hidden valuables</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0020_name">
			<text>Under the hatch</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0021_descr">
			<text>Under a bush the semidug safe, there all I hide</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0021_name">
			<text>Under a bush at a wall</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0022_descr">
			<text>Convenient box that superfluous junk to dump</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0022_name">
			<text>Institute box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0023_descr">
			<text>In the safe has hidden, and military men have come. Not to get now kindly</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0023_name">
			<text>Agrosafe</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0024_descr">
			<text>In a pipe has thrown belongings, then I will take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0024_name">
			<text>a truck Body</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0025_descr">
			<text>Take away things from a smouldering log</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0025_name">
			<text>Rotten log</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0026_descr">
			<text>Convenient box that superfluous junk to dump. Once the institute economic stock was stored in it</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0026_name">
			<text>Box of the supply manager</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0027_descr">
			<text>Convenient box for small things, I in such held metalwork tools of the house</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_secret_0027_name">
			<text>Stock of the mechanic</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_u_secret_0000_descr">
			<text>Bandits hide something under a pipe, it is necessary to visit. From conversation clearly that there their stocks</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_u_secret_0000_name">
			<text>Gangster Obshchak</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_u_secret_0001_descr">
			<text>Has hidden a backpack behind concrete pieces, I will go with light baggage. I will be better hungry, but live</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_u_secret_0001_name">
			<text>Backpack in a back street</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_u_secret_0002_descr">
			<text>Box behind a rusty butt in a vault, all there lies. I there am not going to come back, pipes! What miracle I have knocked down that bloodsucker, till now I do not remember</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_u_secret_0002_name">
			<text>Box of the bloodsucker</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_u_secret_0003_descr">
			<text>Behind a wall lies loot. I am responsible for a market!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_u_secret_0003_name">
			<text>Loot of the stalker</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_u_secret_0004_descr">
			<text>I here stash some values. An artful place for my hiding place. On a yellow butt, figs you will find</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_u_secret_0004_name">
			<text>Hole of the mole</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0000_description">
			<text>Has hidden a backpack near base of "Duty". Then I will take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0000_name">
			<text>Hidden backpack</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0001_description">
			<text>big flight of dogs if the backpack has not left an outpost would not reach has pursued me</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0001_name">
			<text>Left backpack</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0002_description">
			<text>All that remains, have dug under a cross</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0002_name">
			<text>Hiding place under a cross</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0003_description">
			<text>Has thrown off here a backpack so it will be easier</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0003_name">
			<text>Backpack</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0004_description">
			<text>Stash of an outpost of "Duty" is stored in the bunker, but nobody watches a box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0004_name">
			<text>Warehouse in the bunker</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0005_description">
			<text>Saw as Dolg has put something in a pipe, near an outpost</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0005_name">
			<text>Hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0006_description">
			<text>It is all to it belonged, let while here and will lie down</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0006_name">
			<text>Hiding place under a cross</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0007_description">
			<text>I go to the bar, the backpack has left in a hangar</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0007_name">
			<text>Backpack</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0008_description">
			<text>Speak, in "Duty" territory, in an electroguard something valuable lies</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0008_name">
			<text>Electroguard with a hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0009_description">
			<text>Above towers near "Duty" has pushed box so that nobody will notice</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0009_name">
			<text>Hiding place on a tower</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0010_description">
			<text>Has hidden in a pipe under a ladder</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0010_name">
			<text>Hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0011_description">
			<text>Near to a bar has buried kindly, behind anomalies, nobody will steal up. And how to open do not know, and all is simple, there to hook a door it is necessary, at once and will open</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0011_name">
			<text>Tajnik Arni</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0012_description">
			<text>Near to a bar has buried kindly</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0012_name">
			<text>Hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0013_description">
			<text>Near a bar in a box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0013_name">
			<text>Box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0014_description">
			<text>In a back street, near a bar has put by box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0014_name">
			<text>Jashchichek</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0015_description">
			<text>Has dug under a cross, behind fur-trees</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0015_name">
			<text>Hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0016_description">
			<text>Under a cross, near to pass to Wild territory</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0016_name">
			<text>Hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0017_description">
			<text>In a pipe, near Arena has put by box the antiglad</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0017_name">
			<text>Jashchichek</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0018_description">
			<text>Under a tower has hidden belongings in a pipe</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0018_name">
			<text>Hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0019_description">
			<text>Under a cross a hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_secret_0019_name">
			<text>Hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0000_descr">
			<text>Beim Sammeln habe ich mein Armeezeug in einem Waggon versteckt. Nicht vergessen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0000_name">
			<text>Waggon oberhalb der Brücke</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0001_descr">
			<text>Ich habe gesehen, wie eine Anomalie einen Stalker beim Eisenbahntunnel im Wald platt gemacht hat. Er hatte gutes Zeug, glaube ich.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0001_name">
			<text>Sachen aus dem Besitz des Anomalie-Opfers</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0002_descr">
			<text>Für die Bestechung ist alles unter dem Kreuz versteckt.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0002_name">
			<text>Das Kreuz im Banditenlager</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0003_descr">
			<text>Die Truhe, die von den Banditen geklaut wurde, ist im Keller des zentralen Gebäudes. Mit einer Ablenkung kommen wir dran.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0003_name">
			<text>Lagerhaus der Banditen</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0004_descr">
			<text>Meine Kumpel und ich hatten mit diesen Mistviechern in Uniform zu tun, und ich habe Zeug unter der Brücke vergraben. Da kann es erst mal bleiben.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0004_name">
			<text>Unter dem Kreuz</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0005_descr">
			<text>Der Rucksack steckt im Keller. Ich komme später wieder - geht gerade nicht.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0005_name">
			<text>Unterstand im Keller</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0006_descr">
			<text>Auf der Farm ist ein halb vergrabener Safe. Da bewahre ich jetzt alles auf.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0006_name">
			<text>Safe auf der Farm</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0007_descr">
			<text>Ein Vögelchen flüstert, jemand versteckt etwas im Eisenbahnwaggon auf der Brücke. Ich muss auf dem Rückweg da nachsehen. Wer da wohl ...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0007_name">
			<text>Behälter im Eisenbahnwaggon</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0008_descr">
			<text>Das Zeug ist gleich unter dem Dach am kleinen Haus an der Brücke versteckt.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0008_name">
			<text>Besitz des Typen</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0009_descr">
			<text>Mein Scheiß ist in so einer Truhe, nicht weit von der Brücke. Das war's, mir reicht's, ich hau ab aus der Zone, lebt wohl! Ich werde das Mutterland nie vergessen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0009_name">
			<text>Zeug an der Brücke</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0010_descr">
			<text>Am Lager der Neuen hat es einen Stalker erwischt. Mal sehen, was der dabei hatte.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0010_name">
			<text>Der Rucksack ist beim Dorf</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0011_descr">
			<text>Lihoi sagt, das geheime Versteck ist im Keller. Er hat zu viel erzählt, also haben wir ihn endgültig zum Schweigen gebracht.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0011_name">
			<text>Keller im Dorf</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0012_descr">
			<text>Im Keller ist ein tolles Versteck. Sagte man mir. Ich warte noch ein bisschen dann hol ich mir die Beute und Verstecke den Krempel woanders. Ich trau dem nicht.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0012_name">
			<text>Ein guter Platz</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0013_descr">
			<text>Worpal sagt, im Keller gibt es ein Geheimversteck. Unsere Männer waren in der Nähe auf Erkundung. Gehen wir nachsehen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0013_name">
			<text>Worpals Geheimversteck</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0014_descr">
			<text>Im Büro vom Befehlshaber ist eine verzierte Truhe, da ist tonnenweise wertvolles Zeug drin.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0014_name">
			<text>Die Wertsachen des Befehlshabers</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0015_descr">
			<text>Irgendeinen Stalker hat es beim Lager der Neuen erwischt. Wir sollten uns sein Zeug ansehen. Wieso war der überhaupt da?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0015_name">
			<text>Am Rand einer Landstraße</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0016_descr">
			<text>Das Zeug ist im Keller der Banditen versteckt. Bis eben waren sie nicht da. Jetzt wäre es an der Zeit, in einem günstigen Augenblick alles einzusammeln.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0016_name">
			<text>Der Räuberkeller</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0017_descr">
			<text>Hab das Inventar im Rohr gefunden, nicht weit von der Farm. Sobald ich meine Zeit abgesessen habe, komme ich bestimmt wieder.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0017_name">
			<text>Gasrohr</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0018_descr">
			<text>Meinen Rucksack habe ich beim Posten weggeworfen. Ich sollte ihn schnell holen, ehe wir woandershin abkommandiert werden.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0018_name">
			<text>Verstecktes Zeug</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0019_descr">
			<text>Ich habe die Truhe erst mal im Turm gelassen. Ich hole sie, wenn ich kann.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="esc_secret_0019_name">
			<text>Turm am Kontrollpunkt</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0000_descr">
			<text>Ich habe gesehen, wie ein Bandit sein Zeug in einer Truhe im Hangar versteckt hat. Wie komme ich da nur leise ran?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0000_name">
			<text>Lagerraum der Banditen</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0001_descr">
			<text>We with Vase went to look on as, here Vasju and were overtaken Cop by a bullet. And I here at anything. A bullet - the silly woman. Veshchichki has buried on the crane in a pipe</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0001_name">
			<text>Old crane</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0002_descr">
			<text>In Garbage in a railway tunnel behind a diesel engine with all the junk it was covered with the Grizzly. It is a pity the guy</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0002_name">
			<text>Things of the Grizzly</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0003_descr">
			<text>Loot in a pipe on a dump</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0003_name">
			<text>Pipe on northern heap</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0004_descr">
			<text>Things lie on a dump, in one pipe. If not to know, where it is exact, for what you will not find</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0004_name">
			<text>Grist in scrap metal</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0005_descr">
			<text>Has hidden junk in a metal pipe near two tanks. It would be necessary to take away, but there is no time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0005_name">
			<text>Chugunka near tanks</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0006_descr">
			<text>Among radioactive garbage where very few people known about it, some useful things are hidden</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0006_name">
			<text>Pipe on east heap</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0007_descr">
			<text>In lowland someone's backpack, round anomaly rolls. As tough it to reach?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0007_name">
			<text>Neutral backpack</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0008_descr">
			<text>we Have presoaked the informer on a bog, there it and Prikopali. And habarok it under a cross have left, not before was</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0008_name">
			<text>Things killed</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0009_descr">
			<text>In hemp a hiding place, a good place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0009_name">
			<text>Mouldering stub</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0010_descr">
			<text>In wood a log, inside - a hole. In it a treasure to take away it it is time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0010_name">
			<text>Log in wood</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0011_descr">
			<text>Petrenko has told that there is an information about a hiding place of group Strelok in Garbage. Here in lowland there should be a hatch. He has told, how it should be opened artfully. As everything will calm down, it is necessary to be winded there</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0011_name">
			<text>Warehouse of group Strelok</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0012_descr">
			<text>Has hidden in the car, Long spoke, a good place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0012_name">
			<text>Hiding place in the car</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0013_descr">
			<text>In the bus has put a backpack, like imperceptible</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0013_name">
			<text>Backpack of the stalker in the bus</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0014_descr">
			<text>Stock has combined in a box, in a strange small house round the corner. Till now I will not understand, for what that construction</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0014_name">
			<text>Sortirnye stocks</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0015_descr">
			<text>On a heap of garbage the semidug safe, there that it all also lies. Not to forget, what exactly</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0015_name">
			<text>Safe on a southern heap</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0016_descr">
			<text>On a heap of garbage in a pipe has put loot</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0016_name">
			<text>Cache in scrap metal</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0017_descr">
			<text>Commander on a portable radio set has ordered to depart. I have come across a box, have thrown off in it excess weight and have departed with light baggage</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0017_name">
			<text>Stock in a box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0018_descr">
			<text>Loot put in a pipe on a dump. Long it there will not lie</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0018_name">
			<text>Pipe at the bus</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0019_descr">
			<text>In ruins has well hidden a backpack. I hope, will take away easily if bandits do not prevent</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0019_name">
			<text>Backpack in ruins</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0020_descr">
			<text>While Dolg were shot, has put by loot in a carriage. It is necessary to come, take away somehow. And to tell thanks "Duty"</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0020_name">
			<text>Box on a post</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0021_descr">
			<text>Speak, Dohljak in Garbage, it is necessary to visit, loot to look. And that will run interested persons much</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0021_name">
			<text>Rjukzak Dohljaka</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0022_descr">
			<text>In the hatch while I will hide good, perhaps will not find</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0022_name">
			<text>String-bag in the hatch</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0023_descr">
			<text>Near a dredge someone has disappeared in anomaly, a backpack it is visible, and to get hard</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0023_name">
			<text>Under a ladle</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0024_descr">
			<text>has hardly climbed through under beams, but well the backpack has hidden, anybody here will not get</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gar_secret_0024_name">
			<text>Grist under concrete blocks</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0000_description">
			<text>Has put good in a log, I think will not find</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0000_name">
			<text>Hiding place in a log</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0001_description">
			<text>In an oven has put by stuff</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0001_name">
			<text>Hiding place in the furnace</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0002_description">
			<text>In cabin Kamaz has put by stuff</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0002_name">
			<text>Hiding place in Kamaz</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0003_description">
			<text>Under a cross, near village has dug a loot it is sensitive</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0003_name">
			<text>Treasure under a cross</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0004_description">
			<text>In a pipe has thrown belongings, then I will take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0004_name">
			<text>Hiding place in a pipe</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0005_description">
			<text>Hiding place in a water tower, in a box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0005_name">
			<text>Treasure in a tower</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0006_description">
			<text>In an oven has put a backpack, then it is useful</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0006_name">
			<text>Oven hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0007_description">
			<text>Loot has hidden in the car, in village thrown</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0007_name">
			<text>Auto hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0008_description">
			<text>In ruins with radiation has left a backpack. Will be afraid to be put</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0008_name">
			<text>Dangerous secret</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0009_description">
			<text>Has dug loot under a cross, in a secluded place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0009_name">
			<text>Cache of the stalker</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0010_description">
			<text>Has put by a backpack in a secluded place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0010_name">
			<text>Backpack with equipment</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0011_description">
			<text>Belongings has put by on a hill in the car</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0011_name">
			<text>Hiding place on a hill</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0012_description">
			<text>helicopter near abandoned military base Has fallen, the box lies nearby, directly under helicopter. One trouble, anomalies and radiation around</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0012_name">
			<text>Box from the helicopter</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0013_description">
			<text>On a hill under a cross has dug loot</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0013_name">
			<text>Secret in a tomb</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0014_description">
			<text>In hemp a hiding place, a good place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0014_name">
			<text>Secret stub</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0015_description">
			<text>Has left a backpack in a crane cabin, then I will take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0015_name">
			<text>Hiding place high altitude</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0016_description">
			<text>All has combined in a box, in the car near to base. And agreed, now it is necessary to wait only</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0016_name">
			<text>Agreed hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0017_description">
			<text>Has put good in a log, I think will not find</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0017_name">
			<text>Treasure in a log</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0018_description">
			<text>Loot has put in a pipe on the bank of lake</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0018_name">
			<text>Pipe with Swag</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0019_description">
			<text>In iron fitting has hidden goods</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0019_name">
			<text>Hiding place of the stalker</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0020_description">
			<text>Has put good in a log, I think will not find</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0020_name">
			<text>Loot in a log</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0021_description">
			<text>Convenient box that superfluous junk to dump</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0021_name">
			<text>Convenient cache</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0022_description">
			<text>In a tunnel has put by a backpack with Swag</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0022_name">
			<text>Backpack in a tunnel</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0023_description">
			<text>Convenient box that superfluous junk to dump</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0023_name">
			<text>Box with good</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0024_description">
			<text>Has put good in a log, I think will not find</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0024_name">
			<text>Hiding place in a log</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0025_description">
			<text>In a box has thrown good, then I will take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0025_name">
			<text>Temporary hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0026_description">
			<text>In the hatch has buried things, will sometime be useful</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0026_name">
			<text>Steel hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0027_description">
			<text>In a box has thrown good, then I will take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0027_name">
			<text>Box with Swag</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0028_description">
			<text>Loot has hidden in the car near by at "Freedom", time was not to search that better</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0028_name">
			<text>Hiding place in the car</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0029_description">
			<text>Loot has hidden in the box near by "Mercenary base"...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_secret_0029_name">
			<text>Mercenary group stash</text>
		</string>
		<string id="pri_secret_0000_description">
			<text>Speak, any stalker known has disappeared here, kindly till now nobody has picked up it</text>
		</string>
		<string id="pri_secret_0000_name">
			<text>Things of the dead stalker</text>
		</string>
		<string id="pri_secret_0001_description">
			<text>In garage, speak, the box costs, and in it a loot mum do not grieve</text>
		</string>
		<string id="pri_secret_0001_name">
			<text>Treasure in garage</text>
		</string>
		<string id="pri_secret_0002_description">
			<text>In a kindergarten, speak, the box costs, and in it a loot mum do not grieve</text>
		</string>
		<string id="pri_secret_0002_name">
			<text>Old hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="pri_secret_0003_description">
			<text>Fang has buried in Pripyat, under a monument. Weigh its loot has left in the same place - badly to take away from the dead</text>
		</string>
		<string id="pri_secret_0003_name">
			<text>Fang's Loot</text>
		</string>
		<string id="pri_secret_0004_description">
			<text>Last that it was known about it, that it has survived only one after "Scorcher". Stocks has left in any former department store and has set further. All has gone not how was planned, and after all it there was the best leader of "Freedom" for all our history</text>
		</string>
		<string id="pri_secret_0004_name">
			<text>Stocks of the leader of "Freedom"</text>
		</string>
		<string id="rad_secret_0000_description">
			<text>Cross on the way to "Scorcher", has not gone further, has hidden all under it</text>
		</string>
		<string id="rad_secret_0000_name">
			<text>Treasure Gloomy</text>
		</string>
		<string id="rad_secret_0001_description">
			<text>any stalker Here was lost, loot till now rolls, anybody cannot pick up</text>
		</string>
		<string id="rad_secret_0001_name">
			<text>Loot of the dead stalker</text>
		</string>
		<string id="rad_secret_0002_description">
			<text>Speak, in wood the semidug safe is, and there a loot full</text>
		</string>
		<string id="rad_secret_0002_name">
			<text>Loot in the safe</text>
		</string>
		<string id="rad_secret_0003_description">
			<text>Spoke to them not to fly over "Scorcher", here and result. In the middle of wood have landed, hardly someone has survived. Somewhere there that have transferred to us also lies</text>
		</string>
		<string id="rad_secret_0003_name">
			<text>Parcel to "Duty"</text>
		</string>
		<string id="rad_secret_0004_description">
			<text>Speak, there was a stock of group which made the way to the Zone center directly under radiation of "Scorcher". Anybody from them has not returned, and the stock and remained to wait the one who will pick up it</text>
		</string>
		<string id="rad_secret_0004_name">
			<text>Stock of group desperate</text>
		</string>
		<string id="rad_secret_0005_description">
			<text>Speak, the leader of any former grouping, and loot at it with itself rich has disappeared here was</text>
		</string>
		<string id="rad_secret_0005_name">
			<text>Loot of the leader of grouping</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0000_description">
			<text>Has put by a backpack behind iron sheet</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0000_name">
			<text>Hidden backpack</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0001_description">
			<text>Prihoval kindly under a cross</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0001_name">
			<text>Hiding place under a cross</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0002_description">
			<text>Has hidden something in a box, under a small house. Not to forget</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0002_name">
			<text>Box under a small house</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0003_description">
			<text>Has put a backpack under steps, and there these reptiles have appeared. A pancake, as though to get?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0003_name">
			<text>Backpack of the stalker</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0004_description">
			<text>Here in a corner, behind a tree the safe semidug, here my stuff also will stay</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0004_name">
			<text>Hiding place behind a tree</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0005_description">
			<text>that have grasped All during spot-check, have hidden in garage in a box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0005_name">
			<text>Hiding place in garage</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0006_description">
			<text>Behind a box in a box has put by panic</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0006_name">
			<text>Hidden box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0007_description">
			<text>Has put a backpack in a hole, from above like not much</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0007_name">
			<text>Backpack in a hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0008_description">
			<text>Jashchichek has put by in a secluded place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0008_name">
			<text>Box in a secluded place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0009_description">
			<text>Under a roof my backpack lies. It for rainy day</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0009_name">
			<text>Hiding place of the stalker</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0010_description">
			<text>Speak, in this small house the safe is, and in it something is put by</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0010_name">
			<text>Safe in the house</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0011_description">
			<text>Has hidden in a small house, in a pipe. Carefully, there all Fonit</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0011_name">
			<text>Hiding place in a pipe</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0012_description">
			<text>About what have agreed, you will take in drawer, there usually nobody looks</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0012_name">
			<text>Hidden box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0013_description">
			<text>Under a cross has hidden, in a back street</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0013_name">
			<text>Hiding place under a cross</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0014_description">
			<text>Superfluous supplies have hidden on building, under concrete</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0014_name">
			<text>Hiding place under concrete</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0015_description">
			<text>Loot we will put in a box on building, on a case if feet should be carried away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0015_name">
			<text>Hiding place of the Lucky beggar</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0016_description">
			<text>On building has hidden, in a back street</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0016_name">
			<text>Nychka</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0017_description">
			<text>Has pushed all in any pipe, then we will take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0017_name">
			<text>Hiding place in a pipe</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0018_description">
			<text>Near to building has hidden medicine in a box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0018_name">
			<text>Box with medicine</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0019_description">
			<text>Have dragged a box in a crane cabin</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0019_name">
			<text>Box on the crane</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0020_description">
			<text>In a corner, for the Rig has closed the good in the hatch</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0020_name">
			<text>Hiding place in the hatch</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0021_description">
			<text>Has got behind an artefact and has got to anomaly, hardly I go. The backpack has thrown off in a corner, for the Rig</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0021_name">
			<text>Thrown backpack</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0022_description">
			<text>Above, under a roof near a tower has pushed box that nobody has noticed</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0022_name">
			<text>Jashchichek under a roof</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0023_description">
			<text>that have found, have hidden in a pipe, near to building</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0023_name">
			<text>Hiding place in a pipe</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0024_description">
			<text>Has put good in a log, I think, will not find</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0024_name">
			<text>Hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0025_description">
			<text>Nychkanul a backpack near the crane</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ros_secret_0025_name">
			<text>Backpack</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0000_description">
			<text>Under a cross, near mountain has dug a loot it is sensitive</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0000_name">
			<text>Hiding place under a cross</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0001_description">
			<text>Has put good in a log, I think, will not find</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0001_name">
			<text>Hiding place in a log</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0002_description">
			<text>Under the bridge has thrust a backpack, let will lie down while</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0002_name">
			<text>Backpack under the bridge</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0003_description">
			<text>Have put a box in the car near a bog</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0003_name">
			<text>Car with a hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0004_description">
			<text>In hemp a hiding place, a good place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0004_name">
			<text>Hiding place in hemp</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0005_description">
			<text>On a farm has found an excellent box, I will be while there to store supplies</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0005_name">
			<text>Box of supplies</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0006_description">
			<text>In a pipe has thrown belongings, then I will take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0006_name">
			<text>Hiding place in a pipe</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0007_description">
			<text>Has hidden a backpack under a fur-tree</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0007_name">
			<text>Hiding place under a fur-tree</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0008_description">
			<text>Newcomer has pulled down a box at bandits, has put it in the Field turned. Says that by the form like the governmental box. It will be necessary to equip children, to take away it</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0008_name">
			<text>Governmental box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0009_description">
			<text>Around one thieves, already at the place, but mine box will not find</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0009_name">
			<text>Box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0010_description">
			<text>In the hatch has buried things, will sometime be useful</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0010_name">
			<text>Hiding place in the hatch</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0011_description">
			<text>Has thrown a backpack under a tree, differently would not leave from bandits</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0011_name">
			<text>Backpack of the stalker</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0012_description">
			<text>Stuff has put in a pipe, then I will take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0012_name">
			<text>Hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0013_description">
			<text>that has filched All at a Borov, has put by in the safe that under a fur-tree. Now it is necessary to wait, while they on nerves all</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0013_name">
			<text>Hidden safe</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0014_description">
			<text>Temporary staff in a carriage, a box with supplies in the same place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0014_name">
			<text>Warehouse in a carriage</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0015_description">
			<text>has hardly climbed in a pipe, under road, will be now where a backpack to hide</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0015_name">
			<text>Secret place in a pipe</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0016_description">
			<text>In a box has thrown good, then we will take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0016_name">
			<text>Box with good</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0017_description">
			<text>I Hide loot behind a pipe. It is difficult to reach, but not impossible</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0017_name">
			<text>Hiding place behind a pipe</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0018_description">
			<text>Cartridges in an electroguard</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0018_name">
			<text>Hiding place in an electroguard</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0019_description">
			<text>that have found All, have left in a box, we will go back, we will take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0019_name">
			<text>Box-hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0020_description">
			<text>Zanykali a backpack of the newcomer, it and has not found</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0020_name">
			<text>Hidden backpack</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0021_description">
			<text>In a van there was a box, it is necessary to take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0021_name">
			<text>Forgotten box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0022_description">
			<text>Has found the safe in a gas station, has hidden there kindly, like rare who here goes</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0022_name">
			<text>Safe in a gas station</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0023_description">
			<text>Box have dragged on top of the tank</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0023_name">
			<text>Box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0024_description">
			<text>Has hidden supplies in the safe in a gas station</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0024_name">
			<text>Safe in a gas station</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0025_description">
			<text>In camp of bandits, in the car a box lies, it is necessary to make the way imperceptibly, I feel, there to eat than get hold</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0025_name">
			<text>Box in the car</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0026_description">
			<text>Has put a box in a hiding place, a place reliable</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0026_name">
			<text>Box in a hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0027_description">
			<text>Has left a backpack in an abandoned building, well, anybody nearby is not present</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0027_name">
			<text>Left backpack</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0028_description">
			<text>we will Kindly store in the safe, in an imperceptible place. One of these days military men will come, all here a match will insert, well they so the most valuable remains at me will long not ransack</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0028_name">
			<text>Hiding place of Borov</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0029_description">
			<text>Backpack Zanykal near a building</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0029_name">
			<text>Backpack in a secret place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0030_description">
			<text>Has put loot in an imperceptible box, then I will take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0030_name">
			<text>Imperceptible box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0031_description">
			<text>Backpack has hidden under car, there nobody will be put</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0031_name">
			<text>Hidden backpack</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0032_description">
			<text>Loot has hidden in the car near by at bandits, time was not to search that better</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_secret_0032_name">
			<text>Hiding place in the car</text>
		</string>
		<string id="x16_secret_0000_description">
			<text>Hearings go that there was a stalker who has got into this laboratory and has put by the of loot in an electroguard in lift mine. And to take away it could not any more</text>
		</string>
		<string id="x16_secret_0000_name">
			<text>Loot in an electroguard</text>
		</string>
		<string id="x16_secret_0001_description">
			<text>Hearings go that there was a stalker who has got into this laboratory so it has rejected the fads around cages with experimental with all the Swag</text>
		</string>
		<string id="x16_secret_0001_name">
			<text>Backpack of the scout</text>
		</string>
		<string id="x18_secret_0000_description">
			<text>In underground laboratory Smoked all has combined in the safe. A place quite good at anybody keys from laboratory are not present. One misfortune - stones suddenly unexpectedly in air fly, spoke, someone is there...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="x18_secret_0000_name">
			<text>Hiding place Smoked</text>
		</string>
		<string id="x18_secret_0001_description">
			<text>Backpack should be thrown</text>
		</string>
		<string id="x18_secret_0001_name">
			<text>Thrown backpack</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0000_description">
			<text>Cross on a hill, and under it a hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0000_name">
			<text>Hiding place under a cross</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0001_description">
			<text>Speak, on an islet among a bog the safe is the semidug. It is necessary to visit</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0001_name">
			<text>Old safe</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0002_description">
			<text>In a pipe has thrust good, near camp</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0002_name">
			<text>Pipe with good</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0003_description">
			<text>Behind garages has put by habarok</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0003_name">
			<text>Backpack behind garages</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0004_description">
			<text>Has put by a backpack in a box, directly for iron crap</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0004_name">
			<text>Backpack with extraction</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0005_description">
			<text>In the bus has put box, like imperceptible</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0005_name">
			<text>Hiding place in the bus</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0006_description">
			<text>Loot it is hidden in the car, near to territory. Radiation not so strong</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0006_name">
			<text>Extraction in the car</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0007_description">
			<text>Speak, here loot someone's is, only under radiation not to make the way</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0007_name">
			<text>Old backpack</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0008_description">
			<text>Speak, here a hiding place of any grouping as soon as they under radiation have made the way?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0008_name">
			<text>a grouping Hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0009_description">
			<text>next volunteer Has disappeared, the next prototype has not protected from radiation. Could reach only the territory middle, there and remained. Sakharov wants to make gaugings more exact, but I will not go, and even I there will remain, near to territory</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0009_name">
			<text>Backpack of the verifier</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0010_description">
			<text>Speak, here loot someone's is, only under radiation not to make the way</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0010_name">
			<text>Old hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0011_description">
			<text>It is necessary to bring down. Sakharov and Kruglov - full loonies, demand that I have gone with any stalker to the radiation center. Well them Nafig as soon as I will collect all stocks in the hatch, there and then I will fall down</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0011_name">
			<text>Hiding place of the scientist</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0012_description">
			<text>Has put good in a log, I think, will not find</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0012_name">
			<text>Treasure in a log</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0013_description">
			<text>Tell, here a cache someone's, only under radiation not to make the way</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_secret_0013_name">
			<text>Box with good</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_found_new_treasure">
			<text>Information on a cache</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0000_name">
			<text>Hiding place on bogs</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0000_description">
			<text>Zahoval stuff, I hope will not find - to the people here it is a little rummaged. With itself to drag in a regional ohm...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0001_name">
			<text>Hiding place on the stalker</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0001_description">
			<text>Zanykal here which that, will steal it is not a pity</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0002_name">
			<text>Backpack of the dead stalker</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0002_description">
			<text>Speak the stalker one has disappeared, well and stuff which what after itself has left</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0003_name">
			<text>Hiding place of the avenger</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0003_description">
			<text>Saw as one of avengers hid that that on bogs</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0004_name">
			<text>Cache on bogs</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0004_description">
			<text>There is here a stalker one, while drunk has told about the cache. Has told lies, is not present it would be necessary to check up</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0005_name">
			<text>Imperceptible hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0005_description">
			<text>Before spot-check which that Zanykal here is not far, a place not reliable, I am afraid will filch</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0006_name">
			<text>Tajnichek</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0006_description">
			<text>Oh well also has got to me then, it was necessary to escape from two pseudo-dogs, it was necessary habarok to dump, it would be necessary to check up</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0007_name">
			<text>Valuable hiding place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0007_description">
			<text>We then with Zhoroj much all has typed, so it is a lot of that it was necessary a part is direct on bogs to leave</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0008_name">
			<text>Valuable hiding place on bogs</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0008_description">
			<text>Ahh mine where I the backpack has sown. Here a pancake have got drunk then. And all has remembered all, it is necessary to take away good, yet late</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0009_name">
			<text>Loot of the stalker</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0009_description">
			<text>Here one stalker has thrown off the information on Nychku, Intersnyh said lies, no</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0010_name">
			<text>Tajnik Chistonebovtsa</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0010_description">
			<text>Saw as one of these, well Chistonebovtsev hid that on bogs, it is interesting that there?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0011_name">
			<text>Reserved place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0011_description">
			<text>Here with the music one have drunk, and it such talker, allow about Nychki to stir, said lies likely, bragged, though...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0012_name">
			<text>Hiding place of the hunter</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0012_description">
			<text>Has buried which that, here is not far, I will wait while the favorable client will be</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0013_name">
			<text>Valuable things</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0013_description">
			<text>Eh is good then Fraerka on one have put. Well and a part have buried, here it is not far</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0014_name">
			<text>Veshchichki in a cache</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0014_description">
			<text>Here from the brother remains which that, I will bury till time, it is a pity the brother</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0015_name">
			<text>Hiding place with things</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0015_description">
			<text>Here I will save up still a money, I will take Veshchichki those that then has buried and farewell to zone</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0016_name">
			<text>Values on bogs</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0016_description">
			<text>We then in Zavarushku have got, it was necessary habarok in unreliable place to hide. It is necessary to find time to hide</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0017_name">
			<text>Backpack with things</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0017_description">
			<text>Were loaded then with creatures. It was necessary to leave a part on bogs</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0018_name">
			<text>Nychka with things</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0018_description">
			<text>Oh well I also have walked smack, one has gone on bogs, and there mosntrov-shmostrov, hardly feet at bore. Well got it stashed in a reliable place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0019_name">
			<text>Imperceptible niche</text>
		</string>
		<string id="marsh_secret_0019_description">
			<text>It is a pity then one was, has found the stalker dead, and at it with itself so much all was. The most valuable with itself took, but which should what be put by</text>
		</string>
		<string id="limansk_secret_0000_name">
			<text>Hiding place in a Limansk</text>
		</string>
		<string id="limansk_secret_0000_description">
			<text>Then with Koljanom in successful spot-check descended, a part in the same place in a Limansk have left</text>
		</string>
		<string id="limansk_secret_0001_name">
			<text>Cache in Limansk</text>
		</string>
		<string id="limansk_secret_0001_description">
			<text>Has carried to me then many loot has typed, so it is a lot of that a part in a cache has put</text>
		</string>
		<string id="limansk_secret_0002_name">
			<text>Cache of the Monolithian</text>
		</string>
		<string id="limansk_secret_0002_description">
			<text>Have caught with Seregoj of one "afflicted", and at it with itself that only was not, here an infection and whence only take. A part in a cache same place have put. It would be necessary to take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="limansk_secret_0003_name">
			<text>Freedom cache</text>
		</string>
		<string id="limansk_secret_0003_description">
			<text>my friend into a Vortex has 'rolled', we then from spot-check, at me the backpack under an outset, was necessary its backpack Zanykat</text>
		</string>
		<string id="limansk_secret_0004_name">
			<text>Cache of the stalker</text>
		</string>
		<string id="limansk_secret_0004_description">
			<text>Yes here to fear that had suffered. Flight of dogs it that that. Has hardly escaped, truth habarok was necessary to throw off</text>
		</string>
		<string id="limansk_secret_0005_name">
			<text>Nychka of the stalker in a Limansk</text>
		</string>
		<string id="limansk_secret_0005_description">
			<text>There is no more I in Limansk will not tighten, so us cheerfully have met, all was necessary to throw and run</text>
		</string>
		<string id="limansk_secret_0006_name">
			<text>Cache of the stalker in Limansk</text>
		</string>
		<string id="limansk_secret_0006_description">
			<text>Played with the muzhik in maps, well I as always have won, well and it on a game, loot that in Limansk has left. Well also has lost naturally if it will appear there it would be necessary to check up</text>
		</string>
		<string id="limansk_secret_0007_name">
			<text>Nychka in Limansk</text>
		</string>
		<string id="limansk_secret_0007_description">
			<text>Were with Peter recently in Limansk, have found which that valuable not to bear with itself, it was necessary habarok there and to leave, time it will be necessary to be winded to take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="limansk_secret_0008_name">
			<text>Nychka of the dead stalker in Limansk</text>
		</string>
		<string id="limansk_secret_0008_description">
			<text>We then allocate as one stalker has put by habarok, yes here the misfortune has happened to it, nearby the bloodsucker was, has probably guessed us. Hardly feet have carried away, and to the muzhik has not carried</text>
		</string>
		<string id="limansk_secret_0009_name">
			<text>Hiding place of the stalker in Limansk</text>
		</string>
		<string id="limansk_secret_0009_description">
			<text>Here a pancake Oprastovolosilsya then. Such habarok has found, has hidden in a secluded place. And then emission has begun and in that place anomaly "Springboard" was formed. Three days has waited, and it was necessary there is nothing to leave</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0000_name">
			<text>Hiding place of the stalker in red wood</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0000_description">
			<text>Habarok in wood Zanykal. There will be time will take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0001_name">
			<text>Hiding place of the hunter</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0001_description">
			<text>There was here a hunter one. And its zone has not regretted, has bent, and before death he about the hiding place has told</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0002_name">
			<text>Hiding place of the mercenary</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0002_description">
			<text>time Has got as that to us in hands the mercenary. Podranen was. Well so he to us about the hiding place has told, yes only we it all the same slapped</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0003_name">
			<text>Backpack in red wood</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0003_description">
			<text>Such loot it was necessary to leave in wood. A place not the reliable. That also look will filch</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0004_name">
			<text>Hiding place in red wood</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0004_description">
			<text>Place one has found very much Good. Has hidden in such place. Who will find a shit</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0005_name">
			<text>Loot in red wood</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0005_description">
			<text>In red wood has hidden which that the valuable. Time will come to tear from a zone. Not to forget to take away</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0006_name">
			<text>Loot on an edge</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0006_description">
			<text>Have found the dead stalker. In a backpack at it was a lot of valuable. All have not carried away, a part in a cache have left</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0007_name">
			<text>Loot of the hunter</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0007_description">
			<text>I Know one place, speak there a lot of all good it is buried. It would be necessary to visit</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0008_name">
			<text>Cache of the hunter</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0008_description">
			<text>me the hunter one before death about the habarok in red wood has told. It would be necessary to find this place</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0009_name">
			<text>Cache in wood</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0009_description">
			<text>Here then has carried, so much loot have typed that all have not carried away even. In the same place also have left in wood</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0010_name">
			<text>Hiding place in wood</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0010_description">
			<text>it is good we then one stalker have shaken. habarok at it that was necessary</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0011_name">
			<text>Secluded place in wood</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0011_description">
			<text>Vaska Was lost. Well we will drink for it, for Druzhbana mine. I have removed all valuable, yes in the same place in wood and have left. Could not...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0012_name">
			<text>Reserved place in wood</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0012_description">
			<text>Happens and on our streets a holiday. Have caught a good large sum. habarok while have put by. Not safe where</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0013_name">
			<text>Reserved place in red wood</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0013_description">
			<text>Here what to do? Loot in red wood has hidden. And now the second month I can not take away. That ail, affairs</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0014_name">
			<text>Hiding place of the master</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0014_description">
			<text>So has dumped in Taynichok which that. Not so valuable, but nevertheless</text>
		</string>
<!-- new string id's - aleks1970 -->
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0015_name">
			<text>Backpack in wood</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_forest_secret_0015_description">
			<text>Went to a Limansk. To pass then could not, but which that on road sends, have hidden in the same place in red wood</text>
		</string>
	</string_table>
<!--Created/Modified with S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Dialog Extended Editor by Marty Sheppard/ Version: 0.96i ( 2017/02/17) =!!= Last changed: 17.04.2017 05:46:33 -->
