<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 minor edits, removed "string_table" - aleks1970 -->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->
<!-- Partial translation by Def1ne. Reworked and proofed all text - Sword2012 - 09 Feb 17 -->

	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101">
		<text>Thank you, er... Marked One, right? You helped save our associate Kruglov, and in order to show my sincere appreciation I would like to present you with one of our working suits. It's a lifesaver for the environments in which we operate... Is there any other way I can be of help to you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_1011">
		<text>I'm looking for Lab X-16. The Barkeep told me you might know where it is, and how to get into it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_1012">
		<text>We've had a long-standing interest in Lab X-16. Or rather, whatever inside it is generating the emissions that directly affects people's consciousness. I'm afraid I have to disappoint you - the place is impossible to penetrate without special Psi-protection, otherwise the outcome is well-known. Even if you could evade the swarms of zombies that infest the laboratory entrance, you run the risk of becoming one of them the longer you stay - and that's not long at all... However, we've been working on a screening device to help shield you from the emissions, but to fine-tune it we need measurements from close to the emitter. It's a dangerous place and we're not trained for this kind of activity, but if you're prepared to help us then we can provide you with a fully calibrated prototype for field testing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_1013">
		<text>What do I need to do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_1014">
		<text>If you would protect and assist our associate in taking all the necessary measurements, I will prepare a fully functioning prototype of the Psi-protection device for you. It should at least get you get inside the laboratory...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_10141">
		<text>Okay, I agree</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101411">
		<text>Excellent! Please talk to Kruglov and get going. He is already equipped with the necessary gear</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101412">
		<text>Okay</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_10142">
		<text>Okay, I agree</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101421">
		<text>Excellent! Please talk to Semenov and get going. He has everything you'll need</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101422">
		<text>Okay...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_10143">
		<text>Thanks for your offer, but I don't want to sign up for this right now</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101431">
		<text>That's too bad. A real pity... I don't know when, or even how we could carry out these measurements on our own...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_11">
		<text>Yes, sir? What might you be looking for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_111">
		<text>I'm looking for Lab X-16. The Barkeep told me you might know where it is, and how to get into it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_12">
		<text>Thank you, Marked One, for rescuing Kruglov. Please accept this pressurized suit with our gratitude. Also, I suspect you didn't come here just for a reward. Am I right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_121">
		<text>I'm looking for Lab X-16. The Barkeep told me you might know where it is, and how to get into it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_1211">
		<text>We've had a long-standing interest in Lab X-16, but the place is impossible to penetrate without special Psi-protection. We've been working on a screening device to help shield you from the emissions, but to fine-tune it we need additional measurements from close to the emitter. If you're prepared to help us with this, we can provide you with a fully calibrated prototype for field testing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_12111">
		<text>Okay</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_121111">
		<text>Excellent, please talk to Kruglov and get going. He has everything you'll need</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_12112">
		<text>Thanks, but I don't want to sign up for this right now</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_121122">
		<text>That's a real pity. So far we've been unable to send a measurement expedition of our own</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21">
		<text>Yes, sir? What might you be looking for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211">
		<text>We've had a long-standing interest in Lab X-16. Or rather, whatever inside it is generating the emissions that directly affects people's consciousness. I'm afraid I have to disappoint you - the place is impossible to penetrate without special Psi-protection, otherwise the outcome is well-known. Even if you could evade the swarms of zombies that infest the laboratory entrance, you run the risk of becoming one of them the longer you stay - and that's not long at all... However, we've been working on a screening device to help shield you from the emissions, but to fine-tune it we need measurements from close to the emitter. It's a dangerous place and we're not trained for this kind of activity, but if you're prepared to help us then we can provide you with a fully calibrated prototype for field testing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2111">
		<text>Go on...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21111">
		<text>We've had a long-standing interest in Lab X-16, but the place is impossible to penetrate without special Psi-protection. We've been working on a screening device to help shield you from the emissions, but to fine-tune it we need additional measurements from close to the emitter. If you're prepared to help us with this, we can provide you with a fully calibrated prototype to get inside the laboratory...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21112">
		<text>Okay, I agree</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211121">
		<text>Excellent! Talk to Kruglov and get going. He is already equipped with the necessary gear</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2111211">
		<text>Okay</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21113">
		<text>Okay, I agree</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211131">
		<text>Excellent! Talk to Semenov and get going. He has everything you'll need...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211132">
		<text>Okay</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211141">
		<text>You don't understand. There's an emitter. No one has been able to get within half a kilometre of it, because it turns people into zombies. Going there without a suit is simply suicide. Do you understand?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2111411">
		<text>Hmm. That does change things a little...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211142">
		<text>To hell with it. Just tell me what you know...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211143">
		<text>Okay, but don't say I didn't warn you. Vasiliev worked on the laboratory problem. About a week ago, he and a Stalker named Ghost attempted to get inside the laboratory. Two hours later we felt the ground shake, then the emissions stopped. After another hour, we received a signal from Vasiliev. It was coming from the swamp, but then it vanished... From the sound of things, Vasiliev is gone. Would you try to find his body for us? He was carrying the latest information on the laboratory - where the entrance is, and how to get in. He might have also learned how to turn off the emissions. The laboratory entrance is most likely in the basement of one of the buildings in the power plant area</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211144">
		<text>There we go, great...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21115">
		<text>Thanks, but I don't want to sign up for this right now</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211151">
		<text>That's too bad. A real pity... I don't know when, or even how we could carry out these measurements on our own...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_221">
		<text>Thank you, er... Marked One, right? You helped save our associate Kruglov, and in order to show my sincere appreciation I would like to present you with one of our working suits. It's a lifesaver for the environments in which we operate...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_231">
		<text>A splendid job, Marked One! Now that the emissions have stopped, we'll be able to organise new expeditions, and explore previously inaccessible territories in the Zone! Thank you, and from now on we will offer our most favorable pricing policy toward you for anything you need. Oh, I almost forgot... Check your PDA. I've uploaded some info about what we call 'modificate artefacts'. I hope you'll find it useful...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2311">
		<text>Thank you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_241">
		<text>Yes, Marked One? What are you looking for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_31">
		<text>You did an excellent job. If the measurements are correct, the prototype should provide you with optimised protection from Psi-emissions</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_311">
		<text>Thanks. I'm glad to hear that...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_3111">
		<text>Now, your path to the laboratory is clear. However, if the source of the emissions isn't destroyed, or at least fully shut down, you may not have enough time to get back. We've calculated the surface coordinates of the source, and we're certain it's underground so, with respect, I've marked the spot on your map...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_31111">
		<text>But how do I get inside X-16? Where's the entrance?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_311111">
		<text>Vasiliev was working on the lab issue. About a week ago he and a Stalker called Ghost tried to get inside. A couple of hours later we felt a major tremor, and an hour later we picked up a signal from Vasiliev coming from the swamp, but it died away. We assume that Vasiliev died with it. If you can find his corpse, he may still have information on the lab and the way into it. He may have even found out how to deactivate the source of the emissions. Here, I've uploaded all the data we have...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_311112">
		<text>I'd like to take a look at these documents. You think Vasiliev still has them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_311113">
		<text>Perhaps. It depends on the state of... First you need to find Vasiliev's body. If his suit is still intact then you may find information about the lab's location, ideally in his PDA. The body of your friend Ghost must be somewhere there, too. You know, it seemed that he knew a lot more about X-16 than he was telling us. Had he somehow survived... I'm sorry, but that's out of the question of course...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_311114">
		<text>Okay, I'll give it my best...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41">
		<text>Why did he die? You were supposed to protect him!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_411">
		<text>Kruglov got killed by the zombies. I couldn't help it, there were too many of them...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_4111">
		<text>Oh, man, how could this happen? How could this happen! Damn it, everything is going wrong again. Now we'll have to call for more people. We have enough problems as it is... Damn...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41111">
		<text>Listen... Kruglov is gone, but I'm still here. Let me make it up to you. Give me the prototype, and I'll fight my way inside X-16 if necessary...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_411111">
		<text>Here is the only prototype, so be careful with it. It's not calibrated properly, but that's your fault for not protecting the man who was trying to help you. The device won't give you full protection, but it will lower the intensity of the emissions. However, you'll need to move fast to find the the source...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_4111111">
		<text>But how do I get inside X-16? Where's the entrance?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41111111">
		<text>Vasiliev was working on the lab issue. About a week ago he and a Stalker called Ghost tried to get inside. A couple of hours later we felt a major tremor, and an hour later we picked up a signal from Vasiliev coming from the swamp, but it died away. We assume that Vasiliev died with it. If you can find his corpse, he may still have information on the lab and the way into it. He may have even found out how to deactivate the source of the emissions. Here, I've uploaded all the data we have...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41112">
		<text>Anything else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41113">
		<text>You need to find Vasiliev's body. If his suit is still intact then you may find information about the lab's location, ideally in his PDA. The body of your friend Ghost must be somewhere there, too. You know, it seemed that he knew a lot more about X-16 than he was telling us. Had he somehow survived... I'm sorry, but that's out of the question now, of course...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41114">
		<text>Okay, I'll give it my best shot...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_51">
		<text>Why is he dead? Weren't you supposed to protect him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_511">
		<text>Semenov got shot by the zombies... I couldn't help it, there were just too many of them...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_5111">
		<text>Oh, man, how could this happen? How could this happen! Damn it, everything is going wrong again. Now we'll have to call for more staff. We have enough problems as it is... Damn...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_51111">
		<text>Listen... Semenov is gone, but I'm still here. Let me make it up to you. Give me the prototype, and I'll fight my way inside X-16 if necessary...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_511111">
		<text>Here is the only prototype, so be careful with it. It's not calibrated properly, but that's your fault for not protecting the man who was trying to help you. The device won't give you full protection, but it will lower the intensity of the emissions. However, you'll need to move fast to find the the source...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_5111111">
		<text>But how do I get inside X-16? Where's the entrance?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_511111111">
		<text>Vasiliev was working on the lab issue. About a week ago he and a Stalker called Ghost tried to get inside. A couple of hours later we felt a major tremor, and an hour later we picked up a signal from Vasiliev coming from the swamp, but it died away. We assume that Vasiliev died with it. If you can find his corpse, he may still have information on the lab and the way into it. He may have even found out how to deactivate the source of the emissions. Here, I've uploaded all the data we have...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_51112">
		<text>I'd like to take a look at these documents. You think Vasiliev still has them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_51113">
		<text>You need to find Vasiliev's body. If his suit is still intact then you may find information about the lab's location, ideally in his PDA. The body of your friend Ghost must be somewhere there, too. You know, it seemed that he knew a lot more about X-16 than he was telling us. Had he somehow survived... I'm sorry, but that's out of the question now, of course...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_51114">
		<text>Okay, I'll do my best...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_61">
		<text>Yes, Marked One?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_71">
		<text>Yes, Marked One?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_81">
		<text>It's bad news that Kruglov died, but nothing can bring him back. What about the measurement data. Did you bring that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_811">
		<text>Yes, I did</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_8111">
		<text>Thank goodness! Right, let me calibrate the prototype. Wait here for me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_81111">
		<text>Okay...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_812">
		<text>No...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_8121">
		<text>Then go and get them, quickly! How do you expect me to calibrate the prototype without them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_91">
		<text>You did an excellent job. If the measurements are correct and accurate, the prototype should give you maximum protection from the emissions</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_911">
		<text>Can you be a little clearer?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_9111">
		<text>Listen carefully, Stalker. This device will allow you to get through to the laboratory but, unless you turn off the emitter quickly, you won't last long - even with the Psi-protection the device provides. We've calculated the approximate location of the emitter, and we know it's located in an underground facility. Here, I've marked the spot on your map...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_9112">
		<text>How do I get inside X-16? Where exactly is the entrance?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_9113">
		<text>Vasiliev was working on the lab issue. About a week ago he and a Stalker called Ghost tried to get inside. A couple of hours later we felt a major tremor, and an hour later we picked up a signal from Vasiliev coming from the swamp, but it died away. We assume that Vasiliev died with it. If you can find his corpse, he may still have information on the lab and the way into it. He may have even found out how to deactivate the source of the emissions. Here, I've uploaded all the data we have...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_9114">
		<text>I'd like to take a look at these documents. You think Vasiliev still has them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_9115">
		<text>You need to find Vasiliev's body. If his suit is still intact then you may find information about the lab's location, ideally in his PDA. The body of your friend Ghost must be somewhere there, too. You know, it seemed that he knew a lot more about X-16 than he was telling us. Had he somehow survived... I'm sorry, but that's out of the question now, of course...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_9116">
		<text>Okay, I'll do my best...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_101">
		<text>There's no time...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_11">
		<text>Yes, Marked One?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_111">
		<text>The professor asked me to accompany you to the measurement site</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_1111">
		<text>Excellent news! Let's go quickly. I can't do it alone - that is, watch the instruments and my back at the same time - but with you along I think we'll manage quickly. Just make sure you don't let those walking cadavers get too close. Okay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_11111">
		<text>Yep. Let's go...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_111111">
		<text>Look, why don't you go first? You know the area, and those zombies are on the move again...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_1111111">
		<text>Okay...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_21">
		<text>Wow! Marked One here in person! Yes, we've heard of you, and glad you finally got around to visiting us... But first, talk to the Professor. He wants to thank you for rescuing me. Also, check your PDA. I've uploaded some useful info for you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_31">
		<text>Later, later!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_41">
		<text>Hey, Marked One! How are things going?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_51">
		<text>Yes, Marked One?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_511">
		<text>The professor asked me to accompany you to the measurement site</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_512">
		<text>Excellent news! Let's go quickly. I can't do it alone - that is, watch the instruments and my back at the same time - but with you along I think we'll manage quickly. Just make sure you don't let those walking cadavers get too close. Okay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_513">
		<text>Yep. Let's go...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_514">
		<text>Look, why don't you go first? You know the area, and those zombies are on the move again...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_515">
		<text>Okay...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_61">
		<text>I'm sorry, I don't have time for this right now...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_71">
		<text>Hey, Marked One! How's life?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_81">
		<text>One moment, please. We need to finish talking...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_91">
		<text>Wait! I'm not done taking measurements!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_wounded_scientist_11">
		<text>Arghh... Shit! Bastards!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_wounded_scientist_111">
		<text>You alive? C'mon, get up... Slowly, now. It's okay. It's all over...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_wounded_scientist_21">
		<text>Hey, Marked One. How are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_wounded_scientist_211">
		<text>Done! Pack the camera. Time to move!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_wounded_scientist_31">
		<text>Hey, Marked One! How's life?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_1">
		<text>Everyone's been talking about it. Did Sidorovich tell you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_2">
		<text>Yes, he did...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_22">
		<text>So, what do you want to know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_23">
		<text>Did you participate in that expedition?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_24">
		<text>I was meant to, but I didn't... I'm sorry, but it's difficult for me to talk about this. Many of my friends and colleagues...\nBut it was two years ago... If it'll help you, I'll tell you what happened. It began with the scientific congress in Berlin, during which the main interest was the Zone, and its influence on the environment. As a result, they decided to organize a full expedition to the Zone, headed by scientific experts who would study the nature of the Zone and gather information. It wasn't difficult to find sponsors, and the Ukrainian government sanctioned everything we needed. We had some of the leading scientists in the world with us, chemists, physicists, biologists, zoologists, botanists - everyone wanted to be involved! We spent three months training at a military base on the edge of Chernobyl, before the expedition even started...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_25">
		<text>Yes, I remember reading about that. Go on...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_26">
	<text>A lot of equipment had been brought in specifically for the expedition - measuring devices, data analysers, environmental hazard suits, even mobile laboratories. To protect the expedition team, the government supplied specially modified ATVs, and two Spetsnaz units! There were technicians, interpreters, journalists, and even a few Stalkers who helped us organize the expedition. After two weeks of final instructions and preparation the expedition was finally ready to enter the Zone - in Town 32. And guess what happened? Less than 24 hours before the expedition I became ill, and had to spend four days in an infirmary - and that's why I'm still here. But you've no idea how disappointed I was, how jealous I felt of my colleagues - even though they told me that as soon as I recovered I'd be personally escorted to the scientific camp - but I would never be one of the pioneers! Meanwhile, the expedition had reached Town 32. A mobile laboratory, like the one we're in now, had been transported there by helicopter. The connection with the base was set up, everyone set up their equipment, and the research began. At first, everything went as planned. Everyone did their job, like the professionals they were. They systematically measured radiation levels, investigated the properties of each anomaly, studied the chemical composition of every artefact they found. Each day we received regular messages from the camp about their new explorations and discoveries. Every specialist did what they were trained to do - were born to do. Each of them recognized how privileged they were to be there, no one doubted the success of the expedition, and I just lay on a cot in an infirmary...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_27">
		<text>So what happened then?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_28">
		<text>Very soon after they arrived strange things started happening. First was constant irritability and even aggression between everyone. We assumed it was from the stress, the workload, the need to produce results... Then two soldiers disappeared. Three days after the expedition started, we received a message that Professor Rosenberg, one of our chief scientists, had started shouting to himself, before putting a pistol up his mouth and committing suicide. We all knew this wonderful man, and the news shocked us beyond belief! Two days later our radio connection with the camp went dead. We waited and waited for the many communications engineers on both sides of the expedition to get it working again, but nothing. Eventually someone organized a helicopter to the camp, but then it couldn't leave because of bad weather. All we could do was wait. A few days later we received a message from two Stalkers who claimed to have spotted a group of people in an ATV in the Rotten Wood, getting ambushed at night time. The Military immediately sent Spetznaz troops to the area. A lot later I heard that the ambush was carried out by three members of the expedition, who hid in the woods and jumped them. When they were captured, they were more like animals than people - wild, frightened, disconnected from reality - reminiscent of patients in a psychiatric hospital... It was hard to believe that just one week ago they were highly intelligent, mature and loving colleagues. It took over a month to stop them jabbering and biting, and to partially restore some of their minds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_29">
		<text>So what was the diagnosis?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_291">
		<text>After analyzing the entire incident, including stories of the survivors, the Commission concluded that the cause of death of everyone else in the expedition was psychotropic radiation of unprecedented power. From something in the Zone now called the 'Brain Scorcher'. As a result of prolonged exposure to this new type of radiation, the human brain starts to break down, creating symptoms of aggression, rage, even savagery... Some, like the esteemed Professor Rosenberg, couldn't cope with the conflict of what they were becoming, and killed themselves before it was too late. Some took out their aggression on others, attacking and tearing them apart like caged, starving animals. And that was just the start, before the mutants arrived... Those who managed to escape, and who'd not yet gone completely mad, were ambushed by bandits and killed for what they had on them. That was the expedition to City 32...\nAfter that, I vowed never to leave the Zone until I'd learned everything there was to know about it, and how to protect everyone else doing the same...\nThat's my story, Marked One. I hope it helps you understand the Zone, too. Now I must return to work...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_292">
		<text>I'm grateful for your time, professor...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_3">
		<text>Oh, one more thing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_33">
		<text>Ask quickly. I've no more stories...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_0">
		<text>Professor, do you have any advice on the more unusual mutants of the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_1">
		<text>Well, I do have Kruglov's latest update on Poltergeists...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_2">
		<text>Thank you. You don't hear so much about them...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_3">
		<text>Here is what we currently know of Poltergeists:\n1. They are presumed to be enlightened Stalkers who were exposed to high levels of emissions of some sort. They have an incredible mastery of telepathy. They can take control of animals, mutants, inanimate objects, even people - any of which can be an eerie experience to observe.\n2. They are invisible to the human eye but, according to witnesses, they usually have an audible and visible aura of sparks or electricity around them. There is no information on surviving being controlled by one, nor if they can be killed.\n3. Their telekinetic abilities vary. They have been known to throw objects as diverse as bits of wood to large, solid steel doors.\n4. They have the ability to form other mutants by reproductive telepathy - a Controller, for example. When someone has been under the influence of a Poltergeist long enough for their minds to merge, that person becomes a Controller. The Controller then discharges the Poltergeist from its consciousness, but retains the mental abilities of its progenitor. This information was received from fellow scientists stationed in the center of the Zone, and with whom we lost contact over two years ago, so we've had to assume the worst.\n5. Although their appearance above ground is not uncommon, Poltergeists tend to live underground, where they are more connected to the Zone's latent energies.\n6. Careful analysis of a Controller's psychic blasts has linked it to something more powerful and external to itself. This is presumed to be the Poltergeist.\n7. From this data, we can theorize that a Poltergeist's energy can be dissipated by radically disturbing either the balance or flow of its energy construct...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_4">
		<text>Can you be a little clearer about that last part?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_5">
		<text>You need to shoot it, Marked One. Several times, in different parts of its energy manifestation...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_6">
		<text>Got it. Thanks...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_saharov_0">
		<text>Did you want to ask me something, professor?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_saharov_1">
		<text>Yes, Marked One. I need Ghost's PDA. It contains valuable information about partially studied artefacts found only near the center of the Zone. This would help our research so much. Please, if you can find and bring it to me, I'll make sure you're rewarded...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_saharov_2">
		<text>Don't worry. If I find it, I promise I'll bring it to you. No reward necessary...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_saharov_3">
		<text>Thank you. It's not just for me, but the whole scientific world. I cannot stress how important this information is to us...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_saharov_next_0">
		<text>Hi, Professor. Here, I found your documents...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_saharov_next_1">
		<text>Oh, excellent! This means so much to me. I am very, very grateful to you, Marked One. Here, please accept this for your efforts...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_saharov_next_2">
		<text>Thank you, but may I ask you something? In the PDA was a note about Fang, from Strelok's group. Do you know anything about his death?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_saharov_next_3">
		<text>I'm sorry, Marked One, I've heard very little. But just before Ghost accompanied Vasiliev to the underground lab, he told me that he'd worked together with Voronin at the Duty HQ. Maybe he can help you...</text>
	</string>
 