<!-- 1.1.0.0.0.4 -->
<!-- MAJOR REWRITE - Translated and corrected by Steve90k for fluency and ease of reading. Edited and proofed by Sword2012 for clarity, brevity, and consistency. 19 Jan 16 -->
	<string id="bar_ecolog_research_corrupted">
		<text>I, Professor Kruglov, am deleting the entire results of our research for the sake of humanity. This knowledge must not pass into the hands of violent people to further their criminal objectives. Those reading this should know that our largely unarmed group was ambushed in the Wild Territory by mercs, led by the scum named Wolfhound. By the time you read this we will, in all likelihood, be dead...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_research_normal">
		<text>The psychic waves from the emissions primarily affect the advanced areas of cognitive activity.\nExperiments show that only humans, and animals with developed cognitive processes, such as dogs, cats, and pigs, are susceptible to these waves.\nHumans enter a trance-like state, whereas animals exhibit a state of fear, becoming very aggressive.\nJudging by this evidence, we conclude that the emissions are geared quite specifically towards the human brain. Extensive studies on labour camp volunteers have shown that subjects given medication will come out of their trance state, resulting in minor disorientation instead.\nThis research has allowed us to develop experimental devices that can protect the human brain, to some extent, from these waves.\nWe have since determined that the source of the emissions is located in the centre of Lake Yantar. The source itself is likely to be artificial in nature, meaning that it can be disabled, although there is no sign of such a structure on the surface.\nOur greatest concern is of criminals attempting to reach this source, and gaining control over it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_after_agroprom_documents_name">
		<text>Military documents</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_bar_darklab_documents_name">
		<text>Lab X-18</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_bar_x16_documents_name">
		<text>So the Brain Scorcher is man-made?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_before_darklab_documents_name">
		<text>Barkeep</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_before_radar_task_name">
		<text>After meeting with the crazy Stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rostok_tunel_gordon_diary">
		<text>12 Jan 2012\nDamn my supervisors! First Mesa, then some strange town in Russia. Why here, out in the God-forsaken Ukrainian plains? "Gordon!" they said,"Please accept this crowbar as a token of our appreciation, and have fun out there!" Did I really know too much?\n \n20Mar 2012\nFinally made it into the Zone - if the world needed a suppository, this is where it'd stick it... Why are there no bears? And why is every fucking thing here trying to kill me? Thank goodness for my 'gift'... How am I going to survive this place? How am I even going to eat? I've got a constant headache, and I'm not finding my bearings too well. I wonder what the half-life of life itself is here... I've only met one other person, and nearly had to swap my retirement present for a can of meat. Thankfully I was able to teach him something about radiation sickness. Here, knowledge is existence...\n \n26 Apr 2012\nA blowout has started - the Aurora Borealis' evil twin... The Barkeep told me to hide my ass, and keep it hidden. I chased some huge rats out of an abandoned tunnel. It wasn't easy - they were almost as desperate as I was for shelter... I'll wait out the bad weather here until it's safe enough to leave, or too dangerous to stay...</text>
	</string>