<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 minor edits, kostya hints, tex_saharov_pda -->
<!-- Translated and corrected by Steve90k for fluency and ease of reading. Edited and proofed by Sword2012 for clarity, brevity, and consistency. 07 Oct 16 -->
<!-- Names changed as commented below - Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16 -->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->
	<string id="mil_actor_main_quest_descr">
		<text>According to General Voronin, this blockbuster of a weapon can only be found near Freedom's base, making it big problem for Duty. How I get it is up to me, but one way is to gain the trust of the Freedom member named Cook. According to the general, he's a heavy drinker, so I'll take along some vodka - it's always useful for getting information from new aquaintances...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_blockpost_job_descr">
		<text>Help protect the Barrier against an armed attack from the 'Brain Scorcher' fanatics</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_blockpost_job2_descr">
		<text>Lukash: If you're feeling strong, you can go to the Barrier, on the border of Radar. There are signs of an imminent attack from mutants or the Monolith faction. The guys there will really appreciate your help...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_courier_doc_descr">
		<text>Freedom had 2 RG-6's. One kept in their armory, the other stashed in the Bloodsucker village in case of emergency</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_courier_job_descr">
		<text>Lukash: We need you to find an informer, Pavlik. He's on his way to meet up with his contact at the farm. We need to stop this traitor once and for all, so your mission is to follow him there and find out who he's giving his information to. He's just left, so you'll need to hurry. Don't be seen, but remember - only kill him when you have the information! Not before! Once you know the other guy's name, you can kill them both...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_flash_info">
		<text>Today we went on to the next hunt, at the village as usual\n \nA creature is stalking the place! It must have got over here from Radar. It just looked at them, and they were dead. Everyone's dead. I'm all alone. The creature's still out there. I'll try to leave at night time\n \nI don't remember how I got out, but it was hell! My head feels terrible - full of gruesome sounds and images. I can't get rid of them. I don't know where they came from. It must be the devil's radiation, but my detector's broken. I need to find somewhere to hide. I desperately need to sleep...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_dolg_kill_lukash_descr">
		<text>Accompany the Duty party to the base\nTake out the three snipers\nKill Lukash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_dolg_kill_sniper_descr">
		<text>Kill the sniper in the tower. You'll need a single clean headshot to avoid any retaliation...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_flash_bandit_descr">
		<text>Crap! Those stupid goats from Duty have driven us from our base. We're dug in at the farm, and didn't even have time to collect our stuff. The Freedom base is close by. Get to them quickly...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_flash_max_descr">
		<text>Some military guys from Radar had a couple of RG-6's. It's a classy piece - especially for clearing out an area fast. They must have done a deal. Lukash has one, and Gloomy stashed the other in the bloodsucker village - probably in a basement. It should certainly be safe there...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_flash_ugrumy_descr">
		<text>#1. I've been told to carry on to Radar. If I'd stayed here any longer, I'd have died of fucking boredom...\n \n#2. Avoided an ambush by four Bandits, rookies all of them. They didn't want me dead, they just wanted my suit, so I took it off and left it on the floor for them - right in my firing line. Their last mistake - I had a spare - and they fell into my ambush. I'm getting too old for this shit...\n \n#3. Strelok was waiting for me. Yes, with three bloodsuckers around - oh, now there's a fourth! - so it was a pretty safe meeting place. Blood trails everywhere! Smart guy, that Strelok...\n \n#4. Found a code to a door - 19840519 - but no indication of which door\n \n#5. Engaged the Mercs who went into Radar. No documents on them, but at least they had ammunition. I'll stash the RG-6 in the cellar, then move on</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_rg6_task_descr">
		<text>Voronin: Freedom has some new RG-6 grenade launchers. If you were to visit their base, and steal at least one of them, I would remunerate you generously. Since you're not in our faction, you should easily gain their trust. I will send you information on the base. You should look for a man named Cook. He's a member of Freedom, and knows where the RG-6's are. He appreciates good vodka, so you might want to take plenty with you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_go_to_miser_descr">
		<text>I should collect my reward from Miser at the Freedom base</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_hunters_task_descr">
		<text>Destroy all the Bloodsuckers in the village. They're strong, fast, and can drain a man's blood within seconds...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_hunters_task_descr2">
		<text>Destroy all bloodsuckers in the village. They're almost invisible when they attack, which will often be in groups. Your only warning will be the sound of their heavy breathing getting closer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_lukash_job_descr">
		<text>Lukash intends to lauch a counterstrike on Duty at the farm. The operation will be headed by Max, one of the veterans of Freedom. My job is to help them</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_mad_flash_job_descr">
		<text>That's interesting. How can this crazy guy at the swamp know so much? We'll need to find out. The main thing to watch out for is old tripmines - they'll be so corroded that they'll blow at the slightest touch. Maybe even a bolt...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kostya_taynik1">
		<text>Hiding place in Cordon. You'll need to search in the wood, near the abandoned factory</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kostya_taynik2">
		<text>Hiding place in Cordon. At the crossing south of the tracks, under a fir tree</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kostya_taynik3">
		<text>Hiding place in Cordon. To the east of the Rookie village, under a pile of stones</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_kordon_art">
		<text>Bring Kostya the Goldfish artefact from the abandoned factory in Cordon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_svalka_taynik1">
		<text>Hiding place in Garbage. Look beside the wood, near a bog, under some dangling legs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_svalka_taynik2">
		<text>Hiding place in Garbage. Look in the west woods, behind the parking area beyond the machine graveyard</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_svalka_taynik3">
		<text>Hiding place in Garbage. Look in a crane box, on a radioactive heap closest to the vehicle scrap yard</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_svalka_taynik4">
		<text>Hiding place in Garbage. Look on a radioactive heap, closest to a wood behind the swamp. Don't just look on the ground...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_svalka_taynik5">
		<text>Hiding place in Garbage. Look on a radioactive heap, located near the Duty post</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_x18_taynik1">
		<text>Hiding place in laboratory X-18. Indoors, inside an old safe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_x18_taynik2">
		<text>Hiding place in laboratory X-18. Indoors, near some old cages</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_x18_taynik3">
		<text>Hiding place in laboratory X-18. High up, inside the Pseudo-giant's den</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_agroprom_taynik1">
		<text>Hiding place in Agroprom. In a bog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_agroprom_taynik2">
		<text>Hiding place in Agroprom. To the south of the complex, where Stalkers usually make camp inside an irradiated area</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_agroprom_taynik3">
		<text>Hiding place in Agroprom. Near the electrical substation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_agroprom_taynik4">
		<text>Hiding place in Agroprom. In a bush near a nest of tushkanos, to the north of the central complex</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_agroprom_taynik5">
		<text>Hiding place in Agroprom. In a bush near a cat lair</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_agroprom_taynik6">
		<text>Hiding place in Agroprom. In the ravine between the two compounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_yantar_taynik1">
		<text>Hiding place in Yantar. 'PROSIR butane' is hidden under a tank within the factory area</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_yantar_taynik2">
		<text>Hiding place in Yantar. In a container hidden underneath rubbish within the factory area</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_yantar_taynik3">
		<text>Hiding place in Yantar. In a pipe within the factory area</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_yantar_taynik4">
		<text>Hiding place in Yantar. On a tree within the factory area</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_yantar_taynik5">
		<text>Hiding place in Yantar. On top of a tank within the factory area</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_yantar_taynik6">
		<text>Hiding place in Yantar. On an elevated pipe within the factory area</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_as_taynik1">
		<text>Hiding place in Army Warehouses. Under one of the fir trees near the helicopter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_as_taynik2">
		<text>Hiding place in Army Warehouses. Inside an oven in one of the Bloodsucker village houses</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_as_taynik3">
		<text>Hiding place in Army Warehouses. In a chimney in the Bloodsucker village</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_as_taynik4">
		<text>Hiding place in Army Warehouses. On a tree in the Bloodsucker village</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_as_taynik5">
		<text>Hiding place in Army Warehouses. On the ridge of a roof in the Bloodsucker village</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_as_taynik6">
		<text>Hiding place in Army Warehouses. In the minefield</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_radar_taynik1">
		<text>Hiding place in Radar. Near the helicopter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_radar_taynik2">
		<text>Hiding place in Radar. In a wood on a tree, near the hole in the wire fence</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_radar_taynik3">
		<text>Hiding place in Radar. In a wood, on stones near a carriage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_radar_taynik4">
		<text>Hiding place in Radar. In a wood on a tree. You'll need to go from a carriage and along rocks to find it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_x10_taynik">
		<text>Hiding place in laboratory X-10. Security doors will require a code. Guidance notes on codes are always locked away safely inside the laboratory. One door has a seven digit code made up of the numbers 2, 7, 9, 54, 61. You'll just need to figure out in which order they've been applied...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_pripyat_taynik1">
		<text>Hiding place in Pripyat. There should be three - in a kindergarten, in an hotel, and inside one of the apartment buildings</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_pripyat_taynik2">
		<text>Hiding place in Pripyat. There should be three - on a crane, in an hotel, and inside one of the apartment buildings</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_pripyat_taynik3">
		<text>Hiding place in Pripyat. There should be three - on a tree near a service station, in an hotel, and inside one of the apartment buildings</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_sacharov">
		<text>Talk to Sakharov about calibrating a teleport</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kostya_meet">
		<text>Meet up with Bones</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sacharov_pda">
		<text>Sakharov has asked me to find Vasiliev's PDA. It should be in Lab X-16</text>	<!-- Changed 'Vasilev' to 'Vasiliev'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="tex_saharov_pda">
		<text>Sakharov has asked me to find Vasiliev's PDA. It should be in Lab X-16</text>	<!-- Changed 'Vasilev' to 'Vasiliev'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="sacharov_teleport">
		<text>Sakharov will need a Battery artefact to calibrate your teleport</text>
	</string>
