<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 controller vice comptroller -->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->
<!-- Imported all text from English 'Shadow of Chernobyl' game to replace entire previous text. Reworked all text up to Line 81 - Sword2012 - 21 Feb 17 -->
<string_table>
	<string id="stalker_story_1">
		<text>So we're creeping through this hangar, right? Dust and cobwebs everywhere. Filth up to the rafters. The detectors are dead silent - like, not only there's no-one around, but even we seemed pretty much non-existent in this place. So we're getting into positions along the perimeter - Sanya leading the way, the rest covering his back, then all of a sudden WHAM! One of these huge steel joists rusting under the ceiling breaks off and starts plummeting down! Somehow, Sanya managed to dodge it, and the damn thing slams right into the floor exactly where he'd been standing! Well, Sanya dives to the floor, does a roll, and starts blasting upwards. He doesn't even get to his feet! So we all freak out and start firing like lunatics. Then Sanya starts screaming blue murder, about this creature in the corner... I look over there, and don't see a thing, but by now the entire operation is a clusterfuck... We go looking around the ruins for about five minutes, stepping carefully, making sure we don't get under any joists. And it was fucking creepy, man, because one after another of us sees something and starts shooting away at nothing there. Two of our guys got completely screwed - one fell down into a pit, the other got hit by a door that just flew off its hinges! Now we're really worked up, 'cos it's plain that some bitch is fucking with our heads! So we spark up our Psi-protection, throw a gas grenade into each corner and wait, fingers on the triggers. We're waiting, and waiting... but it turns out the motherfucker was flying, or something like that, because while we were all running around on the floor, it was lurking up on the ceiling having a ball… It dawned on us too late, and only by accident. The thing was shaking more joists loose, and half the roof suddenly comes crashing down bit by bit, everywhere, right onto our heads - four of our guys got smashed up right there - but we hit the bastard! As soon as Sanya heard it on the ceiling, he just blazed away by reflex – a hell of a reflex, I've gotta say! You should've heard that thing screech! Well, we all jumped up and let loose with everything we had, and the big fucker came down squalling so loud my ears were almost bleeding. Man, we gave that thing hell, clubbing it, kicking it, stamping on it. Fuck, it was strong. As big as a man, but all hairy! Then when we saw Sanya flick out his knife... well, we all did the same - and that's when the commander shouted and dragged us all off, otherwise we'd have sliced that bastard thing to bits...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_1_name">
		<text>The creature in the hangar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_10">
		<text>Have you heard of Explorer, the very first true Stalker? He was the one who originally broke through into the Zone, and he's still alive! People say he can take you to any place - you just need to name it. Now, finding him's a bit tricky, 'cos there ain't no posters around with his address... And he won't go with just anyone, either. He charges quite a bit, from what I hear, but if you find him and can afford him, you can guarantee he'll take you wherever you need to go, safely. Now, that's someone I'd like to have a chat with. You can certainly bet he's been past the Red Forest...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_10_name">
		<text>Superconductor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_11"><!-- Single " - aleks1970 -->
		<text>Now, having money and having lots of money, that's two different things… You think moolah's easy to get? No effing way! You'll get popped here by a Stalker for your jacket, or cop it with something fugly for your bones…\nNah, you've got to use your noggin. You've got to use your brains over there, and even better over here. Cowboys don't last long around here. Ain't gonna go far if all you got is rats in the attic…\nAnyway, here's how it was. The three of us, me and old Bruise and Loop, were rambling across the farmstead, taking a shortcut, like. All of a sudden we see some bloke hotfooting our way. So we lay low, and the guy's walking right by us, totally unawares. And he's all tiny, hauling this huge sack along, with his SMG hanging at the ready, so we'd be stuffed with lead just like that...\nThen Bruise says to me, "Why don't we shake him up some, see what he's got over there?" And I says, "Shut the fuck up, you dick..." Watch where he's about to stow his loot!\nWell, suddenly, this bloke vanishes into thin air, and we didn't see a fucking thing!\nAlright, so we decide to sit and wait then, and he pops up in about twenty minutes. And while he's standing there, shaking off dust, Loop sneaks up behind and blows his head clean off. We couldn't stop laughing, it was like on Tom and Jerry! Then Bruise gets up and they start frisking this guy - he had a proper bulletproof vest and a bum bag, too…\nI needed to piss, so I left my guys doing what they know best, then all of a sudden KABOOM! Turns out the bastard had his vest all wired, so it'd blow up if someone tried to take it off him. I fucked off from there quick, 'cos you don't know who's gonna show up after a fucking explosion…\nAnyway, I went back there a month later. Not a bone left of Loop, Bruise and that bloke. Fuck all. So I worked out where he could've dived into the ruins, and crawled in there myself… Passed three rooms full of nothing, then suddenly I see a bunch of beds piled up in one corner. Asked myself, what the fuck are they all doing there? So I started pulling them away from the wall, and what do I see there? A hatch! So I lift it up and shine my torch down. Fucking hell, I'm in heaven! Well, what I saw down there is my business, but it sure set me up for life!\nBut just think - had I hung around, I'd be dead already, or running around barefoot and slobbering in the street like some of those imbeciles you see…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_11_name">
		<text>The hatchway to Heaven</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_12">
		<text>They say there's this one gang - they're called Shamans or Druids. Seems they don't use any electronic equipment at all, because they want to stay close to nature and the like… They reckon the Zone reacts stronger to electronic equipment - anything to do with electromagnetic radiation or something. They even say it attracts mutants. Basically, they believe the Zone is a sensitive living organism, so it's no good going into it with all these gadgets, and that you don't really need them anyway. Doesn't stop them from carrying knives and assault rifles, though, since they're all mechanical… I guess using your teeth and nails doesn't quite work for them, eh? But then, you don't hear many stories about one of them kicking the bucket, do you? You never know, they might be on the right track there… Can't say I'll be doing without my GPS and artefact detector anytime soon, though! Hmm, they seem to be coming more from the Belarussian side. I wouldn't mind taking a pop at one of them sometime, and see what kind of artefacts they've got...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_12_name">
		<text>The story of the Battle Druids</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_13">
		<text>Does anyone know the score on these top secret labs, deep in the Zone? They're still functioning, aren't they? But how the heck does anybody manage to survive there, without food or energy? So the question is, what if it's not people working there?\nI talked to this one guy… He didn't see the labs himself. Well, not with his own eyes, but his scanner picked up some weird conversation in Yantar. Two guys were talking about some laboratory, and the first guy was swearing to the other that he'd run into this figure in a suit like Stalkers wear, but much fancier… Translucent, he said. And this figure got angry and told him something like "This is a restricted area. Fuck off out of here..."\nScared the shit out him, it did! I mean, have you ever seen anything like that before? But then it all sort of happened near the Red Forest… You know what I mean, right? So it probably ain't true… But then again, mutations... They take on different forms, right? Well, what if those aren't people any more, but some sort of energy entities? What do you think? C'mon, what are you laughing at?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_13_name">
		<text>Ghost's shadow</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_14">
		<text>Here's what I can tell you. It's almost impossible to sleep in this part of the Zone… I'm lucky I don't sleep much anyway, but the nightmares some people see... I can't imagine a worse way to die, in your sleep with the most horrific thing you can imagine happening to you. So many don't wake up in the morning. Massive heart attack during the night...\nYou ever wonder what happens if you die in a dream? You can't wake up from it, so how can you ever escape it? I've seen some wake up absolutely nuts, driven mad in their sleep, and you just want to end their misery...\nWell, apparently there's a cure. If you really need to sleep, you need to find an old bucket - a big pot will do, a cauldron or something - as long as it has no holes… You stick your head into it, with a pillow of some sort, and rest for the night... Okay, you can laugh all you want, but I'll see you in a couple of days when you're dropping dead from exhaustion. Morons...\nSo tell me, why are grunts roaming around sporting these fancy helmets now, eh? Well, yeah! For about two years nothing, then suddenly they're all over the place! And these brain buckets are something really new. Somebody took one off the body of a dead grunt, and got it examined. There's a mesh inside, made of thin copper wire, attached to the entire liner. So what the hell's it doing there?\nMark my words, there's something strange about this. Look, this place is useless in terms of its artefact-anomaly ratio, and there are far safer areas around, with better pickings… So I reckon they're researching the grounds. Marking the area for their base. I reckon they want to get through to the Sarcophagus, and if that's the case, then we need to stay as far away as possible from them when they do...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_14_name">
		<text>A nightmare-resistant bucket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_15">
		<text>You guys heard about 'Interception' yet? Rumor has it they're real pros, the dog's bollocks and everything! Man, you should see them in action - nothing like those old farts at the cordons! They stay in the Zone for months on end, going into every stinking hellhole! I swear to God! They've got bases everywhere, really cool hideouts, with choppers dropping supplies for them by the perimeter. Their commander is a guy named Gromov, which is probably fake, but they call him 'Major' or 'Grom'.\nYou don't believe me? Well, Pakhomych recorded them once, then got out of there quickly. Didn't want to catch lead poisoning, if you know what I mean... Shit, it was real top secret stuff, man! You know Pakhomych, right? He's the man! But these guys, you know, they're the real thing. Who knows what they're doing here? And the loot they must get! Christ, if I could just get one third - No, just ten per cent of what they have - I'd already have a mansion in Sochi and live the life… Hey, I've heard they've got this gadget that detects mutants up to two hundred metres away. And another that shows you where the anomalies are ahead! Fuck, if I had those things I'd be picnicking all over the Zone, filling my basket with artefacts…\nAnd you know what else they say? There are these other guys - not the dogs of war as such but - more like real Stalkers… Some of them got through to the center of the Zone. Not only safe and sound, but they even learned to tame fucking mutants! These guys never leave the perimeter - they just stay in the Zone, you know? And no one ever goes near them… well, except maybe the ones destined to reach the Sarcophagus… But some artefacts they've got, too! The kind you never see anywhere. You don't know what kind of superpowers they've got!\nDuty knows about them though… those slimeballs know them and fight them, but they never say anything. You try asking one of them, and they just say "Bullshit!"\nSome people, eh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_15_name">
		<text>'Interception', the dwellers of the interior</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_16">
		<text>Brothers, did you hear about the unbelievers who broke through to the antennae? Fortunately, the Monolith guided us, and our brothers opposed them off just in time. One, they killed one immediately, but the other two ran away. Cowards! All cowards! True faith leaves no room for fear! But the Monolith is wise and omniscient, and would not have let them live without a reason...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_16_name">
		<text>The ones who got through to the antennae</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_17">
		<text>Brothers, the Monolith appeared to me last night, and spoke unto me. It was beautiful in its grandeur, its light nearly blinding me, but I was filled with grace beyond all mortal comprehension! I know, and I feel its power within us all! Only firm faith can overcome evil! It revealed to me that our victory is at hand, but that its power can fill only those who have the deepest faith...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_17_name">
		<text>The Monolith in a dream</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_18">
		<text>Brothers, the Monolith put my faith to the test, and I nearly strayed from the path. But I withstood! Glory to the Monolith! Its trials strengthen us! We were on our way back from the Dark Valley, and I fell behind. Evil grabbed at the opportunity and started tempting me. And… I doubted. The image of truth became distorted - the enemy whispered into my ear lies about how the Monolith uses us as slaves. But then I realized - it's a trial! I remembered the glory and the splendor of the Monolith. I regained my inner strength and my confidence. Since then I have no fear of trials and know no doubts. All glory to the Monolith!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_18_name">
		<text>On the test of faith</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_19">
		<text>For as I walked through the Valley of Darkness, I saw a place teeming with unbelievers who had not yet witnessed the power of the Monolith. We were on guard duty, and their attack came at night. We fought bravely, and my brothers stood their ground as befits true believers. Although the Monolith summoned many of us that night, my time had not yet come. My gun stood useless and silent, as did I. Suddenly the Monolith spoke to me, saying, "You are my only remaining son, and now my power rests with you. Stand strong in your faith and you shall defeat my enemies for the greater glory!"\nAnd I became shadow. My head down, I walked through their midst. Ignorant, savage unbelievers, they did not notice my passing amongst them. Walking over the empty shells that littered the ground, including those of our brothers, they thought us all dead. But now I was behind them, and the power of the Monolith burst forth from my hands. And that is how they finally came to understand. I am truly happy to serve you Oh, Light of Perfection!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_19_name">
		<text>Fighting in the Dark Valley</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_2">
		<text>My partner and I had been keeping an eye on this Research Institute for a while. A bleak place, it was. No animals around, no mutants, not even birds overhead. Except we'd heard that every time someone went in there, they returned either scared to death, or had gone bananas, or never came out at all. So we thought we'd give it a try and check it out ourselves. We set before dawn to make good time and avoid being seen, but by the time we got there it was already broad daylight. We left the car on the road, walked to the edge of the forest, and stopped there. My partner stayed on the ground while I climbed a tree to scope out the area. So I once I saw the Institute facilities, I settled down to take it in. They didn't look desolate at all. The windows weren't broken as you'd expect, there was little grass in the yard, but not up to your waist like you see in other place. To all appearances it looked like the place was still inhabited, but it was dead silent and not a single movement anywhere in the area. Then suddenly there's a burst of fire to my right - someone's blazing away with a machine gun. So I zoom in there and see a guy on the roof of one of the buildings, running to and fro like a cat in heat and firing away in every direction. I looked closely but couldn't make out what he was shooting at - he was all by himself. And then, it started...\nRight before my eyes, I'm not kidding you, his subgun just leapt out of his hands on its own, and disappeared over the side of the building… The guy looked terrified. He opened his mouth and started screaming, but it looked as if he was trying to shout at someone or something. Then he whipped out his knife and held it in front of him. And then I saw, I swear, another knife appeared right in front of him! Just hanging there in the air, pointing at him, with no one holding it! What happened next... Well, that thing started carving the guy up. Cutting his clothes, going into him, slicing him, as if it knew exactly what it was doing... The guy looked as if he was frozen, but trying to fight it. Screaming all the time… Then his knife flew out of his hand - it didn't just drop - it looked as if it'd been kicked before falling to the roof. Bit by bit, son of a bitch, the poor bastard ended up in shreds, bleeding from all over… I wanted to stop watching, but I didn't dare move...\nThen he was lifted up in the air and like... twisted. Again and again, like he was a rag doll or something... I've never seen anything like it before. After that… no, I'm not going to tell…\nAfter it was over I must've held my breath for, like, five minutes, just watching in case anything had seen me. I was soaked in sweat by then, my hands were shaking, but I didn't see a damn thing! Not in the normal range, not in infrared or night vision, nothing! When I thought it was it was okay to climb down, my partner just looked at me and decided not to ask questions. We just got in the car and left. After we got back to the base I started tanking up for about a week… Then, when I snapped out of it, I tried asking people if they'd heard of anything like that before. But they just looked at me like I'd gone mental or something. So I shut my mouth after that, and left as soon as I could…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_2_name">
		<text>Horror at the Research Institute</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_20">
		<text>Brothers, as we were patrolling the outskirts of the Dark Forest we came upon an unfaithful loner. We did not kill him, seeing as he was already on his way to conversion, though still halfway from his animal state… Such is the wisdom of the Monolith! Once again it revealed to us the true countenance of our enemies. Now our faith is even stronger! It is at hand, brothers! Our victory over the unbelievers is at hand. Soon the Monolith will fulfill our greatest desires! Those who are truly faithful to it will be drawn to it, its glory, its greatness! We shall abide in its radiance forever!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_20_name">
		<text>A transformation in the Dark Forest</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_3">
		<text>Anyway, here's what this one friend of mine told me. His boss wakes him in the middle of the night, tells him to hurry up to the lab. There's, like, some cargo there. So my friend's half asleep, doesn't know what's going on. What the heck is with this cargo? And the boss is like, you drunk or something? There's a fresh corpse on the table, the dinner is served! Anyway, he goes to the table and sees SOMETHING… Now, he had seen all sorts of stiffs from the Zone: boiled, grilled and ripped apart, not to mention dozens of mutants… But the sight of that thing - gag-a-maggot! Anyway, at first glance it looked just like a human being, except the head was way out of proportion: huge and ribbed like a pumpkin. And the body? Man, straight from a concentration camp, skin and bones. But that's what he figured out afterwards. At first, he says, he only saw a lump of flesh all smeared with some orange-red muck, blood or something…. Those pricks sure didn't spare their ammo. Ya know all they talk about duty… searching for anomalous objects, dang it… search my foot! My friend says it looked like something between a colander and a torn-up hot water bottle… and they obviously trampled it with their shitkickers. Not an object, but a damn piece of meat in black rags. So he worked his butt off the rest of the night and half of the morning. Turns out it was that very creature the locals had been calling the Illusionist: black rags, sending hallucinations onto stalkers, the head about a yard around… You know what's funny? What they thought was its face turned out to be the top of its head. No, it does have a face, but it's tiny-winy: the winkers always shut and the nose the size of a pin, but the cake-hole as wide as a gate. Probably when it walked its head would always hang down, 'cause there's no strength to keep it up… a snip... And get what these creatures eat for lunch. Mushrooms! Damn mushrooms! You've all seen 'em! The Zone's full of mushrooms, so the old-timers swear these creatures squeeze the juice out of them. Talk about shitty food… You know what else he was hiding in this little baggy on his hip? Well? How would you know! Alright, it was dried brains. And you know who's brain it was? The controller's!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_3_name">
		<text>A pathologist's supper</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_4">
		<text>Once we had this one retard tailing along… So we're going our way, stopping every now and then for a brief rest, and as soon as we do he drops on his butt and starts snoring. And when it's time to go he'd be the last one to lift his ass off the ground. Well, once he finally did it… He fell behind, and that's when the controller got him - zap! - and brain was gone. You rookies better pay attention. Any rustle, any movement… Even if a fricking bunny darts by… Though, Lord save you from running into any of the local bunnies… Anyway, you have to be alert every stinking second. Clips and grenades at hand, finger always on the trigger. The moment you spot something, fire off half a clip right away. There's something behind the bush? Shoot first and ask for credentials later. That's the basic training around here: think too much and you'll be dogfood in no time! And about the controllers, now this is a different story. You burst a fire at the rustle and drop down right away, that very second! On your back or face down, it doesn't matter. The controller grabs you if he sees you, he needs to concentrate or something. So you lay low and listen for any noise, checking if any scum is heading your way. You may quietly recharge your gun, take out your grenades… Anyway, if all is quiet, count till three and… Get your ass out of there! As far away as possible! You all got it? You yardbirds… Be on guard every second, that's the only way to survive…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_4_name">
		<text>Easy prey for a Controller</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_5">
		<text>You know, I've been thinking… Well, not really thinking, just had this idea… What if all this, everything around us I mean, is some sort of an experiment on us? You know, like little green men… I mean, why not? It's as good an explanation as any… I'm thinking: if it's really a training ground, what exactly are they trying to prove here? To see what artifacts we are slobbering over the most? And what if them artifacts are like some sort of bombs, eh? They must be all over the world now, in all sorts of laboratories. The rich cough up for them big time, right? Like, wow, cool stuff! Now that's what I want… Hell, you wouldn't believe what sort of useless shit they'd buy from you, as long as it's from the Zone… You know, all this "Now ain't I cool!" stuff, make everybody jealous… and one day - ka-pow! Think of it, man! Wouldn't that be something? Ha! But hey, who really knows what it's all about… Well maybe those who've been behind the radar, they would probably know… Then again, they may know something, but they can't say a word except dribbling and mumbling now. Or maybe that's precisely the reason they're all dribbling and mumbling… Oh well… Can't help thinking about this stuff, you know… It's all pretty sad, really...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_5_name">
		<text>Pitfalls</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_6">
		<text>Right… I seem to remember you asking me about something last night, though I can't recall… Ah, got it. You wanted to know why it's only our eggheads messing around in the Zone. Curious why the foreigners won't show up, even though there's enough stuff here for thousands of Nobel prizes… Alright, let's see. First of all, what the heck do they need coming down here for, when they can simply pay some of our guys and get the results on a silver plate? Second of all, they've actually been here themselves, and quite a lot of them, too. It's just that in the last two years these gringos have been badly scared of going into the Zone… There was this incident, you see. So now they stick to buying loot and information. And they're paying pretty well, so many loners work for them, and the looters, too… What, haven't you heard this story? C'mon! The whole Zone was buzzing about it, and you mean to tell me you haven't heard? Ah, what the heck. There was this large expedition, you see. The scientist alone counted about thirty, people from all over the world… All stars, you know, big shots and stuff… They were all rigged out: all premium-quality gear, heaps of it. Had a whole platoon guarding them, and a couple of our guides. So they all got onto their APCs and took off. Well, what happened then? Came back about a week later… Twelve people in a wreck of an APC. They got as far as the spiker by the Rotten Forest when they fell into an ambush… The looters… Oh yeah… The bastards couldn't care less where you come from… Finished off almost everyone. Only three people managed to get out across the border line, two stalkers and one egghead. The latter went bananas from all the excitement, so they had to send him off to a nut-house. Now he's writing a book about the Zone I hear. The stalkers didn't seem that bad. Must be down to the experience, we thought. Except… I guess they also lost it in their own way: One of them took off to the radar and vanished, the other one went back to the Big Place. And the rest were taken by the Zone. Ever heard about Station 32? That's where they all bit the bullet. It was all quiet at first, pretty much normal… They'd be reading their meters, taking samples, poking their gear into anomalies… And then they all started going nuts. Every friggin one of them. Everyone slowly going off their rocker. One of ours, the one that retired eventually, told me about it… Some actually ripped their own throats open, others would smash their heads against the wall, and some would simply… Gun in their mouth and… And then the beasts started swarming all over them them. Those few who were still sane enough barricaded themselves in the house. You get the picture, right? Dark night, all the local beasties outside, and people going nuts one after another inside. In short, in the morning those who still had it together broke out of there somehow. Went straight on, even got caught in some anomalies… Got to the Rotten Forest… But none of those who had been left behind have been found. They say loads of controllers were recorded in that area. That's how it was… Since then, no one goes anywhere near Station 32, and the foreigners steer clear of the Zone...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_6_name">
		<text>The chronicles of egghead globalists</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_7">
		<text>I'll tell you something. I was right there when them Duty guys captured that Illusionist! Stumbled over them by pure accident! My car, you know, my Niva, had its right front wheel broken off. The bolts chopped off on some hummock. And not a single spare part in stock. Well, I cussed for a minute, and then I thought, why don't I go to the plant, pick me up what I need. It was 'bout half a kilometer away, about thirty minutes walk both ways. Besides, I'd already been there before… All of a sudden, I seen them Duty boys! And not just a patrol, but about fifty of them! What the heck, I thought! So I hid in the bushes right where I was standing. "If they saw me and start combing the area, that'll be the end of me," I thought. Anyway, I'm lying low, holding my breath. All of a sudden I hear a salvo and they start blazing away like crazy! Only once in my life have I heard such blasts and firing... The first base assault, remember guys? Anyway, I'm lying there, listening closely… and it's all like WHAM! and BANG! Five minutes later all goes quiet and I'm listening for anyone walking my way. Nothing. Well, I get my balls together and peep out through the binocs. The guys are trailing out of the workshop… all messy, dragging their dead and the illusionist on a tarpaulin… or the remains of the Illusionist rather… and disappear into the glen. Then I hear the sound of engines and the sound dies away. I waited a little more, to make sure they're all gone. And then I went inside. Well, you know what they say - the Duty guys don't leave leftovers! But I wanted to check it out anyway. And what a sight it was! The walls were all pierced almost all the way through. The joists lay all over the floor, part of the roof collapsed. Up to my knees in shells, a real shooting ground. Blood, some scraps… Didn't find anything useful though - well, two full jets and a machine gun crushed down so bad you couldn't get it out… Needless to say I didn't even think about the bolts… So I went back to my car, chewed the cud for a while, took one bolt off each of the other wheels, and went back on low gear… And what if I had come out there half an hour earlier? Makes you think, doesn't it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_7_name">
		<text>The illusion of Duty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_8">
		<text>Yeah, so I got as far as Pripyat outskirts that time. Well, I though I'd look around first. Found the highest spot, this huge boiler-house with a chimney. I walk in there on tip-toes. Seems alright, dust everywhere, no footprints… So I crawl into the fire-chamber and start clambering up the stairs inside the chimney. So I'm climbing up, and the soot is not even smudging, hard as a rock! I get to the top and peep out… Beautiful view! Half the city spread right there before my eyes! So I take out my binocs and look around. [small pause] And then… I was about to climb down, when suddenly I realize that I'd completely forgotten to check out what's going on right under my nose! So I bend over slightly, look this way, look that way… Holy shit! That would've been some mess! There's this dwarf strolling around the courtyard! And I had almost climbed down! It's a good thing he didn't see me. But I couldn't knock him down either: the Akm hanging on my back, and the chimney way too narrow to stir in it. The Makarov under my arm wouldn't be of much help either, it was about fifty meters, plus the height of the chimney… if I didn't get him the first time, he'd do me in. So I'm sitting there, thinking. And watching what he's up to. And he was up to something weird, I'm telling you. First he was rummaging in a pile of lumber, rubbish flying left and right. And then suddenly he stood stock-still. Sort of listening to something. And then it all started. The garbage in the pile started stirring. The dwarf sprang back, stood up straight, put his hands to his head and twisted them somehow weird… and all of a sudden that rubbish goes flying at him! From everywhere!.. Bits of iron, bricks, rubber, tree branches, crap… Covered him from top to toe. Holy shit, I thought. The little guy's dead and buried. End of the story. But no! For about two seconds the rubbish lay still, and then wham! It goes splattering everywhere! There were iron pipes there, those stuck right into the concrete fence. The dwarf stood there for about a minute, thought something to himself, then turned around and trotted inside the building. It took me a while to catch my breath. "Well," I thought, "Time to save my bacon!" And then, I smell smoke. And it starts getting hot. Holy shit! Someone made a fire down below! A minute later I couldn't breathe anymore. I managed to climb out to the edge of the chimney, but there was no platform or anything, so I just perched there dangling my feet… The smoke was really eating my eyes out by now, I was choking for air… Anyway, I needed to get my ass out of there! Thank God I always have about forty meters of rope with me, just in case, you know. So I folded the rope, it wasn't too thick, barely fixed it to the chimney, tore my necktie in half, wrapped around my hands and started climbing down praying to all gods in heaven… All I could think about was: don't let me fall down! No safety rope, right? Nothing! The rope was really cutting into my hands… and sure enough, as bad luck would have it, it ended about five yards above the ground. Had to jump. I had no choice, did I? And I went crashing down! I was lucky not to break a bone, though I did get quite a few bruises and sprained my right leg alright! Hurt like hell, all over my body. And yet, I took off so fast I could've probably won a gold medal in racing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_8_name">
		<text>Seriy in Pripyat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_9">
		<text>I couldn't even believe my eyes then. You know, I thought I'd seen some really beautiful girls, right? But this one… she was… Perfect. Yes. That's it. Perfect. It felt as if the whole world around her was black and white and sort of blurry. But she... She was sharp and clear and full of color. And the way she moved! Man, I hadn't seen anything like that before. I mean, I had a lump in my throat. What does she have to do with all this science? What has she got to do in the Zone?.. That's right, in the Zone! It was the break of night… There's this nine story block of flats by the bus station. First something flashed by in the window on the first floor. So I unlock my AKM right away, and suddenly there she is, coming out of the building… I nearly rubbed my eyes, I mean, you know you can expect anything from the Zone! So, she comes my way. And I'm just standing there like a moron, staring at her… but holding my gun ready, you know, out of habit… Then she noticed me… Smiled… Said hello… And so I'm listening to her but not hearing what she says, just staring at her. She was wearing blue overalls, bright blue… but it wasn't loose at all, almost like a catsuit… And her body... Talk about amazing! And then I realize that I'm not even paying attention to what she says, just grinning from ear to ear… Turned out she was from the research group. Asked me if I could help her. Help her! I would jump into an anomaly for her right there! She said she was studying the… whatchamacallit … Zone endemics. You know the plants that don't grow anywhere but here. Said she had run off from security because she didn't like having them constantly sniffing around, and came there all on her own. I don't know. I believed her. So I agreed to help her, bring her some stuff. Two days later she came back just as we had agreed. Nearly got knocked out about five times while gathering all that stuff for her. So I'm going there with this one thought in my head: I'm going to see her again! And nothing. I didn't even see the house where I'd met her. And that's it… But you should've seen her! She was like, glowing from the inside...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_9_name">
		<text>Loneliness</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Stories">
		<text>Local Folklore</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
