<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.8 dmx135 controller vice comptroller, doc message in pripyat removed dose_asses...,
 dip: gen/Astrol questline, The Doctor, \\n, cop_prip_msg1, line 981 - removed russian char. aleks1970,
 tex_lukash_pechatka, tex_lysyi_klad and many minor edits, tex_otkrut_seif_sadik, boatswain, amber, lukash,
 doc_alive, map_mil_trader, map_mil_tehnician - aleks1970, tex_klenov_vse -->
<!-- Names changed as commented below - Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16 -->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 13 Dec 16 -->
 
<string_table>
	<string id="blow_phrase1">
		<text>Attention! An emission is imminent! Get out of the open! Find cover!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blow_phrase2">
		<text>Attention! An emission is imminent! Find shelter quickly...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blow_phrase3">
		<text>Attention! Attention! An emission is expected very soon!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blow_phrase4">
		<text>Based on meteorological and seismological data, an emission is fast-approaching! Get under cover!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="important_msg">
		<text>Important Message</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_for_test22">
		<text>The territory of ATP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="peshera">
		<text>Cave</text>
	</string>
	<string id="puzir">
		<text>Forgotten Forest</text>
	</string>
	<string id="av_peshera">
		<text>Labyrinth</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aver">
		<text>Reconoitered Earth</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh">
		<text>Swamp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lost_village">
		<text>Old Village</text>
	</string>
	<string id="red_forest">
		<text>Red Forest</text>
	</string>
	<string id="warlab">
		<text>Military Lab</text>
	</string>
	<string id="generators">
		<text>Generators</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hospital">
		<text>Hospital</text>
	</string>
	<string id="limansk">
		<text>Limansk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dead_city">
		<text>Dead City</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jupiter">
		<text>Jupiter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zaton">
		<text>Backwater</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pripyat">
		<text>East Pripyat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jupiter_underground">
		<text>Jupiter Underground</text>
	</string>
	<string id="labx8">
		<text>Laboratory X-8</text>
	</string>
	<!-- new 10991 -->
	<string id="sniper_novice">
		<text>Novice Avenger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sniper_experienced">
		<text>Experienced Avenger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sniper_master">
		<text>Master Avenger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sniper_veteran">
		<text>Veteran Avenger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nebo_master">
		<text>Master Clear Sky</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nebo_veteran">
		<text>Veteran Clear Sky</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nebo_experienced">
		<text>Experienced Clear Sky</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nebo_novice">
		<text>Beginner Clear Sky</text>
	</string>
	<string id="map_technician">
		<text>Technician</text>
	</string>
	<string id="map_trader">
		<text>Trader</text>
	</string>
	<string id="map_cmdr_freedom">
		<text>Commander Freedom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="map_cmdr_debt">
		<text>Commander Debt</text>
	</string>
	<string id="map_cmdr_clearsky">
		<text>Commander Clear Sky</text>
	</string>
	<!-- string id="cop_prip_msg1">
		<text>I got to the apartment. Pavel Sergeyevich and Shadows have been here but are gone. I found an interesting Notepad about that night's incident in the lab. .. So after all that happened, our friend went back to the lab. Apparently never came out from there...\nBy the way.. there is a receiver here with a strange continuously repeated message. certainly a Military transmission...\nWhat do you think?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cop_prip_msg2">
		<text>You are very close.. BUT We have a problem... our last conversation overheard. And maybe someone else knew about the Cube...\nA squad of Mercenaries has arrived in the eastern part of Pripyat. They know what you're looking for in the apartment...\nNeed to get them to believe otherwise. You do not want to trouble? You can try to merge some of the misinformation in the stalkers network...\nTry to write in the chat through PDA: Sell the cube of shadows, inexpensively. Meet us at the Cordon around the perimeter.\nWrite exactly how I wrote, then perhaps they decide that you have already picked up a cube... Try.</text>
	</string -->
	<string id="bullseye_private">
		<text>Bullseye: private channel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadows_private">
		<text>Shadows: private channel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="labx8_private1">
		<text>I know where is the entrance to the laboratory X-8. Send in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="labx8_private2">
		<text>All right. I hope Pavel is alive... He knows what we want.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="unknown_private">
		<text>Unknown: private channel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="propusk_msg">
		<text>Bullseye, circumstances have changed! One of the soldiers that was with Colonel survived! Just saw him on the way to the checkpoint. Faster race there, until he was told about the incident.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_article">
		<text>Article in journal:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="intel_mutant">
		<text>Intel about mutant:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="intel_group">
		<text>Intel about grouping:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="intel_art">
		<text>Intel about artefact:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="intel_anom">
		<text>Intel about Anomalie:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="intel_local">
		<text>Intel about location:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_history">
		<text>Zone History:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="local_lore">
		<text>Local folklore:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pers_note">
		<text>Personal note:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="intel_transport">
		<text>Intel about transport:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="data_downloaded">
		<text>Downloaded PDA data:</text>
	</string>
<!-- <string id="mil_secret"> - Duplicated with the 119 line in to the "string_table_tasks_military.xml" file - aleks1970 -->
	<string id="mil_secret_arhara">
		<text>Military Secret:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_tip1">
		<text>Danger! Critical pressure!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_tip2">
		<text>Unable to generate flames without colloidal gas or gasoline.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_tip3">
		<text>No flamethrower to refill!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stop_stalker">
		<text>STALKER!! Stop!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mod_downloaded">
		<text>New Artefact Modification downloaded to PDA...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_alive">
		<text>The Doctor is alive!!!\nHurry! Follow him through the teleport to a safe place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tele_ready">
		<text>The Teleport is ready...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kit_enemies">
		<text>Enemies are too nearby to use the Repair-Kit!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rep_slot1">
		<text>The weapon in the first slot has been repaired...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rep_slot2">
		<text>The weapon in the second slot has been repaired...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rep_damaged">
		<text>Weapon too severely damaged!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rep_nofix">
		<text>The weapon does not require repairs...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rep_armor_done">
		<text>Armor successfully repaired</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rep_armor_bad">
		<text>the armor is too severely damaged!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rep_armor_good">
		<text>the armor does not require repair</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rep_no_armor">
		<text>What armor? Moron!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rec_ria10_3">
		<text>Received: three RIA-10 Repair-Kits</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rec_riw10_3">
		<text>Received: three RIW-10 Repair-Kits</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rec_ria10">
		<text>Received: RIA-10 Repair-Kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rec_riw10">
		<text>Received: RIW-10 Repair-Kit</text>
	</string>
	<!-- end 10991 -->
	<string id="tex_take_arhara">
		<text>Yes, in the zone is nothing just do not ... That's an example - to find the minigun for Adrenalin ... It should be found in Yantar, where the helicopter went down... And where is this Yantar? Customer hinted that he needed to talk with a professor by the name of Sakharov ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_baty_zadan">
		<text>It was not so simple. We must take Sakharov's special detector, then go to the Wild Territory and seek with this detector for the military thing. What is that thing, I do not know. However, the detector will signal if I'm at a distance of ten meters away from it. After finding it, I should bring it to Sakharov and pick up a minigun for adrenaline.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_arhara_ekza">
		<text>Waugh, got involved ... Find in the ATP-infested enemies and mutants, the exoskeleton ... This case is highly unlikely. Well, that Voronin told the approximate location of it. They will not immediately give up this armor. Voronin can wait, and I may find the 'cloak of invisibility' to be very useful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_take_shurup">
		<text>Screw this, so droll! Bring him the usual vices through the floor of the Zone ... Quite to the head does not make friends. Although ... All geniuses are a little weird, but this does not look like a genius. And, then, just disabled by brain from childhood ... It's good that there is an approximate figure, where these vices can be. Fitter-taught, mmat it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_take_chaes_ugrum">
		<text>We must get antizombin to watch 'Freedom'. Have to be dragged behind it for new traders. Here I am stump, it was necessary to immediately buy ... And not one, but a couple ... And suddenly, the hog more of them will not sell? Go north in Chernobyl NPP, for sure, then very useful ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_take_mozg">
		<text>It is necessary to extract and bring Lukash brain Controller of at least two pieces. You can search for it in the ATP or trudge to the north of Chernobyl ... In addition, find the anarchist and talk to my will, as long as my pocket will not be three hundred thousand scars.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_take_disk">
		<text>Adrenalin gave me information about one of the exits from the ATP and asks you to bring him to drive for the company, which carried him to one of the stalkers. You can, of course, drive, and do not look for it. I did, after all, and so knew where the exit from the territory ... Adrenalin had no choice as to tell me about it before setting. Otherwise, as I got out? But the conscience I still have. So I'll try to do the job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_atp_way_kordon_text">
		<text>Adrenalin gave me information about one of the exits from the ATP. Go to the Cordon, presumably, is on these stones.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_atp_way_military_text">
		<text>I got information about another outlet with the ATP, the army warehouses. It is somewhere in this corner of the roof. On the third passage knows Sakharov. We must see him, until the bullet is not words ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_take_sumka">
		<text>Yes, but the professor is not very much appreciative of other people's lives ... Because of the bags in this ass posted ... Well, that at least a rough determination of a mobile observation point gave the military. It's somewhere in the Chernobyl-NPP1, near the entrance to the sarcophagus ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_atp_way_pripyt_text">
		<text>I have information on the last, and it seems very proper transition from the ATP - in Pripyat. Judging by this picture, it is necessary to explore this part of the destroyed roof.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_take_arhara_doctor">
		<text>I need to find the lost locket for the Marsh Doctor. It is located in a backpack on the roof of one of the skyscrapers of Pripyat. I can not imagine how I will climbe on the roofs of these ... But the Doc hinted about the possibility of passage for high-rise with the ATP.</text><!-- Changed ‘Bolotny Doctor' to ‘Marsh Doctor '- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="enc_artmod_gusenica_text">
		<text>Sakharov sold recipe Artefact Modification: From a Controller's bezoar in a Burner anomaly can come a Plasma Caterpillar artefact. Transform time of five minutes, the probability of a successful outcome of the transformation 75%</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_pripyt_way_atp_text">
		<text>I have information on the transition from the north at Chernobyl NPP. All Svoboda said that the label from the card could disappear due to abnormal activity at the station. Well, that though the picture is ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_lekarstvo_bandita">
		<text>We must find in the minefield, which left the road at the checkpoint at the cordon, three of the bubble with the medicine and bring them to Akim ... 'In the garden there, in the city, was running a dog' ... Here's your medicine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_vorona_povar_naiti">
		<text>What have I got? ... Steep stalker went to look for Crows Eggs for drunken chef ... We have to go to Akim and find out where these Crows sweep and collect ten eggs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_shaxter_fonarik">
		<text>Shakhtar recovery day view needs two flashlights. Do nothing, will have to find them. And the old man helped himself, and use ... Who we've got trades on the border? Sidorovich, Akim and Kuznetsov ... Take an interest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_akim_kubik">
		<text>Akim hit in childhood, a former army blew the roof ... He needs a Rubik's Cube, who threw one of the bandits on some of the roof of an unfinished building on the base of bandits in Dark Valley. Okay, I'll stay in the role of Batman a bit ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_shaxter_kniga">
		<text>I'll Have to find somewhere on the outskirts of the Forgotten Forest remains Rasstrel's people. Who, when and why did it, I do not know .. I only know that one of these accidents was the book. Minor needs this book desperately. I know also that this place is located next to two or three large stones. And collapsed helicopter there still should be ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_lysyi_klad">
		<text>Baldy decided to share his lost treasure and asked me to bring him the contents, which is in some Cave. Good luck! I have no superfluous gestures learned where to locate the entrance to the cave! That is, only ... Is there this Shakhtar? Or was the cave... a dream? Need to know. Or maybe a treasure I will find.. coins of gold ...\nI should see if the Miner knows anything about it.</text><!-- Changed 'Bald' to 'Baldy'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="tex_arx_strelok">
		<text>Miner needs a 'Controller Scalp' artefact. Otherwise, he will not give me the PDA...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_take_zombie">
		<text>In ... Has not yet managed to escape from the cordon, and have already found ten hands of zombies ... I do not even know where they are found, look like ... Here is the news ... In the Zone is a zombie?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_take_doc1">
		<text>Akim needs some old document. 'In the Dump, on top of something...' he said. A building? A bus? A container? Where the hell do I start?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_take_doc2"><!-- It's Agroprom underground! - aleks1970 -->
		<text>Well .. I knew it ... Now we must bring more to Akim and the second part of documents that are somewhere in the subway Institute ... It is easier for a needle in a haystack to find.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_take_doc3">
		<text>Akim needs a third document from X-18. However, this one has been separated into four sections! He says that three should be inside the lab, and the fourth somewhere outside near the lab's entrance...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_take_doc4">
		<text>Hired a courier's delivery ... I need to get: SCAT-10, the Exoskeleton of stalkers, bandits Exoskeleton, Academic Duty PSZ-9MD. And it's - there's more! We still have to find the PDA and document. The document is located somewhere in the X-16 and the PDA in the area of the crane, which stands at the base of an unfinished building of the bandit's base in Dark Valley. 'Short and sweet' ... Easier to get to Monolith, what does all this get.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_take_doc5">
		<text>To do this, my 'geeky-biologist' friend needs one of each mutant part... What the hell is he is going to do with them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_take_qeast">
		<text>Crest took fifteen arts. Five pieces of each kind: 'Medusa', 'Stone Flower', 'Fireball'. Better just to find the balls, and then the 'Medusa' and 'Flower' to keep radiation down. Well, that Crest did not take as many 'Controller Scalps' ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_take_qeast_bizon">
		<text>Must locate six anomalous 'Bison' for Crest. They have not only military. Caught and Bandos, Vigilante, and Monolith. We'll have to hunt ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_take_teleporter">
		<text>The job is not easy, though nearby, in the forest ... Focusing is extremely insufficient. We need to find a downed chopper, and next to it, a bunch of stones in which the military could stay the night with teleporters in your pocket.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_petrenko_flyga">
		<text>We must ask lanky in Bar, where flasks for Petrenko are. I hope that this gold-plated bottle - the only such expensive for Petrenko, that he has lost in this life.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_dolgovyzui">
		<text>In wrong price, intellectual ... Ten chips have warriors in the cordon to find five 'quirks' to bring, and yes even fifty thousand scars riprap ... Send to himself in the night travel on the Zone, arrange on a regular basis, every five minutes ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_voronin_termos">
		<text>For people who want Voronin thermoses. And different, big and small. Five pieces of each volume. I roughly know where there are large, since there is a picture of their location. They are somewhere near a tree, outside the base of Freedom. To get there, we should go along the power transmission lines. But, the little flasks should learn from Garik, a security guard for bartender.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_garik_vopros">
		<text>For information about small thermos Garik requires ten packs of cigarettes and twenty thousand roubles ... Robust design for a redneck who I'd just stupidly present in the bar. The same to me, the bodyguard ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_petr_sidor">
		<text>Sidorovich offended, and now a present from Petrenko he just did not beg. And sorry to kill him, he suddenly has come in handy? Therefore, I need to bring the two repair kits, each of which includes a hammer, screwdriver and wrench. Hammers and screwdrivers you can get in the ATP, but the keys have to whistle for Screw in his studio.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_voronin_stol">
		<text>We need to find based on the Hog secret room and pick up from her computer with an antenna and videorecorder. All this equipment must be delivered to Voronin.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_sahar_ekolog">
		<text>Well, my e ... Just dragged ... and here ... One environmentalist pulled, will now have two to carry. Hopefully, they will cooperate ... We have to go to move to Rostok and meet these two nerds. Then hold them in a bunker Sakharov. The handles and news? Or a white stick? Well, at least if they die, pick up one phone and bring to Sakharov. Yes, we must not forget. Themselves environmentalists silo door will not open - their hands were busy. We must open the door and wait until they come.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_voronin_infa">
		<text>We must get 'OTS-14 Groza for defense outpost 'debt'. After the report from Voronin. Basically, he's right. Good gun in the upcoming dust-did not interfere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_naemn_shturm">
		<text>Vigorous loaf ... Come on business and got involved ... It is necessary to help repel the attack of mercenaries on a checkpoint of Duty, that on the border with Wilderness territory and destroy their leader, nicknamed Hump. This must be done for me personally, not someone from the Dolg... otherwise Voronin will not communicate with me ... I wonder how he knows about it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_kalinin_atp">
		<text>Well, things ... Not only to me their concerns, so more were added. It is necessary to repel the bandits, and then find and neutralize their leader, nicknamed Shnyrov. He should be in the ATP. Yes, still have to look after Kalinin - in short a stray bullet, and all my efforts were in vain. In addition to awards for the job, I feel the spinal cord, Kalinin, I still need it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_gonets_atp">
		<text>Must meet the messenger who carries Kalinin information. He goes straight from the end of the road leading from ATP (the road the other side of ATP, if you look out from where I went to the ATP) and may die. Then the info and awards I have not seen ... Kalinin advises to use for speed a UAZ.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_kalinin_btr">
		<text>Kalinin is preparing for an attack on his camp from a group of special forces and two armored vehicles. He's asked me to bring him an Iglomet sniper rifle, his weapon of choice for this scenario...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_btr_ataka">
		<text>My goal, personally destroy two APC and commander of the military ... Well, screw yourself! Found the destroyer of technology ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ways_info_way_arhara_peshera_cvalka_text">
		<text>Miner gave information about where the transition to a landfill. It is located on the lower level of the caves. There is a mark on my PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ways_info_way_arhara_peshera_agro_text">
		<text>Shakhtar uploaded information on the transition from a cave to Agroprom. It is located next to the anomalies at the entrance to the Miner camp.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ways_info_way_arhara_cvalka_peshera_text">
		<text>Baldy at the bar said the transition from the dump to the cave, which is located in an abandoned railway tunnel.</text><!-- Changed 'Bald' to 'Baldy'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_agro_peshera_text">
		<text>Baldy in the bar gave a tip about the transition from the Agricultural industry to the cave, which is literally in a railway tunnel</text><!-- Changed 'Bald' to 'Baldy'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_td_les_text">
		<text>Kalinin gave a tip to the transition from the Dark Valley to the Forgotten Forest. Come in handy in any ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_peshera_labirint_text">
		<text>Miner gave information about the transition from a cave to the Labyrinth. He is in a place crash in the cave. It's in the hall, which can be accessed through a narrow shaft, rising on a steep wall on the lower level caves.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_labirint_peshera_text">
		<text>It's good that the prisoner survived. He gave a tip to the transition of the Labyrinth of the cave. The transition is located on the lower level, in one of the caves near the entrance to the second cave of the Labyrinth.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_labirint_yantar_text">
		<text>Fima Coal, a former prisoner Monolith, gave a tip to the transition of the Labyrinth at Yantar. The transition is at the top of the Labyrinth.</text><!-- Changed 'Coal Fima' to 'Fima Coal'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_labirint_earth_text">
		<text>Miner told to move out of the maze on Reconoitered Earth, which said Fima Coal. The transition is at the top of the Labyrinth.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_yantar_labirint_text">
		<text>Adrenalin suggested that there is a transition to Yantar in the Labyrinth, and noted it on the map in my PDA.</text><!-- Changed 'Crank' to 'Adrenalin'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_atp_pripyat_text">
		<text>Sakharov as a reward for the bag said the transition from ATP to Pripyat. With a broken roof ridge on the ATP - the roof of Skyscraper on the Pripyat River.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_atp_military_text">
		<text>Adrenalin gave me information on the transition from ATP to Army Warehouses.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_atp_kordon_text">
		<text>Adrenalin gave me information about the transition from ATP to the Cordon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_atp_svalka_text">
		<text>Kalinin gave me a tip on the trail from the ATP landfill, said it started in my PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_military_earth_text">
		<text>The old man shared the trail from the Army Warehouses to the RECON.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_td_earth_text">
		<text>The old man spoke about the transition from the Dark Valley to the RECON. Find it on the PDA map is not difficult.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_svalka_earth_text">
		<text>Cyclops gave a tip to the transition from the Garbage to the RECON. Useful trail!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_earth_labirint_text">
		<text>Cyclops said about the transition from the RECON to the Labyrinth. The transition is located right in the cave of the Infirmary.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_radar_warlab_text">
		<text>Fang gave information about the transition from the radar to a military lab. It is located in one of the doors on the second floor of a small tank that is located near the crossroads at Pripyat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_warlab_brainlab_text">
		<text>Here's more information on the Fang. On the transition from a military lab to the Laboratory X-16. Apparently, all underground utilities are connected by tunnels that allows you to move quickly underground.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_warlab_skladu_text">
		<text>Bodyguard Panthers announced the transition from a military lab in Army Warehouses, right on the base of Freedom. The transition mentioned in my PDA. Very useful information, by the way ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_x18_warlab_text">
		<text>Maples said that all the underground laboratories of the Zone were connected. One of them he knows that leads from the ground-floor of X-18 to a military lab. In my PDA is a marker.</text><!-- Changed 'Maple' to 'Maples'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_kordon_boloto_text">
		<text>Fanatic threw coordinates of a transition to the Swamps. The transition is located somewhere near the fence-nets for camping novices not far from Sidorovich's bunker.</text><!-- Changed 'Fan' to 'Fanatic'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_radar_forest_text">
		<text>Fang told me at the Bar that he had another scout, Pilgrim, who found a trail to the Red Forest. The transition is marked on the Radar and in my PDA. Just became known passage from Army Warehouses to Limansk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_chaes2_atp_text">
		<text>Senior at the roadblock on the base of 'Freedom' gave a tip to the transition from the North of Chernobyl NPP to the ATP.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_pripyt_village_text">
		<text>Fang uploaded coordinates for the transition from the Pripyat River to the old village. Mark appears on the PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_village_limansk_text">
		<text>Kolmogor spoke about the transition from the Old Village in Limansk. There is a marker on the PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_village_hospital_text">
		<text>Kolmogor told about yet another transition. From the Old Village to the Hospital.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_chaes_generator_text">
		<text>Ghost knows where the transition from the South of Chernobyl NPP to the Generators. It starts at the gate, next to the mobile military communications post at the station.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_hospital_agroprom_text">
		<text>Black Doctor opened a short trail from the Hospital to the Agroprom. It begins near the stairs in the far tail of the third Hospital section and is marked on my PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_agroprom_marsh1_text">
		<text>The cache contained part of a card with a picture and the coordinates of the transition from the Agricultural Industry in the swamp. Just pointed out that the passage opens in the radioactive zone. Better bring a couple of Antirads or Vodka.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_bar_atp_text">
		<text>Adrenalin spoke about the transition from the Bar to the ATP. There is also a mark on my PDA. Finding it may not be easy.</text><!-- Changed 'Crank' to 'Adrenalin'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_gener_pripyat_text">
		<text>Ghost has discovered a trail to the Generators from Pripyat. It begins near the village of stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_chaes2_chaes_text">
		<text>The note from Strelok has information about extra transition from North to South Chernobyl. I copied the coordinates into your PDA</text><!-- Changed 'Arrow ' to 'Strelok '- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_gener_hospital_text">
		<text>Countryman suggested the trail to the Generators in the Hospital. It is located near the barrier on the old Betonka.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_warlab_generators_text">
		<text>In his notebook, is the code for the door, were the coordinates of the transition from the military laboratories to Generators.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_limansk_generators_text">
		<text>Semetsky suggested the trail from Limansk to Generators. It begins near the construction site and leads through a door in a barn in an underground tunnel.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_forest_warlab_text">
		<text>The note by the representative of a dead clan 'Last Day' were the coordinates of the transition from Red Forest in the military laboratories. The trail begins in the cave on a hillside near an abandoned tank.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_dcity_limansk_text">
		<text>With the activation of unknown device found in the cache to unlock trail from the Dead Cities to Limansk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_dead_city_atp_text">
		<text>With the activation of unknown device found in the cache to unlock trail of the Dead City to the ATP. There is a marker on the PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_dcity_rostok_text">
		<text>With the activation of unknown device found in the cache to unlock trail of the Dead City to the Wild Territory. There is a marker on the PDA about this transition.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_atp_dead_city_text">
		<text>With the activation of unknown device found in the cache to unlock trail with the ATP to the Dead City. There is a marker on the PDA about this transition.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_dcity_zaton_text">
		<text>The coordinates of the note Sparks managed to find one unlocked entrance to Backwater. There is a secret passage from the Dead city's Creek ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_arhara_lima_dcity_text">
		<text>To activate the portal in Limansk ... It turned out that he is not in the third dimension, as in Dead City ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_way_bar_wild_territory_text">
		<text>With the way cleared to the Wild territory I can now travel to X-16, a lab somewhere near the Yantar Scientific Outpost ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_shax_plennik">
		<text>My task is to release a prisoner from a Monolith jail. The code to the door is in a notebook at the clock, it is necessary to bring along this notebook. Hopefully, the immortal leader of the fanatics out there at this time will not be about ... The main thing is that the prisoner survives. Only he knows the way back from the Labyrinth.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_artmod_globus_text">
		<text>Miner gave a recipe for artefact modification: From the artefact 'Simbion' in the Anomaly 'Jelly' for ten minutes with a probability of 75% can be obtained with the absolute name of 'Rattle'.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_fima_mulo">
		<text>We must bring Fima Coal ten scientific kits, ten bandages, two pieces of soap and artefact 'Soul'. Soap is in the basement of a house in the village of newcomers to the Cordon.</text><!-- Changed 'Fimke' to 'Fima Coal'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="tex_adr_shkatulka">
		<text>Have to go again in a maze and try to find the box and safe. Box, if found, must bring to Adrenalin. It is located on the second level of the Labyrinth, and you can get there via the teleporter, which is located somewhere on the lower level ... I know where the entrance to the lower cave is, close to the transition to the Miner. Now I can go to the Labyrinth and Yantar ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_tretiy_kod">
		<text>That is, bad luck ... First you need to prepare. Get two artefacts - 'rattle' and 'Plasma Caterpillars'. And then go to Sidorovich and, if lucky, join the group of fanatics. If I have vis armor - well. And if not, you will have to 'walk the gardens.' All around are enemies ... In the Labyrinth we must try to find Shadows of Monolith' missing code from the door, find a safe, again to take to Sidorovich, change the group and then bring safe to Miner. For memory, the first two codes are - 434018 and 206018.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_sidor_amulet">
		<text>We need to find a maze, and bring Sidorovich for the use of the Monolith Amulet: two repair boxes, which are at Monolith, as well as to return the Amulet. Where are these boxes, do not know ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_otshelnik_yzik">
		<text>We must ask one of the pilots on from the collision, where they dropped from the helicopter the box with the weapon. Then find the box and bring it to Hermit. It's simple.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_ginekolog_lekarstvo">
		<text>We must learn from the Cyclops, where to get medical supplies and medications to find this place. Total and business somehow, but there is one thing. You can not kill or hurt anyone ... In short, Stealth ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_jora_accumul_seif">
		<text>We must learn from the old man, where you can get a couple of batteries to open the second door safe. Find them and bring to Jora-Anomaly</text><!-- Changed ‘Zhorka' to ‘Jora-Anomaly'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="tex_starik_zadanie">
		<text>Have to go to the Hermit for information, then find the Fiery cave and try to take out the batteries for Jora. Find watches for elders. We need to find both the entrance to the cave and try to get inside.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_piligrim_britva">
		<text>Hence, so ... We need to find a cache for Pilgrim. It is located somewhere behind the old cabins near the right of the trail leading to the caves. Bring him all that is in the backpack. However, there is a problem. The trail has been made base for snipers, and Pilgrim asked not to make noise and get the job done without unnecessary killings. He does not want punitive responses from the snipers. If you detected... then to the order will have to make more, and seventy thousand. Otherwise, the conversation with the Pilgrim will not happen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_otsh_pda">
		<text>Victor-hologram is terminal but can be treated by special medical device, the Ultra-detector. Get one, and preferably two... and bring to Adrenalin. In addition, Adrenalin will give me the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_golo_detektor">
		<text>Like, an honest deal. I need to get the two elite detectors and artefact 'Plasma Caterpillar'. A Victor-hologram gives a tip on location of the Ultra-detector and other useful swag.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_medik_pribor_1">
		<text>We must learn from the Cyclops, where now there is a floppy disk with the drawings. Find it and bring to the Gynecologist. In short, again, something like, Go, fetch ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_akkum_and_mikposx">
		<text>Well, that one should not be dragged anywhere. Everything here is close. We must find the key to eliminating one of the teleports. Penetrate into the Fiery cavern and see what was on the base. We need to find two power supplies for Svoboda Exoskeleton and chip control (or something like that). And bring it all to the Gynecologist ... So much time here to drag ... Why, one wonders? Got another strange SMS from some colliding, which in the course of an old map ... Wonderful ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_chimaera_zadan">
		<text>That is, how I lived ... To kill Sidorovich, but still bring his head to Chimera as proof. Otherwise, I do not get reagents for Perfuzor. Go to the Gynecologist, something must come up with ...</text><!-- Changed ‘Shura' to ‘Gynecologist '- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="tex_land_oxot">
		<text>We must go to the Rusty Timber, there is one of the rocks that are located around the perimeter of the forest to find the corpse of the Controller and drag it Filin. On payment by the Hunters while no mention was. But, obviously, for nothing they do will not be stuffed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_ginek_vlip">
		<text>Need to talk to a hunter named Owl. It should help make a Scarecrow Head of Sidorovich. Then give the head to Chimera, find the bulb with solutions for Perfuzor and bring the full flask to Gynecologist.</text><!-- Changed ‘Shura' to ‘Gynecologist '- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="tex_vuxod_atp">
		<text>For information on the transition from ATP Kalinin asks you to bring him three of the artefact. 'Glassbeads', 'Moonlight' and 'Flash'. All this can be gathered up in the ATP. Damn, I wonder.. rushed here without talking with stalkers of withdrawal ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_kluk_vstrecha">
		<text>We must explore new territory and find out who lives there and is doing what. The main goal - to find out whether there is the kidnapped daughter of one of the leaders of the 'O-consciousness' there. Then it is necessary to share information with Fang and Pilgrim.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_lukash_pechatka">
		<text>We must stomp on the Radar, to locate there a Monolith called Spider and take the Signet Ring from him. According to Lucas, Spider is at the old bunker beyond the first corner from the main road, before the turn to Pripyat. Once you have it then the Mercenaries will think your one of them and let you enter. Of course we need to return the Signet to Lukash to get the reward... but not before visiting Fang in the Bar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_body_pantera">
		<text>It's not urgent, but the person will pay for his kindness should be, although it is a Mercenary. Job is - to whistle from the headquarters base Lukash Svoboda at Army Warehouses a stuffed Pseudodog and bring it to Panthers. It is better to kill two birds with one stone: to wait for the next job on the Panthers Army Warehouses, and when performing it, take to Scarecrow.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_pantera_fone">
		<text>I have less than fifteen minutes to find the premises of a military lab station for the Mercenary Panthers. It is known that the portable radio is in a backpack, a backpack found in the laboratory. But not on its lower levels. We must remember that backpacks may be several. We'll have to hurry. Now the reputation among the Mercenaries to me is very important.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_pant_zadan">
		<text>Arrive at a fixed point on the bridge and wait in the direction of the checkpoint pops a messenger. You must pick up the disc, but you can not kill the messenger himself. We have to act in another way ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_p_z_tri">
		<text>I feel one place that I still need this mercenary. And she herself - nothing simple... The main thing is not screw around at this time. It is necessary to steal from Oruzheyka Lukash's backpack, well, or its contents. Yes, we must not forget about Scarecrow's Pseudodog for the bodyguard. Task is simplified by the fact that the Panthers gave me map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_gologr">
		<text>Must accompany the hologram on the Reconoitered Earth before entering the Army Warehouses. Further, he knows the way and gets himself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_klenov_gol">
		<text>Have to go to the Hologram, to try to persuade him to return to Maples. In case of success, obviously, and to accompany ... However ...</text><!-- Changed 'Klenow' to 'Maples'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="tex_klenov_vse">
		<text>There is a chance to get an artificial artefact of 'Heart of Poltergeist.' You must bring to Maples: 'Heart Poltergeist' and ten 'Cobblestones'.</text><!-- Changed 'Klenow' to 'Maples'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="tex_vitamin_reyd">
		<text>To get a present from Lucas and the key to a teleport in a military lab, I have to help the group to commit mop-up march on the Radar to the entrance to the military laboratory. Or rather, to show them an open road. With a group I meet on the Radar at the entrance to the Army Warehouses.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_esc_razvod">
		<text>Sidorovich sent text messages and requests to pay with a Stalker, that in a small house near the ruins opposite the farm. That is, give him 70,000! However, the merchant promises to give a percentage for the service.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_za_bablom">
		<text>It is done. We have to go to Sidoravich and get back the money and interest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_kolmogor_say">
		<text>Kolmogor's looking for his brother. There is evidence that punishers took him along with a group of prisoner Stalkers toward an abandoned store. Need help Kolmogor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_sestra_start">
		<text>We need to find her sister Kolmogor. Incredible, but it seems that this Panther. We must find her and find out everything. However, I have long been of it has not received news. Generally not known whether she is alive. There is only one way to learn to send text messages and wait for a response. If the Panthers and sister Kolmogor, anyway, it should lead to the village.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_village_shtab">
		<text>We must help the group to capture the headquarters of the Kolmogor punishers in the Village. All the military is to clean up, and there should be only not numerous guards. The headquarters is situated on a hill in the central house. If the capture succeeds, after talks with Kolmogor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_kolm_obsledov">
		<text>Kolmogor asked to bring Pilgrim and explore the village. It is necessary to determine whether remains there punishers. After the reconnaissance, I need to talk to Kolmogor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_derevny_zashita">
		<text>Need help stalkers to repel the attack squad, returning with a stripper on helicopters. After the successful outcome of the bout to talk to Kolmogor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_klenov_antena">
		<text>Maples can not complete the experiment in a new generator for the artefacts. He needs a Psychiatric Mobile Antenna, the signal which comes from the Cordon. Who set it there? For what purpose? I am a complete layman in physics, higher mathematics and other tricks, so it is unclear how this Hallucinogenic Antenna can help him. However, the label on the PDA, and we should go. Something he mentioned about the mutants? Hmm ...</text><!-- Changed 'Maple' to 'Maples'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="tex_boloto_provod">
		<text>Connoisseur Bolot requests that I reconnoiter the situation on the old farm. He needs to bring the two Zombie Embryos, who hid in one of three caches on this farm. This is his first condition for a tip on the transition from the Swamp to the old village via the Wasted Woodlands. Have to make this work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flesh_cocoon_item">
		<text>Flesh Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flesh_cocoon_item_s">
		<text>Flesh Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flesh_cocoon_description">
		<text>The Embryo of the Flesh. When leaving, the Cocoon immediately reaches adult size by mutated cells of the body, capable to performing billions of divisions a second. Dangerous!. Activated by impact (throw on the ground). Time after the activation before the appearance of an adult organism: within ten to fifteen seconds. Edible, satisfies hunger, a little healing and accelerates wound healing. The recommended distance to the center of activation - not less than ten meters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tushkano_cocoon_item">
		<text>Mutated Rat Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tushkano_cocoon_item_s">
		<text>Mutated Rat Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tushkano_cocoon_description">
		<text>Tushkano Cocoon. Contains up to five embryos. Growth to the state of adult Tushkana - instant. Activated by impact (throw on the ground). Time after the activation before the appearance of an adult organism within ten to fifteen seconds. Edible, satisfies hunger, a little healing and accelerates wound healing. The recommended distance to the center of activation - no less than seven meters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gigant_cocoon_item">
		<text>Pseudogiant Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gigant_cocoon_item_s">
		<text>Pseudogiant Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gigant_cocoon_description">
		<text>Pseudogiant Embryo. Extremely rare. Maturation of the cocoon before activating up to several months. Growth after activation by the accumulated potential is divided by the body's cells, instantly. Is simply an increase in cell size rather than their quantity. Activated by impact (throw on the ground). Time after the activation before the appearance of an adult organism: within ten to fifteen seconds. Edible, satisfies hunger, a little bit healing and accelerates wound healing. The recommended distance to the center of the activation of at least fifteen feet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="poltergeist_cocoon_item">
		<text>Poltergeist Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="poltergeist_cocoon_item_s">
		<text>Poltergeist Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="poltergeist_cocoon_description">
		<text>Poltergeist Embryo. Extremely rare. Necessary for the maturation of the cocoon darkness. Sunlight duration of maturation multiplied. Growth after activation - instant. Activated by impact (throw on the ground). Time after the activation before the appearance of an adult organism: within ten to fifteen seconds. Edible, satisfies hunger, a little bit healing and accelerates wound healing. The recommended distance to the center of the activation of at least twelve feet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="controller_cocoon_item">
		<text>Controller Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="controller_cocoon_item_s">
		<text>Controller Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="controller_cocoon_description">
		<text>The Embryo of the Controller. Insanely rare, since such a method of 'breeding' is not typical for this type of mutants. Able to reproduce only Mother Controllers. In vivo activation produces a parent myself with the help of telepathy. Growth mechanism when activated - is unknown. Growth after activation - instant. Activated by impact (throw on the ground). Time after the activation before the appearance of an adult organism: within ten to fifteen seconds. The recommended distance to the center of the activation of at least twenty-five meters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chimera_cocoon_item">
		<text>Chimera Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chimera_cocoon_item_s">
		<text>Chimera Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chimera_cocoon_description">
		<text>Chimera Embryo. Is unknown, but it seems that the cocoon is already mature individual who has become dormant. Growth after activation - instant. After activation - extremely aggressive and dangerous. Activated by impact (throw on the ground). Time after the activation before the appearance of an adult organism: within ten to fifteen seconds. Edible, fully satisfies hunger, instantly restores health and heals wounds. The recommended distance to the center of the activation of at least twenty-five meters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cat_cocoon_item">
		<text>Feral Cat Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cat_cocoon_item_s">
		<text>Feral Cat Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cat_cocoon_description">
		<text>Embryo of a Feral Cat. Remains a mystery of his immediate increase after activation. Argued that the reason for the rapid maturation of a food parents. And that, basically, Radioactive rats. Usually occurs the birth of two individuals. Growth after activation - instant. Activated by impact (throw on the ground). Time after the activation before the appearance of an adult organism: within ten to fifteen seconds. Edible, satisfies hunger, a little healing and accelerates wound healing. The recommended distance to the center of the activation of at least ten meters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="boar_cocoon_item">
		<text>Boar Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="boar_cocoon_item_s">
		<text>Boar Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="boar_cocoon_description">
		<text>The embryo of a Wild Boar. Infrequent, since it is not the main way of breeding boars. Instantaneous growth following activation is achieved by a sharp increase in air 'layers' in muscle tissue, which, as animal food, replaced the normal fat and muscle tissue. Growth after activation - instant. Activated by impact (throw on the ground). Time after the activation before the appearance of an adult organism within ten to fifteen seconds. Edible, satisfies hunger, a little healing and accelerates wound healing. The recommended distance to the center of the activation of at least fifteen feet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dog_cocoon_item">
		<text>Chernobyl Dog Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dog_cocoon_item_s">
		<text>Chernobyl Dog Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dog_cocoon_description">
		<text>Embryo of the Chernobyl Blind Dog. One species of breeding flocks, reaching more than ten goals. The reason for the growth of instant - instant hypertrophy of the cells under the influence of light energy. Usually comes up to three individuals. Activated by impact (throw on the ground). Time after the activation before the appearance of an adult organism: within ten to fifteen seconds. Edible, satisfies hunger, a little healing and accelerates wound healing. The recommended distance to the center of the activation of at least twelve feet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="psydog_cocoon_item">
		<text>Psi-dog Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="psydog_cocoon_item_s">
		<text>Psi-dog Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="psydog_cocoon_description">
		<text>Psi-dog Embryo. Information about the occurrence of such Embryos, however as the nature of the Psi-dog remains a mystery. Activated by impact (throw on the ground). Time after the activation before the appearance of an adult organism: within ten to fifteen seconds. Growth after activation - instant. Toxic, reduces the health and speed healing of wounds, though, and relieves hunger. The recommended distance to the center of the activation of at least fifteen feet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="psevdodog_cocoon_item">
		<text>Chernobyl Pseudodog Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="psevdodog_cocoon_item_s">
		<text>Chernobyl Pseudodog Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="psevdodog_cocoon_description">
		<text>Chernobyl Pseudodog Embryo. One species of breeding flocks, reaching more than ten goals. The reason for the growth of instant - instant hypertrophy of the cells under the influence of light energy. Is born, usually two individuals. Activated by impact (throw on the ground). Time after the activation before the appearance of an adult organism: within ten to fifteen seconds. Edible, satisfies hunger, a little healing and accelerates wound healing. The recommended distance to the center of the activation of at least twelve feet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krovosos_cocoon_item">
		<text>Bloodsucker Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krovosos_cocoon_item_s">
		<text>Bloodsucker Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krovosos_cocoon_description">
		<text>Bloodsucker Embryo. For this type of reproduction can only individual, long-term feeding on the blood of Chimeras and Pseudogiant. A rare find. The mechanism of instantaneous growth, probably due to a combination of options for the growth of Embryos for Chimeras and Pseudogiants. Extremely dangerous!. Activated by impact (throw on the ground). Time after the activation before the appearance of an adult organism: within ten to fifteen seconds. Edible, satisfies hunger, little treats and accelerates the healing of wounds, lightly displays radiation. The recommended distance to the center of the activation of at least twenty-five meters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="burer_cocoon_item">
		<text>Burer Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="burer_cocoon_item_s">
		<text>Burer Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="burer_cocoon_description">
		<text>Burer Embryo. Rumor has it that this is not the Embryo, but the lure for people who invented themselves a Burer. Probably takes place only apparent activation, and adult Burer teleported to the right place, if the danger to her by the victim is minimal. Very rare find. Chance of teleporting adult when activated - does not exceed 25-50% of the day - a chance to teleport even lower. Activated by impact (throw on the ground). Time after the activation before the appearance of an adult organism: within ten to fifteen seconds. Edible, satisfies hunger, a little healing and accelerates wound healing. The recommended distance to the center of the activation of at least twenty-five meters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zombie_cocoon_item">
		<text>Zombie Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zombie_cocoon_item_s">
		<text>Zombie Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zombie_cocoon_description">
		<text>Zombie Embryo. This is probably one of the baits made by scientists from the 'On-consciousness' militants for the Monolith, with a view to eliminating fear and making the ranks of the Stalkers and other interested persons, tending to the Zone center. Cocoon in this case is a smart teleport. This is probably the test specimens teleport containing tissue. Activated by impact (throw on the ground). Time after the activation before the appearance of an adult organism: within ten to fifteen seconds. Rotten meat! .. poison Zombie. The recommended distance to the center of the activation of at least fifteen feet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="snork_cocoon_item">
		<text>Snork Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="snork_cocoon_item_s">
		<text>Snork Embryo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="snork_cocoon_description">
		<text>Snork Embryo. Complete mystery to scientists. It defies any explanation of the emergence from the Cocoon an adult Snork in the clothing and mask. Probably the cocoon is formed in contact with the mutant in some sort of anomaly, which results in the packaging of the living creatures to the size and weight of the cocoon. Activated by impact (throw on the ground). Time after the activation before the appearance of an adult organism: within ten to fifteen seconds. Stinky meat.. Snork toxic. The recommended distance to the center of the activation of at least fifteen feet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_kapitan_pda">
		<text>Military Captain's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_kapitan_pda_s">
		<text>Captain's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_kapitan_pda_descr">
		<text>Captain Midges' PDA. Unfortunately, the Antenna is damaged. As a phone use it is already impossible. Among the various disk imaging is a record of recent communications. After forty seconds, it will be copied in my PDA and duplicate on the screen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pult_anders">
		<text>Sony PSP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pult_anders_s">
		<text>Sony PSP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_pult_anders_descr">
		<text>Game console with a joystick. Andersen used not only for recreation during free time. The corpus is built Coded chip to disable Psionic Antenna. Operates within a radius of about two meters from the Antenna.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_simulator1">
		<text>Simulator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_simulator1_s">
		<text>Simulator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_simulator1_descr">
		<text>-</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_simulator2">
		<text>Simulator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_simulator2_s">
		<text>Simulator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_simulator2_descr">
		<text>-</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_samop">
		<text>Flight Data Recorder</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_samop_s">
		<text>Flight Recorder</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_samopisez">
		<text>Onboard Recorder</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_samopisez_s">
		<text>Recorder</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_samopisez_descr">
		<text>A typical form of 'Black Box'. Contains records of conversations of pilots, state information systems, helicopter and crew actions.</text>
	</string>
<!-- Excluded -
	<string id="name_adj_psi_gen_1">
		<text>"Adjustable Psi-Generator 1"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="name_adj_psi_gen_2">
		<text>"Adjustable Psi-Generator 2"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="name_adj_psi_gen_3">
		<text>"Adjustable Psi-Generator 3"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="name_adj_psi_gen_4">
		<text>"Adjustable Psi-Generator 4"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="name_adj_psi_gen_5">
		<text>"Adjustable Psi-Generator 5"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="name_adj_psi_generator">
		<text>"The Generator"</text>
	</string>
-->
	<string id="item_mini_antenna">
		<text>Adjustable Psi-Generator #1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_mini_antenna_s">
		<text>Psi-Generator #1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_mini_antenna2">
		<text>Adjustable Psi-Generator #2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_mini_antenna2_s">
		<text>Psi-Generator #2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_mini_antenna3">
		<text>Adjustable Psi-Generator #3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_mini_antenna3_s">
		<text>Psi-Generator #3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_mini_antenna4">
		<text>Adjustable Psi-Generator #4</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_mini_antenna4_s">
		<text>Psi-Generator #4</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_mini_antenna5">
		<text>Adjustable Psi-Generator #5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_mini_antenna5_s">
		<text>Psi-Generator #5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_mini_antenna_descr">
		<text>The generator of electromagnetic interference. Used to block electrical and radio signals. Some specimens are provided with a display for the installation of power generator and set at a certain rate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_mini_antenna_generator">
		<text>The Generator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_mini_antenna_generator_s">
		<text>The Generator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_mini_antenna_generator_descr">
		<text>The generator of electromagnetic interference. Used to block electrical and radio signals. Some specimens are provided with a display for the installation of power generator and set at a certain rate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_zemlyk_zadanie1">
		<text>In order to get access to the basement with the scientist who ran away from the C-consciousness base, we need to locate and eliminate a chopper which is flying around the northern area of the Generators. This chopper is flying high and scanning the area for the lost scientist.\nWhen you locate the helicopter, fire at the chopper with a high calibre weapon to attract it's attention, then when it flies in closer to take a better look, shoot it down. When the chopper is damaged, report back to the Countryman to get access to the basement.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_black_dok_gener">
		<text>Find Ghost, the former Trader of the village in the Generators vicinity. He is bound to a way into the c-consciousness base, and can scout if Panther is being held there.\nHe was last time seen wandering very drunk through the northeren area's of the Swamps. It's most likely he has taken shelter somewhere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_udav_poshli">
		<text>One of the Black Doctor's men will fly a helicopter to the cemetary in the Swamps, to pick up you and Ghost. Travel towards the Cemetary, and make sure Ghost survives. When you get close to the cemetary, the helicopter will make contact with you and give you you're next orders.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_ander_joystik">
		<text>In order to turn off the Psi-Antenna's surrounding the c-consciousness base, Anderson needs his Joystick back which he programmed to edit the software inside the Psi-Antenna's. The only problem is, he didn't know where he lost his Joystick. The only thing he knows is he lost it somewhere during a routine check in the Generators vicinity. He also sent us a picture with the route he walked that day. Locate the Joystick and bring it back to Anderson for further instructions.\nHint: The joystick gives off a red light as long as the batteries are still intact, so searching for this small device would be alot easier at night, except maybe for the Mutants roaming around under the cover of darkness.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_udav_pabota">
		<text>Guide Ghost towards the edge of the Psi-Field and wait for him to deactivate all the Antenna's. For the Psi-Field to lower to safe point of Psi-Emission we need to wait a bit.\nWait for Ghost to get back to the edge of the Psi-Field, in order to not cause suspicion he will walk towards another point more west of your location.\nTalk to him there to find out if he has seen Panther, or any other suspicous activity in the base, and report back to Ghost. Wait for the Psi-Emission to lower to a safe level.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_priz_shturm">
		<text>Capture the base by force, and be very quick. The faster the base is under control, the more chance we have that Panther is still alive.\nFritz and the Black Doctor's men will attack through the western side, where there's a hole in the wall. Together with Ghost we will attack through the main gate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_black_vstrecha">
		<text>Meet with one of the Black Doctor's messengers, up north near the transistion to the Hospital.\nHe should have a Dossier with all the info that the Black Doctor knows about the Astrologer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_peshera_nz">
		<text>Find the secret cave in the Reconnoitered Earth, but do not go into the cave, we don't know what to expect down there.\nThe teleport deactivator we found in the c-consciousness base, indicates that a teleport is blocking the entry, it will deactivate later.\nAs soon as you have found the cave, report to Fang who is residing in the Fiery Cave.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_kl_na_walk">
		<text>Klemenov has some news regarding the experiments with the Heart of the Poltergeist artefact, go towards Warlab and see what has become of this Experiment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_muha_kukl">
		<text>Fly wants you to retrieve a doll that she supposedly lost while on a trip through the Zone when she was younger, she lost the doll somewhere in the Area of the Brain Scorcher, she said that it's most likely in one of the houses she took shelter in.\nRetrieve this "precious" doll, and bring it to her. After this she will hopefully tell us what happened to the artefact she claims to have seen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_voronin_samopisez">
		<text>Turns out the Helicopter with the backpack, with the Water Flower artefact in it, was shot down over the CNPP, together with two other Helicopters, during a raid.\nVoronin asked us to check up with one of these Helicopters who should still have an intact Flight Data Recorder. It is located on top of the Sarcophagus.\nWhen you find this Flight Data Recorder, report back to Voronin and see if he can learn something from the information that should be in it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_vkluchit_generator">
		<text>That had to work on the 'C-consciousness' ... True, the Panthers said it was a myth. But can you believe her? We must return to the generators, to find there, and Andersen Solvador. They will tell you what to do next. As a result, all my bodily movements must earn the third generator. Otherwise, the Fly can not be resurrected. And if this is possible at all? However, we must try. I'm indirectly responsible for her death.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_solv_say">
		<text>The Black Doctor needs a Third Generator to make enough energy to conduct more research.\nTherefore you need to disable five Psi-Field jammers located in the Sub-station next to the C-consciousness base.\nFind these jammers and bring them to Anderson. After you have done this; talk to Anderson and wait for the third generator to go online.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_kluk_ch2">
		<text>Fang will stay behind, while you go the the specified location given to you Fang.\nFang has information that the Astrologer will get to the CNPP North through the gate near this location, so keep an eye on the gate.\nIf the Astrologer appears, call Fang and fight of the Astrologers troops.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_neud_pomozch">
		<text>Fang has found the Astrologer at some other place, and has sent you to an ambush location.\nGet back to Fang as fast as possible, and help him fight off the Astrologer's troops.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- moved string id: "det_art_ultra_info", "detektor_amorf_info" and "det_art_indy_info" in to the "dmx_mod_items.xml" file -aleks1970 -->
	<string id="tex_podval_sarkofag">
		<text>To find accommodation and help Lightning, there is useful information. It is located in a sort of control center, where many corridors.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_podval_lima">
		<text>Find a house in Limansk. According to Lightning, on its roof is a teleporter, which is likely, and took advantage of her friend. We must find this man. He has a Detector Isomorphic and learn about the location of the second portal in Zamonolite.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_strannik_bloknot">
		<text>Wanderer's Notebook</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_strannik_bloknot_s">
		<text>Wanderer's Notebook</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_strannik_bloknot_descr">
		<text>In the Zone is a man who managed to reveal the mystery of the Isomorphic and use their properties. According to reports, he only sells parts to the Monolith, unaware of the consequences. Find this person is not so difficult, he has no legs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_blok_neizvestn">
		<text>Unknown STALKERs Notebook</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_blok_neizvestn_s">
		<text>Unknown STALKERs Notebook</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_blok_neizvestn_descr">
		<text>I do not know who you are. But if you're here, you should be aware of my discoveries, and can repeat my way. Take the gun. It is the only cartridge. Stand in the outlined circle or close to it. From this position most easily seen by Monolith. In fact, it is unrealistic to photograph, but I found a way. You can take a position and closer, but will the illumination of the film. Aim at the top of the Monolith. Autofocus and red mark on my radar without zoom prompts you when you aim. Then, look in the optics and do a shot of the exact coordinates. Cartridge only one, and if you miss it, get a second chance will be gone. If successful attempt, there will be photos. Take it before starting teleporter. Photo you need just to learn the code. This is the code for the portal, which lies somewhere in Limansk. What will happen next, I do not know, but you walk in my footsteps. Good luck ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_odnonog_first">
		<text>If you believe Maximilian, somewhere in the basement of the Sarcophagus is teleport. We must find it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_odnonog_foto">
		<text>If you can find the teleport, you have to use it. We should try to photograph the Monolith, and bring the photo to Maximilian.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_mesto_v_bunkere">
		<text>Looks like Fang something dug out ... One thing is clear, if he is right, without mashalata nothing to do there. We must take a stance in the bunker. Judging by the pictures, it's close to the transition to the Sarcophagus. We will wait for reviews. Fang said that the guests are invisible, unless you turn on flashlights. Then wait until they open the door to the cache. And further, under certain circumstances.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_neizv_zapiska">
		<text>Notebook containing Intel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_neizv_zapiska_s">
		<text>Notebook containing Intel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_neizv_zapiska_descr">
		<text>My best people have made verification of this camera. It seems that this is only part of a design that has an unknown energy. In addition to a kind of glow, possesses regenerate part artov ... Where to look for other parts of the structure is not known. But this piece, by itself, does not work. Corps bombs leave until the cache. They have no chief, those obscure superstrong caps ... Their dealer, one-legged neutral somewhere zapropostilsya. My people are looking for it hard. There is more good news. Managed to introduce agents to collect information and intelligence, almost all local groups. And we need to establish contact with former men of our clan. Continue to work. Otstuchi Chief, let reconsider the fees.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_radist_zhiv">
		<text>We must try to save the life of radio operator. Fang said that he, kind of like, neutral and it can provide valuable information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_taynik_radista">
		<text>According to some reports, in Pripyat, in the kindergarten have caches radio operator. Apparently, it's not a backpack, but the whole housing, where it may Maximilian spent their time between searching for artefacts that are isomorphic and trafficking. We need to find and explore the cache.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_lesnik_say">
		<text>Take a position on the roof of the Forester - the tower, to try to detect and destroy unknown sniper before he kills another stalker. Forester said that particularly need to look at the bushes, trees and other hiding places.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_forest_last_dead_listok">
		<text>Instructions</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_forest_last_dead_listok_s">
		<text>Instructions</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_forest_last_dead_listok_descr">
		<text>PDA thing is not reliable. That battery sits, it will fill with water. Memory, too, girl-shy. Therefore, we write: 'While our sniper distracts stalkers need to get to the station and take away from the local forester chas camera. This is important! After try to ingratiate themselves svobodovtsam and visit some professor or doctor to Warlab ... Mmat, napridumayut Yet these scientists currently ranks ... To our knowledge, it has an interest of our oldest thing. After the assignment - returning a dead city. And yet. In one of the caves that on a hillside, near the destroyed tank, begins transition and just in Warlab. this transition and take advantage if the first part of the plan will succeed. '</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_transmutator">
		<text>Transmutator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_transmutator_s">
		<text>Transmutator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_transmutator_descr">
		<text>Device consists of three lines of slots, and two control buttons (office - scroll and reset - do not count). In the middle range (Inv) - content inventory, the figure on top of an element means number of elements in this form (on the sides - buttons to scroll left and right). Clicking on an item in this range puts it into the top line (COMP) as a potential ingredient for cooking. Clicking on an element in Comp returns it back to Inv. The right of the comp down arrow button is used to reset the entire contents could line COMP ago Inv. In the same line of Complementary displayed in different cells.\n under the top line of a row of lemon-colored to display the name of the anomaly. If anomalies are not close (distance by less than 2m) - there is nothing displayed. If there is an anomaly, but the recipe for it to be developed - also have iformatsionnaya line.\n At the bottom line (Retz) appear prescriptions under the current anomaly in the future as a result of cooking (there are also buttons to scroll left and right). Clicking on an item in Retz is automatically filled Comp in the presence of components in inventory. If some components of the recipe is not enough - below the comp a red bar appears with the information.\n Start button starts the cooking of the selected components. If anomalies are not around - does not work.\n If the inventory is lit by a red line (ie, a recipe is, but lacks the components) - perhaps an unexpected reaction to the owner. If there is no recipe - red line in any case, nothing will - try to cook at your own risk (if not match the existing in-game recipes - the result can be placheven if guessing the recipe - start cooking, the owner transmutatora will be given a prescription). When the coincidence of the recipe ingredients and anomalies, and click Run - will start brewing process, the artefacts of the line comp automatically removed from inventory and launch signaled by flashing the screen.\n Exit button closes the user interface. The interface also closes automatically when the failure starts cooking.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_izomorf_dial">
		<text>Maples gave me isomorphic, saying that he was somehow affects the relationship with the zombie. In addition, he hinted that at Yantar someone svobodovtsev at the plant, where the entrance to the X-16 saw a strange zombie and some interesting subject. But first, the main task. We must get to the X-16 (good move there from Warlab known), and make two photos of fotopistoleta. The first photo - is the brain, which is hanging under the dome of the laboratory in a flask. Snapshot is better to do while on the upper level at the board. In this case about the right tip at the target will be a message on the display camera. Second photo - in the tunnels that lead from laboratory X-16 in Yantar. There lived a mutating controller, which is necessary for the history and photograph. Say, the brain had a sore, just for scientists. Fotopatrona all three. Hence, once can miss. After Maples include photographs, he promised to give to them something else.</text><!-- Changed 'Klenow' to 'Maples'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="item_chemodan_piyan">
		<text>Case Checking</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_chemodan_piyan_s">
		<text>Case Checking</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_chemodan_piyan_descr">
		<text>Case Reviewer. Indeed, it has dirt on some of the soldiers and commanders of divisions, convicted of bribery, drunkenness, and others, not only disciplinary offenses.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_kuzy_artmodifik">
		<text>It is necessary to bring the case to the incriminating documents Kuznetsov. Is not easy. First, we must find at least twelve bottles of vodka. Five bottles gave Kuznetsov. After this you should go to the Agriculture &amp; try not to catch the eye of the military. The approximate scheme of the route is in the image on the PDA. Find time for the complex and try to talk to him. Give him vodka, and wait for checks to guard waiting vertuhu, drink vodka. Then these can be approached. You can not kill anyone. Ahead of time, too, could not go. Have to wait for the action of alcohol on the mortal soldier's head, and then just whistle this case. If Casey did not will have to talk to the captain and find out where he his zanykal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_dovesti_muzhika">
		<text>Withdraw Chernomor from the plant. Go long enough to get to the parking lot of stalkers, that in the hollow across the road from the entrance to the plant. Black Sea should not be lost.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_klenov_opisalovo">
		<text>Instructions from Maples</text><!-- Changed 'Klenow' to 'Maples'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="item_klenov_opisalovo_s">
		<text>Instructions from Maples</text><!-- Changed 'Klenow' to 'Maples'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_klenov_opisalovo_descr">
		<text>I have the honor to inform you the following items. Time to study the subject was not enough, so we found out only the basic parameters. When photographing is emitted from the barrel of energy in the form of an impulse, which is reaching the desired object, part of it is reflected, and partially penetrates into the object itself. If the object is a living creature, he applied considerable damage and sometimes death. Part of the reflected energy is imprinted on the matrix of the camera and converted into a picture. Probably on the images to appear something more than what the normal eye can see. The energy emitted in the production of the image is contained in an airtight container, built in the body. I experimented. Make a simple camera shots of objects is not possible. Probably, the momentum can be sent only to objects that have some additional qualities or characteristics. What are these objects and how to find them - an enigma. However, judging by the pictures made you successful, it is not quite ordinary objects or living beings.\nMaples ..</text><!-- Changed 'Klenov' to 'Maples'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="tex_plot_dialog">
		<text>We'll have to climb to the dump, find the flesh, that ate stuff out of the bag a stalker, pick them up and return to the owner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_f_after_deaf">
		<text>Need to know who brought the bomb into the camp newcomers and established mines. Probably have to use your camera.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_as_ubiysa">
		<text>Find a stranger on the basis of 'Freedom' and prevent an explosion. Will have to re-use fotopushku.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_kvest_vstrecha">
		<text>Go to Reconoitered Earth. There should have a meeting of a stalker and a representative of the clan 'last day' to overhear their conversation. To do this would probably require mashalat as the distance to communicate should be small, and the people of the clan 'last day' experienced and careful. We need to find a group of stones, one of which more than others. They are located on the unexplored Earth, near the trail at the pass at the Army Warehouses. These stones do not appear on the map. Reportedly, this is where an appointment. Necessary to climb this big rock and wait ... It is extremely important not to frighten the negotiators and no one was killed. Information is most important.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_kvest_saxar_telep">
		<text>Find a cache on some tree in one of the buildings inside the perimeter of military bases in the agricultural industry, to take away from him some object and show Sakharov. As a result, the professor should give the coordinates of the teleport, which is rumored to lead somewhere in the X-16, and try to find a lab energy isomorphic. Next on the circumstances, but the laboratory must choose a living ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_planshetka2">
		<text>Cigar Box with a note inside</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_planshetka2_s">
		<text>Cigar Box with a note inside</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_planshetka2_descr">
		<text>A box of cigars under the note by an unknown: Man, I have no more opportunity to catch those isomorphic that you send. Everything that falls into the portal, the next time fall into the hands of bad people. Your only that the administration is isomorphic, in the capable hands has monstrous strength. In addition, he was able to open only one known to teleport in a dead city. But I changed the code. I'm sorry, I initially tried to kill you by sending a mutant and mine. But I see that I was tenacious, and so smart and experienced. Because send you a box with the note. This box is missing a key part of the activation of the portal in one of the basements in Limansk. If you have the correct numeric code, then perhaps we shall meet again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_planshetka">
		<text>Tablet PC</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_planshetka_s">
		<text>Tablet PC</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_planshetka_descr">
		<text>A box of cigars under the note by an unknown: Man, I have no more opportunity to catch those isomorphic that you send. Everything that falls into the portal, the next time fall into the hands of bad people. Your only that the administration is isomorphic, in the capable hands has monstrous strength. In addition, he was able to open only one known to teleport in a dead city. But I changed the code. I'm sorry, I initially tried to kill you by sending a mutant and mine. But I see that I was tenacious, and so smart and experienced. Because send you a box with the note. This box is missing a key part of the activation of the portal in one of the basements in Limansk. If you have the correct numeric code, then perhaps we shall meet again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_port_na_mg">
		<text>Find Limansk basement, which houses the teleport and try to activate it. Where goes this portal, it is not clear. Rather, there is speculation that it is to the mysterious ghost towns.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_nauch_recomend">
		<text>Recommendation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_nauch_recomend_s">
		<text>Recommendation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_nauch_recomend_descr">
		<text>So, Senior Fellow, the latest recommendations:\n On a platform above the brain should be a couple modifiers. For us - a dummy and of no interest. Further, or in conjunction with this, to be activated teleporter. Look down, along the supply cables. You'll have to jump off the platform on the cable to the teleporter. I advise you to wear all the protection you have. Next. Do not rush to the teleporter, and after passing through a cable midway, turn to tank with the brain and destroy at the time of self-healing protective field of the Brain. The right weapon you have. Then you can go to the teleporter. Destroy the shield is essential to use the teleporter. Otherwise, you will die. Two modifiers should be in your backpack. You will get to the very brain. There should be a transformation in modifiers necessary for us to break the psy-ray influence of the Brain. Further activates the teleport to take you back to the surface. '</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_starsh_say">
		<text>Will have to raise the morale of stalkers engage in robbery. We need to find the stalkers, the leading surveillance camp of bandits and place them at the right moment to commit robbery at the camp. Probably will not profit as much as, but we need to bring: twenty cans of corned beef, ten first-aid kits, five bottles of vodka, ten packs of rounds, 'Kalash' and two truncated AKMA. Question. But whether all this is in the camp of bandits? Then you have to gather and bring the survivors of stalkers to their guests.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_dci_kontrik">
		<text>It is necessary to pay a visit to this village and to protect the country Controller ... Really do not know how to defend a hostile mutant to you ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_uhod_iz_mg">
		<text>Is not easy. We must enlist the support of the Swoon ... Attempt to penetrate the security zone of the city and in the attic to find a stash of Norman, the figure he gave. Following directly from the attic to reconnoiter the situation in the area, and using any weapon, try to shoot someone from the people the last day. Most importantly, we must destroy the assistant chief of protection. He wears a green scientific kombeza environmentalists. With luck, connect with malicious and send it away ... Further, should help this Fainting with fire on the path of my departure ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equip_stco">
		<text>Global Positioning Device</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equip_stco_s">
		<text>Positioning Device</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equip_stco_descr">
		<text>System for determining the geographic coordinates, direction and true solar time. For accurate compass work to the horizontal position of the device, which is achieved by coincidence cross compass. Activating the device is in the pistol slot.\nCostav devaysa:\n1. Magnetic compass\n2. Laser Rangefinder\n3. GPS receiver\n4. Hours</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_agro_tainik_norman">
		<text>With the device, which gave Norman have the coordinates found on the Agricultural Industry input into the unknown stash and pick out another device that allows you to remove protection from transitions in the dead city, established by people from the clan 'last day'.\n Here are the coordinates:\nDolgota 1924 ^ 14 * 30 '.61\nShirota 51 ^ 30 * 55 '.64\nVysota 183m</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_spasty_doka">
		<text>Should be released Marsh Doctor who was taken hostage by people from the group 'The Last Day.' There are two options ... Perfumer was able to negotiate with the chief security officer by the name Duda ... It is located in a house with columns, which is near the area. The Doc is obviously held somewhere. If you have enough money to pay ransom, and finish the job 'peaceful' way. The Doc is released and he gets to the house of Perfumer. After it will be possible to arrange a showdown with the very group that if you disable protection center.\n The second option is also available. If money for the ransom is not enough, you can try to force release of the Doctor. But that he got to the Perfumer, it will have to change, that is, to give him time his masthalat and anomalous M-16.</text><!-- Changed ‘Bolotny Doctor' to ‘Marsh Doctor '- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="item_iskra_listok">
		<text>Spark's Note</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_iskra_listok_s">
		<text>Spark's Note</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_iskra_listok_descr">
		<text>Hello ... I knew it all end badly ... Here are the coordinates ...\nDolgota 24 ^ 14 * 28 '.00\nShirota 51 ^ 30 * 53' .47\nVysota 188m\n Do not know how you're going to define them, but that place should be reachable, a leading .. .</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tex_otkrut_seif_sadik">		<!-- 109984 -->
		<text>Open the safe but do not let the radio operator die</text>
	</string>
	<string id="local_energy_zone">		<!-- 110000 -->
		<text>Unknown Anomolous Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="map_mil_technician">	<!-- 110007 - aleks1970 -->
		<text>Military technician</text>
	</string>
	<string id="map_mil_trader">
		<text>Military trader</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
