<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.1.0 new .7.0, desolation, zep_start_entry, additional entries, tb3d_mush_arts_quest_entry, tb3d_warlab_desc, levelup2_desolation_entry -->
<!-- Names changed as commented below - Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16 -->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->
<string_table>
	<string id="tb3d_journal">
		<text>Collector Entries</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_journal_entry">
		<text>New data stored in Collector Journal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_gbar_info">
		<text>Important Note</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_collector_info">
		<text>Personal Entry</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_collector_entry">
		<text>Not sure what happened in Dead City but now I am back in Cordon. I have no idea what to do next but seem to have a sense of urgency.\nThere is still something undone here... like energy building up all around me. I need to see Sid and get the latest on what is happening in the Zone..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_zep_docs">
		<text>ZEP Documents</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zep_start_entry">
		<text>After talking to Sid I am even more concerned, I need to explore this Darkscape region and see what I can dig up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zep_sid2_entry">
		<text>Well, Sid and Tweed know each other, go figure. I have been given a sniper rifle and ammo from Sid to give to Tweed. This should help her fight off the military that keeps trying to move in there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zep_bar1_entry">
		<text>Darkscape turned up a document that may be about what the stranger is looking for. It seems that this man is a well educated scientist and is looking for something very important. It also appears that I am part of his search yet I haven't a clue why. I will follow him into the Wasted Woodland to try and discover what it is he is looking for.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_zep4_article1">
		<text>This 'AX' fellow is starting to get on my nerves! He is obviously starting to get desperate... only reason he would take such a risk.\nI need to check out the Wild Territory and see if I can find him or hopefully his corpse.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_zep4_article2">
		<text>This 'AX' fellow is starting to get on my nerves! He is obviously starting to get desperate... only reason he would take such a risk.\nI need to check out the Warehouses and see if I can find him or hopefully his corpse.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_zep2_article">
		<text>Nice to know that my PDA is not trackable unless I have communicated privately, then only to that person.\nI am also back on the trail of my Soul Cube which may be somewhere in the NPP.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_zep1_article">
		<text>Voronin is a total nut job at this point and any thing I get from him has gotta be worthless!\nI have no idea where to find these codes now, should see what Petrenko and maybe Ivantysov know..</text>	<!-- Changed 'Ivancov' to 'Ivantsov'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_zep5_article">
		<text>Petrenko said that Voronin chased 'AX' into the Wild Territory. He also described his faction patch to me: Helix over a silver cloud with a small round symbol not unlike a radiation warning sign. Who can that be? Where is he from and why the Hell is he after me..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_turret_article">
		<text>Turret guns... how did he get them and how many of those things does he have? I must be getting close and he knows it..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_karina_trade_article">
		<text>Karina has offered to trade rare items and remedies she finds in the swamps for food, she will take a certain portion of whatever I have at the time so I don't starve.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_x14_article1">
		<text>Got an SMS from a secret lab in the Northeast region of the NPP which I need to check out immediately. A scientist there is calling for help and from the sound of it I may find answers about AX!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="secret_tunnels_info">
		<text>Tunnel Teleport Activation Sequence</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_tunnels_desc">
		<text>Intel has been gathered that describes the strange portals that can be activated by dropping specific gold bars in their proper slots.\nEach bar has a code that indicates which slot it belongs to. The sequence appears to be:\nWS-6,WN-5,WS-3,WN-2,CS-6,CS-4,EN-3,CS-2,W-0,C-0,Center.\n.\nThe center slots can be identified by the large valve hanging overhead. Activation of the portals has never been done so the consequences of doing so are unknown.\n.\nInformation gathered by the AX scientific teams has produced a list of the portal targets that should be activated:\nWS6 - Marshes\nWN5 - Facility F1\nWS3 - Cordon\nWN2 - Broken Road\nES6 - Darkscape\nES4 - Black Market\nEN3 - Generators\nES2 - NPP North\nW00 - Waiting Room\nE00 - RECON</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_warlab_desc">
		<text>Barman sent a message informing me that a stranger was in the Warlab recently. I should check it out as it could be 'AX' or one of his men.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_agentax_info">
		<text>Unknown operative: Agent X, also referred to as 'AX'. His team is apperantly looking for research material and objects being worked on when the Zone first errupted.\nData collected so far indicates that he is searching for a particular person who was known to be at the NPP when it happened. He has been asking about a man with the tattoo 'S.T.A.L.K.E.R.' on his arm and is considered to be extremely ruthless in getting answers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_final_zep_info">
		<text>Trail for 'AX' has gone cold. Messages about some raid happening from the North. Vaugue information about a secret underground lab and a WORKING Alien object.\nA message from Syak in the Radar about the Cube which I need to check out immediately!\nSeems like a good time to go South and see what is happening at the bar in Rostok and maybe check on Tweed as well.</text>	<!-- Changed 'Syac' to 'Syak' - Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_contact_info">
		<text>Important Contact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_notes">
		<text>Important Notes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_tweed_entry">
		<text>Tweed is a want to be trader in the Darkscape region. She has asked me to find her lost book: 'For Women with an Adventurous Notion to Explore the Zone' by L. D. Tweed.\nIt should be somewhere around the old bar far to the Northeast.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_karina_entry">
		<text>Karina Zetraphonic is a technician hiding out in the Dead Marshes, hoping that her colleagues will return. So far she has been very helpful and is a good source for info about that region.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zep_purged_tunnel">
		<text>Well that was fun... not sure exactly what they were here for as there is nothing in the Distribution Center. I should go back and tell Karina that the tunnel is clear. Looks like I should pass through the Generators to get to the old research station where it looks like 'AX' was messing with the comm center there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_tractorist_entry">
		<text>Abandoned geek in the Broken Road area. He spoke about an attic in the old town and the possibilty there were gold bars hidden there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_informer_entry">
		<text>Informant from Rostok, now a deserter in the old Distribution Center looking for a way out through the north. Maybe they will take him in at the old bar to the Northeast, might get around to asking someone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_hunt_info">
		<text>Caesier's Treasures</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_hunt_name">
		<text>Important Note</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_treasure_hunt_entry">
		<text>Sid talked about a man that wandered the Zone collecting rare artifacts and some other items. Supposedly the man was hanging around the old red house all the time looking for something.\nSid suggested that I might search around there as he may have left something behind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_hunt0_entry">
		<text>STALKER .. once you read this .. it means that I may already be dead. This all started when I was on a job near the Radar for the Initiative. They wanted me to find a couple of 'rare' artifacts that can only be found up there. I found myself hiding for my life from those Monolith freaks. I ducked down behind some bushes, and found myself enveloped in a thick dense fog that seemed to suddenly form out of nothing. It only enveloped me for a few seconds, my Geiger counter and anomaly detector went wild, and I felt very strange .. the rest .. well, I lost consciousness... I woke up feeling fine, and somewhat rejuvenated. Some time later, I began to notice something .. I could sense nearby artifacts. And then it started .. I found the Artefracts for each order with ease. I made it to the Chernobyl NPP but I could not find the Sarcophagus. I did manage to gather a lot of rare unknown artifacts and unusual mutations of mushrooms. The Mushrooms are very interesting as these have very high levels of Caesium-137, strontium-90, barium-137, Iodine-131, tellurium and rubidium isotopes, plutonium and other heavy elements - all naturally absorbed, a characteristic of mushrooms.\n Each time I came back to the Cordon, I left well concealed caches in the areas I traveled through as well as notes with hints of other locations. With my fading health and memory I knew these cryptic clues would be needed. With each passing day, the cumulative affects of CS-134 and other radioactive isotopes are quickly bringing me to my demise. Each time I look at my reflection I am significantly older. Only a few months after that incident at the Radar, my life is at an end.\nBut lucky for you .. you found my last note. Good luck to you STALKER, in pursuit of my treasures.\n.\nSo I'm not sure if he is gone or if more treasures are out there... will need to have a look when in those areas.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_hunt1_entry">
		<text>After a difficult search I have been able to find Caesier's treasure stashes as far as the Radar.\nIt puzzles me as to why he went for so many portals! He must have been a real paranoic!\nThe trail ends abruptly here so not sure if he is gone or if more treasures are out there..\nI will keep my Eyes and Ears open for any clues during my travels.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="levelup2_desolation_entry">
		<!-- 110010, removed wharehouses, added text -->
		<text>After destroying the strange Generator in the Secret Lab, I ended up in Jupiter, in the underground complex. I must have caused the storm raging around the NPP which appears to have also affected:\nRadar\nDead City\nEast Pripyat\nRECON\nGenerators\nBlack Market\nthe old Cemetery\nWarnings have gone out to stay out of those areas due to high radiation. The undergrounds in those areas are said to be safe but there has been no confirmation to that.\nShould talk to the Barman and Geeks about it, maybe they have some news to share.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="levelup3_reclemation_entry">
		<text>Storm has dissipated and now it seems every faction wants to get there first... but what did the storm do to that area of the Zone and can it be dealt with?\nAre the possible treasures there worth the risk? Sure as Hell I'm going to find out, and soon!\n BUT.. I need to plan my way back to the center to avoid enemies and discover what new perils are lurking out there..</text>
	</string>
	<!-- 109982 -->
	<string id="levelup2_get_suit_entry">
		<text>Now what? The storm has made the Warehouses and beyond immpassable, so how can I get to them?\nMaybe the geeks at the bar can give me help. No telling how long this storm will last, maybe forever..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="syslov_items_quest_opisanie_entry">
		<text>Syslov, with the Clear Sky base asked for some things. In exchange for them, he promised to give the Soul Cube of Shadows, which has unique properties. List of things:\nDegtyarev Light Machinegun 'RPD' - he seems to have sold some merchant in Agroprom,\nMercenary Researcher suit,\nfive bottles of "Nemiroff" vodka,\ntwo military rations,\nthree "Amber" cheeses,\nfive cans of nuts,\nthree cans of "Chernigov" beer,\nfive "Adrenalin Rush" Power drinks.</text>	<!-- Changed 'Suslov' to 'Syslov'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
	</string>
	<string id="cop_prip_info_lab_opisanie_entry">
		<text>Grozny said that in one room of the old hospital, he saw the plan of Pripyat. Apparently it was marked by a complex of underground facilities ... Perhaps the plan will be able to help me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cop_prip_instr_quest_opisanie_entry">
		<text>Sage - with stalker base in East Pripyat needs tools. If I can find them, then Sage will repair gear, including my own. In such a remote place a repairman would be of great value!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="soulcube_quest_opisanie_entry">
		<text>Interestingly all the twists and turns ... It was not the real Soul Cube. In any case, according to Shadows it should be located in the eastern part of Pripyat. The first thing to check out are some apartments on the top floor of a skyscraper. Another stalker said that the skyscraper is located near the cinema and has a strange vine along it's side. I hope there will be at least some intelligible information...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="outfit_blockpost_quest_opisanie_entry">
		<text>Need to find Beryl-5M armor, to mislead the military and to enter the checkpoint undetected.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_railroad_passage_text">
		<text>Before I go deep into the Zone, it is necessary to cross an old railway embankment. The only safe pass is protected by the military. However there is a small tunnel to the left, rookies usually go through it. There I am to meet a guide who will help me through and provide me with tips on survivng the Zone beyond.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_mil_pda_entry">
		<text>Found this dead Military guy, appears to have been shot at close range in the back..\nThe note I found on him indicated that he was carrying a special PDA with important info on it. It might be wise to try and find this PDA and the 'good friend' that shot him in the back..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_five_tails_entry">
		<text>Tolik asked for five blind dog tails, he tried to collect them himself, but somehow he wasn't able to grab a few tails, ha! If we do this simple task for him he will share a valuable artifact recipe with me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_artifact_entry">
		<text>Sidorovich gave me a small job to earn some money while he tries to figure out information about my situation. Apparently some rich jerk from outside of the Zone want's an Night Star Artifact, for who knows what, and Sidorovich promised he will get him one.\nSome Loners reported the sighting of a Night Star in the local area. Because the Artifact is heavily radiated, Sidorovich gave me a special Container. When I find the Night Star I need to immediately put it in the container and report back to him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jaw_for_prapor_entry">
		<text>Prapor, one of the Duty Officers guarding the Duty Checkpoint, has asked me to find him a Bloodsucker Jaw, in order for him to give me Fox' Parcel. Apperantly Prapor has some kind of sickness, and some Doctor is gonna make a strong medicine out of this Bloodsucker Jaw. Well, better find a Bloodsucker and return to Prapor before he needs me to find more "medicine" for him!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_desert_eagle_entry">
		<text>Freeman at the Bar has asked me to find his Desert Eagle handgun. He beleives he lost it in the Wild Territory, possibly in a tunnel.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_come_to_trader_entry">
		<text>I need to get back to the Barman but the path to the Garbage is blocked by the Military. I have been told that there is a path South to the Cordon that should be clear.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="case_to_freeman_entry">
		<text>Gordon Freeman has asked me to go to the Wild Territory and meet up with this DeJames character. I am to get a case from him and return it to Freeaman at the Bar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_mush_arts_quest_entry">
		<text>Storm may have some benefit as now the Barman will pay top dollar for mushroom Artifacts that are cooking in the storm around the NPP Generators.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tb3d_lanky_mush_art_quest_entry">
		<text>Lanky has a prototype suit that he beleives will protect me from the storm. Of course I have to test it out AFTER I find him a unique Mushroom Artifact from F1 or maybe one of the old research labs up North.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
