<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.6 removed '-' -->
<!-- Stats rationalisation by GlowWormToo - 16 Jun 16-->
<!-- Partial reworking of text. 31/31 artefact descriptions still to do - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16-->

  <string id="enc_zone_rudiment_small_d">
		<text>Fima told me the first part of the recipe: If you drop a Zombie's tooth and a sausage into a Tornado anomaly, you get a better and therefore more expensive Zombie part. Unfortunately, he doesn't have the second part of the recipe...\n%c[255,255,255,255]Time for transmutation %c[255,224,224,160]5 minutes\n%c[255,255,255,255]Probability of successful transmutation %c[255,1,255,1]50 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Probability of destruction %c[255,255,1,1]50 %%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_babka_4_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Health %c[255,1,255,1]+200 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Stamina %c[255,1,255,1]+18\n%c[255,255,255,255]Bleeding %c[255,1,255,1]-133 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Chemical Burn %c[255,255,1,1]-10 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Explosion %c[255,1,255,1]+8 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Bulletproof Cap %c[255,1,255,1]+5 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+11\n%c[default]\nThe absolute received by a transmutation of the artefact 'Elder Beads'. The recipe, obviously, has been received by practical consideration. What became with its author - it is possible to guess by a skeleton lying nearby. From merits it is necessary to note increase in stability of the owner of the artefact to bullet wounds in comparison with predecessor. It is radioactive.\nModify 'Elder Beads' throw in anomaly 'Burner'.\n%c[255,255,255,255]Time for transmutation %c[255,224,224,160]5 minutes of the Zone\n%c[255,255,255,255]Probability of successful transmutation %c[255,1,255,1]75 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Probability of degeneration %c[255,255,1,1]25 %%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_arhara_globus_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Nourishment %c[255,255,1,1]-4000 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Burn %c[255,1,255,1]+10 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Impact %c[255,1,255,1]+5 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Telepathy %c[255,1,255,1]+20 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Chemical Burn %c[255,1,255,1]+5 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Bulletproof Cap %c[255,1,255,1]+2 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+5\n%c[default]\nThis absolute on appearance is completely not similar to the predecessor, reminds a children's rattle with prickles, whence and its name has gone... Assert that in the course of transformation play a role connections of the silver which is present at anomaly a jelly unknown to a science. Possesses quite good qualities, in spite of the fact that the main feature of its predecessor - protection against psi-influence a little weakened... Moderately radioactive. Has quite a good price.\n \nModifiy 'Simbion' throw in anomaly 'Fruit Punch'.\n%c[255,255,255,255]Time for transmutation %c[255,224,224,160]10 minutes of the Zone\n%c[255,255,255,255]Probability of successful transmutation %c[255,1,255,1]75 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Probability of degeneration %c[255,255,1,1]25 %%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_caterpillar_d">
    <text>%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,1,255,1]-15\n%c[255,255,255,255]Bleeding %c[255,1,255,1]-133 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Burn %c[255,1,255,1]+15 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Rupture %c[255,1,255,1]+15 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Bulletproof Cap %c[255,1,255,1]+1 %\n%c[default]\nRare artefact. You will not find it in one anomaly as it is a live biosubstance. It is formed from bezoar a stomach of old controllers at influence on them anomaly 'Burner'. It is not enough, who in the Zone knows this recipe and existence of the given artefact. Sakharov people assume that this live substance is formed of not digested bones of bones of an electrochimera under long influence of the perverted gastric juice of the controller, hypnotic aura constantly surrounding it and the subsequent influence extremely high temperatures. It is necessary to guess only as this biomass thus does not perish.\n \nBezoar of the controller in anomaly 'Burner'.\n%c[255,255,255,255]Time for transmutation %c[255,224,224,160]5 minutes of the Zone\n%c[255,255,255,255]Probability of successful transmutation %c[255,1,255,1]75 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Probability of degeneration %c[255,255,1,1]25 %%c[default]</text>
   </string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_medusa_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Bulletproof Cap %c[255,1,255,1]+2 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+3\n%c[default]\nArtefact formed in the 'Springboard' anomaly. Represents the remains of plants pressed and fancifully bent by strong gravitational field. At artefact carrying on a belt immunity to influence of gravitational anomalies, such as 'Vortex' and 'Whirligig' increases, and also the insignificant effect of the protective field reducing defeat from small arms is shown. It is slightly radioactive. The sale price is low because of wide circulation. Interest in the artefact is shown by scientific organisations.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_cristall_flower_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Bulletproof Cap %c[255,1,255,1]+4 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+5\n%c[default]\nIs born in anomaly 'Springboard'. Such artefact can be found in few areas of the Zone. Impregnations of metal connections give a beautiful play of light. Examining of this artefact near to a fire calms one at night.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_night_star_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Bulletproof Cap %c[255,1,255,1]+6 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+10\n%c[default]\nArtefact extremely seldom formed in anomaly 'Springboard'. Beautiful formation with a smooth surface and phosphorescent colour impregnations. Shines with greenish light all round itself in a radius of 1-2 metres at night, hence stalkers gave it such a name. Represents the remains of plants, soils and in general everything that gets into direct contact with anomaly pressed and fancifully bent by strong gravitational field. At artefact carrying on a belt immunity to influence of gravitational anomalies, such as 'Vortex' and 'Whirligig' strongly increases, and also the effect of the protective field reducing defeat from small arms is shown. But thus the artefact is strongly radioactive, therefore long carrying is counter-indicative. The sale price very high. Interest in the artefact is shown by scientific organisations and military men.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_vyvert_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Impact %c[255,1,255,1]+2 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Rupture %c[255,1,255,1]+2 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+3\n%c[default]\nArtefact formed in anomaly 'Vortex'. Represents the remains of plants, soils and other small objects that get into contact with anomaly pressed and fancifully bent by strong gravitational field. At artefact carrying on a belt immunity to influence of gravitational anomalies, such as 'Springboard' increases The sale price is low because of wide circulation. Interest in the artefact is shown by scientific organisations.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_gravi_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Impact %c[255,1,255,1]+5 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Rupture %c[255,1,255,1]+5 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+5\n%c[default]\nBeautiful artefact formed in anomaly 'Vortex'. Represents the remains of plants pressed and fancifully bent by strong gravitational field. At artefact carrying on a belt immunity to influence of gravitational anomalies, such as 'Springboard' increases. The price is of sale and probability of occurrence is average. Interest in the artefact is shown by scientific organisations, collectors and jewellers.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_gold_fish_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Impact %c[255,1,255,1]+8 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Rupture %c[255,1,255,1]+8 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+10\n%c[default]\nArtefact extremely seldom appearing in anomaly 'Vortex'. Beautiful formation with a smooth surface. Shines space round itself in a radius of 1-2 metres at night. Represents the metal pressed and fancifully bent by strong gravitational field with a mix of everything that in general gets near to the anomaly at the moment of discharge. At artefact carrying on a belt immunity to influence of gravitational anomalies, such as 'Springboard' increases. The sale price is very high. Interest in the artefact is shown by scientific organisations, collectors and jewellers.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_drops_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,1,255,1]-5\n%c[255,255,255,255]Stamina %c[255,255,1,1]-73\n%c[default]\nArtefact appearing near to anomaly 'Burner'. Tear small formation with the cracked lustrous surface. Stalkers say that at carrying of this artefact radiation level in an organism decreases, but because of a strong thermal emission personal stamina worsens. The price is low. Interest in the artefact is shown by collectors and jewellers.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_fireball_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,1,255,1]-10\n%c[255,255,255,255]Stamina %c[255,255,1,1]-36\n%c[default]\nArtefact found near anomaly 'Burner'. Translucent reddish formation of a spherical form. Stalkers say that artefact carrying reduces radiation level in an organism. But because of a strong thermal emission personal stamina worsens. The price is average. Interest in the artefact is shown by collectors and jewellers.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_cristall_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,1,255,1]-15\n%c[255,255,255,255]Stamina %c[255,255,1,1]-27\n%c[default]\nArtefact very rarely found near anomaly 'Burner'. Its name describes the artefacts form, it is a big poured crystal of reddish colour. Stalkers assert that at its carrying radiation level in an organism considerably decreases. But, alas, the artefact does not in the best way influence personal stamina. The price is high. Interest in the artefact is shown by scientific organisations.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_blood_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Health %c[255,1,255,1]+100 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,1,255,1]-3\n%c[255,255,255,255]Impact %c[255,255,1,1]-3 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Rupture %c[255,255,1,1]-3 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,1,255,1]+3 %\n%c[default]\nArtefact formed in anomaly 'Whirligig'. Represents ugly reddish formation from pressed and fancifully bent polymerized remains of plants, soil, a flesh and bones of lost stalkers and mutants. At artefact carrying on a belt the mystical image slightly accelerates healing of wounds. At the same time reduces stability to physical damages. Among stalkers exists a legend that in this artefact the force of people who were lost in the anomaly is contained. The sale price is low because of wide circulation. Interest in the artefact is shown by physicians and many religious cults.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_mincer_meat_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Health %c[255,1,255,1]+200 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,1,255,1]-5\n%c[255,255,255,255]Impact %c[255,255,1,1]-5 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Rupture %c[255,255,1,1]-5 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,1,255,1]+5 %\n%c[default]\nArtefact formed in anomaly 'Whirligig'. Represents ugly yellowish formation from pressed and fancifully bent polymerized remains of a flesh and bones of the lost stalkers. At artefact carrying on a belt the mystical image slightly accelerates process of healing of wounds. Among stalkers exists a legend that in this artefact the force of people who were lost in the anomaly is contained. At the same time reduces stability to physical damages. The price is of sale and probability of occurrence is average. Interest in the artefact is shown by physicians and many religious cults.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_soul_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Health %c[255,1,255,1]+300 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,1,255,1]-10\n%c[255,255,255,255]Impact %c[255,255,1,1]-7 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Rupture %c[255,255,1,1]-7 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,1,255,1]+10 %\n%c[default]\nVery rare artefact formed in anomaly 'Whirligig'. Represents zheltovato-red brilliant formation from pressed and fancifully bent polymerized remains of a live fresh flesh. Among stalkers exists a legend that in this artefact the force of people who were lost in the anomaly is contained. At artefact carrying on a belt the mystical image within several seconds completely restores health, and any bleeding stops. At the same time stability to physical damages considerably worsens. The sale price is very high. Basically this artefact appears in anomalies absorbing a great number of organic objects. Interest in the artefact is shown by physicians and many religious cults.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_electra_sparkler_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Stamina %c[255,1,255,1]+27\n%c[255,255,255,255]Electric Shock %c[255,255,1,1]-10 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]-10 %\n%c[default]\nArtefact formed in anomaly 'Electro'. The translucent amorphous very simple formation which is seldom letting out round small sparks. Artefact carrying on a belt slightly increases personal stamina, but leaves the person vulnerable to electricity. The price is average. Interest in the artefact is shown by scientific organisations, collectors and jewellers.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_electra_flash_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Stamina %c[255,1,255,1]+64\n%c[255,255,255,255]Electric Shock %c[255,255,1,1]-10 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]-10 %\n%c[default]\nArtefact formed in anomaly 'Electro'. Basic translucent amorphous formation with rays of light beating from within, seldom emiting round itself small sparks. Artefact carrying on a belt slightly increases personal stamina, but leaves the person vulnerable to electricity. The price is high. Interest in the artefact is shown by scientific organisations, collectors and jewellers.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_electra_moonlight_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Stamina %c[255,1,255,1]+100\n%c[255,255,255,255]Electric Shock %c[255,255,1,1]-10 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]-10 %\n%c[default]\nArtefact found around anomaly 'Electro'. Easy translucent amorphous formation with the shone core, letting out round itself small sparks. Artefact carrying on a belt considerably increases personal stamina. But if hit by anomaly 'Electro' chances of survival of the person carrying this artefact remain minimal. The price is very high. Interest in the artefact is shown by scientific organisations, collectors and jewellers.%c[default]</text>
  </string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_ameba_slime_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Bleeding %c[255,1,255,1]-66 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Burn %c[255,255,1,1]-20 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Chemical Burn %c[255,255,1,1]-10 %\n%c[default]\nArtefact found near to anomaly 'Fruit Punch'. Represents translucent jelly formation. At artefact carrying on a belt the probability of loss of a considerable quantity of blood decreases at severe wounds, but vulnerability to any kinds of burns thus increases. The price is low. Interest in the artefact is shown by scientific organisations.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_ameba_slug_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Bleeding %c[255,1,255,1]-133 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Burn %c[255,255,1,1]-10 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Chemical Burn %c[255,255,1,1]-10 %\n%c[default]\nArtefact found near anomaly 'Fruit Punch'. Carrying of this translucent jelly formations on a belt reduces probability of loss of a considerable quantity of blood at severe wounds, but makes the person vulnerable to any kinds of burns. The price is average. Interest in the artefact is shown by scientific organisations.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_ameba_mica_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Bleeding %c[255,1,255,1]-233 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Burn %c[255,255,1,1]-5 %\n%c[255,255,255,255]Chemical Burn %c[255,255,1,1]-10 %\n%c[default]\nArtefact formed in anomaly 'Fruit Punch'. At artefact carrying on a belt the probability of loss of a considerable quantity of blood decreases at severe wounds, but vulnerability to any kinds of burns thus increases. The price is high. Interest in the artefact is shown by scientific organisations.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_dummy_spring_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Impact %c[255,1,255,1]+10 %\n%c[default]\nOrigin of the artefact is not known. Represents two hard disks linked together by viscous slime. It can independently move, making small jumps thanks to a variable gravitational field. At carrying on a belt reduces probability of occurrence of serious traumas as a result of blows is little. The sale price is very high. Interest in the artefact is shown by scientific organisations.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_dummy_dummy_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Impact %c[255,1,255,1]+4 %\n%c[default]\nOrigin of artefact is not known. Two hard disks linked together by slime. The artefact slightly reduces defeat from all types of gravitational anomalies and explosions, absorbing shock waves. The price of sale is high. Interest in the artefact is shown by scientific organisations.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_dummy_battery_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Electric Shock %c[255,1,255,1]+15 %\n%c[default]\nOrigin of artefact is not known. Ridge brilliant formation. Very useful artefact for its carrier. Improves all characteristics of radiating firmness and a susceptibility to an electricity. The impression is made that the artefact strengthens any processes proceeding round it. The price of sale is huge. Particular interest in the artefact is shown by scientific organisations.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_dummy_pellicle_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Chemical Burn %c[255,1,255,1]+15 %\n%c[default]\nThis artefact is so rare that many researchers do not guess at all that such substance can exist under natural conditions. Tears away caustic chemical components.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_dummy_glassbeads_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Bulletproof Cap %c[255,1,255,1]+5 %\n%c[default]\nRemarkable artefact, protect it. It is good that has only merits (the most unique phenomenon as only positive properties the absolutes and rare hypermodified, as a rule, possess). Scientists break grey-haired heads how similar properties can be received in vitro. Interest to it show, perhaps, all who feel like it.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_rusty_thorn_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,1,255,1]-5\n%c[255,255,255,255]Bleeding %c[255,255,1,1]+100 %\n%c[default]\nArtefact very often it is possible to find outBleeding near anomaly 'Witches Galantines'. It reduces radiation from a human body. However with the weakened immunity the artefact also causes strong bleedings in people. The price is low. Interest in the artefact is shown by scientific organisations, collectors and jewellers.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_rusty_kristall_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,1,255,1]-10\n%c[255,255,255,255]Bleeding %c[255,255,1,1]+100 %\n%c[default]\nArtefact can be found near to anomaly 'Witches Galantines'. It reduces radiation from a human body, but at the same time opens bleedings so at carrying of this artefact it is necessary to be careful and not to forget about its negative influence. The price is average. Interest in the artefact is shown by scientific organisations, collectors and jewellers.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_rusty_sea_urchin_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,1,255,1]-20\n%c[255,255,255,255]Bleeding %c[255,255,1,1]+100 %\n%c[default]\nArtefact found near the anomaly 'Witches Galantines'. It deduces radiation from a human body. However at constant use of this artefact the person has a risk of loss of a considerable quantity of blood. The price is high. Interest in the artefact is shown by scientific organisations, collectors and jewellers.%c[default]</text>
	</string>

  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_fuzz_kolobok_d">
		<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Rupture %c[255,1,255,1]+4 %\n%c[default]\nArtefact of an unknown origin. Scientists cannot solve till now the recipe of reception of this miracle of the Zone. At carrying on a belt firmness of an organism to any physical damages considerably increases. It is radioactive. The price is very high. Particular interest in the artefact is shown by physicians.%c[default]</text>
	</string>
