<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 lis_doctor_dialog_3 patch to path, The Doctor, naemn_shturm_otbit, something -->
<!-- GAME START -->
<!-- ASTROLOGER -->
<!-- Names changed as commented below, and edited the text up to Line 254 - Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16 -->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->
<string_table>
	<string id="zvezdochet_talk_0">
		<text>Entschuldige - kannst du mir sagen, wo ich bin? Was ist passiert. Ich fühle mich echt miserabel und fertig und - ich weiß nicht wie ich hierher gekommen bin ... Scheiße was ist nur los ....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zvezdochet_talk_1">
		<text>Hey, Hey ... ganz ruhig! Du hast Glück am Leben zu sein ... Es war ein Unfall. Der Toten Laster hat sich überschlagen und du wurdest mit ein paar anderen rausgeschleudert. Du lagst dort drüben in den Trümmern... Ich habe dich dann rausgezogen\n \nWarte - Zieh dir erstmal diesen Mantel über. Bevor dich hier die Strahlung tötet. Ich habe ihn von einem der Toten Banditen. Kannst du dich überhaupt an was erinnern?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zvezdochet_talk_2">
		<text>Toten Laster? Nein.., Ich kann mich an absolut gar nichts erinnern. Was zur Hölle meinst du mit dem - Toten Laster? Wiso war ich da drin?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zvezdochet_talk_3">
		<text>Also der als Fahrer oder Beifahrer warst du nicht da drin. Der Tote Bandit da drüben, der war der Fahrer. Du warst wohl hinten auf der Lade drauf. In deinem Fall bin ich aber auch etwas überfragt. Denn - normal werden die Toten Laster dazu verwendet Leichen abzutransportieren, also die Opfer die bei der Explosion in Tschernobyl umkamen. Wirklich furchtbar was sich letztens dort zugetragen hatte.\n \nWiso du auf dem Laster warst .. keine Ahnung. Aber sei froh, das du am Leben bist... Jedenfalls musst du erstmal zu Kräften kommen - hier, das  wirst du brauchen. Nimm dieses Medikit und dann gehe nach Süden zum Ausbildungs Lager für Neu-Ankömmlinge. Sobald du es erreicht hast, frage nach dem Arzt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zvezdochet_talk_4">
		<text>Artzt? Sag mal wer bist du? Wie ist dein Name?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zvezdochet_talk_5">
		<text>Später ... finde erstmal den Arzt im Anfänger Dorf. Du musst an der kaputten Brücke vorbei. Der Arzt arbeitet die meiste Zeit im Unterirdischen Funk Raum. Er wird dir helfen - sag ihm nur, dass der "Astrologe" dich geschickt hat und sag ihm das ich auf ihn warte. Hinter der Brücke - er weiß Bescheid. Tu mir diesen gefallen und beim nächsten Mal, wenn wir uns wieder treffen, werde ich mich revanchieren.\n \nNun höre mir genau zu. Du wirst nicht so einfach bei der Brücke vorbeikommen. Die wurde vom Militär besetzt und als Kontrollposten eingerichtet. Du musst den Typen dort was anbieten. Ich kann dir kein Geld geben aber ich weiß aus sicherer Quelle das die Jungs ein paar Schwere Alkoholiker sind. Ich habe eine Flasche Wodka und ein Ersatz Medkit in einer Holzkiste bei der alten Farm, vor der Brücke, verstaut. Hol dir das - und siehe dich um, ob du noch etwas benötigst. Schau mal im Alten Haus, gegenüber der Farm, vorbei. Dort könnte auch noch was nützliches rumliegen - Hier und da liegt immer irgendwo Material rum. Nur sei Vorsichtig - und nun schnell beeil dich!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zvezdochet_talk_6">
		<text>Ok, Ich mich auf den Weg zum Lager. Danke für deine Hilfe!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zvezdochet_talk1_0">
		<text>I saw the Doctor and gave him your message. You mentioned something about a repayment for a favor. Were you serious? After all the help you gave me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zvezdochet_talk1_1">
		<text>Yes, indeed! Here you go - wear this on your belt. It'll help you survive here. I'd also like to offer you some advice, Marked One - stay away from the ATP! It's been completely overrun by Bandits, and unless you know the way out, you'll be stuck there forever!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zvezdochet_talk1_2">
		<text>Thanks, Astrologer</text>
	</string>
<!-- SWAMP DOCTOR -->
	<string id="kordon_doctor_dialog_0">
		<text>Ah-ha! Da bist du ja?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kordon_doctor_dialog_1">
		<text>Ja? .. Der "Astrologe" hat mich geschickt. Ich habe Probleme mich zu erinnern. Ich weiß nicht einmal, wer ich bin. Mein Körper ist ein einziger schmerz, und mein Kopf fühlt sich an, als wäre er als Sandsack missbraucht worden! Er bat mich auch, Ihnen zu sagen. Dass er auf Sie wartet - hinter der Brücke. Er meinte - Sie würden es verstehen. Können sie was für mich tun?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kordon_doctor_dialog_2">
		<text>Hmm... Du sagst dass du dich nicht erinnern kannst wer du bist? Nun - ich weiß wer du bist. Aber dafür haben wir jetzt keine Zeit. Ich werde später wiederkommen und nach dir sehen. Hier, trinke diese Medizin und Ruhe dich erstmal für eine Weile aus.\n \nWenn du wach bist, gehe zum Händler hier im Lager. Sein Name ist Sidorovich. Er wird dich auf den richtigen Pfad  bringen. Es macht absolut keinen Sinn jetzt zu ihm zugehen. Er wird, wie alle hier, solange du nicht die Medizin genommen hast, nicht mit dir Sprechen wollen. Der Geruch des Toten Laster begleitet dich zurzeit überall hin, als hättest du eine Flasche vom Stärksten Parfum aus Douglas. \n \nTrinke die Medizin und leg dich hin. Wenn du aufwachst, dann sprichst du mit Sidorovich. So - Ich muss nun los mich mit dem "Astrologen" treffen. Angenehme Träume... Gezeichneter. Wir sehen uns wieder, das verspreche ich dir ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kordon_doctor_dialog_3">
		<text>Okay, danke für die Medizin. Mal sehen ob die hilft...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lis_doctor_dialog_0">
		<text>Good to see you again. That medicine had quite a kick to it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lis_doctor_dialog_1">
		<text>You're starting to look better already. Have you remembered anything about yourself?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lis_doctor_dialog_2">
		<text>No. Nothing at all. I fell asleep after taking your medicine, and dreamed I was in a horrid place - an endless maze of caves, full of all kinds of mutated creatures, all trying to kill me! In the end I met a man, a Doctor like yourself, but rather strange. He had two companions with him, but they didn't talk much. I focused on the man - I think he said he used to work in the mines down there - and he gave me something like what you gave me to take, except that it brought me back here. I mean to reality. I still don't remember anything, though. You said you knew my name?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lis_doctor_dialog_3">
		<text>Possibly, but it'd be meaningless to you at the moment. Just be patient, and it'll all come back to you. You need to rediscover yourself. I'm heading North with Astrologer, but I'm certain our paths will cross again in due course...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lis_doctor_dialog_4">
		<text>Yes, I need to find out more about myself. But to do that, I'm going to need some better weapons and armor...</text>
	</string>
<!-- BLAND FLASH-DRIVE -->
	<string id="bland_say_norma_0">
		<text>Most impressive, Stalker! You took every of them out single-handedly, even though they were well-trained and armed! Don't assume they were my men though, because they weren't! I suppose you're here for the flash drive... Who snitched on me this time?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_say_norma_1">
		<text>So whose men were they, then? And yes, I am here for the flash drive - and I'm not leaving without it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_say_norma_2">
		<text>Those guys were Mercs! I'm afraid my affiliation is, let's say, complicated, and you don't need to know about that just yet. But have you any idea what's on this drive? No? Neither have I, but several people have been trying to get their hands on it. I couldn't make any sense of it, because all it contains is useless garbage, but I'd have been happy to sell it for profit. In fact, this whole meeting was a sham!\nLook, don't ask questions, 'cos I can't answer them for you yet, but I can offer you a deal... I give you the drive for 50,000 rubles and we call it a day. Otherwise, you'll have to kill me for it. Which won't help either of us because in the future, maybe, Fate will bring us together again, and we both may gain from it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_say_norma_3">
		<text>Wow, you certainly talk in riddles - but I need the drive. I don't mind paying for it, and I've no reason to make an enemy of you, let alone kill you! Here's your money...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_say_norma_4">
		<text>You made the right choice, and now, I must go. May we meet again...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_say_norma_5">
		<text>I look forward to it, my friend. Be seeing you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_say_norma_6">
		<text>You certainly have the gift of the gab, but I think you mistook me for someone else. Do you think I give a shit, you two-faced con merchant?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_say_lapti_0">
		<text>So whose men were they, then? And yes, I am here for the flash drive - and I'm not leaving without it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_say_lapti_1">
		<text>Those guys were Mercs! I'm afraid my affiliation is, let's say, complicated, and you don't need to know about that just yet. But have you any idea what's on this drive? No? Neither have I, but several people have been trying to get their hands on it. I couldn't make any sense of it, because all it contains is useless garbage, but I'd have been happy to sell it for profit. In fact, this whole meeting was a sham!\nLook, don't ask questions, 'cos I can't answer them for you yet, but I can offer you a deal... I give you the drive for 50,000 rubles and we call it a day. Otherwise, you'll have to kill me for it. Which won't help either of us because in the future, maybe, Fate will bring us together again, and we both may gain from it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_say_lapti_2">
		<text>Wow, you certainly talk in riddles - but I need the drive. I don't mind paying for it, and I've no reason to make an enemy of you, let alone kill you! Here's your money...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_say_lapti_3">
		<text>You made the right choice, and now, I must go. May we meet again...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_say_lapti_4">
		<text>I look forward to it, my friend. Be seeing you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_say_lapti_5">
		<text>You certainly have the gift of the gab, but I think you mistook me for someone else. Do you think I give a shit, you two-faced con merchant?</text>
	</string>
<!-- SCREW MISSION START -->
	<string id="arhara_atp_0">
		<text>Hi, I'm told that you offer more than just repairs. You have useful information to trade as well?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_atp_1">
		<text>Maybe. What exactly are you looking for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_atp_2">
		<text>Anything useful would be appreciated</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_atp_3">
		<text>Well, as you said, I'm a trader. And some things I can tell you could be dangerous in the wrong hands. You know what I mean? You need to prove yourself. Maybe help me out with something first. Then I'll tell you something useful, and perhaps reward you as well...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_atp_4">
		<text>I'm listening. Go on...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_atp_5">
		<text>Have you talked with Lukash yet? If not, then you should, and he'll send you on a mission to search for two important objects. Well, I have one of them already, and I'll give it to you if you can get me something in return. I know that, in the ATP, there's a working vice. It's heavy, but it needs to be for the work I do. If you can get it for me, then we have a deal. Okay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_atp_6">
		<text>Sure, I'll help you out. It may take me a little while, but I'll be back with your vice. I promise</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_atp_7">
		<text>You're asking me to lug a fucking great vice around the Zone? You're crazy. Now I know why they call you Screw...</text>
	</string>
<!-- SCREW MISSION COMPLETE -->
	<string id="arhara_shurup_atp_propusk_0">
		<text>Hi, Techniker. Ich habe ine paar tolle Neuigkeiten...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_shurup_atp_propusk_1">
		<text>Aha ... Du warst ganz schön lange weg. Ich habe schon angenommen das du dich in der Zone verlaufen hast!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_shurup_atp_propusk_2">
		<text>Hier - das verdammte ding wiegt ja'ne Tonne! Bin froh es loszuwerden...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_shurup_atp_propusk_3">
		<text>Vielen Dank.\n \nDas macht es mir aber um einiges leichter. Hier ist das "Gehirn eines Controller's" das du für den Job von "Lukash" benötigst. Es kommt von einem Controller im AKW1. Sollten dort keine seien, sind die im Nördlichen Teil von Tchernobyl - AKW2. Da muss du hin. Sei aber auf der Hut. Dort wirst du mitsicherheit weitere finden.</text>
	</string>
<!-- CHERNOBYL-2 TRANSITION MISSION -->
	<string id="ugrum_perexod_0">
		<text>Hey, I heard you've been to Pripyat...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ugrum_perexod_1">
		<text>Greetings, Stalker. Yes, I've just returned from there. Why do you ask?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ugrum_perexod_2">
		<text>Did you run into any Monolith forces?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ugrum_perexod_3">
		<text>Yes, and they're total fanatics! But they certainly know what they're doing. One of them told me how they plan to spread from the center of the Zone all the way to the Cordon...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ugrum_perexod_4">
		<text>How do they plan to do that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ugrum_perexod_5">
		<text>I'm not sure exactly, but I made contact with one of them. I learned about about a trail they use to infiltrate the South from the center of the Zone.\nHey, can you do me a favour? I have to return to Pripyat, but I need protection against Zombification. If you get me some of the antidote - it's called Antizombin - I'll tell you about the transition from Chernobyl NPP2 to the ATP. What do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ugrum_perexod_6">
		<text>You can prevent yourself from being zombified? I'll get you your antidote, and maybe some for myself, too...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ugrum_perexod_7">
		<text>You're shitting me, aren't you? I've never heard of the stuff. And I'm not going on a wild goose chase around the Zone...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ugrum_plaer_otdat_0">
		<text>Here's your Antizombin. I didn't realise it'd be so expensive, but I'm sure the transition will be worth it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ugrum_plaer_otdat_1">
		<text>Everything in the Zone is expensive! Nobody comes here for a holiday!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ugrum_plaer_otdat_2">
		<text>Hey, I wanted to ask you. How did you manage to make contact with the Monolith?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ugrum_plaer_otdat_3">
		<text>Easy - through the sights of my Vintorez! No, I'm joking. Here, take the transition coordinates. What makes it easier for Monolith is that the transition marker disappears from time to time, because of the anomalous activity at NPP2. No one can find it unless they actually know where it is, so I've uploaded a photo of it to your PDA. That should help you...</text>
	</string>
<!-- LUKASH MISSIONS -->
	<string id="lukash_mozg_0">
		<text>Hi, I hope we can cooperate. I don't want to join Freedom right now, but I'm hoping we can help each other out...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_mozg_1">
		<text>Well, don't expect anything for nothing. I'll only offer you jobs that are advantagous to Freedom or myself</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_mozg_2">
		<text>Okay, what do you have at the moment?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_mozg_3">
		<text>Since you asked, I do have a job for you, if you choose to accept it - but it's not an easy one. I have a request from Moscow. Do you know the city?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_mozg_4">
		<text>I certainly know of Moscow, but I don't pretend to have been there...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_mozg_5">
		<text>Okay, at least you didn't try to bullshit me... You'll be suprised to hear that Controller brains have become a delicacy for the Muskovich elite. Not just any any Controller, though - only the ones found in Chernobyl NPP1 and 2 have the right taste. texture, and halucinative qualities. They're rare, but they're not difficult to find, because all mutants eating a dead Controller in that area will avoid the brain, so you should be able to find them discarded on the ground. \nHowever, there's a rumor that the Monolith have reconnoitered the ATP territory, and they might have brought some of these brains with them for their own use. Talk to Screw, behind my HQ. He's been looking for a Stalker to explore the ATP for him, and he might have some useful info for you. I'll send the details to your PDA. Two undamaged brains, I need.\nOh, and I also need you to come up with 300,000Ru. You're going to have to take this on faith, but your reward will be worth it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_mozg_6">
		<text>I'll try to find you a couple of brains, but that's a lot of money you're asking for!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_mozg_7">
		<text>I do promise you it'll be worth it! One of our guys found some really special items, but they're not of so much use to us here. To someone like you, however...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_mozg_otdat_0">
		<text>Sorry about the wait. I didn't find anything in the ATP. I had to search for them at Chernobyl NPP2. Here are your brains...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_mozg_otdat_1">
		<text>You were in Chernobyl? Oh, only two? I hope there are more! I need three!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_mozg_otdat_2">
		<text>You specifically asked me for two. Had you asked for three, I'd have brought you three. Here they are, and I'm happy to give them to you. The 300,000 though? Well, I hoped that we could help each other, so I'm trusting you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lukash_mozg_otdat_3">
		<text>Thanks! I hope you didn't damage the goods. You didn't try to eat them... no, I don't see any bite marks. Now, your reward...\nFirst, a rare artefact\nNext, a directory of teleports that belonged to the Monolith leaders near their base in the Sarcophagus. Extremely useful to any Stalker worth his salt!\nAnd finally, a Camouflage Exoskeleton! I heard these items belonged to Strelok, one of the few to ever reach the Sarcophagus - but that might just be a rumor...</text>
	</string>
<!-- ATP TRANSITION INFO -->
	<string id="tolik_info_0">
		<text>Whats new in the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tolik_info_1">
		<text>Not much, unless you haven't heard about the new path yet. Look in your PDA, there is a mark, bandits have found a transition to a new territory!!! It's in the Bar territory, if you can get past all the dogs then you have to jump a fence</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tolik_info_2">
		<text>Now that's something I haven't heard about!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tolik_info_3">
		<text>The problem is though nobody knows of an exit! You will get stuck in there forever! Best to walk around the Zone and find out where the return path is first! After all someone must know</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tolik_info_4">
		<text>I'll try to find a Veteran stalker who might know a way back</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tolik_info_5">
		<text>Be careful, after the last emission a strange anomaly has appeared behind the bridge!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tolik_info_6">
		<text>Thanks for the warning</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arh_disk_nayty_0">
		<text>Listen, you can likely help me, I've heard there is a path to a new territory, the ATP I believe thier calling it. But I do not know where it begins. Do you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arh_disk_nayty_1">
		<text>Yes, I know of such a path. Only it's useless to you, from that territory you will not get out. There are three exits: to the Cordon, Army Warehouses, and Pripyat, I know of only one, to the Cordon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arh_disk_nayty_2">
		<text>That's great, will you show me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arh_disk_nayty_3">
		<text>I will tell you, but you've got to agree to do something for me first</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arh_disk_nayty_4">
		<text>What is it you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arh_disk_nayty_5">
		<text>A disk. A normal computer disk. The disk to you is useless, as its information is ciphered. Last message from my courier was one week ago. He had hidden from mutants in one of the sheds in the ATP. If you accept this task you will be rewarded. I must warn you though, bandits ernestly search for this disk, they think that on it is data of a transition from the ATP to the Zone's center, so be careful!!! The entrance and an exit from this location are on your PDA. This is dangerous territory, stalker!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arh_disk_nayty_6">
		<text>Mmm, yes, this better be worth it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arh_disk_nayty_7">
		<text>Well you know the road better than I do, go yourself</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arh_disk_otd_0">
		<text>Greetings Adrenalin! I found your disk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arh_disk_otd_1">
		<text>Hello. I'm glad that you have returned alive. And the courier?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arh_disk_otd_2">
		<text>Saw, only a body, In appearance it was untouched. But there was no time to investigate as bandits appeared suddenly, seriously armed, and wanted to play!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arh_disk_otd_3">
		<text>Well we can put these affairs to an end! As a reward take a pair of my personal nodes and some information. While you were gone I was able to find one more exit from ATP to the Army Warehouses. I sent the info to your PDA. And where the third path to Pripyat is, Sakharov knows</text>
	</string>
<!-- SAKHAROV MISSIONS -->
	<string id="sahar_sumka_dost_0">
		<text>Prof, do the military visit here often?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_sumka_dost_1">
		<text>Are you not on friendly terms with the military? Ah yes, they have no love for stalkers. Though, if you do a job for them, then possibly you might convince them of your loyalty. They arrive sometimes when the zombies threaten the bunker. I often call for thier help too, especially these days. By the way, about military men, I've got an offer for you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_sumka_dost_2">
		<text>And what might you need Professor?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_sumka_dost_3">
		<text>About one year back The Doctor visited me. A very kind and wise person you know. He gave to me, as a keepsake, a medical bag. But for me it was a very memorable gift!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_sumka_dost_4">
		<text>OH, Why?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_sumka_dost_5">
		<text>I was stopped at a military check point. They demanded vodka but I didnt have any. My bag was taken by a military captain, to give or sell it back to me he refused, and to spoil relations with the military is impossible for my research here. That captain is quite often on duty in the Chernobyl area. Try to get this bag and I will reward you with a transition from the ATP directly to Pripyat. It is assured, this transition will be very useful to you. Will you do it? I will let you have a good artefact, and an approximate location of the captain in Chernobyl. I will send the info to your PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_sumka_dost_6">
		<text>Thats a big risk for a common medical bag. And the road for me to the north is unexplored, But the artefact will be useful, and the info about the transition is very important</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_sumka_dost_7">
		<text>You want me to face untold danger for an old bag in Chernobyl! Look for another sap!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_sumka_otd_0">
		<text>Hello Professor! I made it back alive!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_sumka_otd_1">
		<text>Great to see you Marked One! Have you really brought my bag? How did you manage to persuade the captain?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_sumka_otd_2">
		<text>Yes, Ive brought your bag. And the captain was persuaded by the sight of my weapon, he quickly agreed, even got money he did'nt take! Ah, just a joke Professor, he recieved an early retirement, job security, HA!, what can ya say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_sumka_otd_3">
		<text>Well I've never found death so humorous! Thanks for the bag! It is very important to me. Here's your information on the transition from the ATP to Pripyat</text>
	</string>
<!-- DOCTOR MEDALLION MISSION -->
	<string id="arhara_doctor_doct_0">
		<text>Doc, have you heard about the abandoned mine and the Miner? He asked about you, I have left the Monolith splinter with him</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_doctor_doct_1">
		<text>The Miner? So he lives, good news!. I thought for a long time he was dead. You were supposed to bring me this artefact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_doctor_doct_2">
		<text>The miner will give it to me only if I bring him some object</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_doctor_doct_3">
		<text>Ahhh, the Medallion, but I don't have it presently</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_doctor_doct_4">
		<text>And where is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_doctor_doct_5">
		<text>Almost right after the accident in Chernobyl, I dropped a backpack on a roof of one of the skyscrapers in Pripyat. In this backpack is the Medallion the Miner seeks. I tried many times to get it, but, too many snipers! Once the military nearly killed me, other times I nearly fell!! Bring, the backpack and I will be grateful. The reward for this difficult and dangerous work you will find directly on the roof. To get there is only possible through the ATP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_doctor_doct_6">
		<text>Okay, Doc, I will try. Always glad to help, for a price!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_doctor_doct_7">
		<text>Doc, since childhood Ive been afraid of heights, and above 3 floors, FORGET IT!!! Forgive me, but let somebody else be engaged in your acrobatics!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_doctor_otd_0">
		<text>Hi, Doc! Here, take your medallion</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_doctor_otd_1">
		<text>I knew Strelok that you would succeed, after all you are the best!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_doctor_otd_2">
		<text>Here take it, to get on the skyscrapers, it was necessary to pass through a teleport</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_doctor_otd_3">
		<text>Thanks your task was long, dangerous, but interesting. After all you are a stalker. And the Medallion, take it to the Miner. And give my regards to him. The Monolith Splinter you can keep for yourself. But remember its very radioactive!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_sahar_bezo_0">
		<text>Prof, I have a question</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_sahar_bezo_1">
		<text>Yes, I'm listening</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_sahar_bezo_2">
		<text>I need the recipe for the transformation of the stomach of a controller into a rare artefact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_sahar_bezo_3">
		<text>Yes, I know of such a recipe. Only it is a question not of stomach contents, about a Bezoar, it is the big old lump of food, and not only, which has got stuck in the stomach and cannot leave, A very rare find!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_sahar_bezo_4">
		<text>Ughhh, bowel blockage? Crap!, Ok, Prof, can you give me the recipe?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_sahar_bezo_5">
		<text>Certainly, but not so fast. It is not necessary to go anywhere, Whats required is a 50,000ru donation for the development of local science. And with the present crisis behind this perimeter, about us the world has absolutely forgotten!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_sahar_bezo_6">
		<text>A Donation? If thats what you want to call it. Here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_sahar_bezo_7">
		<text>Prof, this is hogwash!, No donation from me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_omlet_0">
		<text>With all the vodka you drink, how do you get any work done?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_omlet_1">
		<text>Works no problem. My problem is I want to make an omelette, but there is one thing missing</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_omlet_2">
		<text>What, fresh Anchovies, Mimosa bubbly, what? I'm just DYING to know, all verklempt already!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_omlet_3">
		<text>We have Sausage, Bread, canned food but no Eggs! Chickens can't live in the zone, just Ravens, circling Ravens...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_omlet_4">
		<text>Just how much have you had to drink today? Three or four bottles?, dude!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_omlet_5">
		<text>SERIOUS!!! I need Ten eggs, will you get them for me? I can get you a very special weapon in exchange. I advise you to ask Akim, the new dealer from Cordon, he can tell you where to look</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_omlet_6">
		<text>Well, a special weapon always sounds fun! Ill see what Akim knows</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_omlet_7">
		<text>Cook, you think a stalker-veteran is going to search the Zone for ten eggs? No way! You ARE plastered!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_omlet_otdat_0">
		<text>Greetings, any vodka left?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_omlet_otdat_1">
		<text>Your back! I hope you found something</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_omlet_otdat_2">
		<text>Sorry I got hungry and fried them up, taste like S###!!! Just jokin, here's your precious eggs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_omlet_otdat_3">
		<text>What?! Oh no! You have broken one!!! Here, take the weapon anyway, OAF!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_omlet_akim_0">
		<text>Akim, greetings. Do you know where it is possible to get eggs?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_omlet_akim_1">
		<text>Whose eggs? Raven? OH, a Burer? I will tell you a secret, they are not present!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_omlet_akim_2">
		<text>Not present? What is this, a riddle??? Just tell me where they nest already!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_omlet_akim_3">
		<text>I Know a place, but for the info you are going to have to do some work. I have ordered some medicine for an important customer, one of the leaders of a local criminal gang. My courier lost his nerve and dropped the viles in the dark while sneaking into the Cordon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_omlet_akim_4">
		<text>And where to search for this medicine?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_omlet_akim_5">
		<text>The vials of this medicine are in a minefield near the military post, in south Cordon. To the left of the road when facing the checkpoint. It is necessary to bring me only three. You will find more but I just need three</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_omlet_akim_6">
		<text>Thanks, a minefield next to a military checkpoint and I thought you were going to give me something difficult!\n Care to give me a mine detector before I go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_omlet_akim_7">
		<text>Stroll into a minefield? Not for lousy raven eggs! You're NUTS???</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_lekar_akim_0">
		<text>Well Akim, I have brought the medicine. It stinks terribly!, the patient will die from the stench!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_lekar_akim_1">
		<text>It is necessary that he drink a teaspoon. Stinks you say, most likely you have more bottles in your backpack then</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_lekar_akim_2">
		<text>So where are these devil eggs?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_lekar_akim_3">
		<text>In the Forgotten Wood, search the stumps of trees, or near them, and you should find eggs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_shaxter_0">
		<text>Hello, who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_shaxter_1">
		<text>I'm the Miner, I've been here since before the accident in Chernobyl, Quite a few we were, but now remains just three, the others were lost to mutants, illness, and when part of the mine collapsed</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_shaxter_2">
		<text>Why do you still live down here and what was here earlier?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_shaxter_3">
		<text>I Have gotten used to living underground. It was'nt safe to go above ground after the accident, so we stayed bellow. I have not seen the sunlight for so long that Im afraid of going blind if I go to the surface, For a long time now nobody from the surface has appeared here. This was a coal mine but that was long ago! Now mutants and anomalies have appeared and, recently, the Monolith! And you, are here for what?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_shaxter_4">
		<text>I dont know how I got here, I know only I should give you the Monolith piece, I'm sure that I will return for it. I can't carry it any further for now</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_shaxter_5">
		<text>Leave it with me and when the time feels right, you'll come back, it will be here. Here, take this medicine for weariness, it will return you on your journey, good luck to you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_shaxter_6">
		<text>Thanks, we will meet again, if I survive!, I Know that I should give you this piece of the Monolith, but, who am I?, and when will this all become clear? When I find out, I will return</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shaxter_fonar_dost_0">
		<text>Hello Miner, I Have returned! I need that splinter of the Monolith that I left with you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shaxter_fonar_dost_1">
		<text>Greetings, Im glad that you are still alive! A lot of time has passed since we last met</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shaxter_fonar_dost_2">
		<text>The Doctor has told me to bring you this Medallion, it's what you requested, right? Do you still have my artefact?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shaxter_fonar_dost_3">
		<text>Yes, it is the Medallion!, many thanks!. Your artefact is still here, there is nobody here to steal it anyway, and mutants wouldn't eat it!!! But I want to ask you something</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shaxter_fonar_dost_4">
		<text>About what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shaxter_fonar_dost_5">
		<text>Yes, I want to get used to the light again. The book that you have brought to me, I cannot read, Could you bring me two small lamps? Where to get them you ask? I do not know, ask the dealers that are closer to the Zone's border</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shaxter_fonar_dost_6">
		<text>I will go to the Cordon to find out about these small lamps</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shaxter_fonar_dost_7">
		<text>I will not go anywhere, Its too dangerous!, use a match!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shaxter_fonar_otdat_0">
		<text>Here Miner, I got your lamps</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shaxter_fonar_otdat_1">
		<text>This is good news</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shaxter_fonar_otdat_2">
		<text>Here you are, and the batteries are still new!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shaxter_fonar_otdat_3">
		<text>Thanks, I hope I am able to read the book of the father now, Take your artefact, but dont forget its EXTREMELY radiocative. Transfer my greetings to The Doctor, my brother. I Hope this isnt our last meeting</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akim_kubik_nayti_0">
		<text>Akim, where can I find a couple of small lamps?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akim_kubik_nayti_1">
		<text>Greetings, what do you need the lamps for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akim_kubik_nayti_2">
		<text>Its a long story, can you get me some lamps with fresh batteries?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akim_kubik_nayti_3">
		<text>I was once scared of the dark you know, as a child I kept a small lamp in my room. Oh those were the days of being naive, ha-ha</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akim_kubik_nayti_4">
		<text>Are you listening to me? Cut the bullshit, can you get them or not?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akim_kubik_nayti_5">
		<text>Certainly, but I need you to do something for me first. I get quite bored here between customers so I want you to get me a Rubik's Cube. In the Dark Valley, in the bandit base. This moron threw it on the roof of one of the buildings, You bring it to me, and you'll get the lamps</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akim_kubik_nayti_6">
		<text>Okay! Okay! I will go get it, what's next, a Barbie Doll!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akim_kubik_nayti_7">
		<text>Go get your own Cube psycho!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akim_kubik_prines_0">
		<text>I've got the cube, give me the lamps</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akim_kubik_prines_1">
		<text>Thanks for the cube, but the small lamps are not here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akim_kubik_prines_2">
		<text>What! Give me what you promised or I'll feed you to a sea monster!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="akim_kubik_prines_3">
		<text>Calm down, calm down, I know where they should be. In the Forgotten Wood, in the camp of Crest next to a helicopter. Look on the ground</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_kniga_naity_0">
		<text>Hello, just recently I found the entrance to this Cave, Ive come for my artefact and some council</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_kniga_naity_1">
		<text>Greetings. If you have come for the fragment of the Monolith you should first bring to me one item from its present owner, then I can give it to you. And what council do you seek?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_kniga_naity_2">
		<text>Though you have hinted, Im not sure who this person is that I need to get the item from. And for council, Ive been asked to find a treasure that someone has lost somewhere in this cave</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_kniga_naity_3">
		<text>Talk to the Doctor, I've known him for a long time. The treasure, these are ancient coins, people came already looking for them, only to have not found anything except, death! You must descend to the lower part of the cave to look for the coins. There is also a place, in the lower tunnels, where you can climb the wall to another part of the cave we call the Labyrinth, horrible place! Be Carfull!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_kniga_naity_4">
		<text>And how do I exit the cave?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_kniga_naity_5">
		<text>From here there are two ways, the first is to the Agroprom, absolutely nearby. Next to the entrance to our camp, on the map its visible. The second, to the Dump, its at the bottom levels of the cave, I think you will find it, hopefully without problems. I need to make a request of you. In the Forgotten Woods is a book, would you please find it for me? Near the coins you will find a valuable artefact, if you will bring the book, I will give to you the second one!, There's only two! They are born only every 10 years!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_kniga_naity_6">
		<text>I will try to find the treasure, and I will look for your book</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_kniga_naity_7">
		<text>I haven't found the book yet, this cave is almost as bad as takin the subways used to be!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_kniga_prines_0">
		<text>Here, I have brought the book</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_kniga_prines_1">
		<text>Thanks. It was my father's book</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_kniga_prines_2">
		<text>Strange, so much time has passed and its like new! That must make you happy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shax_kniga_prines_3">
		<text>Its not a simple book, Yes, here, take your reward. Im very happy how this has turned out</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lysyi_klad_nayti_0">
		<text>Greetings. You look like a man who can be trusted, do you have any information I could use?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lysyi_klad_nayti_1">
		<text>Hey, You, badly needing a shave, yeh, you look tough enough so here's whats up, I've got some dirty work to offer and its not a job for ah... Men in Diapers!, know what I mean?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lysyi_klad_nayti_2">
		<text>You're not checkin my pants!!!, but if its dangerous, it better pay well!!! Im brave, not stupid</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lysyi_klad_nayti_3">
		<text>I think you are the man for the job. Theres an abandoned cave, it was there long before the failure in Chernobyl. A treasure was lost somwhere inside, nobody's ever been able to find it, or bring it out anyway</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lysyi_klad_nayti_4">
		<text>What kind of compensation and where can I find an entrance?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lysyi_klad_nayti_5">
		<text>I know of two entrances, both are in the train tunnel, one in the Garbage, another in Agroprom. Compensation, VERY large monetary payment. In the cave there is a miner, or miners. Talk to them, they will be able to help you find an exit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lysyi_klad_nayti_6">
		<text>I will try to find this treasure, just hope it's real!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lysyi_klad_nayti_7">
		<text>Who needs money in the Zone? I have just reached the Bar. Im getting drunk, now piss off!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lysyi_klad_prines_0">
		<text>There I was in the cave and I found this treasure!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lysyi_klad_prines_1">
		<text>Shhhh, Are you serious?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lysyi_klad_prines_2">
		<text>Take your coins, HEY EVERYBODY, the drinks are on HIM!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lysyi_klad_prines_3">
		<text>Heres your cash Marked One, good or bad, your making a name for yourself quick around here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_shaxt_strelok_naity_0">
		<text>Hello Miner, I had absolutely forgotten that I left you my PDA. I remembered only at the Monolith, well I read the note I found there</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_shaxt_strelok_naity_1">
		<text>Yes, your PDA is in this cave</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_shaxt_strelok_naity_2">
		<text>It has a lot of useful data that I need</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_shaxt_strelok_naity_3">
		<text>I can't read or use such devices, I never had time for gadgets. But before I can give it to you I must ask you something</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_shaxt_strelok_naity_4">
		<text>About what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_shaxt_strelok_naity_5">
		<text>There is a controller who quite often appears here. To kill him is useless, a clever creature! When I send men to eliminate it, at once it leaves! I need an artefact for protection, but in such a cave its not present. It Is called the Scalp of the Controller, for certain such a skilled stalker as you can get one. How about it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_shaxt_strelok_naity_6">
		<text>Controllers can be a real pain in the ass, but, I will get you the artefact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_shaxt_strelok_naity_7">
		<text>Its a rare artefact and I can't do without it, I can't help you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_shaxt_strelok_vzyt_0">
		<text>Here's the scalp of the controller, enjoy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_shaxt_strelok_vzyt_1">
		<text>Thanks! Now I will have immunity against the controller!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_shaxt_strelok_vzyt_2">
		<text>Can I have my PDA now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_shaxt_strelok_vzyt_3">
		<text>Ah yes, it was stolen, but the thief never left the cave. The mutants killed him, find his corpse and you'll find your PDA. I can help a little, you already know where the transition to the Labyrinth is. Look for it there</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flyga_naity_0">
		<text>Hello commander! you dont look very happy! What's up?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flyga_naity_1">
		<text>I dont need questions, I need answers!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flyga_naity_2">
		<text>Whats wrong? A high rank, plenty of vodka, what else could you wish for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flyga_naity_3">
		<text>There is a reason, not terminal, but gets to me sometimes, maybe you can help. A long time ago when I was a green lieutenant, I was on campaign during the Chechen Republic war. I was presented with a flask by the First Division's Commander. I kept it with me always, but now it's missing!! You help me, I'll help you, Eh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flyga_naity_4">
		<text>So where in the big wide Zone will I find any flask, let alone yours?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flyga_naity_5">
		<text>Ask Lanky in the Bar. Rumours have reached me that someone tried to sell him such a flask</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flyga_naity_6">
		<text>I must be nuts, but I'll look into this, it couldn't have gone far</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flyga_naity_7">
		<text>I don't have time for this, I have the Monolith to worry about</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flyga_vzyt_0">
		<text>Ufff, Lanky is a low-life and a jerk!, difficult to do business with!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flyga_vzyt_1">
		<text>Has he told you anything?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flyga_vzyt_2">
		<text>That parasite Lanky made this very expensive for me, I hope you consider that when it comes to compensation. Here, is this your flask?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flyga_vzyt_3">
		<text>Ah! Yes! I need to fill it up. Your reward can be picked up from Sidorovich, you will tell him I sent you. For now here's some cash, more than my fighters receive in TWO months!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolgovyzui_lentyi_0">
		<text>Hello, I would like to ask you something</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolgovyzui_lentyi_1">
		<text>Well, out with it then. Ive got a lot of work to do today, so be quick</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolgovyzui_lentyi_2">
		<text>Did someone try to sell you a stolen flask, I need it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolgovyzui_lentyi_3">
		<text>To me it doesn't matter that it's stolen or not. My price for service: 100 bottles of vodka and the Scalp of the Controller artefact and, uhm, also ten microcircuits aught to do it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolgovyzui_lentyi_4">
		<text>Slow down there!, who are you?!, one of the TRUMPS or sumpthin?! not for a stupid flask??? Now listen, I'm not asking to get anything for free!, but your gonna have to lower that price or I walk out of here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolgovyzui_lentyi_5">
		<text>Okay, Okay, chill a little! We will drop the price to 50,000ru, and instead of the Scalp of the controller, make it, uhm, five Quirks, and ten microcircuits. The microcircuits can be found in the Cordon. The military recently repaired thier transmitters and the old microcircuits have simply been thrown out. I was pumpin a soldier full a vodka and got him to spew something about throwing them into the latrine, well, I think he said latrine, he sorta went bar diving after that</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolgovyzui_lentyi_6">
		<text>Okay, that's better, still a ripoff but I need to stay tight with Petrenko</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolgovyzui_lentyi_7">
		<text>Your greed is unmatched in the zone, no way, chow!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolgovyzui_urod_0">
		<text>Here's all your loot, those micro-circuits smell like the place I found them in or, come to think of it, this place as well! I'm gonna have to sanitize my backpack after this</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolgovyzui_urod_1">
		<text>This is excellent!. But the flask, it isnt here!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolgovyzui_urod_2">
		<text>You had better be joking! After all I went through!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolgovyzui_urod_3">
		<text>Dont get so angry. The man who tried to sell me the flask was drunk. When I wouldn't pay him what he wanted he left, then came back and told me he threw it through the gate. It's the gate on the right as you pass those Duty morons coming in from the dump. There's a couple of places you can get over the fence there. Aught to be a pretty sight in that suit! The flask should still be behind that gate</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_termos_naity_0">
		<text>Greetings!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_termos_naity_1">
		<text>Greetings. I have a task for you. If you will help I will be grateful</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_termos_naity_2">
		<text>And what do you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_termos_naity_3">
		<text>I had some info smuggled out of the Freedom base. It is contained in thermoses, believe it or not</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_termos_naity_4">
		<text>Thermoses?! Where did you get thermoses?, Ahhh, forget it, and where will I find these thermoses?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_termos_naity_5">
		<text>There are several, and they are different in size. Five are big and located behind the Freedom base somewhere, under a tree I think. Follow the powerlines and you can get behind the base, watch out tho, towers at corners with snipers, best going at night. I sent a sketch of the place to your PDA. To find the five small thermoses you'll need to talk with Garik, always in the Bar, says he likes the beer, go figure</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_termos_naity_6">
		<text>Well chief, another fun puzzle, All right I'll find them for you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_termos_naity_7">
		<text>Sorry I can't help, I'm engaged in other matters at the moment, liquid matters that is!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_termos_otdat_0">
		<text>Here, take this crap</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_termos_otdat_1">
		<text>Thermoses, all ten?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_termos_otdat_2">
		<text>All made of stainless steel, not a western made one in the group!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_termos_otdat_3">
		<text>This is excellent! I Will give you the location of a cache. My men caught this military soldier with a backpack, somewhere in the Dark Valley, its been some time ago. Bandits have somewhat of a base there as you probably know by now. Anyway, Checkout the observation towers, I hear there's quite a bit of loot in em</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_vopros_0">
		<text>Garik, I need to ask you something</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_vopros_1">
		<text>What is it you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_vopros_2">
		<text>The thermoses, I want to know where you took them</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_vopros_3">
		<text>It is classified information, bug off... No wait, how bout say 10,000ru</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_vopros_4">
		<text>Hmph, you got me by the Kahonas this time, Okay, choke on it! Now tell me where they are!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_vopros_5">
		<text>Eh? Alright droppings of a pseudodog! Wait! There's more I think. I smoke, so I want 10 packs of cigs as well, lots of stalkers trade in them</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_vopros_6">
		<text>Damn! Money is no problem but the cigarettes, they might take awhile, ah, srew it, I'll be back</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_vopros_7">
		<text>Garik, you're nothing but a petty crook with a bad habit. You can stick that info up your ass!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_otvet_0">
		<text>Here's your money and cigs, use the first for kickin the second, loser</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_otvet_1">
		<text>Man, you are desperit! Thought I'ld never see you again!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_otvet_2">
		<text>Kiss off and just give me the info already</text>
	</string>
	<string id="garik_otvet_3">
		<text>Okay, Okay, don't be such a snorkass about it, the thermoses are in a building in Pripyat. Next to the bus station is a destroyed shop, look on the top floor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_sidor_vzyt_0">
		<text>Hey there Sid, how's it hangin?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_sidor_vzyt_1">
		<text>Long time no see, Marked One, been keepin busy eh, seems I've heard some chatter lately, take care</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_sidor_vzyt_2">
		<text>No time for chit-chat Sid, I'm here on business. Petrenko sent me to see you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_sidor_vzyt_3">
		<text>Well then, don't get too comfortable, I'll save this beer for another time then, Eh?! So, I'm sending you somewhere</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_sidor_vzyt_4">
		<text>I need to pick up the package that Petrenko has left here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_sidor_vzyt_5">
		<text>Well, Hmmm, Maybe you need to do a job for me first! If you want that package that is. SO, Mr. tough guy!! The Military from Agroprom has ordered two tool boxes from me. Apparently someone messed up some of their Armored vehicles, some Rambo kinda dude, this nut fall of a death truck or what? OH Shh, sorry Marked One! Anyway, this Rambo stalker aught to be careful, they are probably looking for him very intently, no dought there's a bounty. Anyways, each toolbox contains a hammer, wrench and screwdriver. Hammers and screwdrivers have been seen around the ATP, and the wrenchs are probably at the Army Warehouses, most likely still in Screw's workshop. Since you are probably to blame for this mess, you are the one that is going to fix it, understood?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_sidor_vzyt_6">
		<text>Someday you are going to push me just a little too far Sid, might do a Rambo on YOUR butt someday, might be fun, who knows, Eh Sid?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_sidor_vzyt_7">
		<text>Heh, wow, don't take it out on me, man, I'm not here for vacation either, damn! Just do this job, and I will gladly turn over Petrenko's package and you can go about your bussiness of killing people Okay, McBain?, Crap your a cold one!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_sidor_zabrat_0">
		<text>Man!! When you said hammers, you could have told me that you meant frikn SLEDGE hammers!! This crap is heavy!! You should try and carry these things around for a while, maybe lose 100kg or so, lard butt!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_sidor_zabrat_1">
		<text>If I had told you that, then you probably wouldn't have agreed to take the job, here, set them up here on my desk. And, Stop with the crap already!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_sidor_zabrat_2">
		<text>I ought to smash your desk into a thousand pieces with one, Ah, Well, Anyways, take them. Now, Petrenko's package, where is it? I need to get out of this hole where I can breath and get back to work!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_sidor_zabrat_3">
		<text>Well, as you can imagine, Petrenko doesn't seem to trust me with the case itself. All he gave me are these coordinates leading to its location. It is located somewhere in the Forgotten Forest. Just after the transition, you want to keep moving along the edge of the border, there you find some stones, one of which is flat, that's where it is, Good Luck! You'll need it!, tough guy!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_stol_dostat_0">
		<text>General, I need your help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_stol_dostat_1">
		<text>Could, but whats in it for me? I think there's a task I need done, Hmmmm, yes, I've got one!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_stol_dostat_2">
		<text>Crap! Okay, Im listening, shoot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_stol_dostat_3">
		<text>Marked One, you've done pretty good for yourself so far, so listen: Data indicates that bandits have established communication with the mercenaries and have been informing them of our movements. Things are serious, my men are constantly getting ambushed, they don't grow on trees you know, although anything seems possible in the Zone, eh stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_stol_dostat_4">
		<text>Well?, I don't read minds, ESPECIALLY yours!, so spill it already!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_stol_dostat_5">
		<text>Mister CONGENIALITY we have here! Go find me a computer and videolink device. The video signal has been tracked to the ATP, and the computer is somwhere inside the base in the Dark Valley. My agents report there,s a secret room in the basement that houses the equipment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_stol_dostat_6">
		<text>General if I get all these pieces of garbage would you prepare for me an officer's uniform, not below colonel?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_stol_dostat_7">
		<text>I have no love for bandits, but your better to send than Ivantsov, he just sits around playing with himself, poor sap! Okay, deal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_stol_dostat_8">
		<text>A real Soldier, I knew that you would agree</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_stol_dostat_9">
		<text>You've rewarded me well so far, so, how can I refuse</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_stol_prines_0">
		<text>Well is my uniform of the colonel ready, is it possible to try on?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_stol_prines_1">
		<text>It is possible. Only where's the goods?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_stol_prines_2">
		<text>Here're your toys General, play nice on line now, you never know who is out there in cyber-space eh?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_stol_prines_3">
		<text>Look, screw the uniform! I've got something MUCH better! Hope this makes your day!</text>
	</string>
<!-- ESCORT THE SCIENTISTS -->
	<string id="sahar_info_0">
		<text>Hey Professor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_info_1">
		<text>Greetings Stalker, I have urgent business for you, no time to talk of reward now, but it WILL be good</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_info_2">
		<text>Why? Whats happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_info_3">
		<text>Some of our scientists have been attacked by Mercs in the Wild Territory, I need you to escort them out</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_info_4">
		<text>I thought you were under the protection of the Military, call them on the radio, they can send a chopper, or are they all drunk again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_info_5">
		<text>HA, HA, you crack me up Marked One! Close tho, they have the only phone with them but they cant get the military to respond. They are almost at the bunker, I need you to meet them near the transition from Yantar to the Wild Territory. Escort them to the bunker and you'll have to open the door for them. Wait ther until they have entered safely. Whatever happens, get me that phone, thats the MOST important thing!, got it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_info_6">
		<text>Im going, gees, calm down before you soil yourself already!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_info_7">
		<text>Well, I do need some sleep!, can't help you out much today, sorry</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_info_prines_0">
		<text>Here, take the phone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_info_prines_1">
		<text>This is excellent! And what happened with my people?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_info_prines_2">
		<text>Professor you know how the doors to the bunker slam open and shut, well,\nnot to difficult to guess, not too pretty, glad I don't have to clean it up!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_info_prines_3">
		<text>Well, sad, well anyway, young man, accept a modest gift from science!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_buy_pda_0">
		<text>Greetings, Mr. all-knowing</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_buy_pda_1">
		<text>What? Oh, Yes, stalker, I have a business offer for you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_buy_pda_2">
		<text>Blow something up? Someone to hunt?, Well?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_buy_pda_3">
		<text>No, sorry, not so fun I'm afraid. I buy up stalker PDAs, live, dead, broken and whole</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_buy_pda_4">
		<text>So this is recycle central for all those lost PDAs, how green of you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_buy_pda_5">
		<text>Well, I AM the informant you idiot, I scan them for any valuable info. as I should know as much as possible, the trade obliges. Listen, for every 20 PDAs you can play a small lottery. Rewards can be: cartridges, artefacts (except rare of course!), or maybe a weapon. For 40 PDAs, I will share information on a hiding place with you. Truth be that it could have belonged to a master or, maybe a rookie, the risk could be rewarding, or not</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_buy_pda_6">
		<text>Sounds like a big production to me! But, I will collect them, exchanging them makes more sense than trashing them, Eh</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_beret_pda_0">
		<text>Greetings</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_beret_pda_1">
		<text>Well, have you brought some business my way?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_beret_pda_2">
		<text>Here I've got 20 PDAs for you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_beret_pda_3">
		<text>Man, my backpack is about to burst, take the 40 PDAs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_beret_pda_4">
		<text>Im too busy now, I ain't got time for no stinkin PDAs. Maybe some other time, Im dry as a bone!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_beret_pda_5">
		<text>Well you've brought 20 pieces, LET'S PLAY THE LOTTERY!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_beret_pda_6">
		<text>40 pieces?!! I'll be hacking all week! I can just imagine how many YOU have sent to the other world! Alright, give me the PDAs, I will give you the information on the hiding place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_beret_pda_7">
		<text>Well then, later dude</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_infa_gg_0">
		<text>A real live general! Why aren't you in Moscow living the good life?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_infa_gg_1">
		<text>Hmph, stalkers, smart mouths, all of em! Open your eyes! Your in a war-zone if you didn't notice. There are never enough soldiers and we need all the firepower we can get! So, are you ready to show what you've got?, or you gonna tuck your tail in your behind and run like a blind dog?!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_infa_gg_2">
		<text>Big words General! Whats going on?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_infa_gg_3">
		<text>I have just been informed that Mercenaries are going to attack Duty's northern post bordering the Wild territory. Ive already sent more men, and your presence would help the defense. I dont want to send someone who is going to hide in a corner and shit himself while my fighters perish! Therefore your task is to destroy the leader of the group, he goes by the nickname Hump</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_infa_gg_4">
		<text>Hump?! Where are we? Notre Dame? Sounds like a snoozer to me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_infa_gg_5">
		<text>Its all about the Hardware!!!! Not Idle talk! I expect you to destroy Hump, there'll be no further dialogue otherwise. Your reward is what you find on Hump and his Mercenary mob. You will approach me later, I will give you a signal when they are about to attack. But before you can do this task you'll need to aquire a Thunderstorm rifle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_infa_gg_poluch_0">
		<text>Hey General, Say Hello to My Little Friend! One kick-ass Thunderstorm. Im ready to rock-n-roll!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_infa_gg_poluch_1">
		<text>Good Man! Now I see you mean business!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_infa_gg_poluch_2">
		<text>Guys just like to have fun. So whats up with the Merc mob?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_infa_gg_poluch_3">
		<text>Hold on, while I contact the post, here take these first-aid sets, might be useful!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="naemn_shturm_poluch_0">
		<text>Well, any news?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="naemn_shturm_poluch_1">
		<text>Yes, our forward reports that the Mercenaries are already on the way!!!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="naemn_shturm_otbit_0">
		<text>Well General, you've been de-Humped! how's it feel?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="naemn_shturm_otbit_1">
		<text>This is excellent, bit of a mess, but excellent indeed! Duty is grateful to you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="naemn_shturm_otbit_2">
		<text>No problem General, I told you I could fight. Now I've shown you, so?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="naemn_shturm_otbit_3">
		<text>Yes, I'm persuaded, I will adhere to our friendly verbal agreement. We need a good man like you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="naemn_shturm_otbit_f1">
		<text>Maybe so but you were supposed to get Hump, heard it was one of my lower recruits in fact!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="naemn_shturm_otbit_f2">
		<text>Well General... in such a rucus and in such tight quarters anything can happen</text>
	</string>
	<string id="naemn_shturm_otbit_f3">
		<text>Still a deals a deal and you get what you got off the trash we just took out. But at least you tried and we won't forget that</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
<!--Created/Modified with S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Dialog Extended Editor by Marty Sheppard/ Version: 0.96h ( 2017/02/01) =!!= Last changed: 17.02.2017 01:11:52 -->
