<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.5 bar_men_kpk_remont1 removed, dialog edits, boddles too bottles, bar_men_kpk_remont1, The Doctor, chernomor_stalk_say_hello, removed russian: à, î, â, å letters aleks1970, Perfumer -->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->
<string_table>
	<string id="final_agro_say_ok_0">
		<text>Greetings. You of that here? And Doctor has come...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_say_ok_1">
		<text>Greetings. Here, have come to learn results of your dialogue with the Black Doctor, yes Fang to remember... I to it grave here have built... To Bury there was nobody, but on Stalker Skomu to custom - to the lost friend it is necessary to establish a cross. I and a photo have found... Judging by that you not one has come, means, it knowingly was lost there, at Station...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_say_ok_2">
		<text>Senseless death happens a little... He wanted, that she lived. Here she also lives. I could not in another way. I have learnt truth and much have understood. It is good that we all the same have gathered all... Well, almost all...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_say_ok_3">
		<text>Consider - all. It always with us. Close people do not die, is simple we for ever we lose possibility to be with them nearby... What will be further?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_say_ok_4">
		<text>And further - in the Zone it is still full of riddles, it is full malicious. So and for us always there will be a work. The Zone was, is and will be - and not I so has solved</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_say_ok_5">
		<text>Yes, by the way, has forgotten to tell to you - today - rare event - an arrow at all clans of the Zone - type of negotiations. All mighty of this world was reached by hearings that the Zone is not eternal and just about will disappear. Therefore - it is declared perimirie for the period of a meeting, and it will take place here. You hear, Vertuhi rustle?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_say_ok_6">
		<text>Helicopters? Yes, I hear</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_arhara_ok_0">
		<text>Greetings, Arhara. You were late Maltz - Zone Elite have already scattered... Have grumbled a little, languages have scratched, tails have twisted, have calmed down and have left to the following meeting... Like all it is quite good, and on a shower it is sad. What further?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_arhara_ok_1">
		<text>Greetings. I also did not hurry up, and to elite I, fortunately, I do not concern. These are their problems. What's next? You have learnt the past, have given much for the sake of life of all one person, live in the present. The basic problems are solved. What is necessary for Heppienda? Time you here - you already three times as much the good fellow - not maintains many. To whom it is boring, for someone there is no logicality, to someone is difficult and abstruse, someone does not like to kill, who the coward, who in general the idiot, and for someone we idiots... At everyone - the destiny and the purpose in the Zone and in life. You have chosen the, and your choice not so and erroneous. To change immortality for life of the unfamiliar person - on it not everyone to dare</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_arhara_ok_2">
		<text>Yes, but all the same something not so... The Friend was lost. Arty and money is not necessary to me. I have understood is do not aim for me. Perhaps earlier, by youth also was. Those who will be twisted though months' in this porridge understand pair - that the Zone is a style of life, something special. And for such it opens the secrets. The others - simply leave or perish. I have understood one - meaning of the life in friendship, love. Yes-yes, do not laugh. Only having passed school of separation, lie, let even - murders - you start it to understand. But - I much now would make in another way</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_arhara_ok_3">
		<text>I am glad that all so. I into the account "in another way" - never late to start all over again, from a blank leaf... By the way, what it you have relaxed? The part of questions and remained not resolved</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_arhara_ok_4">
		<text>Yes, but they are already unimportant... I will go in Chernobyl I descend, Ghost has told that it there the next cross has put to Fang - and this time last...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_arhara_ok_5">
		<text>Well if sight to me does not change - that far it is not necessary to go. Yes, nearly has not forgotten - the exit teleport is at gate. I do not say goodbye - probably, our ways will still be crossed</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_arhara_ok_6">
		<text>Why, it is not necessary to go far? Sometimes you not to understand. All right, we do not say goodbye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_kluk_ok_0">
		<text>Fang???? What, here?...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_kluk_ok_1">
		<text>Greetings. Yes, it has turned out a little ugly. I grow old, likely, has not sustained. Nobody should know that I live. It is necessary for me a few time for check of one guess...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_kluk_ok_2">
		<text>Ah you, pepper bearded - you that, could not tell? Or we any more a command? I saw explosion. There has jerked so, what hardly the station has not scattered...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_kluk_ok_3">
		<text>Just because you have spent a unique artefact in the Zone for life of the girl, I and have not sustained. Here, has come to tell thanks. And into the explosion account - here it to me also should be reconnoitered. Before that explosion I have intercepted dialogue of this Astrologer - it appears, this bomb was its purpose and... It is made on the base of artefacts. It was, as I have understood, the trial version. Somewhere in a Zone other, more powerful thingummy becomes. You represent, what will be, if it use somewhere behind Perimeter? Here also it is necessary to learn, who and where it does. And into the friendship account - is not present, here it is a little not so. I know you, I know Ghost - you there and then will rush to help me. And this help while I will not find out an essence - for me is premature, forgive. While I ask about one - to ours to say that I am live - it is not necessary. And beter - n... There all is simple - a direct site, a brick on gas, a tower on the automatic machine... Well I that this shithead together with a bomb has faded could not admit...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_kluk_ok_4">
		<text>Here, means, what for this artefact was necessary to the Astrologer... For a bomb... Yes, ideas of Black Dock anything in comparison with its mean ideas... Can - together to investigation we will go? Ge... And that Ghost to you will personally present that cross that has established behind my back. It is what your tomb under the account? Already the third. Mnogovato-whether?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_kluk_ok_5">
		<text>Just right. God loves a Trinity. No, into the investigation account - while I. I am grateful to you for the Fly. We will soon meet. For now - the teleport waits for you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_kluk_ok_6">
		<text>Moscow you to it have on a visit gathered?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_kluk_ok_7">
		<text>Gee... No. To whom I there am necessary? To the Moscow measures - I the vagabond, the first cop will plant me. And you know, I and beetle can... More shortly - a crime. I will soon appear, only I will make which-what inquiries. And then, if the version about a bomb proves to be true - we will work together</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_agro_kluk_ok_8">
		<text>it is fine, we will wait</text>
	</string>
	<string id="muxa_final_say_0">
		<text>Here we and on Agroprom. It already near to Zone border</text>
	</string>
	<string id="muxa_final_say_1">
		<text>It pleases. And what for muzhiks there? It seems that they wait for us</text>
	</string>
	<string id="muxa_final_say_2">
		<text>Muzhiks? They are there, be not afraid. It is strange only that they here do. We will go, we learn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_priz_agro_neud_0">
		<text>Greetings. You of that here? And Doctor has come...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_priz_agro_neud_1">
		<text>Greetings. Here, have come to learn results of your dialogue with the Black Doctor, yes Fang to remember... I to it a cross have built with a photo yes a hillock... There was However, nobody to bury, but on Russian custom... Judging by that you one has come, means with that girl it has turned out of nothing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_priz_agro_neud_2">
		<text>It is possible to tell and so... I have an offer - can we will wave to America? All questions in the Zone are solved, and sometimes there is a sense in time to fasten with all. Money is</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_priz_agro_neud_3">
		<text>You know... For all I will not tell, but I will not go. I have got used here. A Zone - my house, and delights of America are not necessary to me. I think, at all ours such opinion. You - arrive as you wish, anybody will not condemn you - at everyone in the Zone the purpose. Sometimes it is crossed with the purposes of other people and becomes General. It is a pity that at us so it has not turned out. And now it is time to us. Farewell, Streloks</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_priz_agro_neud_4">
		<text>Eh, to one is boring to go... It is a pity that you not with me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fin_agro_arhara_neud_0">
		<text>Greetings, Arhara. You of that here? Like all it is quite good, and on a shower it is sad. What further?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fin_agro_arhara_neud_1">
		<text>Greetings. What's next? You have learnt the past, live in the present. The basic problems are solved. What is necessary for satisfaction? Time you here - you already three times as much the good fellow - not maintains many. To whom it is boring, for someone there is no logicality, to someone is difficult and abstruse, someone does not like to kill, who the coward, who in general the idiot, and for someone we idiots... At everyone - the destiny and the purpose in the Zone and in life. You have chosen the, and nobody has the right to condemn you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fin_agro_arhara_neud_2">
		<text>Yes, but all the same something not so... The Friend was lost, and I leave</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fin_agro_arhara_neud_3">
		<text>If has managed to stop in time is too not badly. Though, should you tell - you have not understood the most important thing - an essence of the Zone and remained for you a riddle. But do not forget - much can be corrected, begun anew. As speak - from a blank leaf. And at you such chance always is. And now it is time to me. Farewell. If you will decide something to change - a teleport at gate. The Zone is always open for the people who have lost...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fin_agro_arhara_neud_4">
		<text>Farewell, Arhara. Thanks for council</text>
	</string>
	<string id="adren_ak_strelok_nachalo_0">
		<text>Listen, I wanted to ask if you repair weapons?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="adren_ak_strelok_nachalo_1">
		<text>I'm not a repairman. I can only exchange only, and for just one weapon in the Zone. A truly unique weapon, though two were made. The first was crafted for an experienced Stalker named of Strelok. Where he is now, and where the weapon is, I don't know. But I knew the man who made it, and he made another afterwards. A truncated automatic AK-74, with a fixed suppressor and a butt carved especially to the client. The rifle has fixed optics and an increased rate of fire. Strelok was a master and known to prefer a close contact fight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="adren_ak_strelok_nachalo_2">
		<text>And where is the master who made these weapons?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="adren_ak_strelok_nachalo_3">
		<text>He was lost... Taken by one of the Zone's many anomalies... The weapon remained, and entered my possession, but I've no need for it other than as a collector's item. It's in pristine condition, and I'd happily exchange it for Strelok's original, which must be in pretty poor condition by now, knowing what he got up to... Oh, plus a 30,000Ru service fee to cover custom internal parts and specialized labour... If you ever find this weapon, don't throw it out. We can help each other gain something very, very special...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="adren_ak_strelok_nachalo_4">
		<text>Understood. Thanks</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ak_strelok_obmen_0">
		<text>Hi, Adrenalin. You said you wanted to exchange a new identical model for Strelok's original AK-74 automatic?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ak_strelok_obmen_1">
		<text>Yes, I would definitely honour such an agreement...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ak_strelok_obmen_2">
		<text>Here. The original weapon, and your thirty thousand service fee</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ak_strelok_obmen_3">
		<text>Wow! Where did you find it? As I promised, I'll give you the new one in exchange. Are you sure?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ak_strelok_obmen_4">
		<text>Sorry, I can't tell you where I found it, but here's the original and the money. We've helped each other...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saxar_minigan_nachalo_0">
		<text>Professor, I've been wanting to ask you something, but you've kept me so busy... I need to know what time the helicopter will arrive?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saxar_minigan_nachalo_1">
		<text>Strange, how did you learn about that? Or are we talking about different things?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saxar_minigan_nachalo_2">
		<text>Im talking about the military helicopter. I've heard they will sell a mini-gun...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saxar_minigan_nachalo_3">
		<text>Unfortunately, I'm not an intermediary in this kind of business. It would be better if you spoke to them yourself. Also you're in luck. Before you arrived they contacted me, and should be arriving at the bunker in a couple of minutes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saxar_minigan_nachalo_4">
		<text>Thank you professor. I will go and look. I hope that these military morons don't shoot on sight at everything that moves...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baty_zadanie_0">
		<text>Greetings stalker, you must either be brave or just plain stupid to approach a military helicopter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baty_zadanie_1">
		<text>Greetings colonel. I think the first variant describes me best, besides I know that you sell good weapons. Im looking for a mini-gun</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baty_zadanie_2">
		<text>Im just a major, however you flatter me. A good strategy. I wonder where you got this info about me... The Gun really is not for sale, I was bringing it to be installed on the professors helicopter. But that helicopter was brought down by mercenaries over the Wild Territory before the weapon could be installed. You can pick it up from Sakharov if you will do a task for me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baty_zadanie_3">
		<text>Is this some kind of dirty trick... Dealing with the military cannot be that simple</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baty_zadanie_4">
		<text>What I propose is not difficult, however we are short of helicopters and people are now worth their weight in gold. I just cant spare the manpower. Go talk to Sakharov and he will supply you with a detecor that will let you know when your within 10 metres of the target. The pilot, of the helicopter shot down over the wild territory, had instructions to dump the classified material if about to crash. And this is what happened, he ejected it. So, what I need you to do is go get the detector from Sakharov and find this classified object. Its probably in the area where the helicopter was first hit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baty_zadanie_5">
		<text>Well, I will look. I hope this deal is not a trick</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saxar_after_baty_0">
		<text>Professor, I'm here for the detector that you made for the military. The major instructed me to go on the Wild Territory and find something, then bring it to you in exchange for the Minigun...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saxar_after_baty_1">
		<text>Well this is odd.. I thought you didn't get on too well with the military... Yes, I've made the detector, but exactly what you're searching for I don't know. They only asked me to calibrate it for a certain type of thermoplastic. You don't need to put it on your belt, just keep it in your backpack. When you get within range it will beep and transmit a message to your PDA. Then you can take this ridiculously large machine gun away, which is just taking up space here. Here's the detector. I can only advise you to follow the flight path of the helicopter before it crashed...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saxar_after_baty_2">
		<text>Thanks, professor...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saxar_prines_baty_0">
		<text>Professor, I found it! Your device really helped. Now may I pick up that Minigun?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saxar_prines_baty_1">
		<text>Marked One, you're an excellent police dog. You probably find lots of artefacts with your sharp eyes... Forgive me. Here's your weapon...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saxar_prines_baty_2">
		<text>Bloody hell, it's big! And heavy, too. No wonder you want it out of here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="docent_kpk_remont_0">
		<text>Greetings, Lanky. I was told you can fix my PDA. Someone fried it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="docent_kpk_remont_1">
		<text>Hmmm...only the monolith has jammers that powerful, but not around here. It's possible to try. I have the micro-circuits, so it's about a five minute job. But it's not free work, are you prepared to pay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="docent_kpk_remont_2">
		<text>How much do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="docent_kpk_remont_3">
		<text>I owe a months rent to the Barman. Also he's cut me off till I pay my bar tab... Practically nothing, about 12 thousand... Go and pay while I fix your PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="docent_kpk_remont_4">
		<text>Here's the PDA, I will go pay your debts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="docent_kpk_remont_5">
		<text>Twelve thousand? How could you drink that much? Forget it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="docent_kpk_remont_6">
		<text>Up to you. But remember, a stalker without a PDA has no chance in the Zone. You will come see me when you cool down, try the Arena if your so broke</text>
	</string>
	<string id="docent_kpk_remont_7">
		<text>It's fine, take a look</text>
	</string>
	<string id="strelok_after_otkaz_remont_0">
		<text>Take the PDA and fix it, I will go see the barman</text>
	</string>
	<string id="strelok_after_otkaz_remont_1">
		<text>I spoke. All right, the price for repair - former</text>
	</string>
	<string id="strelok_after_otkaz_remont_2">
		<text>Excellent. The capitalist workshops make poor contacts, but I sorted it. Capitalism, it's better to have a tabasco enema any day!... than have democracy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_men_kpk_remont_0">
		<text>Barman I've come to pay a debt</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_men_kpk_remont_1">
		<text>What?, you don't even have a bar tab...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_men_kpk_remont_2">
		<text>I'm here to pay the repairmans debt, he's sort of got me by the balls at the moment. Here's 10 thousand...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_men_kpk_remont_3">
		<text>How much?, it's more like 12 thousand...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_men_kpk_remont_4">
		<text>Well, I must have made an honest mistake, ok, here 12 thousand...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_men_kpk_remont_5">
		<text>Well your quite the humorist, nice try... All in Euros, must be killing plenty mercs. Only Freeman pays in dollars, some I won't accept, it looks like he's used them for toilet paper</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_men_kpk_remont_6">
		<text>You might be onto something about Freeman, he was trapped in that tunnel for at least a few days. He had to wipe with something. Well, anyway, here's your 12 thousand and write me a receipt so I can show Lanky</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_men_kpk_remont1_0">
		<text>Barman Ive come to pay a debt</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_men_kpk_remont1_1">
		<text>What?, you don't even have a bar tab...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_men_kpk_remont1_2">
		<text>I'm here to pay the repairmans debt, he's sort of got me by the balls at the moment. Here's 10 thousand...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_men_kpk_remont1_3">
		<text>How much?, its more like 12 thousand...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_men_kpk_remont1_4">
		<text>Well, I must have made an honest mistake, ok, here, 12 thousand...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_men_kpk_remont1_5">
		<text>Well your quite the humorist, nice try... All in Euros, must be killing plenty mercs. Only Freeman pays in dollars, some I wont accept, it looks like he's used them for toilet paper</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_men_kpk_remont1_6">
		<text>You might be onto something about Freeman, he was trapped in that tunnel for at least a few days. He had to wipe with something. Well, anyway, here's your 12,000. Would you write me a receipt so I can show Lanky?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="docent_kpk_gotov_0">
		<text>I paid your tab. Here's your receipt. Is my PDA fixed?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="docent_kpk_gotov_1">
		<text>Y-yes... I overheard your delightful dialogue... Yes, your PDA is ready. Fortunately, there was no serious damage. I replaced the battery and cleaned the contacts. Here you are...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="docent_kpk_gotov_2">
		<text>This will work precisely now? What are the chances of this happening again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="docent_kpk_gotov_3">
		<text>It's better than new to be honest. I've made some alterations so you won't have this problem again... It feels good to have a clean slate at the bar. Time for a cocktail...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="docent_kpk_gotov_4">
		<text>Let's see if this thing works</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dosent_zhuchok_say_0">
		<text>Well, Kulibin... Either be pricked, or pray. To me to Feni that I in a bar and here am forbidden to kill</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dosent_zhuchok_say_1">
		<text>EH???...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dosent_zhuchok_say_2">
		<text>Not, do not include Durikov - tell, what for you have pushed Tipster in mine PDA? Or you with all PDA do such preventive maintenance???</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dosent_zhuchok_say_3">
		<text>It is not my initiative... To me have paid... Money then was very necessary, and I took a sin on soul. The person came, has shown your photo, has left money and the transmitter. Whence he has learnt that at you will break PDA - I do not know</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dosent_zhuchok_say_4">
		<text>Listen, to me here recently the buddy the knife has presented - tell such the Samurai trimming did... I Want to try on you this ancient ceremony. Or you nevertheless will remember still that eh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dosent_zhuchok_say_5">
		<text>I am More I know than nothing - that person was with a bandage on the person and in a hood. Kombez at it was a little unusual - ashy colour... I such did not see never... The work Radius beetle - is insignificant - therefore somewhere there is powerful enough receiver of signals. Still I can tell with the big share of probability that that person has come from Pripyat or about Chernobyl - NPP as if was Monolithian...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dosent_zhuchok_say_6">
		<text>it is fine, while we will postpone an ancient ceremony. Impotent men and so suffices</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_say_one_0">
		<text>Greetings. What happens? Something you is oddish look for the Zone. Girls here any more in wonder, but... In the Sarcophagus... By the way, whence you have learnt about Bugs in my PDA?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_say_one_1">
		<text>Greetings, Streloks. I knew that you will come, and it is more help me to ask there was nobody. My name is the Lightning. I want it or not, but we should co-operate. I hope, as you not against - advantage of it will be mutual. At us many go in similar overalls. Conveniently. Their protection much more exceeds any your copies of suits. About Bugs - was to establish the necessary frequency only enough... Initial our plans included an establishment of contact to the person which you know as the Black Doctor, however it's plans and workings out can damage to the purposes which we pursue</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_say_one_2">
		<text>We? But I of anybody more you do not see. What for the purposes and why I?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_say_one_3">
		<text>You are impatient and hot. There is time for everything. In this cellar there is a portal in other measurement. Be not surprised. Your Black Doctor was mistaken in the Zone origin a little. The portal was formed recently, but there is also one more, older. Both were inactive, but explosion on stations and, especially, repeated explosion on Generators somehow could activate them. Where they conduct - to you to know early, and it is not necessary, likely. I will tell one - after their activation the part of isomorphs has moved to the Zone, and it is inadmissible</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_say_one_4">
		<text>If it is fair, I have understood nothing. What portals and isomorphs? I live in the real world</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_say_one_5">
		<text>I too live in real, but the world. All is simple. I here to collect isomorphs - let in your understanding it there will be simply subjects. If it not to make - fragile balance between two streams of energy will be broken. But will make it not so simply - the part of isomorphs is found already out and used in the Zone. The first example - that artefact which you have recovered recently any girl. The second - weapon manufacturing - that bomb, which explosion you saw - a variant of use of a part of an isomorph, fortunately - inept - differently anything live would not remain on many miles. But - weapon workings out go. On how many I know - you with a companion wanted to stop manufacturing of these killing bombs. Through both portals in the Zone for the purpose of gathering of isomorphs have sent me and one more person, but teleportation has appeared unsuccessful - I hardly was not lost, and here my companion who used the second portal - most likely was lost</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_say_one_6">
		<text>Also what further?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_say_one_7">
		<text>And further - affairs are bad. My device for search of isomorphs was gone at porting. But it is half-troubles... It has appeared that in your environment I cannot depart for a long time from an active portal - as soon as its energy ceases to operate - I feel extremely badly. The second device was at my companion... Where there is an old portal - I do not know. I ask - find for my person, last message from it has come some hours ago - he tried to make the way on a roof of one of houses in a Limansk - there there should be a teleport, but in the house there were any people, and I do not know, whether it is live and where the device. Without this gauge isomorphs not to collect. A house picture on which roof I will send a teleport in your PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_say_one_8">
		<text>Well... I while have understood it is a little, but I will be engaged in searches. And how you? I will send you the little man good for protection</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_say_one_9">
		<text>It while the superfluous. It is not necessary, that someone knew about my presence, even the friend. For me it is not necessary to worry - while the portal nearby - me threatens nothing. I have managed to open all Drury in this laboratory. Go forward and you will find a way out. But be careful - the gauge shows presence of live beings</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_say_one_10">
		<text>Mysticism any... Though... If there is any energy of what I was convinced all is possible. Especially in the Zone. I will get out through a hall with generators aside Chernobyl-2 - there just the door is</text>
	</string>
	<string id="semetskiy_vstrecha_0">
		<text>Hello, the stalker. Thanks for the help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="semetskiy_vstrecha_1">
		<text>Greetings, Yury. How many on the Zone I go, and with you the destiny did not reduce</text>
	</string>
	<string id="semetskiy_vstrecha_2">
		<text>And it is good that did not reduce. I about you too heard. Artefak? Uk I at you was... The Monolith Splinter you remember? Not-not, it to me without need now. The destiny my such - to die and be revived. When I have thought for the first time of desire at the Monolith - have noticed this splinter - visors... Yes only have fallen down me mutants near to station. Has revived an hour later - and artefact in a backpack and is not present - someone has cleaned... Then this Art at you has appeared - these are hearings</text>
	</string>
	<string id="semetskiy_vstrecha_3">
		<text>I know the one who has taken away from you Art - but excuse, you a corpse were... By the way, I want to ask - whether you met in the Zone of the person without a foot and whether you heard about isomorphs?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="semetskiy_vstrecha_4">
		<text>I Will answer - is not present, about isomorphs I did not hear, but heard about some subjects with unusual properties... By the way, I have found a backpack in this house with entertaining cartridges - all could not take away - not to carry away... The part should be thrown out on a floor - you can descend, look. It is rumored that from these subjects ways on not reconnoitered territories can open a part - and believe, not too it is not enough these territories. These subjects are easy for defining - from them characteristic light, and a part proceeds - are similar to unfamiliar artefacts. On one-legged - there is such stalker, recently it saw, and strangely enough - he too was interested in these isomorphs. Bragged that at it is Pribotchik any for their definition. It has left on Generators</text>
	</string>
	<string id="semetskiy_vstrecha_5">
		<text>In this house, you speak? Thanks, I will look. Yes, and for Navodkau on one-legged thanks - it is necessary to visit behind it on Generators. Far, truth. And you that will do further? I too was at the Monolith - but, apparently, that it is a deceit...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="semetskiy_vstrecha_6">
		<text>It now a deceit. I too repeatedly there happened - thought, I can return the death - to revive and be constant in the Zone - business not from pleasant. It seems that a real artefact, big and powerful someone has now replaced on simple luminous a Dummy which continues suit stalkers... What's next? And further business habitual - I will go on the Zone to be wound - can also the destiny will reduce us. I know a short path on Generators, time you there has gathered, hold co-ordinates - it is useful</text>
	</string>
	<string id="semetskiy_vstrecha_7">
		<text>we Will hope that else we will see. For Perehodik - many thanks. I will go, in the house I will look - that there for unusual cartridges, and then - for one-legged at Generators</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_first_0">
		<text>Well and where you were going to descend, a companion Maloholny? By the way, it is bad to kill stalkers for the sake of a profit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_first_1">
		<text>Yes so, anywhere... Simply now Marauder has divorced - more than artefact cheap... I did not kill Anybody, it already was dead... Yes, I will not hide, I searched for it. But not to kill, and to understand...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_first_2">
		<text>Understand? I will tell to you - you have got too far for the invalid in a hat. Forgive, anything personal. Give the device, and in the next world to you be reckoned as the choice at you is insignificant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_first_3">
		<text>And there is it, no device... More truly - to you it not to find, and without it - not to find and all the rest. But time such business - agrees barter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_first_4">
		<text>Barter? It from what maternity home you took, what I with you will conduct a primitive exchange? Do not climb there where does not follow. From your trade in subjects known to us can there will be an irreparable. Give the detector on-good and be engaged in more peace affairs. Not the secret that on your fault is created the deadly weapon. I saw its trial variant. I at all do not ask, to whom you submitted these subjects, I hope for your long tongue</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_first_5">
		<text>I simply dealer. I and itself collected for a long time info about unusual properties of some subjects, and on it earned. That with them did further - me uninvitingly. Money is necessary to me. If you not in a course - a normal artificial limb for my foot in Russia manage in one million - so to say - all for the people and for its blessing. And outside of Russia - and that is more expensive... I once again will repeat - I killed nobody, I knew that somewhere in a Limansk there is an unusual teleport. For the sake of its searches I have spent there many days. I have noticed the person in unusual outfit and only wanted to communicate, but was not in time. At that stalker there was only a notebook - but to take I it there was no time - the dinner, and the soldier from me bad wanted to continue mutants...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_first_6">
		<text>it is a pity To me... But I do not contain an orthopedic workshop, however I know the life price in the today's world behind perimetre is a copeck. For life of the one-legged invalid - I give half-copecks. But I not the barbarian, therefore that you sell - should return there, whence undertook. So you want in exchange?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_first_7">
		<text>the photo is necessary To me. In total one and only. This photo of the Monolith in the Sarcophagus. I the invalid, and time at me will not be the detector for these strange subjects - that let though there will be this photo. To the Sarcophagus to me not to get any more. I will tell to you truth - about one year back, on Pripyat one fanatic has shot at me from grenade launcher - as a result - I have lost a shin and bled to death. However one person - fine has helped me, is more true - has saved life. No, it there was not The Doctor... As I have understood - it was long found somewhere in Sarcophagus cellars... In one Perkrasny day - it has told that leaves for ever - leaves in other measurement and has given me the detector, having told that it is more to it it is not required. I then have thought that it has gone balmy. The only thing that I could hear intelligibly - in one of Sarcophagus cellars there is a teleport which should transfer to any place where there is a special camera - the Monolith cannot be photographed simple Fotikom. More - I did not see this stalker. Bring to me a photo - and I will give you the detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_first_8">
		<text>Somehow all it is oddish looks... Either you keep back, or something do not know. Well, I will try to find a teleport in cellars of the Sarcophagus and to photograph the Monolith. For now - Ghost for you will look, I will recommend it you to send in other measurement without any teleports if you have deceived me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_fotka_okey_0">
		<text>I to you Have made the Monolith photo... But, seemingly, that you have a little deceived me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_fotka_okey_1">
		<text>Has deceived? I promised to give the detector - and a word I will constrain. Where a photo?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_fotka_okey_2">
		<text>Here it, take away</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_fotka_okey_3">
		<text>Yes, it is. Billeting... Also it is all - more anything? Here, like figure should be...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_fotka_okey_4">
		<text>Figures? What figures? I have found a teleport, it has transferred me almost to the Monolith. I took a photogun which there someone has left, and have made a picture. Or something not so?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_fotka_okey_5">
		<text>it is strange... Such impression that on a photo someone has erased something...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_fotka_okey_6">
		<text>Yes it is simple in a backpack dangled, while I on the ground was dragged - here and rubbed. Give the detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_fotka_okey_7">
		<text>Eh... Here an I'll luck... Here the detector. As operates, and that defines - will understand itself. And I should think what further to do</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_fotka_okey_8">
		<text>Here is a business market. If you anywhere have not gathered yet - my person - Ghost call - with you will stay here - together more reliably from mutants to be protected. I hope - make friends. I will warn him</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_fotka_neud_0">
		<text>There was I at the Monolith, but a photo to make decernable - the film in a gun lighted has appeared...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_fotka_neud_1">
		<text>Here an I'll luck... It is loss of losses. Give the detector I to you I can not</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_fotka_neud_2">
		<text>you Can. You perfectly know that if you a corpse - that it more and most it not to be necessary for you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_fotka_neud_3">
		<text>Time so - that I go on a principle, and any more I will not concede, even if I will die - from you 120 pieces on my future medical survey and treatment. Believe, this detector costs Garazdo more. There is at you such money?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_fotka_neud_4">
		<text>Not the question, certainly is</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_fotka_neud_5">
		<text>it is good, here's your detector. As operates, and that defines - will understand itself. And I should think what further to do</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_fotka_neud_6">
		<text>Here is a business market. If you anywhere have not gathered yet - my person - Ghost call - with you will stay here - together more reliably from mutants to be protected. I hope - make friends. I will warn him</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_fotka_neud_7">
		<text>Is not present, such money at me is not present...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_fotka_neud_8">
		<text>Is already your problems. As there will be grandma so will be and Dedkov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnonogiy_fotka_neud_9">
		<text>it is good, there will be to you grandma</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnon_bablo_detektor_0">
		<text>Here your money, Rockefeller...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnon_bablo_detektor_1">
		<text>Here's the detector. As operates, and that defines - will understand itself. And I should think what further to do</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnon_bablo_detektor_2">
		<text>It is a business market. If you anywhere have not gathered yet - my person - Ghost call - with you will stay here - together more reliably from mutants to be protected. I hope - make friends. I will warn him</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pili_foto_poddelka_0">
		<text>Greetings. I look, you here were not bad arranged. Village, the nature, vodka, Kosterok... Here Ghost has told Me terrible secret...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pili_foto_poddelka_1">
		<text>There is such business. And you remain - not nevertheless circles on the Zone to reel up - rest is always necessary. What for secret?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pili_foto_poddelka_2">
		<text>Speak, you the two at school from a diary Striral. Has not forgotten still how it becomes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pili_foto_poddelka_3">
		<text>Eh. So it was for a long time... There peroxide, vinegar and potassium permanganate is necessary. Where them here to take? If only an edge to try...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pili_foto_poddelka_4">
		<text>Here also try. Here a photo - evidence from it it is necessary to erase</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pili_foto_poddelka_5">
		<text>it is possible to Try, but result I can not guarantee. Take a walk minutes five - ten</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pili_foto_poddelka_6">
		<text>Apprx. I Will have a rest while it is sensitive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pili_psevdofoto_ok_0">
		<text>Well, how affairs? It's a go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pili_psevdofoto_ok_1">
		<text>It has turned out, but it is not especially good. Here, hold</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pili_psevdofoto_ok_2">
		<text>Eh. Yes you that, a stupid axe of figure cleaned off? To a hole Daughter a photo... And at what school you studied - there, likely, teachers either blind, or slanting were...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pili_psevdofoto_ok_3">
		<text>Well, as has managed... You will Give - you will tell that the lock from a backpack rubbed...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pili_psevdofoto_ok_4">
		<text>M-yes... The Counterfeiter from you will not turn out. Well it is fine. I have gone on Generators, still we will meet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizr_odnonog_say_0">
		<text>Greetings, thanks that insure. I should be winded in the Sarcophagus... You after all heard dialogue... Look after the client - suddenly again plants - if I will not return - pay off under the account</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizr_odnonog_say_1">
		<text>it is good, I will look after. Not Rastraivaytes. You again have started something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizr_odnonog_say_2">
		<text>Then I will tell. By the way - Fang is live, an old fox... Only you while keep mum - he asked not to speak yet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizr_odnonog_say_3">
		<text>It is live? It is good news. Well, I look - I here one yet at affairs... All right - if that - send SMS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizr_odnonog_say_4">
		<text>the EC. I will try to be winded in a quickly way</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizr_odnon_foto_0">
		<text>Like all it has turned out. The special detector at us. It defines rare Arty and isomorphs - be not surprised, I too thought that it is delirium, yet have not done some shooting found in a Limansk interesting Patronchikami...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizr_odnon_foto_1">
		<text>Isomorphs?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizr_odnon_foto_2">
		<text>Yes, is such then. In the former control center of O-consciousness the portal has opened - there was a girl... EEh... In vain you smile - I seriously. So here, seemingly, that it from other measurement, also that communication of energy of the Zone with any other energy nevertheless is. The Black Doctor was not right or it is simple about it has held back... You still stay with one-legged - he does not finish speaking obviously something, and try to find out, to whom he sold isomorphs and that he knows about a code in a photo. And I - and I will try to contact this girl - the Lightning her name is - I will consult what further to do</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radist_say_one_0">
		<text>you will not deign to share the information after happened, the neutral? Who these people also what you with with them here did?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radist_say_one_1">
		<text>Yes I, actually, not at affairs at them... Something of type semicaptured. They are people from grouping Last day. I a little that know about them...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radist_say_one_2">
		<text>Mda... It is Sometimes better to chew, than to speak. It is not necessary to think that hedgehogs all around in a fog. Your portable radio set behind the back in weight in 15kg just also says to me that you here casually and at all at affairs...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radist_say_one_3">
		<text>it is good, be on yours. I use a portable radio set for communication with the companion... Not so long ago it has found out at the stalker of one about different strange subjects... We also were engaged in Their search last two months and that found - sold - the gain goes quite good, much more, if Arty to sell... Not so long ago it has left towards a Limansk behind any device, and I, as usual, remained to wait on our small base in Pripyat... My companion does not have portable radio set, therefore I only can catch a signal of its PDA...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radist_say_one_4">
		<text>It seems that at it not only portable radio sets are not present - but also feet...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radist_say_one_5">
		<text>Eh. Here... And whence you know???? It as does not contact three days...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radist_say_one_6">
		<text>I Know. But - at first I will listen to your fables. What further?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radist_say_one_7">
		<text>Yesterday with me buyers of the goods have communicated - we still had some packs of abnormal cartridges... Have offered money Neplozhie, have hammered in an arrow at a review Wheel, have met... It also were here these people - are not present, not that you have killed - the first group. They are almost invisible, and I Opredlyayu them on voices. I asked them to sell to me one of their bullet-proof vests, but they have told - that it is impossible - each armor works only with the individual owner - if it to remove, it will be usual Bonezhilet... The good hiding place was necessary to Them - two from them dragged something big and heavy - as in a consequence it has appeared - cases from shells. I did not begin them to speak about our dwelling on Pripyat, and have moved here - from a door I knew a code, especially, these people did not stint money. They have carried here the things and have left, having told that others will soon come and all from a hiding place will take away. Here they also have come, I it have again opened a door, and here you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radist_say_one_8">
		<text>it is harmonious at you it turns out, it is direct Roots Chukovsky... Who these people? They it is obvious enemies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radist_say_one_9">
		<text>I Gororyu truth. To me all the same who they - me have not touched, though, apparently, silently despised, but they have no place to take the goods more... Yes, they asked, when there will be still goods - but communication with my companion was not, and I could not answer them... I a little that know about their clan. It is said that their former leader was killed several months ago by someone from neutrals... The Clan has broken up, people have dispersed on different other groupings... But any person and anew all Oedinil has then come... Whence they have come - I do not know...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radist_say_one_10">
		<text>That in a hiding place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radist_say_one_11">
		<text>You can to look itself also if any more has not looked. There any letter, a part from the camera and any shells...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radist_say_one_12">
		<text>That for the camera? And where this your habitation in Pripyat? Something I will not remember there caches...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radist_say_one_13">
		<text>It only its part. Speak, it consists of three basic parts - mostly photo equipment, bases and lenses. In our dwelling on Pripyat, in the safe there is this lens. But my companion very strictly has forbidden me it to give. Where there is a base from the camera and a film - I do not know. And we live - in kindergarten - there there is a pair of premises about which nobody knows as the door is closed...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radist_say_one_14">
		<text>it is fine, Relax, and we will consult what further to do</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bunker_kluk_say_0">
		<text>Greetings. How you managed to track down them??</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bunker_kluk_say_1">
		<text>Cunning of hands and any swindle. This radio operator has recustomized the portable radio set on other frequencies and I have overheard dialogues. By the way, it and its companion not still to you have told... Yes - the radio operator long watched and removed conversations and co-ordinates - and know whose? Yours... The Bug at you was in PDA, and and - long time so all our actions were known</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bunker_kluk_say_2">
		<text>Mda... Here means, who me a pass... The Rights there was a Lightning... But - info obviously somewhere merged, it is obvious that it worked by request. Only here on whose? This clan? As there it... Last Day</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bunker_kluk_say_3">
		<text>This grouping has broken up - Ghost has settled the leader is was to our first meeting. I to it will tick - it is time to tell that I am live - and it to you in a PDA will throw off all that at it is on this group. It is visible that it not simple marauders, and at all mercenaries - and the weapon and ammo - nice... Judging by that they did not have a hiding place on Pripyat - they here not often happen, and judging by that shells - they have dragged, possibly, and are engaged in their manufacturing. Here only where and from what... Yes, and who such Lightning???</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bunker_kluk_say_4">
		<text>You forgive, I have already ticked Ghost that you are live... Vidilis we with it - it now just grazes a companion of this radio operator - one-legged it. And on the Lightning - in general mysticism... Zamonolite, isomorphs and other... Though the theory part - proves to be true - energy of the Zone co-operates with any energy, some portals in any measurements have opened... Therefrom and taken these strange subjects, and it is probable, and charges for bombs... I to you will throw off in PDA info if there will be a free minute, and with the Lightning - I will acquaint. Only do not fall - Vidon at it - obviously not local... What we will do further?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bunker_kluk_say_5">
		<text>Cases of bombs - we will leave while here, tough weight to drag - if bombs - they them are necessary to these insurgents and in bank will make, would be from what. I think, we will make so: you Porasprosi this radio operator into the account beetle - who, when and where - after all somewhere it the info merged - but not now, later. For now - we with it remain here - it will necessarily be kindled, if muddles - I will guess... And at the same time - can and little people to Taynich will come... And you while - descend to Pripyat - look that at them for dwelling in kindergarten - it after all has broken up, though it for language and did not pull that there there is which-that an interesting... Can - in a trap us wants to send - SOS, but it is necessary to check up. And if will not tell, to whom the info about our group merged - I it will adhere to a knife switch also Jerboas I will beckon... The Joke. But - Poshantazhirovat - it is necessary it is sensitive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bunker_kluk_say_6">
		<text>Eh. And if them will come much? People serious...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bunker_kluk_say_7">
		<text>Not so it is terrible lines, as its baby. I have put pair of traps - on the quiet even the rat will not slip - I will have time to be prepared</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bunker_kluk_say_8">
		<text>Frets. Throw off SMS, if that</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_radist_deth_0">
		<text>Greetings. How you managed to track down them??</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_radist_deth_1">
		<text>Cunning of hands and any swindle. This radio operator has recustomized the portable radio set on other frequencies and I have overheard dialogues. It is a pity that it was lost... Now we do not learn much. However, which that is. He long watched and removed conversations and co-ordinates - and know whose? Yours... The Bug at you was in PDA, and and - long time so all our actions were known</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_radist_deth_2">
		<text>Mda... Here means, who me a pass... The Rights there was a Lightning... But - info obviously somewhere merged, it is obvious that it worked by request. Only here on whose? This clan? As there it... "Last day"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_radist_deth_3">
		<text>This grouping has broken up - Ghost has settled the leader is was to our first meeting. I to it will tick - it is time to tell that I am live - and it to you in a PDA will throw off all that at it is on this group. It is visible that it not simple marauders, and at all mercenaries - and the weapon and ammo - nice... They, possibly, here not often happen, and judging by that shells - they have dragged and are engaged in their manufacturing. Here only where and from what... Yes, and who such Lightning???</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_radist_deth_4">
		<text>You forgive, I have already ticked Ghost that you are live... Vidilis we with it - it now grazes foreheads of one - similar, from the same company - one-legged. And on the Lightning - in general mysticism... Zamonolite, isomorphs and other... Though the theory part - proves to be true - energy of the Zone co-operates with any energy, some portals in any measurements have opened... Therefrom and taken these strange subjects, and it is probable, and charges for bombs... I to you will throw off in PDA info if there will be a free minute, and with the Lightning - I will acquaint. Only do not fall - Vidon at it - obviously not local... What we will do further?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_radist_deth_5">
		<text>Cases of bombs - we will leave while here, tough weight to drag - if bombs - they them are necessary to these insurgents and in bank will make, would be from what. I think, we will make so: is info that on Pripyat at this radio operator Taynichok was, and judging by their negotiations - somewhere around kindergarten - descend - look that at them for dwelling, can you will find that the interesting. And I while here will remain - possibly, little people a hiding place still will visit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_radist_deth_6">
		<text>Eh. And if them will come much? People serious...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_radist_deth_7">
		<text>Not so it is terrible lines, as its baby. I have put pair of traps - on the quiet even the rat will not slip - I will have time to be prepared</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_radist_deth_8">
		<text>Frets. Throw off SMS, if that</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_sadik_dialog_0">
		<text>Well what now to do? There are two parts from any camera, where a missing detail and for what it in general is necessary - not clearly. The radio operator has told that any paper from the safe of visors One-legged...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_sadik_dialog_1">
		<text>do not panic. We will make so. First of all - own safety of. Restlessly at me on a shower... Take mines - and establish on a ladder - in case visitors will welcome - for control - only itself do not undermine, and I while with Ghost will communicate - let will shake on-svoemski it Odnogogogo...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_sadik_dialog_2">
		<text>Frets. Now pair-three traps on a ladder I will put</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_sad_dialog1_0">
		<text>Well what now to do? There are two parts from any camera, where a missing detail and for what it in general is necessary - not clearly. In the safe - it is empty... Can One-legged Tryahonut Horonenko?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_sad_dialog1_1">
		<text>do not panic. We will make so. First of all - own safety of. Restlessly at me on a shower... Take mines - and establish on a ladder - in case visitors will welcome - for control - only itself do not undermine, and I while with Ghost will communicate - really, let will shake on-svoemski Odnogogogo...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_sad_dialog1_2">
		<text>Frets. Now pair-three traps on a ladder I will put</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_sad_after_mina_0">
		<text>Well, what there at Ghost?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_sad_after_mina_1">
		<text>Business such. There is an electronic address of any forum... At this forum there is foreheads one - that the hacker, whether the buddy of the former owner of this paper... So here, URL, by data - just conducts in its profile, and in a profile there is a map on which the place one is noted... It is known that it somewhere in red wood, but where exactly, and that in this place - is not clear, not to glance yet in a profile to this forehead... Here's URL: http://www.tecnobacon.com/final.html</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_sad_after_mina_2">
		<text>Well affairs... The Internet is necessary. All right, my advanced PDA can will manage to hook on this forum... Conspirators, Mlyn. And if is not present - it is necessary all Red Forest climb round...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_sad_after_mina_3">
		<text>Try. We while here remain</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kluk_sad_after_mina_4">
		<text>it is good. It will turn out or not - and it is necessary to move to the Red Forest</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_say_snip_0">
		<text>Hello, old man. Like I did not see you here last time...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_say_snip_1">
		<text>Hello. The I am Forester... Has fulfilled a life in this park for many years. Indeed that did not see - I sometimes leave the new shanty - bones Porazmyat, on the Zone to walk, news to learn... Though I am old, and still much I can, and district well I know. What for do I have this company?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_say_snip_2">
		<text>Eh, I will ask on good luck - can it is fair you will answer - one is necessary to Circuits me for the camera. Only it not the usual camera. And still - I search for subjects different - they can look somehow, are shone as Arty and possess different properties...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_say_snip_3">
		<text>Well. I will tell to you fairly - is at Circuits me for the camera. I have found it casually - have faltered in wood - have looked narrowly - and he... or she is the soldier dead in the invisible armor. Took a sin on soul - has searched - at it and there was this Circuits... And Chertezhik was how to collect the given device. And that person to one of the oldest local clans belonged - Last day is called. Very long ago I did not meet them, but speech not about that. I the person not greedy, and age not that am will take behind what has come. But there is at me a request to you - the sniper appeared in district. It is visible - that the extremely skilled and from former local - well is guided. Every day here Navedovatsya became, Chertyaka - will make a shot, will kill the person - and disappears. What for - it is not clear. Children that at my dwelling have located that only did not do - both protection exposed, and ambushes arranged, and mines-traps put - and track down it could not. It is insulting. I have thought - it is time also to me to remember youth - Mosinka with optics is, eyes see still well, wood I know - I will sew the rascal... And here you come... Has put just for the master - you will try humanity one to track down it yes to hit while it still weight to the people has not ruined?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_say_snip_4">
		<text>it is possible to Try...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_say_snip_5">
		<text>one life depends On result of your work not, but anyway - I will give you a camera part, and at successful issue of a suit - I will give still something, yes I will tell weight of the curious. I advise to make so - district here big - from the earth or from hills you it you will not see, and it will not approach close, therefore - get on a roof of this station - there there is a platform Nepolohaya... Take Ruzhishko with good optics yes the field-glass. When and where there will be this murderer - it is not known, so it is necessary to you to conduct the review on station perimeter... Try to see it earlier, than he will have time to make a shot and to disappear. Special attention give to bushes, trees and hills</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_say_snip_6">
		<text>Has understood, I will try. As I will climb on a roof - I will inform</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_ok_0">
		<text>Well, old man - I have settled that reptile... Has hardly noticed - distance big, and to hide it is able...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_ok_1">
		<text>the Good deed has made. Give me all details of the camera - I will collect it - Shemka at me is. I hope, all at you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_ok_2">
		<text>Yes, here - all here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_ok_3">
		<text>Well. Business not the artful. For now listen that I will tell. This unit can be used differently - as a usual pistole, using optics from the camera, and it is direct - to do photos, using shop under a film. That for a film where it to find and than pictures will differ from the usual camera - I do not know. Now - about those subjects that you spoke... It is known to me which-that... There was at me a companion - the pupil to me has come even before failure at station... It Has found casually plan any - with marks. Saw I that plan. One mark was somewhere in the bunker around the present Sarcophagus, the second - in a Limansk - in one of houses. As I have understood are there were teleports. Year two has passed, as my companion has left towards Pripyat - to investigate these teleports - here such it was inquisitive... Some times sent me messages - said that one teleport has found and conducts researches, and itself lives somewhere on Pripyat...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_ok_4">
		<text>Listen - it a case not the invalid? Eh. Wanted to tell - feet at it whole?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_ok_5">
		<text>the Invalid? No, it was more healthy than the healthy. Why was - it was gone... I have received Last message about two months ago. He has informed that it managed to use one of teleports... Teleported it, obviously. Not there. Where planned - in any city - judging by the description is a so-called Dead City - there was before failure a small town near to the Military warehouses, yes only all ways and exits there and therefrom are now closed - anybody still did not manage recently to reach there, and all people that there were - have appeared in a trap... Many stalkers and now catch not clear messages - possibly just therefrom... It is More than messages from my pupil did not come. Recently I went - looked old paths in that city - they are impassable...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_ok_6">
		<text>On how many I know a situation - possibly, your companion has used a portal in other measurement, and has got to the Dead city... Someone wanted to repeat it itinerary, but was not in time. It seems that it should be done and me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_ok_7">
		<text>If I will be necessary - you know, where me to find - if I will not be going to walk on the Zone. Yes - here still that - I saw in wood a corpse... Judging by outfit - someone from the Last Day clan. Look there, where a funnel. Nearby hunters like have broken camp - said that the animal there has appeared the strange... Be more careful</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_ok_8">
		<text>Thanks, I will look</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_ok_9">
		<text>Is not present, in Nychke they...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_ok_10">
		<text>Bring - without the scheme anybody as this weapon is necessary will not collect. And then and conversation we will continue</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_ok_11">
		<text>it is good, I will be winded to Nychki and back</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_neud_0">
		<text>has not carried to me, old man - that reptile has left... It is good to hide is able, even my skill has not helped...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_neud_1">
		<text>Yes, I heard a sound of its shot sniper... It is necessary to children again on funeral to be sent, yes to a family money to collect. I hope, you will bring the feasible contribution - badly when the family without the supporter remains... Thousand 50 quite will suffice. Yes, here still that - give me all details of the camera - I will collect it - Shemka at me is. I hope, all at you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_neud_2">
		<text>Yes, here - all here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_neud_3">
		<text>Well. Business not the artful. For now listen that I will tell. This unit can be used differently - as a usual pistole, using optics from the camera, and it is direct - to do photos, using shop under a film. That for a film where it to find and than pictures will differ from the usual camera - I do not know, but while, obviously, you can use it only as a usual pistol with optics. Now - about those subjects that you spoke... It is known to me which-that... There was at me a companion - the pupil to me has come even before failure at station... It Has found casually plan any - with marks. Saw I that plan. One mark was somewhere in the bunker around the present Sarcophagus, the second - in a Limansk - in one of houses. As I have understood are there were teleports. Year two has passed, as my companion has left towards Pripyat - to investigate these teleports - here such it was inquisitive... Some times sent me messages - said that one teleport has found and conducts researches, and itself lives somewhere on Pripyat...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_neud_4">
		<text>Listen - it a case not the invalid? Eh. Wanted to tell - feet at it whole?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_neud_5">
		<text>the Invalid? No, it was more healthy than the healthy. Why was - it was gone... I have received Last message about two months ago. He has informed that it managed to use one of teleports... Teleported it, obviously. Not there. Where planned - in any city - judging by the description is a so-called Dead City - there was before failure a small town near to the Military warehouses, yes only all ways and exits there and therefrom are now closed - anybody still did not manage recently to reach there, and all people that there were - have appeared in a trap... Many stalkers and now catch not clear messages - possibly just therefrom... It is More than messages from my pupil did not come. Recently I went - looked old paths in that city - they are impassable...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_neud_6">
		<text>On how many I know a situation - possibly, your companion has used a portal in other measurement, and has got to the Dead city... Someone wanted to repeat it itinerary, but was not in time. It seems that it should be done and me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_neud_7">
		<text>If I will be necessary - you know, where to find me - if I will not be going to walk on the Zone. Yes - here still that - I saw in wood a corpse... Judging by the outfit - someone from the clan Last Day. Look there, where a funnel. Nearby hunters like have broken camp - said that the animal there has appeared the strange... Be more careful</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_neud_8">
		<text>Thanks, I will look, I know this place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_neud_9">
		<text>Is not present, in Nychk they... And money while such is not present...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_neud_10">
		<text>Bring - without the scheme anybody as this weapon is necessary will not collect. Well, and of the finance - also I will not remind - itself not small. And then and conversation we will continue</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_snip_neud_11">
		<text>it is good, I will be winded to Nychk and back</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_babki_0">
		<text>I Have brought money and parts from a photopistol</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_babki_1">
		<text>Well, give. Here business not the artful. For now listen that I will tell. This unit can be used differently - as a usual pistole, using optics from the camera, and it is direct - to do photos, using shop under a film. That for a film where it to find and than pictures will differ from the usual camera - I do not know, but while, obviously, you can use it only as a usual pistol with optics. Now - about those subjects that you spoke... It is known to me which-that... There was at me a companion - the pupil to me has come even before failure at station... It Has found casually plan any - with marks. Saw I that plan. One mark was somewhere in the bunker around the present Sarcophagus, the second - in a Limansk - in one of houses. As I have understood are there were teleports. Year two has passed, as my companion has left towards Pripyat - to investigate these teleports - here such it was inquisitive... Some times sent me messages - said that one teleport has found and conducts researches, and itself lives somewhere on Pripyat...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_babki_2">
		<text>Listen - it a case not the invalid? Eh. Wanted to tell - feet at it whole?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_babki_3">
		<text>the Invalid? No, it was more healthy than the healthy. Why was - it was gone... I have received Last message about two months ago. He has informed that it managed to use one of teleports... Teleported it, obviously. Not there. Where planned - in any city - judging by the description is a so-called Dead City - there was before failure a small town near to the Military warehouses, yes only all ways and exits there and therefrom are now closed - anybody still did not manage recently to reach there, and all people that there were - have appeared in a trap... Many stalkers and now catch not clear messages - possibly just there from... It is More than messages from my pupil did not come. Recently I went - looked old paths in that city - they are impassable...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_babki_4">
		<text>On how many I know a situation - possibly, your companion has used a portal in other measurement, and has got to the Dead city... Someone wanted to repeat it itinerary, but was not in time. It seems that it should be done and me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_babki_5">
		<text>If I will be necessary - you know, where me to find - if I will not be going to walk on the Zone. Yes - here still that - I saw in wood a corpse... Judging by prinadlehnosti - someone from a clan Last Day. Look there, where a funnel. Nearby hunters like have broken camp - said that the animal there has appeared the strange... Be more careful</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lesnik_babki_6">
		<text>Thanks, I will look, I know this place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_video_story_0">
		<text>Greetings. Here base of Duty. And what there is in general such a Duty? Before whom a duty?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_video_story_1">
		<text>Eh. You from what Russian remote places here have got? Or you pretend to be? Whatever was your answer - better once to see, than hundred times to hear. Here, look in mine PDA and remember - that there is a DUTY and that waits for it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_video_story_2">
		<text>Well, we will look...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dialog_0">
		<text>Greetings to a science and to all who is connected with it. I have read recently a note one, speak at you is artefact one unusual?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dialog_1">
		<text>Greetings. How it correctly to tell on yours slang - who snitched? Like a Zone not small, and you will conceal nothing. Yes, has brought one svobodovets from Yantar a find... Has sold to me. Has told that a flower-flower, and properties - strange - tells, zombie friends of a steel... I now study this artefact - at it is and still not clear properties. One I can not understand - on all laboratory indicators is a usual window plant. A riddle...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dialog_2">
		<text>Partially I know the answer. In this flower - particles of alien energy which, possibly, it is impossible to define in the laboratory ways. Concede me this isomorph... Eh. An artefact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dialog_3">
		<text>As you have told? An isomorph? The strange name. Well, I will give you it. Absolutely free of charge. From you it is required only two photos in exchange...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dialog_4">
		<text>Here, it our way. At once it is visible a grasp of the Russian businessman - absolutely free of charge is called... What for photos to you are necessary? I have a camera, but I do not know a principle of its work and there is no film</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dialog_5">
		<text>I have three packs of a film - it will approach to any camera, even to the digital. It is a film-hybrid. Where your camera? Allow to look... Eh. What strange model... It seems that it while is intended only for usual firing, and for photographing replacement gate the mechanism is required. As I have understood - or it can photograph, or is simple Srelyat. Simultaneously it to make Navryatli it will turn out, but modernisation will occupy less minute, and after all it will be easy to return how was before. One but - the film will take more places, than the usual cartridge, therefore shop capacity will be reduced. The design and the sizes of optics say that it is possible to do by the given weapon any unusual pictures... There is a mechanism of dry instant development... Where you it took? If want to learn hardly more about this entertaining machine - I recommend it to leave at me for a while. After will make the necessary pictures for me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dialog_6">
		<text>Leave? That it has turned out as with Heart of the Poltergeist? I will think. Now a reality - that for photos are necessary to you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dialog_7">
		<text>you happened in X-16 and know that from our laboratory there there is a short transition. As you in a course that there are installation which someone has muffled recently, but has not destroyed. It looks like the big brain... The Similar copy is and at me - but I plan to create similar on the base of a brain of the controller, instead of for the account of artificial energy. No, do not think - I do not gather anybody zombie - I simply plan to receive in such a way energy. That from you it is required - rise to a control panel at top level X-16, and simply photograph this brain. About correct focus by manufacture of a picture to you will specify an inscription on the camera display. Further - the second picture... Here it is more difficult and more dangerous... There is data that on an exit from this laboratory on any tunnels - in them there was a new version of the controller... It is unusual and extremely dangerous - under stories - a brain and sticks out from his head... You should find these tunnels and to make a photo of this controller. I ask to consider - that at you only three units of a film - the miss is possible only one. And, please, it is not necessary to try to do pictures of everything that moves - once again I will repeat - you have only two Konkternye the purposes and one photocartridge for emergency</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dialog_8">
		<text>Has understood, not the first day married. I know these tunnels... It seems that I soon will become the professional photographer...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dialog_9">
		<text>Yes, here still that... Take at once with itself this new artefact - in the form of a window plant - it behind your back - zombie should become to you more friendly... And still - somewhere in factory territory where the entrance in laboratory, is zombie with which you Nepomeshalo to communicate - svobodovets that has brought this artefact, has told that saw at it an interesting subject - but has not had time to buy - it was frightened off by children from grouping Duty - speak, they now protect the bunker of mister Sakharov. At successful performance - you are waited also by one more gift personally from me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dialog_10">
		<text>Have intrigued. Well, I will go to do photosessions for the Playboy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_0">
		<text>There was I in X-16 and on Yantar, saw that controller...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_1">
		<text>Saw? And it was possible to make photos? And a photopistol have brought for studying?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_2">
		<text>Yes, here they, take away. You wanted to learn possibilities of the camera and the purpose of all this design? Take - but do not break. I hope for your fair answer Vvdalneyshem. Yes, you wanted to give me something still?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_3">
		<text>Photos... Really they at me? Yes, yes... Leave the camera - I necessarily will look at it also to you I will inform result. In an award - take some packs of cartridges - say that they abnormal. Itself I can not check up - I am not on friendly terms with the weapon...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_4">
		<text>Here for it - thanks, cartridges are always necessary. I wait from you for messages. And still - I want to warn - someone hunts for this camera, I advise to ask to strengthen Vitamin protection</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_5">
		<text>Is not present, photos to make Nepoluchilos... And what for to you they? Same a paper...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_6">
		<text>Here disappointment... Yes, indeed - a paper... I will leave Well, that abnormal flower to you, I will more truly sell - I after all have bought him. 50000 I will arrange</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_7">
		<text>Here money... You wanted to learn possibilities of the camera and the purpose of all this design? Take - but do not break. I hope for your fair answer further. Yes, you wanted to give me something still?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_8">
		<text>Yes, yes... Leave the camera - I necessarily will look at it also to you I will inform result. And about what award speech - you after all have not executed the commission...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_9">
		<text>Is not present so is not present. I wait from you for messages. And still - I want to warn - someone hunts for this camera, I advise to ask to strengthen Vitamin protection</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_10">
		<text>Is not present, money while at me such is not present. Will be - I will bring. You wanted to learn possibilities of the camera and the purpose of all this design? Take - but do not break. I hope for your fair answer further. Yes, you wanted to give me something still?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_11">
		<text>Yes, yes... Leave the camera - I necessarily will look at it also to you I will inform result. And about what award speech - you after all have not executed the commission... Money do not forget to return</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_12">
		<text>I will not forget. I wait from you for messages. And still - I want to warn - someone hunts for this camera, I advise to ask to strengthen Vitamin protection</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_13">
		<text>It was possible to make only one photo... The Brain from X-16</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_14">
		<text>One? Well, it too not absolutely bad variant. Give. Yes, yes... Leave also the camera - I necessarily will look at it also to you I will inform result. But, unfortunately, from me you do not receive a bonus...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_15">
		<text>Well... I Wait from you for messages. And still - I want to warn - someone hunts for this camera, I advise to ask to strengthen Vitamin protection</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_16">
		<text>It was possible to make only one photo... Mutating the controller</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_17">
		<text>One? Well, it too not absolutely bad variant. Give. Yes, yes... Leave also the camera - I necessarily will look at it also to you I will inform result. But, unfortunately, from me you do not receive a bonus...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_18">
		<text>Well... I Wait from you for messages. And still - I want to warn - someone hunts for this camera, I advise to ask to strengthen Vitamin protection</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_19">
		<text>I do not have with itself photopistol</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_20">
		<text>Bring - very much it would be desirable it obtain. And we will continue dialogue</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izomorf_dial_ok_21">
		<text>it is good</text>
	</string>
	<string id="money_vernul_klenovu_0">
		<text>Here, I repay a debt</text>
	</string>
	<string id="money_vernul_klenovu_1">
		<text>Ah. It to eat very well. Your photopistol is almost analysed</text>
	</string>
	<string id="money_vernul_klenovu_2">
		<text>It pleases</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chasovoy_trezv_say_0">
		<text>the Weapon is? Though - about what it I... Do not take in head to get it. What Lyada you as the tank here Presov? To live has bothered?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chasovoy_trezv_say_1">
		<text>Zdraste to you. I from Cordon go. Asked a parcel to transfer to the local captain - 10 bottles of good vodka...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chasovoy_trezv_say_2">
		<text>Something is suspicious... And who asked to give?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chasovoy_trezv_say_3">
		<text>eh... The Dealer local - Sidorovich a nickname...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chasovoy_trezv_say_4">
		<text>a Sidorovichovich? Strange... However, at it for a long time balls for rollers call in. Vodka not singed? Is not present? Give here, and itself - go whence has come - tough by the stranger in the Zone to do</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chasovoy_trezv_say_5">
		<text>Aha. Has understood-has understood, I leave...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chasovoy_trezv_fail_0">
		<text>Health I wish</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chasovoy_trezv_fail_1">
		<text>the Stalker, whether has gone nuts you here to gad, Chertyaka? That it is necessary?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chasovoy_trezv_fail_2">
		<text>Bore parcel to you - vodka... Yes has broken pair of bubbles on the journey... Not many, still I will approach - as soon as I will find replacement to that has broken...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piyan_kap_say_0">
		<text>Sssstalker? By what Xhrena you here do? Vodka is?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piyan_kap_say_1">
		<text>Greetings, Captain. Yes, vodka is</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piyan_kap_say_2">
		<text>Well so that was silent???? Pour... Hryapnem, and I Ssekretttt will tell to you, therefore as I sail away from this bucket to the Earth on Bolshujujujujuju... Yes that remains in a bottle - Syudy give</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piyan_kap_say_3">
		<text>Eh, Vmazhem for the Earth for Big... Yk... You something wanted to tell?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piyan_kap_say_4">
		<text>Ufff... To Tell? Instead of a shit I did not want to tell. I carry here to the heads Chumodyn with the report on our valorous assholes... And tries I carry it? It is necessary to you? You can those papers half a year ago. To wipe up, also remains. About! No, it is better to wrap in them mother-in-law's pancakes! It you is necessary? Yes it has gone all far and with whistle. More shortly, I change for a bottle. And if is not present - stamp from here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piyan_kap_say_5">
		<text>Here, there is still a vial for the good person...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piyan_kap_say_6">
		<text>Here it Zammmechchatelno. Dddavay it, darling here. And in Adyutany it Preosvyaschens... The excellency you do not wish? Bbbudesh big-poppies free of charge Hawala. Ha-ha... Time has brought vodka - take away chumodan - it from that... Not it is at that, a distant tree... Also stamp, stamp from here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piyan_kap_say_7">
		<text>Has understood, already I stamp. Arividerchi, chief</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piyan_kap_say_8">
		<text>Not, vodka is not present more...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piyan_kap_say_9">
		<text>Neeetttt???? Then correct skis in other party. On Nett and vodka... Vessels are not present</text>
	</string>
	<string id="piyan_kap_say_10">
		<text>Well is not present so is not present, I leave</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_artmodifikator_0">
		<text>Well chief, vodka for you and a recipe for me. Is there anything else you can offer?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_artmodifikator_1">
		<text>A stalker with a head for business, you've proven yourself to be reliable. See the sad faces of my men? Its not because we don't have enough vodka, thats not the problem. There is another reason. Recently an officer came for a suprise inspection. We had a little too much vodka that day, and the report looks bad. He has threatened to send us to the Zone center, and I will miss the chance to be promoted. You will ask, why am I telling you all of this? I need to get that document case before he goes back to Kiev with his report. You will find him camped with his gaurd in a ravine behind the agropom base. The document case is with him somewhere near...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_artmodifikator_2">
		<text>I don't understand, what am I gonna do. Just walk up and say Hey... gimmie the documents? Going in guns blazing doesnt seem like good odds to me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_artmodifikator_3">
		<text>Theres no need to kill anybody. Ive got a plan, approach the gaurd in the ravine and don't have a weapon in your hands. You will take 10 bottles of vodka with you. Five I will give to you, the other five you need to find yourself. But I advise you to take 2-3 more bottles in case of an emergency. So bring at least 12 bottles. You will approach the sentry, you will give him 10 bottles, you will ask him to give them to the captain. Further - hide nearby, watch with your binoculars, be patient. When you see they are obviously drunk, approach the captain and get him to talk. You might need to give him somemore vodka before he will talk. Find the document case and bring it to me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_artmodifikator_4">
		<text>Whats in this for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_artmodifikator_5">
		<text>You will be very pleased. You bring me that case, and I will give you A transmutating device. One of my comrades took it off a dead scientist. A useful tool for any Stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_artmodifikator_6">
		<text>But nevertheless, why me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_artmodifikator_7">
		<text>I cant send any of my men to Agroprom. For the stalker to do this would be much easier. When the shit hits the fan when the documents come up missing they wont be able to trace it back to me. But the most important condition is - don't kill, shoot, or cut anybody. All that is required from you is - to give the vodka, to look and to wait. Here, I sent the location to your PDA. Stay away from the lookout towers on Agroprom so you don't cause an alarm...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_artmodifikator_8">
		<text>Ok I understand. If I bring the case I can pass through your checkpoint free of charge?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_artmodifikator_9">
		<text>What? You will receive the device and further donations to fund our drinking you will regularly pay in the form of vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_artmodifikator_10">
		<text>I really like gadgets so I will do this... Give me those 5 bottles...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_chumodan_otchet_0">
		<text>I'm worn out from carrying all that vodka, they drank so much I don't think they will remember I was ever there...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_chumodan_otchet_1">
		<text>You brought the case?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_chumodan_otchet_2">
		<text>Yes, here it is. Seven kilos of pure compromising evidence...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_chumodan_otchet_3">
		<text>Fantastic!... Give it here, we will use these papers for fire kindling. Here's your device as promised</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_chumodan_otchet_4">
		<text>Well you major are very sharp... Now I understand, why our army is invincible...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_chumodan_otchet_5">
		<text>Yes, here it is. Seven kilos of pure compromising evidence... But it didn't turn out as stealthy as planned...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_chumodan_otchet_6">
		<text>Give it here. We will use the paper for fire kindling. Only here I am afraid because of your bad luck there's going to be trouble. And its necessary for you to pay for our troubles. You will need to bring 25 bottles of vodka to finish our original deal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_chumodan_otchet_7">
		<text>Well you major are sharp... Now I understand why our army is invincible... Alright, I will go collect the 25 bottles...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_chumodan_otchet_8">
		<text>Failure is all I've returned with. I don't know where the case is hidden. Maybe try again tomorrow?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_chumodan_otchet_9">
		<text>This is very bad... It is necessary to get drunk and forget this mess, and you will help me with it. Bring me 40 bottles of vodka. Then you can have the device</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_chumodan_otchet_10">
		<text>How many???? That much would get a company drunk for a week. Well major, Now I understand why our army is invincible... Alright, this is going to take awhile...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_chumodan_otchet_11">
		<text>Failure is all I've returned with. I don't know where the case is hidden. Maybe try again tomorrow?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_chumodan_otchet_12">
		<text>Give it here. We will use the paper for fire kindling. Only here I am afraid because of your bad luck theres going to be trouble. And its necessary for you to pay for our troubles. You will need to bring 40 bottles of vodka to finish our original deal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuzy_chumodan_otchet_13">
		<text>How many???? That much would get a company drunk for a week. Well major, Now I understand why our army is invincible... Alright, this is going to take awhile...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vodku25_prines_0">
		<text>Major... Here's the vodka - 25 bottles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vodku25_prines_1">
		<text>Give it here. And one - for pass. A joke. Take your device</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vodku25_prines_2">
		<text>Thanks major...soon to be the lieutenant colonel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vodku40_prines_0">
		<text>Major... Here's the vodka - 40 bottles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vodku40_prines_1">
		<text>Give it here. And one - for pass. A joke. Here's your device</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vodku40_prines_2">
		<text>Thanks major...soon to be the lieutenant colonel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernomor_zombi_say_0">
		<text>Eeeee... The Soldier-soldier... Do not shoot! EEh... And I know you. And for a long time I know... Give an antizombie - to steam of pieces - the is not present... There is it at you???</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernomor_zombi_say_1">
		<text>Yes is. And whence you know me???</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernomor_zombi_say_2">
		<text>Give, give an antizombie... Then I will tell, how we will get out from this territory... Together me n you will take away - that behind road - I hope that with you they will not shoot down me... But remember - after I will accept a preparation - zombie both you and to me enemies will be - I already passed this school - last time Semetsky to me have helped...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernomor_zombi_say_3">
		<text>it is good, we will reach stalkers. Here an antizombie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernomor_zombi_say_4">
		<text>There are no at me now two packings of an antizombie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernomor_zombi_say_5">
		<text>Eee... Well, bring then... At Night I saw it at the tunnel under road - but have not had time to take - very nearly have not killed...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernomor_zombi_say_6">
		<text>it is good, wait. I will bring</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chern_zombi_dialog_0">
		<text>Here, I have brought an antizombie. And whence you know me???</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chern_zombi_dialog_1">
		<text>Give, give an antizombie... Then I will tell, how we will get out from this territory... Together me n you will take away - that behind road - I hope that with you they will not shoot down me... But remember - after I will accept a preparation - zombie both you and to me enemies will be - I already passed this school - last time Semetsky to me have helped...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chern_zombi_dialog_2">
		<text>it is good, we will reach stalkers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernomor_stalk_say_hello">
		<text>Hail my zombie friend!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernomor_stalk_say_0">
		<text>Well here, have reached. Yes, Vidon at you not so...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernomor_stalk_say_1">
		<text>Thanks for the help. And Vidon - and what you wanted from the person, which 2 times zombie? In general, not clearly, as I can is still normal think. Have betrayed me, all have betrayed... I from a clan Last day... More truly - was from it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernomor_stalk_say_2">
		<text>Well, for all do not speak. Anybody from itself respecting anywhere against the will will not go also anything will not do, with rare exception. And into the account of Last day - hardly is more detailed. Our roads were crossed by will of destiny, but the information has not enough</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernomor_stalk_say_3">
		<text>And that to tell - the leader Captain Maine about one year back have eliminated. The grouping has broken up... All have crept away as cockroaches... Basically are former local residents - like me. But not so long ago - the clan managed to choose the new leader. Who it - very few people knows. I personally - never saw. The former Monolithians, any members of spetsnaz and small group of scientists have entered into a grouping top. A main objective - the full power in the Zone, and accordingly - and all incomes of sale and other... But tactics - another - is going to wage now nobody more sniper war and to eliminate singles in the form of leaders of hostile groupings... Tactics of their involving in clan numbers as has not crowned success - and now there is a plan of global elimination of groupings. Yes-yes... Bombs. No, nobody will put rocket attacks on bases - charges with artefacts of awful force will be simply put...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernomor_stalk_say_4">
		<text>It you are serious? And the monolith - that stone, what in the Sarcophagus refers to it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernomor_stalk_say_5">
		<text>I was only the ordinary fighter... On how many I know - this Monolith is the energy compiler. To which - does not know. The group of scientists studied this question - they managed to use partially this energy. But - this group for the unknown reasons has collapsed. Was called - O-consciousness</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernomor_stalk_say_6">
		<text>Yes, I heard about the such... What did you do on Yantar? Yes, and where a staff of Last day? I searched almost all the Zone, but did not meet...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernomor_stalk_say_7">
		<text>And Navryatli you will meet. It in the Dead city. There there is no road - at least - very few people knows it. And here therefrom - there are some paths and to get on known territories easier. On Yantar - I repeatedly already... You in a course that someone have disconnected burner... But that brain, as now Zombiruet many in district - is live. It eats a reserve energy source - and this source - is almost eternal... I know where it, but to get to that premise could not - Nesmorya on protection - zombie me... Has once helped Semetsky, but also repeated attempt to find an entrance in this premise has appeared unsuccessful... Such impression that a teleport is somewhere in other place - not in the laboratory and not in factory territory. My task just also was - to bring these energy sources</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernomor_stalk_say_8">
		<text>But after all somehow you were going to return to the Dead city?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernomor_stalk_say_9">
		<text>I should meet the person who knows road. But on communication with it in due time I did not leave - who with zombie will communicate? You here that - I will have a rest a little and I will try to contact this person... It is necessary to me though it is sensitive in itself to come. And you - you while be engaged in the affairs. I will inform you, if that. Yes - here still that. On a building roof, where in a cellar an entrance in a lab - a rifle washing lies also cartridges a little. Cartridges - at a ladder on the second floor. I take away it could not - with such rifle Zombirovonnomu three times as much dangerously - stalkers on me would open hunting. Vintovochkami especial, abnormal, easy and reliable. You with the weapon you will not surprise - but can will fit - it unique in the Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernomor_stalk_say_10">
		<text>it is fine, we will look at a gift. Give, come to feelings - at us still will be to talk about what. And I while Dolagok will return to Professor to one on Warlab</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_esc_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello. We will talk after - and where the Panther???</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_esc_dialog_1">
		<text>Yes it just from a cellar has pulled out any backpack and has incurred it towards a post. Speaks, all APPRX</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_esc_dialog_2">
		<text>All GONE???? For a long time has left? Here blah... Give, the father, move with pistons - it is necessary to catch up urgently with it, differently will be late. Show the way...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_after_deaf_0">
		<text>You of that here, instead of to a fire?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_after_deaf_1">
		<text>Yes what there a fire while... I will find, who has dragged here this bomb... Eh, it was necessary not to stop in village, and to do a halt already behind perimetre. We after all have solved for couple of months, and can and on absolutely - on Continent to move... Here to you also have moved... It after all for me has come to the Zone... And now - even there is nothing to bury...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_after_deaf_2">
		<text>the Father, do not strew salt... To me too now not Sakharov... My fault that happens - above a roof... It after all, as a matter of fact - all village has rescued. I will be engaged in this business - more truly, already I am engaged - only problem places more many...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_after_deaf_3">
		<text>You know - I with you will go. Now it nothing me, and hunting most personally to strangle those who has made it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_after_deaf_4">
		<text>There is no father... You remain while here - nerves treat. One I have got used to be wound on the Zone and if together - I worry about you... I pledge a word that as that I learn - you will not pass the ending. That is why - collect the strength - your help for certain is required. By the way - you from local. Heard about grouping Last day? Speak, a staff at them in the Dead city, and there nobody knows roads...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_after_deaf_5">
		<text>For a long time I was not in a city volume but which that I know. In a Limansk - precisely there is there a transition - in one of cellars. The teleport there is... But to activate it it is not simple - there protection strong. It is necessary to know access to doors, the code number of the panel of activation moreover and to clean protection from a control lever a teleport. Itself did not see, but I know - the buddy my intimate friend - used that teleport. Yes it only was lost, for a long time was lost - still before I that Art - Heart of the poltergeist have found... Is, for certain, and still paths - but all of them have exchanged after repeated explosion on Generators where them you will find...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_after_deaf_6">
		<text>It is helpful information. It seems that the code from the panel of that teleport is available for me, but much still is not present - though, likely, to find a cellar in a Limansk - not a special problem... I will reconnoiter all - and I will let to you know. A bomb in Novice camp - a grouping handwork Last day it is exact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_after_chernomor_0">
		<text>Greetings. To you here it is not boring? And scary, likely - one in the bunker...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_after_chernomor_1">
		<text>I habitual. You have collected a part of isomorphs? It is good. Show, what are. So... Yes, undoubtedly - they are important - but there are no main things which possess energy... All right, time still is, I hope, and these isomorphs will lower power hyperactivity</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_after_chernomor_2">
		<text>What to do with them further?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_after_chernomor_3">
		<text>Come into a portal that nearby, and simply throw out on one all isomorphs, except cartridges. If the isomorph is suitable - the portal will take away it, and in exchange will send you any thing or a subject. What exactly it will be - it is not known - from a piece of bread or a piece of paper to rare artefacts. But - be careful - can teleport and mutants... Do so - send an isomorph, collect that energy of a portal and only granted to you then send the following isomorph. After successful sending - we will continue dialogue</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_after_chernomor_4">
		<text>Has understood, now I will try</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_sey_tri_0">
		<text>Crap...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_sey_tri_1">
		<text>It is surprised? I, by the way, too. And you have collected a so-called photopistol?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_sey_tri_2">
		<text>the Photopistol? Yes, but at me it is not present with itself. And whence you about it know? I, like, spoke nothing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_sey_tri_3">
		<text>I know much. As it is the extremely important to send this photopistol in other measurement. Because of it there can be many problems</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_sey_tri_4">
		<text>Yes? Here did not know... And about what Energitic isomorphs you spoke? Though as they look and where to search - even with the detector - all Zone not Obbegat...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_sey_tri_5">
		<text>They can look somehow. I heard that one or slightly earlier were used in any laboratory... With their help installation which that the zombie, whether killed received additional energy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_sey_tri_6">
		<text>Somewhere I already heard the such... Hmmm... Similar on X-16... I just therefrom... All right, I will think how further to arrive. There will be news - will inform. By the way - time you monogenic know - can will organise a teleport somewhere more close to Yantar? At me so the familiar person is - I will try to enquire</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_sey_tri_7">
		<text>I am not especially assured, but it is possible to try. In a room where someone has destroyed microgenerators of a projector of scientists - them called - O-consciousness - become in the center of their radius - I will try to direct energy portatora to this place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniy_sey_tri_8">
		<text>Someone? Hmmm... It is good. As I will take of a position - I will inform</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plot_dialog_say_0">
		<text>Hey, the master, gain...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plot_dialog_say_1">
		<text>What happens?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plot_dialog_say_2">
		<text>You will not believe. I was in the Zone recently. I go from Cordon, become tired, fall in sleep near to the road... I Wake up that Chuvstruyu that on the person someone a hot rough rag drives. Eyes has opened and... It is good that the pampers were... I Look, near me three Fleshes... One which is closer to me licks me, and the second or third guzzles in my backpack...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plot_dialog_say_3">
		<text>Ge-ge-ge... You, hour, to it under a tail have not looked? Possibly, it is a female was, they Novice love... Well, has seized a portion of adrenaline?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plot_dialog_say_4">
		<!-- changed "Deserted Eagle" with "Fort-14 and Bear Detector" - aleks1970 -->
		<text>eh. To you it is ridiculous... And I the first time in centimetre from the person have seen such physiognomy. And it was necessary to lie motionlessly and to suffer its mockeries. Then they were frightened off by something, and they have escaped... But the matter is not in this, the second or third flesh escaped together with meal from my backpack and they have also take my Fort-14 pistol, Bear Detector and letters in their stomack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plot_dialog_say_5">
		<text>Well so to you has carried - well that it you for the male not Poschitala and has not continued the relation. Ge-ge-ge... Than I can help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plot_dialog_say_6">
		<text>Find those animals, which are eaten my things and return me my pistol, decoder and letters</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plot_dialog_say_7">
		<text>Well, it you, the brother, has bent... Well, you offer, that I of all fleshes on a dump have found and have settled, moreover and have learnt contents of a stomach of everyone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plot_dialog_say_8">
		<text>Well, in general yes... If you will help - I will tell to you Sekretik one. Saw I here something a pair of clocks back...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plot_dialog_say_9">
		<text>That, still to steam of fleshes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plot_dialog_say_10">
		<text>Is not present. I saw people in invisible suits... No, do not think that I am crazy - I have noticed them only because the weapon at them hardly was allocated... They of fleshes also have frightened off. And here that was further - I will tell, if you will help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plot_dialog_say_11">
		<text>it is good. Wait here. I will go in Garbage of fleshes to drive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plot_dial_ok_0">
		<!-- changed "pistol" with "weapon, detector" - aleks1970 -->
		<text>Well. I Sent on errands fleshes, have found your pistol, detector and letters. Now - I listen to your story</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plot_dial_ok_1">
		<text>That's great! Listen. From outside the scaffold that at a bog on the right - left small group of people - the person 6-7. Have stopped almost at gate - where now and we stand. Two from them have removed armor, really, is invisible. One has dressed a jacket of the rookie, took the big backpack and has left and Cordon. Another - has dressed another armor - any greenish with yellow strips...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plot_dial_ok_2">
		<text>It is color of Freedom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plot_dial_ok_3">
		<text>Yes, can be - I yet did not see people from this grouping. And so, this the second too took a backpack and has left on road deep into dumps. The remained five have conferred, have left a backpack, and have left in a direction of parking with the thrown technics. I have caught only one - it was a question about any generators...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plot_dial_ok_4">
		<text>the Backpack? They have left a backpack? Where it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plot_dial_ok_5">
		<text>It at one of trees that to the right of me. I wanted to look that there - but it Fonit - and at me while is not present artefact against radiation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plot_dial_ok_6">
		<text>it is fine, thanks. Take away the belongings. Letters should hardly be washed - in a stomach at a flesh unsterily. And contents of a backpack of those people - I will take</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chern_foto_dialog_0">
		<text>Greetings. How do you feel?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chern_foto_dialog_1">
		<text>Health - that shit cow. Time at you the loved one was lost because of some morons from Last day listen. This Photo-Pistol was made by one blind master, and it intended for the clan top management - it was necessary to them to find somehow the people who have dispersed on different groupings earlier. For work of this pistol the son of that master specially went on bases of groupings and put in certain places special labels - one - in the location of the photographer, the second - as a target for reflexion of an impulse of the camera. Usually such places settled down at fires where it is a lot of stalkers. After successful photographing on a film the necessary stalker or his name was highlighted. As it turns out - I plainly do not know, but said that each insurgent has a label. Probably, it is and at me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chern_foto_dialog_2">
		<text>it is clear. But as how to find the necessary position for a shot and where to aim?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chern_foto_dialog_3">
		<text>Well where to aim - the photogun will prompt to you - crosshair a sight you will redden also learn that the camera is ready and it is necessary to shoot at this place. And here into the position account - whence to shoot... It is a problem. I have approximate points only for base of freedom and village of rookies on a cordon. In both cases these places on heights - houses, towers and to look and direct the camera it is necessary towards fires. Here, on it to a photo - an approximate arrangement of a point of a shot in Cordon, and a point on the base of Freedom I will throw off in yours PDA a bit later. Usually, at correct Zatyatoy positions to the photographer the signal arrives</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chern_foto_dialog_4">
		<text>And where now that master what has made the camera?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chern_foto_dialog_5">
		<text>Eh... After tracing of the majority of the insurgents who have left in other groupings, it have simply eliminated, that he did not stir the superfluous. And his son - tried to burn alive, simulating accident, but it managed to survive. I then have a little helped it, but it is strong Obgrel... He to me also has told all this story. Where it now - I do not know. I know only that it has disassembled a pistol and has thrown all in parts in a teleport, and that is has scattered them on the Zone... The Big good luck that you have gathered all</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chern_foto_dialog_6">
		<text>Well... You have rendered me the big service, thanks. If that is required, or will go where - let know. I now in Cordon - it is necessary to find the murderer. And then - on base to Svobodovtsam. Listen, has absolutely forgotten... And whether it is a lot of to people about this pistol knows? And then to me recently have suggested it to exchange... Though - I did not speak about it words</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chern_foto_dialog_7">
		<text>About a gun the person 10 knows, it is no more. Mine to you council - while to anybody it do not give. Good luck. I while here will remain</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chern_foto_dialog_8">
		<text>it is strange... All right, still we will meet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shuher_dialog_0">
		<text>Something you, the guy, is not especially similar to the local. Where a way you hold?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shuher_dialog_1">
		<text>Well, and you are unlike the local. I here already - from the Zone have a rest very long ago... And you that that??</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shuher_dialog_2">
		<text>Not so often masters dress jackets of rookies to have a rest. What, dodge with a bomb and the heap of death - has not turned out? Not clearly, that you of a foot have not made at once or for the next goods wait?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shuher_dialog_3">
		<text>WOW, drive like a maniac do you??. What bomb, what goods?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shuher_dialog_4">
		<text>the Goods are simple. At you exactly ten seconds to repent in Sodeyanom. Why I speak - here, you see, the gun at me is the interesting. I know that your bosses to it very much are interested... And still a backpack - you in Garbage at transition to Cordon have left it, when the group has dispersed. You learn?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shuher_dialog_5">
		<text>Yes you have gone... To the Goat in a crack. I do not know any guns, bosses and backpacks and never I regret that has made and I do. Pity - last feeling</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shuher_dialog_6">
		<text>Well... Good bye. Consider that you have missed possibility Popolzovavshis the last feeling and to cause it in others. But - not to me to decide your destiny though - I would crush you as a bug</text>
	</string>
	<string id="say_nashel_uroda_0">
		<text>the Father, has found I that freak that a bomb has brought also mines has placed. Though... Even if it and not it, the moron still that. Here his name on a photo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="say_nashel_uroda_1">
		<text>It is assured, what it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="say_nashel_uroda_2">
		<text>For 99 percent</text>
	</string>
	<string id="say_nashel_uroda_3">
		<text>it is good, I will talk to it - all I will understand. Thanks. You now than plan to be engaged?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="say_nashel_uroda_4">
		<text>Under data - the same bomb have dragged on base of Freedom. It is necessary to find or it, or that reptile that has dragged it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="say_nashel_uroda_5">
		<text>it is good. Hurry. Business important. Keep me informed</text>
	</string>
	<string id="say_nashel_uroda_6">
		<text>Not, I while with you will remain - when such moron on village Laziet - to hold an Ear Vostro better</text>
	</string>
	<string id="say_nashel_uroda_7">
		<text>For it do not worry. I took for a long time myself in hands - itself a problem I will settle, if this person still from here has not made a foot. Go, you have a business more important</text>
	</string>
	<string id="say_nashel_uroda_8">
		<text>it is good. If that - you will let know</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svob_bomba_bazar_0">
		<text>Hello, Maine. I see, not local you, but not in it business. SMS read - that, what the recently general channel transferred? Know I to what? To that pale with a plait already from Cordon here goes. Also you know for whom? Correctly, for you. But the chance at you still is - tell where a bomb which you here have dragged</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svob_bomba_bazar_1">
		<text>Eh. Yes there is no its bomb... I See that you not from a clan Last day therefore I speak. Razabral I it, and the case - in a bog has thrown out. Not, it will not blow up - there system artful - yet there will be no interaction of two substances one of which liquid - will be nothing. A node with that liquid I have broken also a liquid have evaporated</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svob_bomba_bazar_2">
		<text>It is assured?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svob_bomba_bazar_3">
		<text>I am not sillier than a steam locomotive - have agreed to establish here it only because differently not to fade to me was from the Dead city... And here those Uwharrie Navryatli will get me - to the people much, protection quite good. Hunting it is sensitive free life to live... And how you have found me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svob_bomba_bazar_4">
		<text>the Scent, sight and experience. By the way, here your photo - take away, it to me more Nikchemu. I hope, you truth to me have told. Tell here that else then - where transition in this Dead city?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svob_bomba_bazar_5">
		<text>Here I do not know it. It is known only by seniors of groups, and that - when they come back from tasks - teleports it specially open... Therefrom... There is no there a free way. While, on-extreme measure, no. And glory to eggs that is not present</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svob_bomba_bazar_6">
		<text>That for a city such? There only your former clan?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svob_bomba_bazar_7">
		<text>the City small. People there different - but, basically, a crime and killers. It is few usual stalkers - them either destroy, or hire. And with me so was</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svob_bomba_bazar_8">
		<text>But after all somehow you for the first time there have got???</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svob_bomba_bazar_9">
		<text>Yes I do not know, how it happens. On Yantar from psi-blow of the controller me has cast away metres on 50-60. Saw that I treat metres in three over the earth... Thought - a fuck-up... Has regained consciousness - and a place has not learnt - and it has appeared in the Dead city...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svob_bomba_bazar_10">
		<text>Here blah... Anybody cannot prompt. And grouping big?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svob_bomba_bazar_11">
		<text>I too do not know It - a part constantly on tasks... In the city - not less than 20-30 persons. About the leader - at all do not ask - never saw. But - I know its one sign, is more true - the symbol is at a clan is the unusual, wide belt, similar cowboys carried or worn... And so this belt - at the leader, you will see - you will not mix. And still - I will tell though - all my troubles from a long tongue - the arrow is hammered at group of Last day in which structure I and have come with any neutral on not Reconnoitered earth... I know, where exactly - at the big stone that near to transition to Militari. Only business - hopeless - it is necessary to creep to them too close to hear dialogue, or somewhere to hide beforehand. But how many it is necessary to wait - it is not known. You can try - climb on this stone - probably that you will not notice and use masking</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svob_bomba_bazar_12">
		<text>Here is efficient info. I know this stone - it at that transition one such, and you - have a rest on freedom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnon_aver_say_0">
		<text>My God, what people... Here a successful meeting... I look, you here had a business conversation of the intimate maintenance? At me already ears have reddened with envy. By the way, Ghost asked greetings to tell to you. Spoke - Popolzuet at personal meeting...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnon_aver_say_1">
		<text>Eh. You heard? Well and the shit with it, I after all anything bad has not told - at everyone the secrets. Money they should me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnon_aver_say_2">
		<text>You are naive as flight of files. Yes who will return money to you? These morons? And whether you know, what they are engaged in terrorism? And bombs do of those isomorphs which you it sell... Eh. sorry - free of charge you give. And it already firing article, the guy, even in the Zone. And it is good that it did not leave yet for territory - though attempt already was</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnon_aver_say_3">
		<text>I did not know It. I was not interested, what for it these isomorphs. My purpose - to earn money and to get into other measurement...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnon_aver_say_4">
		<text>Into the account of other measurement - I doubt, and here that on your fault the person close to me it was lost is exact. Everything that I can make is to facilitate your fate a bullet in a forehead. But with the account that you not in a course - you will give me hiding place co-ordinates this the mongrel and will lie down somewhere on a bottom, differently - you the dead man</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnon_aver_say_5">
		<text>it is good. Now will come SMS with co-ordinates. What's next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnon_aver_say_6">
		<text>And further - I will find a hiding place and I will go to Sakharov. And you - on SMS from these freaks answer tersely - the type is not present, yet has not found... Or at all do not answer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnon_aver_proval_0">
		<text>My God, what people... Here a successful meeting... I look, at you here an arrow? By the way, Ghost asked greetings to tell to you. Spoke - Popolzuet at personal meeting...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnon_aver_proval_1">
		<text>Eh. What for you here? Eh, now - my money cried, and I never learn how to get to other measurement...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnon_aver_proval_2">
		<text>You are naive as flight of files. Yes who will return money to you? These morons? And whether you know, what they are engaged in terrorism? And bombs do of those isomorphs which you it sell... Eh. sorry - free of charge you give. And it already firing article, the guy, even in the Zone. And it is good that it did not leave yet for territory - though attempt already was</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnon_aver_proval_3">
		<text>I did not know It. I was not interested, what for it these isomorphs. My purpose - to earn money and to get into other measurement...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnon_aver_proval_4">
		<text>Into the account of other measurement - I doubt, and here that on your fault the person close to me it was lost is exact. Everything that I can make is to facilitate your fate a bullet in a forehead. But with the account that you not in a course - spread that you know</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnon_aver_proval_5">
		<text>that I know - insufficiently. On Svediniyam, professor Sakharov on Yantar knows, where there is a confidential teleport in X-18 - but it does not know that this teleport conducts in a confidential premise - and in it there should be the power isomorphs supporting work of the Brain from these labs. But Sakharov will not tell where a teleport - I already tried. No arrangements, money and Arty on it operate - it has simply included Little Fool - type I do not know, about what speech. And at Spiteful - there was a material which could Sakharov to talk... Now - all was gone...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnon_aver_proval_6">
		<text>crinkle Pressures - not all can so badly?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnon_aver_proval_7">
		<text>There was a hiding place at Last day on the base of military men on Agroprom - there someone from soldiers - their person. I precisely do not know, where this hiding place - but it somewhere on an attic. Can there and there is that a useful</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odnon_aver_proval_8">
		<text>it is enough of It. I will try to find it, and to you - my council - lie down on a bottom for a while while this Zavarushku will not cease - differently neither money to you not to see, nor lives. If will be necessary - I will find you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saxar_zhena_say_0">
		<text>Professor, hello. I heard that you know about any teleport...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saxar_zhena_say_1">
		<text>AH. Streloks - and you there... But personally for you I will repeat without intonation increase - I do not know, about what speech. By the way - you not about it ask the first me. You, a case, have not sent?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saxar_zhena_say_2">
		<text>If it is fair, have simply given Navodkau. And you tell me a lie. I thought - we old acquaintances. Then - take here it - this subject on you can will affect. Do not perceive it as blackmail or threat - it is better - as mutually advantageous information interchange...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saxar_zhena_say_3">
		<text>Elza? Whence at you a photo? It is live - the photo is made recently. Answer, immediately!!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saxar_zhena_say_4">
		<text>Prof, without nerves. I would like to listen at first to you, but I see that you will not calm down. Accept Sedukenchika - it helps. I do not know, whether this woman and where it now, but I can assume is live. And here that it precisely to learn - teleport co-ordinates are necessary to me, differently both of us remain without the helpful information and we will look against each other as Beech and Byaka...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saxar_zhena_say_5">
		<text>Yes, nerves became to hell... She is my wife - Elza. It was gone very much for a long time under obscure circumstances somewhere in Army Warehouses - it took part in that ill-fated expedition of scientists to the Zone center... About a teleport... Yes, I know its co-ordinates. Still I know that it conducts directly from a surface somewhere in laboratory X-16. Ask - whence I know - I will answer - I casually saw group of scientists - I admit fairly - because of chemical protection could not learn, who it was. They have entered into a teleport, and in some days I have learnt that stalkers saw some bodies of scientists in territory of factory... Their rests picked snorks...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saxar_zhena_say_6">
		<text>Professor, it is not necessary horrors. Tell, where a teleport, and I will try to find out about something about your wife</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saxar_zhena_say_7">
		<text>the Teleport is invisible, therefore he and is difficult for finding out. I have not used it also others there did not send - I not crazy and not the murderer. The teleport is on the blade of the helicopter which has fallen on a bog behind the bunker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saxar_zhena_say_8">
		<text>Well - I should to them use. If I will not return - your wife, possibly, in the Dead city at grouping Last day. But is extremely unreliable information. While I ask you not to be foolish and not to do rash acts. I will keep you informed events</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nashel_plastilin_say_0">
		<text>Greetings. You were right - the teleport to a brain has appeared not in X-16. I have found isomorphs - whole two. But I should give them...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nashel_plastilin_say_1">
		<text>Well... I Congratulate - you have appeared more successfully and is more capable me. These stones are not necessary to me, but I know, who hunts for them...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nashel_plastilin_say_2">
		<text>I too. But to them they will not get</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nashel_plastilin_say_3">
		<text>I do not bear your of malice, you know it. Therefore - listen to my council - do not hurry up to leave these stones - a gait more cleverly. Tell that you have only one - and the second - leave for emergency - I an interior feel, not simple it is isomorphs... And the camera yet do not give</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nashel_plastilin_say_4">
		<text>Yes, it is good that I have not given photo - it very much was useful to me. I and will make - one monolead I will leave to myself. Thanks for council. Still we will meet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniya_plastilin_ok_0">
		<text>the Lightning, greetings. How your affairs?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniya_plastilin_ok_1">
		<text>Greetings. I was already tired here is. You that eh have brought?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniya_plastilin_ok_2">
		<text>Yes, there is something. Look...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniya_plastilin_ok_3">
		<text>It it... Yes-yes is that is necessary - Energetic an isomorph. It one at you? It is said that their only a little</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniya_plastilin_ok_4">
		<text>Eh. Yes, one... And who speaks?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniya_plastilin_ok_5">
		<text>It at us tell - it is known that it was formed not simply at penetration into an artefact of particles of energy - it is required also influence of a powerful psi-field... Yes it is fine, that there to explain - throw it in a portal, receive an award, and after - I can return to the - this isomorph can adjust a portal on carrying over of live organisms to other measurement</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniya_plastilin_ok_6">
		<text>Means, and with you it is possible for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniya_plastilin_ok_7">
		<text>Is not present, Streloks... At the best - simply will occur nothing, in the worst - you will be broken off by energy of a portal... Forgive, but it is truth. Throw a monolead in a portal. Yes, before I will leave - you can and use further this portal for sending of isomorphs is stabilises two opposite streams of energy even more. And we - we hardly will meet more...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="molniya_plastilin_ok_8">
		<text>Well, let will be as you have told</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zlobnuy_sity_one_0">
		<text>I do not care who you are and what you do. You - on foreign soil, and here their orders, which means that you will live on local laws</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zlobnuy_sity_one_1">
		<text>And what kind of laws are?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zlobnuy_sity_one_2">
		<text>You will soon he will understand everything. Either you are with us or you're dead, and no matter who you make it a corpse - mutants, famine or looters. But in their ranks - the ranks of worthy warriors clan last day we just do not accept even the masters, although I admit skilled fighters, we need</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zlobnuy_sity_one_3">
		<text>And who said that I want to join your clan???</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zlobnuy_sity_one_4">
		<text>In this area, only three ways - either death or be jackals and underlings, such as local thugs, or be full-fledged representative of our group. You'll have plenty of time to think, but explain on the fingers - in the direction of the city - do not poke your nose - if you do not have time to shoot our snipers, the shield you will still fail. Stay on the edge of the area - pick up grass... Very soon you're truly hungry, run out of ammo... And famine - their laws</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zlobnuy_sity_one_5">
		<text>What next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zlobnuy_sity_one_6">
		<text>And then - we'll see. If you can survive at least 5-6 days - so there will be a second dialogue with a view to joining our ranks. Do not agree or you'll die before that time - hence, your fate like that. Few people say - but I will give you some advice - somewhere on the outskirts of a group of stalkers - we will not touch them - because they fill up our ranks, recognizing that there can not survive. You can search them and asked farther. I hope you will not get to dine with the monsters, while getting at</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zlobnuy_sity_one_7">
		<text>All right. I find those stalkers and know that you are for fruits such</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zlobnuy_sity_one_8">
		<text>In the in and find out down to business, Tarzan... But remember - you will die - no one will rescue will not come. I will contact you within a few days, if survive...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zlobnuy_sity_one_9">
		<text>Okay. I wish you and you do not glue fins these days - and then there will be nobody to send SMS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parfumer_say_one_0">
		<text>Hello. This, obviously, you sent me a SMS... Strange name. Perfumer eat?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parfumer_say_one_1">
		<text>Yes, I sent SMS. Perfumer, I do not drink. Nickname given for another reason... If I'm not mistaken, you're the one stalker who sent isomorphs through the portal? If this is you, then admire your persistence to get here and before your naive trust everyone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parfumer_say_one_2">
		<text>Well, get here I was not going through that portal, although the visit so hot spot like... And what have the naivete?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parfumer_say_one_3">
		<text>You sent isomorphs those who intended to fight, as far as I know. Good thing I was able to intercept, changing the direction of the portal. Maybe Zamonolite, which not only are you looking for one and there, but you're wrong address. Actually - you adroit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parfumer_say_one_4">
		<text>Lightning? That girlfriend of former Control Center O-consciousness?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parfumer_say_one_5">
		<text>I do not know of such nicknames. But - if this girl wearing a slinky kombeze - that there are several of them, and they all - from top management, last day of the clan</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parfumer_say_one_6">
		<text>M-AH... I'm not used to destroy the women... But, obviously, have to break the law of the mountains. What's wrong with your face?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parfumer_say_one_7">
		<text>Those for whom you are going to break the law of the mountains killed my father and tried to blind me to burn alive, though once we have faithfully served this group... Fortunately, there was one man who has helped me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parfumer_say_one_8">
		<text>Chernomordik. I know him. He was a zombie, but now, like, all right. I collected Photo-Pistol from your father and he told me in very handy. True - the death of a man who was dear to me. For that reason - I'm here. There is another - people from the clan made a deadly weapon and kill their innocent people</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parfumer_say_one_9">
		<text>You're still nothing can be done. The city is protected, I can not help you. I myself - an outcast here... but I do not want to leave, and hence there is no way - portals for exit may open only clan chiefs... I think you have yet to go to stalkers - they are few and they are downtrodden and hungry, they crap all over here think... But I warn you - there are bandits on the location - their camp at the pump - and also, as the city closed the security field, and there are mercenaries. Bypass and those and other long side - or they kill stalkers, and these punitive measures nor I nor you do not need. Mark on the senior - his name is Sanya Tyumen I'll put on the PDA. Talk to him, learn a bit, arms Razzhiveshsya - then - think about what to do next</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parfumer_say_one_10">
		<text>All right. See. Talk - obviously there are still about</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starshoy_say_one_0">
		<text>Hello. You are a senior? Maybe a little to clarify the situation?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starshoy_say_one_1">
		<text>Yes, a senior like me, though debatable. Then - every man for himself - the only thing that is done together - is protection from mutants and more - no one to defend himself - but is useless and there is nothing - no weapons of sensible and if there is - that for him a pair of bullets - and they - bandits yes mercenaries are selected through the day... They argue there is no point - just kill another... That's normal stalkers and go from hopelessness to those bandits, and who in this last day, damn it. Wong, yesterday, only two left. I told them - where you rank beginner? Shot... No, it is still gone. And you, obviously, another victim of one of the teleporters? Prepare for the worst</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starshoy_say_one_2">
		<text>Well, all gloomy... it seems you're a senior in a funeral parlor...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starshoy_say_one_3">
		<text>Not funny. When I went to look for the Forester portal to another dimension, and came here - I too at first was an optimist. But time changes people, and I hope only one thing - that nobody in the Sarcophagus will not find that ill-fated teleport and the camera gun...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starshoy_say_one_4">
		<text>And do not count. I found it and used the code in the Limansk basement. But - in the past. Perfumer has sent me here. I heard of him before. He can be trusted?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starshoy_say_one_5">
		<text>So you read my note... I still did not know the consequences... Perfumer - yes, it belongs to us loyal. It helps, but mostly - advice - he is among strangers... I think that you can trust him. And you continue that going to do? No way out of here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starshoy_say_one_6">
		<text>There is, always, even through well... That's it I'm going to find. Then - to deal with the leadership of shit clan - the more so because my pal has successfully done this with their former ringleader of a few months ago, but it is clear that removing one, it does not resolve the problem</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starshoy_say_one_7">
		<text>And what are you going to shatter the skull in helmet exoskeleton? Dubina? And you do not act shield of the city and you have a magic stick of how his beard Khottabych? Ah... I also found a Spiderman... All of these are coming here, but after a couple of days, think better...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starshoy_say_one_8">
		<text>And what do you suggest? Live and on?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starshoy_say_one_9">
		<text>First - should give people confidence - and that means - to feed and give weapons. And after - and plans to build. And where his arms, then take? In the city - not round your neck. There is a base of bandits near, at the pump. A little bit, there is food and the trunks can profiteer... But - who would? And then - will begin retaliatory punitive measures... Although - there is one idea...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starshoy_say_one_10">
		<text>Go on</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starshoy_say_one_11">
		<text>Every few days - the bulk bandyukov starshengo accompanies her into town. As I understand it - there they are given small jobs, food and stuff, but they are artefacts that accompany the stalkers who agree to join the clan. In the camp at this time is people 7 - 10 protection. It was at this time and there can pomoraderstvovat - yes, exactly. if not ugly word for a stalker. Remove the protection from their base just - I have a few chips removed from the corpses of bandits. Retaliatory attacks can not be afraid - they do not even think that the raid carried out and scored a paltry stalkers, moreover, that they do not get along with the mercenaries - a few times watching their disassembly...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starshoy_say_one_12">
		<text>The plan is not bad. I'll go, but who else? And when?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starshoy_say_one_13">
		<text>A couple of my people watching the bandit camp, they'll help. More - no one will - all too scared, although this does not mean to say. Of provisions with us for a couple of days - then - either hunt mutants, or of the ax to cook porridge. You'll find my people - a label I'll give their location. They will remove the protective field camps, and more - and more - lawlessness and banditry. We need to take food and weapons, while the bulk of the bandits did not return to there feet. You know as the Russian saying? He sits a lot, some less steals. You need to steal a lot. I'll give you a little list about - you'd better try</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starshoy_say_one_14">
		<text>Well, the options for refusal can not see, moreover, that most weapons were needed</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starshoy_marader_ok_0">
		<text>Ah, pomaroderstvovali... Like, it's not particularly noisy happened. Also there were mercenaries - their bodies quite get off the bandits for the tip-off that their camp hirelings pohozyaynichali. Take provisions and weapons</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starshoy_marader_ok_1">
		<text>That's it. The first successful, albeit small operation... Relax - the time you have a sea view. Can perimeter poissledovat, maybe more than Razzhiveshsya. But - in the city did not meddle. Will keep - let you know</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starshoy_marader_ok_2">
		<text>All right. Wander in the area, knowledge of the terrain never hurts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tema_talk_one_0">
		<text>Hello. I'm from Sani Tyumen, to help you. Once the bulk of the gang goes to town?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tema_talk_one_1">
		<text>Help - this is good. The main band is about three hours as the left. That's about to return. The camp remained 6-7 people - mostly small fry... There is one truth - in the exoskeleton... He already wanted to try them a little posherstit - and a couple of drunken mercenaries cornered - one of them a master in Ekze... The operation had to be postponed - we do not pull - too dangerous...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tema_talk_one_2">
		<text>Well, I'm on that? Three of us - we can. What is the plan? But there is one thing but - I did not go through the shield base</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tema_talk_one_3">
		<text>At the expense of margins - do not worry - we ponabrali with dead bandits full chip, which disables this field. And you give. A plan is simple. You're the master - and lure you to be nevpervoy. Try to fill up one or two vrazhin, distracting others - and here we strike. But hurry - soon the main crowd from the city stopovers...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tema_talk_one_4">
		<text>M-AH... Plan a genius. Ah, the warriors... Again, I as cannon fodder to speak?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tema_talk_one_5">
		<text>You and all the loot will get... Well, almost all. By svediniyam - in one of the houses are safe, and always a lot of different boxes lying around... Do not be shy - we can help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tema_talk_one_6">
		<text>Okay. But if any of you zakosit after the commotion begins - and find a safe one zasunu... If everything is successful - dumped after shakedown gardens along the spines in the camp of stalkers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kontrik_say_one_0">
		<text>E... Sorry... How the Zone go, seen a lot, but this... Well, that inertia is not shooting began...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kontrik_say_one_1">
		<text>Hello. Nothing, I'm used to. Many of the shooting, and, in principle, they are right. I nepovezlo, and maybe vice versa - a mutation in the controller not over... I had to go deep into the radar Zone, away from the people. The city then was empty. I know a lot here, and many of the people who came here this fear... I have them - as an unnecessary thorn. To leave me nowhere - and now I stroll along the perimeter. How did you know that they come for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kontrik_say_one_2">
		<text>Perfumer said, asked to help. Says - you know a lot. Anyway, I myself need help now - do not go with this territory, and the city itself does not get - the protection it is installed. Can you advise that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kontrik_say_one_3">
		<text>Perfumer... I know this. He himself was a loser - was stupid enough to fall in love with one of devchenok that guide the clan that inhabits the constant despite the fact that they killed his father and himself almost did not burn... At the expense of help - it is possible, but not easy. To the old trail to the territory, and it again became passable first have to get out of here. And it is hard. All exits and entrances - under the control of the Last Day and are activated only for a short time, when groups are on the job or returning from them. You probably already invited to join the last day? If not - then the offer, but I do not recommend - first, you still will not be released from this territory, and secondly, will be checked - forced to kill innocent people and other craziness... But - there is another option - a talk with the leader of the gang - he explored here for the transition home mom sell. Obmorok his name</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kontrik_say_one_4">
		<text>Obmorok?? M-AH... I'll try to call it a dialogue. What's next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kontrik_say_one_5">
		<text>And unknown. Ask for help - should locate last day that they sent in the right direction from the group. For the group will open the portal - could be to try to slip to freedom. If this works out - I know how to activate the old trail... In the attic of a dilapidated five-story building that area - there taynichok. The gun is there good, you will do. Try it out right from the attic to fill up a couple of snakes in the area. But the main thing - to destroy the assistant chief of security - that is called Beast - do it in the optics of the attic once you see - he wears a green nauchnik. Nix must arrange... Here, take this picture, where cache with weapons. The point from which to shoot - I said blue</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kontrik_say_one_6">
		<text>Well, I'll try. You stay here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kontrik_say_one_7">
		<text>While yes, and then - to be seen. Yes, now, hold one widget... She shows the coordinates. If you can get - I'll send you the coordinates of a small town - there you will find deactivator defense conversion bad job in this city...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kontrik_say_one_8">
		<text>And for that - thank you. If the idea can - send a message</text>
	</string>
	<string id="obmorok_say_one_0">
		<text>Why calling? Live sick? It seems, in appearance - not blotter already</text>
	</string>
	<string id="obmorok_say_one_1">
		<text>Tied with slang. Time has come - therefore you here the most shit. I need access to the city. You go there with our brother. Share. Do not ask what more. Then - after some of my gestures people from the last day of transition and will open a group here and I uliznu with the location. But I'll be back - since infoy of constant transition</text>
	</string>
	<string id="obmorok_say_one_2">
		<text>Folding stele. La Grande skiing - where are the guarantees that come back? I know these... Earn hemorrhoids on their rear, and you have free will? Heather, you rogue...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="obmorok_say_one_3">
		<text>I'll be back. The thing I have here. But without snaryagi, which remained in Limansk - have been slow. Also - if it does not come off - I've got the perimeter teleports Hand... Share. As a safeguard - I give the floor to the master. Obmozguy - the choice you have is still low, and the risk lighted small</text>
	</string>
	<string id="obmorok_say_one_4">
		<text>Word?? Well, who is now on the word believe?? Although the risk - really small, even if nothing srostetsya - I am clean. Smell here: in the perimeter, two defense. For central neither you nor I can not go - it covers the area and adjacent buildings. Appearance - You can turn off, but only for a time. If ever - then you have to implant a chip tracking. It you want? In short, switched off the external, taymerok the PDA you will see - if you do not have time to leave the area before the watch strikes - you're dead. The rest - it is not mine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="obmorok_say_one_5">
		<text>It is quite enough. There is a request, without it, nothing happens. If you do not die - once in the city hum rises, please let malicious, that the city had gone neutral toward ATP. It managed to escape the - unknown</text>
	</string>
	<string id="obmorok_say_one_6">
		<text>Swept up by sending malyavu. Knock knock so, moreover, that the public itself requests. Go to the first perimeter, until you reach - everything will look like in morale. E... The camp I do not forget to ignore the - and then grab a pen before reaching the town. Yes, in the city Do not you dare to stick their noses in the area - otherwise you're dead, too. And now - most importantly, that the Duc Get your body... Ge... but not the one - the hearing organ stiffened. The city can chip poke a limited time - 10 minutes. We have found an easy way to chop their security system - will not fit in time in their gestures - just get out of the perimeter and then log back on. Silly protection system will update your chip time</text>
	</string>
	<string id="obmorok_say_one_7">
		<text>Info separately. By hand, the appearance of morality...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parfumer_say_two_0">
		<text>Hello. I opened the road, track, and he returned - must stop this outrage...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parfumer_say_two_1">
		<text>Yes, I see that opened. It is good, only the local boys will not bast shoe sipping soup, while you were not there... There are two news, and both are bad for you. From where to start? I'll start with the well-known - a force field of the center is still active and disable it from outside Neudastsya, and this means that and make a rampage of shooting you do not succeed. News of the second - held hostage by them... And you know who? Whoever you roads, as far as I know... Dr. Marsh... So scratch now turnips, what to do... I know where he is being held - in a building that the columns - in the square itself. There, an autonomous system of protection, which is independent from the city center. However, the guard boss Tarabya - Bubble up briskly avid... Duda his name. You can try to negotiate, but the MNT will have to be decently - the higher the rank - the more bribes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parfumer_say_two_2">
		<text>Hmm... Here nits... Well, how does he stack must for Doc?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parfumer_say_two_3">
		<text>And now you know how much you give him a non-returnable loan betray... And maybe - he will not talk - the salary he did not like a servant. Do you still smoke, but I'll try entogo companion to the quick hook</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parfumer_say_tre_0">
		<text>Well, go to this party... I do not know whether there is enough money...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parfumer_say_tre_1">
		<text>If not enough - there is always options... I hope you brought masthalat and gun type of abnormal M-16? If all goes as planned - Doctor not get out without your mask... Will you give him snaryagu - let changed and to me gets while you're there you'll geroystvovat. If the deal goes through - doctor comes on the calm water and without masthalata. But - in an area you still can not get through. Until you solve the problem with a hostage, I will try to solve the problem with PROTECTIVE field. On the result - will tell. Do not forget - Duda on the second floor of the building with columns</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parfumer_say_tre_2">
		<text>All right. I will try to settle the sale of a large bribe an official in the performance. Waiting for news</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duda_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello. I'm from Perfumer. How much money do you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duda_dialog_1">
		<text>Business talk. Pollimona satisfactory to me. In stalker with your rank, such money should be. If anything - you're still a gain, and I - a man and a soldier just like the Zone can not climb, and did not want. So - with your Salvage, with me - your doctor. Next - I wind up here, and you - do what you want. Do you have the correct amount???</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duda_dialog_2">
		<text>Yes, I have money. Take. Where is the doctor?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duda_dialog_3">
		<text>Doc here, on the second floor. How to get out of the room - turn right - you'll see time in the tail of the corridor. Tell - me - he is in proportion - and you miss. Wait a bit, now I warn him by radio. I do not recommend making noise until your doctor did not get out of here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duda_dialog_4">
		<text>Got it, waiting</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duda_dialog_5">
		<text>E... And not a lot?? No, that kind of money I have. There is a sum, but less</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duda_dialog_6">
		<text>No bargaining is misplaced. So I give you a moment the fact that you took away his legs, otherwise - do not be offended...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duda_dialog_7">
		<text>Well... will change tactics...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zad_dialog_0">
		<text>E... Man... With your status here Nehram do. Anyway, as you to get here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zad_dialog_1">
		<text>Once arrived - so necessary. The thing I have to your elders. He waits</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zad_dialog_2">
		<text>Yes... There was a bazaar. I thought - a joke... Come</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zad_dialog_3">
		<text>Yeah here are a joke...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_oxran_dialog_0">
		<text>What do you want Bitch?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_oxran_dialog_1">
		<text>Whoa...Miss an anger management course?\nDuda sent me to get the prisoner.\n...\n...\nDo you have a hearing impairment? Will you let me pass?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_oxran_dialog_2">
		<text>Don't get upset inferior...I'll step aside in my own time. Duda has ordered me to do so - but it could be his last orders</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_oxran_dialog_3">
		<text>Okay just let me to the prisoner. I don't care about your problems with Duda - you can sort out any leadership issues yourself</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dcity_dok_obychnyi_say_0">
		<text>Doc, hello. I have bribed Duda for your release. Come on, let's get going before he changes his mind. Perfumer is expecting you at the safe house</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dcity_dok_obychnyi_say_1">
		<text>Hey, I didn't even know I was being held! So does this mean, I've been held hostage?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dcity_dok_obychnyi_say_2">
		<text>You didn't notice?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dcity_dok_obychnyi_say_3">
		<text>So that's it... they have trated me well but I know they are after something? Secrets, forbidden information, hidden stashes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dcity_dok_obychnyi_say_4">
		<text>Doc, I can't believe you are so naive. If you had of told them anything then you would have been no further use to them. They are sly and kill for the sake of it. Let's get going</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_nevid_say_one_0">
		<text>I'm here to rescue you Doc</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_nevid_say_one_1">
		<text>Hey, Stalker. I'm pleased someone has come for me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_nevid_say_one_2">
		<text>No problem - you have helped me an I'm happy to return the favor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_nevid_say_one_3">
		<text>The Last Day clan will now realise that I must be an important person for someone to take such a risk to free me. Its going to get hot around here soon. This clan has been after me for some time now - but I refuse to help them. I'm going to need some Invisibility armor and a good gun to get out of here - can you help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_nevid_say_one_4">
		<text>Here, take this camo suit and Anomolous M16. You will be completely invisible and able to defend yourself. Perfumer is in a safe house on the West side of the city. He is expecting you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_nevid_say_one_5">
		<text>Damn... I don't have a Camo suit I can give you. Perfumer warned me that I would need one - I will have to go find one for you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_nevid_say_one_6">
		<text>I'll be safe if I stay here then</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_nevid_say_one_7">
		<text>All right, I'll go see what I can find</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_obychnyi_say_two_0">
		<text>Doc, here's the Camo outfit and Anomolous M16. I'll wait a bit until you can not get to a safe place, and then finish what I came here to do</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_obychnyi_say_two_1">
		<text>Okay - I'm outta here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_obychnyi_say_two_2">
		<text>Move quickly - the Last Day Clan don't know what's going on yet - you can probably cut through the city center safely for the next 5 minutes, unchallenged</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_u_parfumera_one_0">
		<text>Doc, you made it back okay - good</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_u_parfumera_one_1">
		<text>Yes its safe here and I have my good friend Perfumer for company. Here have your Camo outfit back, it was very useful - thanks again</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_u_parfumera_one_2">
		<text>Yes, its an excellent suit. Are you going back to Pripyat?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_u_parfumera_one_3">
		<text>No, I'll stay here for a while. The new Territories can be reached from here - when they become accessible I will go and explore them</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_u_parfumera_one_4">
		<text>Okay. I'll know where to look for you. Be careful - the people from the Last Day may not be so friendly should you run into them again</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_u_parfumera_two_0">
		<text>Doc, you made it back okay - good</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_u_parfumera_two_1">
		<text>Yes its safe here and I have my good friend Perfumer for company. I was really silly to let Last day to manipulate me that way - I'm too trusting</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_u_parfumera_two_2">
		<text>In the Zone you have to choose you're friends wisely... Are you going back to Pripyat?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_u_parfumera_two_3">
		<text>No, I'll stay here for a while. The new Territories can be reached from here - when they become accessible I will go and explore them</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dok_u_parfumera_two_4">
		<text>Okay. I'll know where to look for you. Be careful - the people from the Last Day may not be so friendly should you run into them again</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parf_shtab_say_0">
		<text>You found a letter?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parf_shtab_say_1">
		<text>Yes, there is such a thing. In it - some coordinates</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parf_shtab_say_2">
		<text>This is likely to coordinate alternate portal. But how to define - I do not know. According to rumors - it's somewhere near the city, in one of livnevok</text>
	</string>
	<string id="parf_shtab_say_3">
		<text>Under the city? I know how to determine the coordinates. Norman gave me a detector - it should help. You come on yet - complete dismantling of local and wait for the signal - if I can find - will tell</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
