<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1250"?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.7 Redirected strings from the Misc folder - aleks1970 -->
	<!-- from misc-tb3d_uniq_news.ltx file - aleks1970 -->
	<!-- section "news_uniq" - aleks1970 , added two 'b' forms of message-->
	<!-- Comprehensive text editing for more dramatic impact - Sword2012 - 10 Oct 16 -->
	<string id="news_uniq_1">
		<text>A couple of helicopters have just passed me. Coordinates enclosed. Stay safe. I don't know what their orders are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_2">
		<text>We're continuing on the same bearing from the downed helicopter in the marshes. Nothing so far.\nShit, it's Duty!\nGo to the private channel, quickly!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_3">
		<text>Waves of mutants coming from the northwest. See attached coordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_4">
		<text>Waves of mutants, coming from the northern valley.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_5">
		<text>Waves of mutants heading east, presumably from the Dark Valley.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_6">
		<text>Mayday! A pack of dogs is coming straight for us! Exact coordinates attached. Anyone! Please help!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_7">
		<text>If it's not mutants, it's bandits...\nPotap:\nYes, we can guess...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_8">
		<text>Just been rushed by a Pseudodog. Barely shot it in time!\nPotap:\nWell done...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_9">
		<text>Mayday! A battle has broken out at the Agricultural Industry in the central complex!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_9b">
		<text>Duty:\n Anyone doing the same as in here, be warned - you WILL be raided...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_10">
		<text>Lukash, the Merc's been shot, as you ordered. On my way back.\nFreedom\nSwitch to the private channel, assholes!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_11">
		<text>Two, Three, Seven, return to base and consolidate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_12">
		<text>Marauders! We're being attacked! Help!\nNo one can help unless you attach your coordinates. Idiot...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_13">
		<text>We need access to the Internet. Should we make our way to the Bar, where it's crowded, or go further on to Sidorovich where it's more private?\nPotap:\nYes, the Bar will always be busy, but you can try the signallers at Duty. They also have access</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_14">
		<text>Has anyone figured out where those ALD weapons are?\nIt's probably a trap anyway...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_15">
		<text>Crap!\n Just stepped in the biggest pile of boar shit ever!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_16">
		<text>Where the hell am I?\nWhy is it so foggy out here?...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_17">
		<text>I'm lost! I need help...\n Is anybody receiving me?\n Anybody...?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_18">
		<text>So that explains it, but I don't know where the signal is coming from...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_19">
		<text>In the Swamps, a Stalker named Kalmyak sells medical ointment. It really helps! Almost all my symptoms have gone. Much better than vodka. Really!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_20">
		<text>I'm going to try using emoticons more often :) ;) 8)... Communication scrambled...\nPotap:\n Idiot blocked...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_21">
		<text>There's a huge beast in the swamps. It's incredibly strong, and almost two metres tall! All the Bandits near the church are covered in blood, and it's still alive. I gave them a bandage to share...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_22">
		<text>Just came from the Reconnoitred Earth. There's an an Electric Chimera grazing by the lake! I do NOT advise going there...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_23">
		<text>Attention, all fighters! Bandits are trying to take over the ATP! This is our territory! Help us defend it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_24">
		<text>\n A group of five heavily armed men are moving towards the Barrier. They look like Monolith. Take immediate action!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_24b">
		<text>Barrier:\n Understood. Those fucking lunatics!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_25">
		<text>Warning: In a small village in the Dark Valley, if you're offered a Gauss rifle for 800 roubles - don't believe it. It's a scam!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_26">
		<text>What the hell? Just when you think everything's quietened down for the night, at exactly 21.00 a shitload of fucking green-eyed zombies appear! I've heard of it, but never seen it happen here before!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_27">
		<text>I've just heard that in the Red Forest there's a huge catfish swimming in the river. That would look great on a wall...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_28">
		<text>You're not going to believe this, but a dead dog has just fallen out of the sky right next to me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_29">
		<text>I've heard that twenty people, on average, die each day in the Zone. I'm still here, but I see fewer and fewer old faces each day. My time is bound to come soon...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_30">
		<text>The client has accepted our price, and given us the details. Now we have a job to do...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_31">
		<text>I heard you know about some laboratory. X-16? X-18? X-20? Tell me what you know, or you're dead...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_32">
		<text>I heard that at the Bar there's one guy, an informant of sorts. He sells transmutation Recipes for artefacts. Check it out...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_33">
		<text>Fuck! It's impossible to get through Pripyat, what with those bastard helicopters shooting the shit out of anything that moves!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_34">
		<text>On the way to Limansk, I got trapped in a construction site full of Monolith! Gettin' outa here quick before I'm seen!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_35">
		<text>I drank some crap vodka. This is the second day I've been sat on the shitter, throwing up in a bucket...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_36">
		<text>Nobody knows who the shooter is? Well, one group is very interested in finding out - and they're offering a large reward...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_37">
		<text>There's a Snork here still alive after taking both barrels in the head. That's one tough mofo!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_38">
		<text>Looks like the bastard offspring of two mutant species is living in the woods here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_39">
		<text>Just killed a Chimera, but they usually go around in pairs...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_40">
		<text>Just saw a pile of withered corpses, totally sucked dry. Must be a den of Bloodsuckers near by...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_41">
		<text>Looking for a technician, preferably with experience of night vision devices. Dust-free working environment. Decent pay</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_42">
		<text>Found an exoskeleton in the ATP. Put in on and used it for ages, until I fell into a Springboard. Now, it's up in space somewhere...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_43">
		<text>For Sale - Old exoskeleton. Sealing system is damaged, but otherwise in good condition</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_44">
		<text>Just fended off a large wave of mutants. Expecting another one soon. Anyone who can help, please come quickly...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_45">
		<text>The Duty warehouse has just received a batch of brand new FN-2000's. You need to get there quickly if you want to loot... sorry, buy one</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_46">
		<text>Damn! The area around Yantar is full of zombies again! Neat job you did there, people!\nPotap:\nContinue with the mission. We still need that information...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_47">
		<text>Talk with the Bandits. They should know how to get through that area quietly...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_48">
		<text>Attention all Stalkers who wish to clear their debts - go to a private channel for information on the upcoming mutant raid and... other operations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_49">
		<text>Went to Darkscape looking for Tweed\nGot chased out by a group of soldiers. No idea who they were...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_50">
		<text>Is anybody out there?\nI need assistance. Anybody?\nWhere the hell am I?...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_51">
		<text>FSS?\nWhat the hell is that, anyway? Probably a bunch of jerks looking to cause trouble, no doubt!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_52">
		<text>I had it!\nIt was awesome! But I lost it...\nIt just flew right outta my hand and disappeared... I can't find it... I've got to find it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_53">
		<text>Did you hear about F1?\nEveryone's dead. It's far too hot to enter, and there's no clues as to what happened!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_54">
		<text>Let's meet at the Bar up north. Don't forget some vodka for the guards at the gate...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_55">
		<text>Just tried to go to the old research station.\nWatch out! There's something definitely something wrong with that place. Something very, very hostile...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_56">
		<text>Top end military goods!\nAt the Black Market, for the next few days only...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_57">
		<text>Almost had it back!\nOn the rooftops, near the generators. But then it sliced up some Monolith bastards and disappeared again!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_58">
		<text>Hey, did you hear?\nThe Duty commander in Rostok has lost his marbles. He actually sent out a team to find a panda bear for him to take back to Moscow...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_59">
		<text>Watch out at the Dead Marshes.\nOur whole village has been occupied by group of military assholes!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_60">
		<text>Need a Stalker. Must be discreet to carry out some... delicate work. Do not respond to this directly, but to the Base.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_61">
		<text>Work available, to search for equipment. Payment per item found. Look for me in the Reconnoitered Earth, in the Infirmary.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_62">
		<text>Looking for experienced Stalkers to raid for artefacts. Contact Colonel Petrenko.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_63">
		<text>In exchange for rare artefacts, I can now upload new firmware to your PDA. Even a satellite channel. Contact Lanky.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_64">
		<text>Heh-heh, even at my highest rates, the client is still desperate to do business with me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_65">
		<text>Looking for a Stalker specialising in combination locks, with experience of raids in the north of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_66">
		<text>I heard the Americans sent us a superhero. It'll be interesting to see him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_67">
		<text>Do not go through the underground tunnels. They're full of mutants! Take the surface routes instead...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_68">
		<text>Hey, they've got a shisha pipe in the Bar! Best get there quick before it gets raided!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_69">
		<text>Everyone! Beware of staying in warehouses in the countryside. They're being burned down systematically, and bodies staked out on posts!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_70">
		<text>Sakharov pays well for exclusive items from raids! Requires resourceful Stalker to explore Lab X-16. Must have experience with zombies and Bloodsuckers...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_71">
		<text>We need Stalkers for incursions into the Wild Territory. High rates of pay for successful results. Kruglov.\nLabelled\nStalkers, if you want to keep your sanity, do not meet up with this so-called Scientist. He's a fucking nutcase!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_72">
		<text>Join our ranks of experienced trackers. No admission fee. Zahar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_73">
		<text>Baldy\nGet a move on! If I see something coming I'll shoot...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_74">
		<text>We need Stalkers with expertise of deep raids into the Zone. Payment commensurate with skill and results. If interested, respond privately to discuss a meeting</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_75">
		<text>Wolf, if you can talk freely, please come in...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_76">
		<text>Stalkers, join Duty! Defend the planet from the new plague that is upon us...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_77">
		<text>Spam\nMoskvin coffee - a really, truly, nasty coffee made in China!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_78">
		<text>Spam\nLost - weapons. If found, please return them to me at the old Stardusk wreck in Backwater. Come alone!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_79">
		<text>Spam\nAntizombin - keeps the zombie in you at bay - even better than vodka!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_uniq_80">
		<text>Spam\nMoskvin coffee relieves you of constipation in exactly 30 seconds. No more, no less...</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- from misc\tb3d_news.ltx file - aleks1970 -->
	<!-- section "dolg_news" - aleks1970 -->
	<string id="dolg_news_1">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]DUTY:\n%c[default]We have a problem with the equipment. If it carries on like this, we'll lose contact with the Base altogether within the next 48 hours...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_news_2">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]DUTY:\n%c[default]Stalkers - Join Duty! Help us to protect the world from the dangers of the Zone...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_news_3">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]DUTY:\n%c[default]Switch to a private channel, then download the security updates.\nWe could have a total network breach, just because you were too lazy to patch your PDA... Asshole!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_news_4">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]DUTY:\n%c[default]Information on the upcoming mutant raid, and other operations, available on a private channel. Downloading now...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_news_5">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]DUTY:\n%c[default]Stalkers - join Duty. Defend the planet from the infected Zone!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_news_6">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]DUTY:\n%c[default]Looking for experienced Stalkers to assist in eliminating a group of Snorks. Rewards will be on a per capita basis...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_news_7">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]DUTY:\n%c[default]Looking for experienced Stalkers for a raid against mutants. Usual rates apply...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_news_8">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]DUTY:\n%c[default]Looking for experienced Stalkers for a raid on Freedom. See General Voronin at the Duty base</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_news_9">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Petrenko\n%c[default]I was a rust repairer. A rust repairer and full-time survivor.\nAll the major earthquakes, a tsunami, and multiple air crashes... So stop telling me what to do!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_news_10">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Voronin\n%c[default]It is far better to have a lion at the head of an army of sheep, than a sheep at the head of an army of lions...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_news_11">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Anonymous\n%c[default]My life fades. The vision dims. All that remains are memories. I remember a time of chaos. Ruined dreams. This wasted land.\nBut most of all, I remember the Wish Granter, and the man we called Strelok.\nTo understand who he was, you have to go back to another time - when the world was powered by black energy...</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- section "freedom_news" - aleks1970 -->
	<string id="freedom_news_1">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]FREEDOM:\n%c[default]Long live Freedom! Let us make peace with the Zone, and make it a better place for everyone!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_news_2">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]FREEDOM:\n%c[default]Join Freedom! Together we'll make the Zone a better place!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_news_3">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]FREEDOM:\n%c[default]Looking for experienced Stalkers to join a hunt for rare artefacts. Fair prices offered!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_news_4">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]LUKASH:\n%c[default]Stalkers! Save Freedom! If you want to live a peaceful life in the Zone, without Duty oppression, then come join us!\nWe always welcome new blood!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_news_5">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]LUKASH:\n%c[default]Attention Freedom! Switch immediately to a private channel, and update your PDA's with the latest protection patch. Then your transmissions won't be intercepted by Duty...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_news_6">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]FREEDOM:\n%c[default]If you're on a mission, switch to a private channel. Always assume that there are people listening...</text>
	</string>

