<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4, changed Devil to Bes, amber, lukash -->
<!-- Names changed as commented below - Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16 -->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->
<!-- Reworked all text to first draft standard from def1ne's file - Sword2012 - 14 Jan 17 -->
		<string id="scaintist_docs_name">
			<text>Dokumente vom Toten Wissenschaftler</text>
		</string>
		<string id="scaintist_docs_desc">
			<text>\nDen Notizen nach, haben die Wissenschaftler ein sehr ungewöhnliches Artefakt transportiert.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="pda_krysyka_name">
			<text>Krysjuk's PDA</text>
		</string>
		<string id="pda_krysyka_desc">
			<text>\nKrysjuk hat viele "sensible" Informationen in seinem PDA notiert. "Borow" will diesen PDA und belohnt einen dafür sehr gut.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_borov_secret_name">
			<text>Borows Versteck</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_borov_secret_descr">
			<text>"Borow" sagte - hier kann man viel holen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="vodka_rad">
			<text>Selbstgebrannter Wodka</text>
		</string>
		<string id="vodka_rad_s">
			<text>Selbstgebrannter Wodka</text>
		</string>
		<string id="vodka_rad_descr">
			<text>\nEs gab mal in der Zone einen "schlauen" Händler, der versuchte selbstgebranntes Zeug in Original-Flaschen abzufüllen und zu verkaufen. Nun gibt es ihn nicht mehr - solche Tricks werden hier in der Zone nicht verziehen. Aber das selbstgebrannte Zeug, das wird weiterhin fortgeführt .. ohne Original Flaschen</text>
		</string>
		<string id="food_bread_rad">
			<text>Verstrahltes Brot</text>
		</string>
		<string id="food_bread_rad_s">
			<text>Verstrahltes Brot</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_food_bread_rad">
			<text> \nWar mal ganz normales Brot... Jetzt ist es nur noch ein Stück radioaktiver Müll. Wenn man lebensmüde ist - kann man mal reinbeißen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_krysyk_secret_name">
			<text>Beute-Versteck von "Krysjuk" die Ratte</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agr_krysyk_secret_descr">
			<text>Krysjuk hat hier sein Versteck mit der ganzen Beute.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_0">
			<text>Hey, man... Wollen wir quatschen?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_1">
			<text>Yo Alder!. Hast du was zu trinken? Was gibts?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_2">
			<text>Nichts, nur so... Bisschen sitzen, Schluckchen nehmen...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_3">
			<text>Na dann, mach voll die Tassen!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_41">
			<text>Prost!...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_42">
			<text>Was für ein Scheiß... Nichts mehr da..</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_5">
			<text>U-u-uch... Das ging durch, wie geschmiert...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_6">
			<text>Hey, erzähl ma-a-al was intere... hick... interessantes...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_71">
			<text>Das erzähl ich aber nur dir... Klar? Hab bei einer Leiche 'n PDA gefunden, da war was über versteckte Sachen drauf... Kein Bock dahin zu latschen, weiste... Aber du bist ja voll in Ordnung - weiße wat, hier - kannste ha-haben...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_73">
			<text>Eh, Bruder... Was soll hier geben?... Voll ätzend hier...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_81">
			<text>Danke für den Tipp. Da schau ich mal vorbei.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_82">
			<text>In Ordnung, Mann... Ruf an, wenn du was Feines findest...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_0">
			<text>Wie geht's so? Bock auf Reden?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_1">
			<text>Immer, Man... Was geht ab?..</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_2">
			<text>Hab voll Hunger, du auch?...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_3">
			<text>Lass uns 'ne Flasche teilen..</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_41">
			<text>Na dann, auf die Brüder...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_42">
			<text>Neee, Alter, wenn ich was hätte....</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_5">
			<text>Auf die Brüder, Mann! Voll konkret...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_6">
			<text>Pfeif mir mal was interessantes, Man...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_71">
			<text>Interessantes? Ich habe da 'wat bei der Versammlung aufgeschnappt, da gibts wohl ein Versteck, das nicht durchsucht ist... Mir ist es voll zu weit - ich kann mir auch hier einen Dummen schnappen... Kannst ja selber gucken, wenn du Bock hast...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_73">
			<text>Fang dir einen Vogel, der kann dir was pfeifen...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_81">
			<text>Neee, keine Lust. Wenn's nicht so weit wäre, vielleicht...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_82">
			<text>Ein anderes mal Vielleicht.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_0">
			<text>Hey Räuber Hotzenplotz! Was macht denn so die Runde?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_1">
			<text>Wa.. Tag auch. Borow sagte zwar, das wir dich in Ruhe lassen sollen, aber nicht frech werden...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_2">
			<text>Bleib locker. Wann hast du das letzte Mal einen echten Wodka getrunken?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_3">
			<text>Quatsch nicht rum, sondern gieb lieber einen aus..</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_41">
			<text>Na gut. Brüder! Auf die verkackte Beute!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_42">
			<text>Verdammt, ich dachte, ich hätte noch eine Flasche.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_5">
			<text>Mmmm... Respekt! Warum nicht gleich so..</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_6">
			<text>Und... wie ist es so mit den Gefangenen. Hat da einer mal gequatscht?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_71">
			<text>Ah, nix... Die "Wächter" die wir uns Gestern geschnappt hatten, die sind ja nur mutig, wenn sie sich in ihren Blockposten verschanzen... Als wir sie verhören wollten fing einer sfort an zu flennen - "Jungs, nicht doch", "ich kann euch gute Beute zeigen"... "Beute", lächerlich... Die wollen einen nur volllabern und still abhauen, und dann uns hier mit der ganzen Mannschaft überrennen... Und der Sack meinte - "Das Versteck ist ganz in der Nähe", mit seiner piepsigen stimme.. so ein Arsch... Egal, die können mich echt alle. Und sein Versteck auch... Klar... "in der Nähe"! Guck.. Hier soll es sein! Überleg doch mal...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_73">
			<text>Nichts? Jeden Tag das Gleiche. Nichts..</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_81">
			<text>Ha-ha, das ist ja mindestens ein Tagesmarsch, die wollten euch verscheißern...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_82">
			<text>Na dann, wenn du mal ne Pulle übrig hast - komm vorbei...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_0">
			<text>Hey, wen sehe ich denn da! Seit wann bist du den hier?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_1">
			<text>Laß mich, Mann... Siehst du nicht, bin voll fertig nach dem Gelage gestern...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_2">
			<text>Dann laß uns doch was für dir Gesundheit tun.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_3">
			<text>Nich mehr da, Alter... Alles ausgesoffen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_41">
			<text>Ich hab immer was dabie, Bruder. Geht halt nicht ohne. Dann los!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_42">
			<text>So ein Mist! Und ich hab nichts.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_5">
			<text>Du bist mein Retter, Kumpel.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_6">
			<text>Was erzählt man denn so bei euch? Gibt's noch gute Beuteplätze?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_71">
			<text>Sicher, Mann! Aber sei nicht so laut. Weißt du, ich sah mal, wie Borow's Schuldner was versteckt hatten. Ich... ich würde das nicht nehmen, harte Sitten herschen hier... Kannst dann auch mal mit einem Messer im Bauch wach werden... Also, und du - du bist gekommen, du bist gegangen... Keiner hat was gemerkt. Und wenn du mal wieder hier bist, quatsch mich mal an, dann können wir was drehen... Deal?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_73">
			<text>Alles hat sich hier Borow unter den Nagel gerissen, wir kriegen nur Reste...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_81">
			<text>Deal!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_82">
			<text>Na gut, ich muß dann los.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_0">
			<text>Grüß dich, Bruder.. Wie siehts aus?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_1">
			<text>Geht so. Wolltest du was, oder fragst du einfach so?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_2">
			<text>Ach, nur so... Ziehmlich Ruhig zurzeit, da dachte ich wir könnten ein wenig sitzen und was für die Gesundheit tun.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_3">
			<text>Gesundheit - das ist wichtig, dann mach mal voll den Becher.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_41">
			<text>Na los, runter mit den drei Tropfen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_42">
			<text>Besser wäre es, wenn mir jemand was ausgeben würde.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_5">
			<text>Mann, ist das Zeug gut. Geht ja durch und durch... Stück Schinken dazu wäre fein.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_6">
			<text>Gutes Zeug... Erzähl mal was interessantes, weißt du da was?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_71">
			<text>Na .. so vor nicht so langer Zeit haben wir mit Wolf, einen Stalker aus einer Anomalie gezogen, oder, besser gesagt, das was von ihm übrig blieb. Tja... Er hatte einen Notiz Zettel mit Koordinaten dabei. Wohl ein Beuteversteck. Aber Wolf sagte, wir sollen es erst gar nicht versuchen. Hier, schreib dir diese mal auf, falls da was lohnendes gibt - kannst ja später bescheid geben... Abgemacht?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_73">
			<text>Neee, ich bin hier noch nicht lange, war noch nicht weit in der Zone... Kannst ja so in einer Woche vorbeikommen - vielleicht gibts dann was Interessantes</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_81">
			<text>Abgemacht. Ich schaue nach.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_82">
			<text>Na gut, wir spechen uns noch irgendwann mal...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_0">
			<text>Ich grüße dich, was macht denn das Stalkerleben denn so?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_1">
			<text>Sei auch gegrüßt, Gezeichneter. Geht so! Könnte besser sein...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_2">
			<text>Wie wär's mit fünf Tropfen auf die Brust?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_3">
			<text>Wäre nicht schlecht! Gibst du einen aus?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_41">
			<text>Na dann runter damit, für's tapfer sein...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_42">
			<text>Schoiße, ich hol nur schnell was von Sidorovich.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_5">
			<text>Alter... Aus was ist das gemacht? Aus Holzspäne? Kriegt man ja kaum runter.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_6">
			<text>Hier ist alles möglich. Erzähl mal was...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_71">
			<text>Vor kurzem haben ein Paar Stalker Sidorovich besucht. Ich hatte bei ihm im Vorraum gepennt. Na ja, wirklich geschlafen hab ich nicht, nur so, mit halbem Auge. Die Stalker wollten bei ihm wohl Ausrüstung einkaufen, aber auf Kredit - sozusagen... Sagten was davon, das sie viel beute gebunkert hätten und beschrieben sogar die Lage. Aber der alte Sack gab nichts darauf - so ein Geizhals, nicht wahr? Er hat sie jedenfalls rausgeschmissen. Ich dachte, ich schaue mal da nach, aber irgendwie weiß ich nicht.. Hier ist dieser Ort, siehst du? Wenn da was schönes liegt, vergiss mich nicht, OK?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_73">
			<text>Was soll man da erzählen. Die Zone ist halt die Zone. Würde am liebsten abhauen von hier..</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_81">
			<text>Wenn da was von Wert drin sein wird - vergess ich dich schon nicht.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_82">
			<text>Irgendwann hauen wir hier schon ab, sicher.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_0">
			<text>Warum so grimmig?.. Brauchst du Hilfe, oder so?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_1">
			<text>Ach Scheiße, Bruder.. Ich habe halt einen schlechten Tag..</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_2">
			<text>Hier, trink mal einen, nicht des Saufens wegen, sondern um die  Stimmung zu heben.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_3">
			<text>Ja, machen 'wa, komm! Vielleicht wird's dann besser.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_41">
			<text>So... Halt still den Glas... Auf die Hoffnung!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_42">
			<text>Dafuq! ich erinnere mich, ich hatte noch eine Flasche! Nichts mehr da!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_5">
			<text>Genau, darauf stoß ich gern an! Danke dir, Bruder. Gibt's doch noch echte Kerle in der Zone...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_6">
			<text>Man erzählt - mann könnte in der Nähe auf gute Beute stossen. Irgendwas davon mitbekommen?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_71">
			<text>Ja, man sagt das es, nicht weit von hier, ein Versteck gibt, wo manche Leute ihre Beute und Ausrüstung zwischenlagern. Aber keiner von denen, die es plündern wollten, ist zurückgekehrt. Ich zeig dir das mal auf der Karte - hier ist es...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_73">
			<text>Nee-e, nichts gehört. Aber wenn du auf Gerüchte stehst versuch es mal bei Facebook.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_81">
			<text>Wenn ich mal in der Nähe bin - schaue ich mal nach.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_82">
			<text>Vielleicht sollte man es ruhen lassen...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_0">
			<text>Sei gegrüßt. Na.. was hälst du von einem Freundschaftstrunk?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_1">
			<text>Alter. Lass mich bloß in ruhe. Ich habe mit angesehen wie mein Kumpel von einem Mutierten Wildschwein in Stücke gerissen wurde. Das Vieh war dermaßen in Rage. Seitdem habe ich Alpträume von der Schei?e und komme nervlich nicht zur ruh'.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_2">
			<text>Tut mir leid. Hier nimm mal ein Schluck für deine Nerven.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_3">
			<text>Das würde vielleicht helfen. Und..</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_41">
			<text>Da ist die Flasche, klar wie eine Träne!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_42">
			<text>Ach mist. Nichts dabei. Du? Ich komme später wieder.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_5">
			<text>Mann tut das gut! Geht ja durch bis zum Hintern.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_6">
			<text>Standard Medizin von meinem Arzt des vertrauens.. Was hört man so in der Zone?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_71">
			<text>Vorgestern hatten wir mit Soldaten ein paar Fläschchen geleert. Saßen am Feuer und plauderten... Du musst wissen, die schleichen sich oft aus Agroprom raus, Sidorovich beliefert sie mit Wodka und so. Sie erzählten, das sie einen Zombie artigen Stalker geschnappt haben - du weißt ja, der brachte kein Wort raus und wollte nur ballern. Ihr Kommandeur wollte ihn aber lebend, damit die Soldaten in der "Außenwelt" mit ihm Experimente anstellen können. Wenn's nach mir ginge - dann lieber sofort eine Kugel in den Kopf bekommen... Wo war ich? Ach ja... Also, dieser Zombie hatte einen Zeichnung auf dem Arm, wie ein Tatoo, aber nicht ein richtiges Tatoo, sondern als ob es jemand mit einem Messer eingeritzt hat. Wie eine Karte sah es aus... Der Kommandeur hat es mit Armee-Karten verglichen - und tatsächlich, sieht so aus als ob es in der Nähe ein Versteck gibt... Schau mal hier...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_73">
			<text>Vieles hört man. Über Anomalien, über Monster, Gerüchte - alles kann man gar nicht auf einmal erzählen. Bin zurzeit knapp dran, komm mal wieder vorbei..</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_81">
			<text>Harte Sache, Mann. Meine Meinung ist - lieber sofort verrecken, ohne Qualen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_82">
			<text>Das werde ich machen, bestimmt...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_0">
			<text>Hallo, Bruder... Wie geht es euch hier so?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_1">
			<text>Mutanten brechen manchmal durch... Aber sonst geht's halt...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_2">
			<text>Wollen wir einen heben, so aufs Kennenlernen? Oder erlauben es gegen die Regel?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_3">
			<text>Regel hin, Regel her? Unser Feldwebel ist ein alter Hase, der versteht schon das es ohne in der Zone nicht geht. Also, sei nicht zimperlich, mach voll...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_41">
			<text>Na dann! Auf die Freundschaft!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_42">
			<text>Ich würde ja gern voll machen, aber den letzten halben Liter mußte ich als Medizin verbrauchen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_5">
			<text>Na dann! Auf uns! Hier, Wurst hab ich auch...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_6">
			<text>Danke. Was hört man hier so bei euch? Gibt es irgendwelche Neuigkeiten?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_71">
			<text>Besondere Neuigkeiten gibt es nicht. Aber - hast du von Max Lubero gehört? Ihn und seinen Kumpel haben die Banditen aus dem Dunklen Tal geschnappt. Prapor, Freund von Max, hat die Spur aufgenommen. Und vorher sagte er, das dieser Kumpel noch die Lage von einem Versteck übermitteln konnte. Tja... Prapor bat drum, das jemand es prüfen sollte, aber der Feldwebel hat es nicht erlaubt. Sagte, das es schon so viel zu wenige Kämpfer für die Wache da sind.\n \nKurz gesagt, hier ist dieser Platz - hole es ab, damit die Banditen es nicht bekommen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_73">
			<text>Eigentlich nichts besonderes, nur Frauen Klatsch...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_81">
			<text>Alles klar, danke für den Tip. Das hole ich ab...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_82">
			<text>Na dann, lass es dir gut gehen, wir sehen uns noch...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_0">
			<text>Ich grüße dich, Soldat!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_1">
			<text>Ja, du mich auch.. Was willst du?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_2">
			<text>Ach, ich streife nur so durch die Zone... Was denkst du über Wodka?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_3">
			<text>Was für 'ne Frage! Los, schenk schon ein...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_41">
			<text>Hier... Auf Ex!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_42">
			<text>Nichts da, Ich werd mal gleich ein Paar Sachen an den Wirt verscherbeln, und komme wieder...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_5">
			<text>Heh, der ist ja gut runtergegangen... Zu so einem Nektar muß man nicht mal was nachessen...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_6">
			<text>Das stimmt, heutzutage ist die meißte Scheiße die man Kaufen kann eh gepanscht. Erzähl mal was...
</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_71">
			<text>Die Tage war hier mal Bes, als Gast bei uns, ein guter Mann, auch wenn er ein "Einzelgänger" ist.. Ist nicht persönlich gemeint, Ok?. Wir haben ihm ein wenig mit Munition ausgeholfen, ein bisschen geredet. Er hatte nicht viel von Wert bei sich, darum erzählte er uns von einem geheimen Versteck. Da war aber nichts drin... Sah aber so aus, als ob da jemand öfters was zwischenlagert hat. Wenn du Bock hast, kannst ja versuchen herauszufinden wem das Versteck gehört...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_73">
			<text>Was soll man erzählen... Hier wird nur gesoffen. Ein Kater hab' ich. Kann mich gar nicht an die Letzte Nacht erinnern. Höllische Kopfschmerzen - war wohl wieder so ein Chemischer Billig Fusel. Komm doch nächstes mal vorbei.. </text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_81">
			<text>Ich versuche das herauszufinden.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_82">
			<text>Na dann, ich muß weiter.. Reduzier' dein Alkohol Konsum..</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_0">
			<text>Grüß dich, Man. Dein Gesicht kommt mir irgendwie bekannt vor. Haben wir uns schon mal getroffen?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_1">
			<text>Deine Gesicht kenne ich nicht... Ich kann mich nur an meine Freunde gut erinnern...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_2">
			<text>Dann las uns doch einen kippen, nicht um des Saufens wegen, sondern auf die Freundschaft...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_3">
			<text>Weißt du, jetzt erinnere ich mich doch auf ein Mal an dich... Mach voll die Becher!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_41">
			<text>So! Halt das Glas gerade... Auf die Freundschaft!!!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_42">
			<text>Verdammt! Nichts da! Ich weiß genau, Da war noch eine Flasche.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_5">
			<text>Auf zuverlässige Freunde! Mit denen man sich sogar in der Zone sicher füllt!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_6">
			<text>Man sagt, man kann auf gute Beute in der Nähe stoßen ... Ist da was dran?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_71">
			<text>Ich hab's noch keinem gesagt, aber dir erzähl ich was, H.ic..  als Freund... Scheinst in Ordnung zu sein. Ich hab ein Hinweis auf ein Versteck... Hab ich zufällig erfahren... Vielleicht ist da auch nichts drin, vielleicht aber ist da auch richtig gutes Zeug Vorort. Wenn du ein wirklich guter Freund bist, teilst du doch, oder?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_73">
			<text>Neee, nichts gehört... Alles, was in der Nähe ist, wurde schon eingesammelt... Und was da weiter gibts - weißt der Strelok...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_81">
			<text>Sicher doch, keine Rede, Mann! Für ein Freund ist nichts zu schade....</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_82">
			<text>Strelok? An den Typen habe ich auch ein paar Fragen..</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_0">
			<text>Hallo, wollen wir ein paar Worte wechseln?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_1">
			<text>Klar doch, kein Ding... Hier setz dich!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_2">
			<text>Vielleicht nehmen wir mal fünf Tropfen, zur Entspannung?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_3">
			<text>Gieß ein, auf was wartest du? Hier ist noch was zu essen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_41">
			<text>Halt die Gläser grade, sonst sehe ich den Rand nicht...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_42">
			<text>Ach mist! Aber das Wichtigste fehlt...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_5">
			<text>He-he... Wow, Das wärmt bis auf die Knochen...!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_6">
			<text>Das muss doch Nerven. Tagelang hier rumzusitzen. Macht ein doch total fertig oder...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_71">
			<text>Ach, warum denn? Wirt schickt uns schon was zu essen, so als Bezahlung für die Bewachung. Stalker kommen oft vorbei, erzählen dann ab und dann, das Neuste. Und was zum abschie?en gibt es auch genug.\n \nLetztens, da gab es was zu Lachen - das Banditenpack ist echt dreißt geworden in letzter Zeit, legen Hinterhalte in Gebieten und so... Na ja, einer lag wohl in der Nähe rum, hat einen Verletzten gemimmt, auf allen Frequenzen SOS gesendet. Und plötzlich sind da ein paar Bürer aufgetaucht.\n \n Also.. Dieser "Verletzte", als er die Bürer gehört hat, haste von dem nur eine Hacke und Staubwolke gesehen. Wie hatten ihn mit dem Fernglas aus den Augen verloren.. wir hörten nur noch ein lautes knallen, das er hier bei uns voll gegen die Kisten gerannt ist. Wir schauten uns an und das gelächter ging los. Wir schnappten uns ihn und merkten auf einmal - das er bis zum Abwinken stank. Hat der sich doch tatsächlich in die Hose gepinkelt - der Schisser!\n \nZitternd bat er uns dann die Bürer abzuknallen, hat was von Beute gefaselt und versprochen, sogar uns eine Marke auf die Karte gesetzt. So ein Dummbeutel... Die Bürer haben wir auch so abgeknallt, und für irgendwelche Beute wird keiner von uns den Arsch riskieren.\n \nWenn du Interesse hast und dein Arsch riskieren willst - hier ist diese Markierung von dem Kerl.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_73">
			<text>Ein wenig schwermütig ist es hier schon, ja. Aber man ist ja beschäftigt - wir beschützen schließlich die Welt gegen die Kreaturen der Zone!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_81">
			<text>Ha-Ha, ist ja Hammer! Werde bei Gelegenheit mal nachschauen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_82">
			<text>Dann störe ich den Helden nicht weiter. Mach's gut!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_0">
			<text>Hey, Bruder! Was macht das Leben?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_1">
			<text>Die verdammten Banditen, Mann... Die nerven, sowas von! Kommen immer wieder, wie Kakerlaken!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_2">
			<text>You need to let off some steam... A stiff drink will help you relax...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_3">
			<text>It's been a long time since I went on a good binge... Let's drink, while things remain calm...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_41">
			<text>Let's drink to a better tomorrow!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_42">
			<text>My bottle is empty, sorry about that - I will have to restock...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_5">
			<text>Drink! If you want to die from old age!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_6">
			<text>Going down smooth... That takes away the tension... What have you heard?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_71">
			<text>All around here keep their thoughts to themselves... But I have heard about a pair of Stalkers who stashed some loot while on the run from the military... I was going to profit from this information myself, but I dont think I will be going there... So, if you want to check it out, go ahead...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_73">
			<text>Everyone around here keeps their thoughts to themselves... Even friends don't trust each other with their caches...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_81">
			<text>Yes. It's hard to to trust people...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_82">
			<text>Maybe later you will hear something interesting...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_0">
			<text>What were you shooting at?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_1">
			<text>We shoot to scare our enemies away...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_2">
			<text>Shall we drink to bravery?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_3">
			<text>Certainly... pour!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_41">
			<text>Here's a full glass! The good stuff!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_42">
			<text>I'm almost dry, I will check back with you later...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_5">
			<text>Phew! Tastes like diesel fuel, but it's strong...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_6">
			<text>Heh, what were you expecting... lemonade? So have you overheard any talk about loot?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_71">
			<text>I was in the Swamps with a group when we came across a ruined village... It looked like the devil had just had a party, corpses and body parts strewn all about... I searched one of the bodies and found a map with a mark on it about hidden loot... Here is the map, try to reach it if you can, I could not. We were attacked by snorks and had to leave the territory...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_73">
			<text>I've heard a lot of rumours, but nothing worth wasting your time on...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_81">
			<text>If I can find it, half is yours...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_82">
			<text>Alright, if you hear anything, please remember me...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_0">
			<text>Comrade, do you have time to talk?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_1">
			<text>It depends on what you want...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_2">
			<text>I'm not trying to sell you anything. I just hate to drink alone. Would you like to share a bottle with me?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_3">
			<text>Well then, I'm glad to meet you... Let's not waste any of that precious nectar...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_41">
			<text>Let's drink to our new friendship!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_42">
			<text>I'm sorry, it seems my bottle has gone missing...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_5">
			<text>You speak too much when you drink! A person should remain silent until something important or enlightening should be said...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_6">
			<text>Looks like I've met a philosopher. Well educate me, how should we live?...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_71">
			<text>Everyone's life is different, and to learn another's life is impossible... Have you heard of 'Lucky Levka'? Everyone praised him because he was lucky with women - they just loved him. In the zone, even mutants stayed away from him... But he loved to drink, and when he did he would not stop talking. He was blabbing away and walked right into a Fruit Punch anomaly... And where is he now? Not even a scrap of hair remains - all dissolved into jelly. I went through his backpack to find an address of a relative of his, but all I found was a map with a stash location... And I think there will be no happiness for me from that loot. So I prefer to pass on this information...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_73">
			<text>If there is one thing I've learned, there is no such thing as luck. A clean weapon and a backpack full of ammo will get me through the day. Thanks for the info...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_81">
			<text>It's necessary to care about what comes tomorrow, not just live for today...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_82">
			<text>Well, personally, I believe in destiny... I was meant to be here in the Zone. I'll speak with you later...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_0">
			<text>How are things going, my friend?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_1">
			<text>I'm feeling a little depressed about life today...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_2">
			<text>I've got something that will change your mood! Would you like some vodka?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_3">
			<text>I would love to have a drink, you really know how to cheer a guy up...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_41">
			<text>Let's drink to happier days! Pour away...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_42">
			<text>Oh, I thought I had a bottle, but I can't find it...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_5">
			<text>It's good, but it burns like a she-devil!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_6">
			<text>Have you heard of anything interesting?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_71">
			<text>I did hear a story, but I don't think it's true. I will tell you about it... Do you know a Stalker named Eureka? He recently stopped by and said he had just returned from a mission with some skilled stalkers... No telling how long he had been on his drinking binge, we could barely understand what he was saying... Our laughter made him mad, he was flashing his PDA in our faces so we could see his mark on the map to prove his story. Nobody believed him - just another snotty nosed rookie from the Cordon... What do you think?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_73">
			<text>I really can't share anything at the moment. Perhaps tomorrow I will have something to tell you...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_81">
			<text>I can see why you would not believe him... But I might take a look if I'm in that area...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_82">
			<text>Maybe tomorrow, my friend...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_0">
			<text>Greetings, how are things here with you?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_1">
			<text>Things are cheerful enough. If you're looking for cheer, you want go to the Bar. If you want to fight for money, then go to the arena. The Bar is almost in the Zone centre...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_2">
			<text>We should have a drink and share some conversation...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_3">
			<text>That's a good idea... Pour me one, then I can finish you off in the arena. Just a joke!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_41">
			<text>Drink, for the good spirit!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_42">
			<text>I think I left my bottle in my stash. I will get it and return... Wait here!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_5">
			<text>Well, let's drink...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_6">
			<text>What talk have you heard, anything interesting?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_71">
			<text>Yes, I hear a lot of talk...Like there is a story about a teleport directly to the Monolith. I doubt it. Also, there was a story about a new monster called a 'Deathclaw', but I've never seen one. Then I heard Duty and Freedom were planning to divide the Zone. I hear that one a lot, actually. But enough about stories...I was tracking down an artefact when I found a PDA in the bushes. In it were some coordinates of what I believe to be a cache. Here, you see... We can go check it out together...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_73">
			<text>Come in the evening to the Bar, we will gather, we will talk... A lot of useful gossip to hear, only do not forget to buy lots of drinks...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_81">
			<text>That's a long way, and I have another job to attend to...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_82">
			<text>Okay, I'll come...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello, comrade. How are you?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_1">
			<text>I've got a lot on my mind... Please stop bothering me...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_2">
			<text>You are in a bad mood... perhaps a drink might make you feel better?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_3">
			<text>That would make me feel better! Break out the bottle...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_41">
			<text>That's the spirit! Forget all your problems!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_42">
			<text>I have to go...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_5">
			<text>Nothing like a good drink to make the day better... Pour some vodka...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_6">
			<text>Let's wash away the gloom with good vodka, it works for me... Do you know the location of any caches?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_71">
			<text>The Zone has too many people who can't be trusted... You are different, you help when you can... I do know of a stash, but I don't have anyone to cover my back to go get it, so I had given up on retrieving it - but I'm sure it's still there... Do you think you could find it by yourself? Here's the location...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_73">
			<text>So many people putting on fronts here, it's impossible to trust anyone... I don't want to talk anymore...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_81">
			<text>I'll come back again. I will try, if possible, to restore your faith in people...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_82">
			<text>No, you're up to something. I'm leaving...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_0">
			<text>Greetings, brother, Have we met before?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_1">
			<text>I don't think so. What's your name?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_2">
			<text>They call me Marked One...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_3">
			<text>Nice to meet you, Marked One. Let's drink to our meeting. Do you have a bottle?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_41">
			<text>Of course I do! Here! The strong stuff, it will put you on the floor...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_42">
			<text>I'm all out, I had to trade all my stock for ammo...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_5">
			<text>Ha! You speak the truth! Strong! Well, the Zone has seen a new friendship created...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_6">
			<text>So tell me, is it possible to find any loot nearby. Did you hear anything?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_71">
			<text>Well, you're a good person it seems, and good people should help each other. I'll tell you about something that happened to me recently. You'll think I'm telling ghost stories, but it's true... Zombies constantly wander into this territory, even though all approaches are blocked by Duty. A moose shouldn't even be able to get through, but these Zombies still appear. Last night I was taking a rest from drinking, the barman would not take credit, so rest was my only option. I rolled out my sleeping bag in one of the empty hangers and went to sleep. I awake to a horrible smell, the stench of death. I opened my eyes and there is a Zombie standing right over me, I practically shit myself... I couldnt move, I was frozen with fright. The Zombie is mumbling these figures, over and over. I closed my eyes, and when I opened them again - there was nobody... Only the stench remained... And the figures were fresh on my mind, they are similar to coordinates. Only it's far from here. If you want them, here they are...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_73">
			<text>All the loot which was in easy places has already been found. You will need to go to the Zone's center - they say you can find a new artefact called a Klondike...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_81">
			<text>I'm glad you're still among the living! Thanks for the tip...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_82">
			<text>Klondike, I've never seen one, Well maybe you will hear of something later...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_0">
			<text>What is bothering you, my friend?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_1">
			<text>I think it's time I got out of the Zone... Every day things get worse and worse. Every mutant is more dangerous and vicious, the weather is crappy, there's anomalies you can't see, and people who'll just kill you on sight...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_2">
			<text>You need a drink! Lets wash those bad thoughts away with vodka...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_3">
			<text>That will certainly help. Do you have any?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_41">
			<text>Of course I do... Only the best...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_42">
			<text>Shit! I know I had a bottle! It's been stolen!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_5">
			<text>Eh-r-r-m, that is good, you certainly do have the best vodka!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_6">
			<text>You've been around here for a while. What got you so spooked?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_71">
			<text>It's a long story... I hope you're not in a hurry?. I used to go on deep raids all the time with a Stalker named Serioga Bezuhim... Sometimes we would venture onto the Radar territory where we would see phantoms and other strange sights...\nSerioga was always someone I could count on to cover my back... He was tough veteran of Chechan war, where he lost an ear. On our last raid together, we ran into a Pseudo-giant. I tried to warn him, but Serioga was already too close to the beast... The Pseudogiant slammed its feet into the ground and knocked Serioga to the ground... And it in consciousness was... The beast closed in on him, and by the time he had stood up. It rammed him right into Fruit Punch anomaly... He melted in agony, right in front of my eyes. I threw down my backpack and ran for my life... I will not go back for it, I do not want it... If you find it, remember Serioga...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_73">
			<text>I can't talk about it... The Zone has nearly broken me... I'm getting out of here in a couple of days...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_81">
			<text>I will remember him...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_82">
			<text>Maybe you will want to talk later...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_0">
			<text>Hi, can we talk?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_1">
			<text>I hope you're not trying to sell me something...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_2">
			<text>I'm not a trader... I just don't like to drink alone...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_3">
			<text>Well, that's more like it! I will drink with you...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_41">
			<text>Let's drink to our acquaintance...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_42">
			<text>Damn, I thought I still had some...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_5">
			<text>To our acquaintance... Christ! That is some strong vodka!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_6">
			<text>Yes, not that Smirnoff piss! Hey, what's the word in the Zone?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_71">
			<text>Well, there is lots of talk... Like there are rich hiding places, hoards of loot Bandits have collected from their victims... There are secret caches of every clan, but I've never met anyone who found them... I did manage to find a PDA which contains the location of a hiding place, and I can share it with you... Very likely I'll not go that far...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_73">
			<text>Come in the evening to the Bar, we will gather, we will talk... It's possible to hear a lot of useful information, only do not forget to bring vodka...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_81">
			<text>Thanks, I will be in that area - I will check it out...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_82">
			<text>Alright, I will see you later...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello, old timer. How are you?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_1">
			<text>Who the hell are you calling old?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_2">
			<text>I'm sorry. I didn't mean to offend you. May I offer you a drink?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_3">
			<text>Now you're talking! No offence taken...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_41">
			<text>Here's to a long life! Spit on all our enemies!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_42">
			<text>I should leave now...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_5">
			<text>I'll drink to that... With vodka we can forget everything...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_6">
			<text>Good vodka, not that watered down piss the bartender sells... Have any information to share?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_71">
			<text>I do have one piece of information... I was going to check on it with a friend, 'cos I like to have someone watching my back... But he's fallen sick with an infection, and I won't go alone. You're a good person, maybe you want to try finding it? Here's the hiding place...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_73">
			<text>So many people putting on fronts here, it's impossible to trust anyone... I don't want to talk any more...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_81">
			<text>I'll come back another time. I will try to restore your belief in people...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_82">
			<text>No, you're up to something. I'm leaving...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_0">
			<text>Greetings, brother. Haven't we met before somewhere?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_1">
			<text>I don't remember meeting you...what's your name?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_2">
			<text>They call me Marked One...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_3">
			<text>Nice to meet you Marked One. We should drink to celebrate our meeting. Do you have anything?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_41">
			<text>Yes, a drink to our new friendship! Here you are! So strong, it could floor a monk...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_42">
			<text>Sorry, I had to trade all my vodka for ammo...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_5">
			<text>Ha! You were not joking! It is strong! Well, my new brother, it's always good to meet generous people in the Zone...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_6">
			<text>Since we are on such good terms now - is it possible to find any loot nearby? Have you heard anything?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_71">
			<text>I recently went to Yantar, to have a look around... I did not get to far, before my brain started to feel the effects... I saw there these poor fellows - stalkers who are now zombies! How is it possible? How does their brain still function? I found one laying on the ground barely clinging to life. I searched has jacket and got poisoned, it took awhile for me to recover... In his jacket, I found a map with a mark about a cache... But I won't risk going to find it, I will share that info with you...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_73">
			<text>All loot which was in easy places, has already been found... If you want loot, then make your way to the Zone's center. They say it's full of rare artefacts...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_81">
			<text>Thanks for the info, I don't mind taking the risk!...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_82">
			<text>Lots of rare artefacts, you say? Well, well...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_0">
			<text>Why the long face, my friend?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_1">
			<text>I think it's time I left the Zone... Every day things get worse and worse. The mutants are more dangerous than ever, the weather's shit, there's anomalies you can't see, and worst of all are the people who'll kill you just for what's in your pockets...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_2">
			<text>What you need is a stiff drink! then you can relax...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_3">
			<text>That does sound good. Do you have any?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_41">
			<text>Of course! I always have vodka!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_42">
			<text>What the hell! I know I had a bottle! Some bastard must have stolen it!...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_5">
			<text>Ahhh, that's better. I feel more relaxed already...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_6">
			<text>Do you have any interesting stories to tell?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_71">
			<text>It's a long story... I hope you're not in a hurry? I used to go on deep raids all the time with a Stalker named Serioga Bezuhim... Sometimes we would venture onto Radar territory where we would see phantoms and other strange sights...\nSerioga was always someone I could count on to cover my back... He was veteran of the Chechan war, where he lost an ear. On our last raid together, we ran into a Pseudo-giant. I tried to warn him, but Serioga was already too close to the beast... The Pseudogiant slammed its foot down and knocked Serioga to the ground... He almost lost consciousness... The beast closed in on him, and by the time he had stood up it had rammed him right into a Fruit Punch anomaly... He couldn't get up. He just dissolved, in agony, right in front of my eyes. I threw down my backpack and ran... I'll not go back for it... I don't want it... If you find it, please think of Serioga...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_73">
			<text>I cannot... The Zone has broken me... In a few days, I will get out of here...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_81">
			<text>I promise to remember him...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_82">
			<text>The outside world provides even more senseless ways to die...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_1_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello, brother. How are you?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_1_dialog_1">
			<text>I couldn't be better... Recently some of us got some R 'n' R, three days outside the Zone... It's a shame that it had to come to an end...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_1_dialog_2">
			<text>Yes, we all need a break from the Zone sometimes... Can we talk?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_1_dialog_3">
			<text>You want to ask a question? Over a drink, then. Do you have a bottle?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_1_dialog_41">
			<text>Yes, I even have the good stuff!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_1_dialog_42">
			<text>I don't have anything. Another time perhaps...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_1_dialog_5">
			<text>Ugh, not as good as what I used to have outside the zone. But you can't be picky here...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_1_dialog_6">
			<text>Have you heard about a Stalker bragging in the Bar? Says he found the cache location of a high ranking mercenary and planned to clean it out. He was so pleased with himself, and even said he found the information on a PDA here at the Warehouses... Next day he was gone, and nobody has seen him since. Maybe you have heard something about him finding the stash?...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_1_dialog_71">
			<text>I think I know who you're talking about... We were observing the Duty base when an emission suddenly hit... As I was running for shelter, I tripped over a corpse. In his hands was a PDA, so I grabbed it and continued running... When I reached shelter, I investigated this PDA and found a mark on the map. I don't have time to check it out, but you can have the information...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_1_dialog_73">
			<text>Yes, to hell with it. Nefig was to show off, and may be longer lived. Che me something to dream pulled... Come again! Let's chat about this and that...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_1_dialog_81">
			<text>Thanks, I will check up on this...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_1_dialog_82">
			<text>I will come back later. Maybe you will hear something about this incident...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_2_dialog_0">
			<text>Comrade Max! How is life treating you?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_2_dialog_1">
			<text>We need to increase our numbers. Can you join our ranks? It will make your life here easy...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_2_dialog_2">
			<text>Well, I need time to think about it... What do you guys do around here for fun?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_2_dialog_3">
			<text>We have a good group of guys here, always friendly conversation, and always people ready to share their food and drink...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_2_dialog_41">
			<text>Now that you mention drinking, I present you with a Ukrainian treat... 'Cossacks' vodka. Have a big drink!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_2_dialog_42">
			<text>I don't have any vodka to share, I'll have to get more...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_2_dialog_5">
			<text>Brrr... My liver will appreciate some good spirits for a change!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_2_dialog_6">
			<text>Well, Max. Tell me what's going on around here. Any information to share?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_2_dialog_71">
			<text>Recently, Lukash sent me to the Barrier... He said there was trouble coming... Well, I took all these monkeys who just sit by the fire all day...When we got to the Barrier, it was under a mass attack by zombies! At least fifty. We wiped them all out, except for one.... When I approached it, I noticed it was mumbling the same numbers over and over. I put the poor creature out of its misery. When we got back to the base, I checked the numbers on a map and they were coordinates. But I can't tell you what is located there. You can take a look for yourself if you want...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_2_dialog_73">
			<text>There's plenty going on all the time. But I've got nothing valuable to share at the moment. Come back another time...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_2_dialog_81">
			<text>Yes, putting these zombies out of their misery is a good deed! I'll check up on the coordinates</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_2_dialog_82">
			<text>Well, I will see you later</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_3_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello, comrade! Could we have a talk?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_3_dialog_1">
			<text>Good to see you, Marked One! You are always welcome here!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_3_dialog_2">
			<text>Thanks for the hospitality. Would you like to share a bottle and maybe a little information?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_3_dialog_3">
			<text>I never turn down a drink! If I can help you, I will</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_3_dialog_41">
			<text>A good drink leads to good conversation! Cheers!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_3_dialog_42">
			<text>Where have I put it?... I can't find my bottle. I'll have to return another time...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_3_dialog_5">
			<text>A good drink makes everything better!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_3_dialog_6">
			<text>Yes! The more the better! I've been looking around for some loot, do you know of any?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_3_dialog_71">
			<text>Listen, the Cook was drunk the other day. Yeah, no surprise...and he was blabbing about a place he keeps some swag. Would you like the info?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_3_dialog_73">
			<text>If I had any information I would share, but there's nothing today. Come back another day and we will drink and I might have something for you...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_3_dialog_81">
			<text>Yes, the Cook is probably the vodka drinking champion of the entire Zone! Well, we will see what he stashed...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_3_dialog_82">
			<text>Certainly, I will come again. I hope you keep your ears open!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_4_dialog_0">
			<text>Greetings! What's wrong? What has made you upset?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_4_dialog_1">
			<text>Greetings, Marked One. Life is shit at the moment. I've got no artefacts, there are no women here, and I'm totally out of vodka...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_4_dialog_2">
			<text>Well, at least I can help with the vodka... I have a full bottle...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_4_dialog_3">
			<text>What are you waiting for? Open your backpack! I have the drinking glasses...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_4_dialog_41">
			<text>Where have I put it? Ah, here it is - at the bottom! We will drink to both women and for finding the most rare of artefacts!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_4_dialog_42">
			<text>Where... Where did I put it? I will have to fetch another bottle, then we can drink...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_4_dialog_5">
			<text>I really needed this... It's a shame these glasses are so small. Well let's drink to strong women!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_4_dialog_6">
			<text>We drink!... Ah, that's good! Do you know about any loot?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_4_dialog_71">
			<text>I was recently sent with a group to reconnoiter a pass from the Dark Valley to the Army Warehouses. It's not a straightforward job... Duty controls the Bar, and the Monolith and mutants threaten the Barrier. We're in the Dark Valley when we see this sign: 'DANGER - Do Not Proceed'. We got used to ignoring things like this, but twenty metres on we see four bloodsuckers!!! They had a Bandit up a tree and were unaware of our approach, so we focused our fire on the bloodsuckers, and they never knew what hit them. The Bandit came down from the tree with shit running down his jeans. We let the smelly little fucker go - he'd had enough - but we kept his PDA. Inside was a mark on the map. You can have the information, my friend...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_4_dialog_73">
			<text>I constantly hear these stories, but nothing worth sharing...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_4_dialog_81">
			<text>That's quite a story! I'll check out this information...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_4_dialog_82">
			<text>Well then, I need a rest anyway...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_5_dialog_0">
			<text>Greetings, comrades!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_5_dialog_1">
			<text>Hey, don't shout - the Zone can get angry... It always reacts violently to disrespect. Now, be calm...sit down. What is it you wanted?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_5_dialog_2">
			<text>I thought I'd come here and share a drink with my comrades...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_5_dialog_3">
			<text>Well, that's better, because we don't have any vodka. Be a friend and pour me a full glass...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_5_dialog_41">
			<text>Here, it's the good stuff...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_5_dialog_42">
			<text>Well, comrades, I thought I had a bottle... I will have to go and find one at the base...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_5_dialog_5">
			<text>Thank you, I really needed a drink... We are waiting here for our men to return. They have gone to the village to clear out a den of bloodsuckers. They have been gone too long... I think the worst may have happened...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_5_dialog_6">
			<text>The breathing sound of a bloodsucker always makes my hair stand on end. Even vodka does not help... Whats going on in this village?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_5_dialog_71">
			<text>There have been many stories, or legends you might say... Before the emission of 2006, this village was similar to the rookie village at the Cordon. Everyone lived here quietly and peacefully. Then suddenly... an emission erupted with such force that everyone not under shelter had no possible chance of survival... Shouts and screams... Waves of mutants came from the barrier, one after another... The emission lasted maybe ten, fifteen minutes, but it seemed more like three hours. We lost many friends. My own brother was killed here... The next day we came to find the corpses, to take them away and and bury them... I found my brother, lying in a cellar. It was a pitiful sight... I took his weapon and his PDA, and found a unique mark on his PDA map. Here... He left me a hastily scribbled message too, but that's personal...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_5_dialog_73">
			<text>A lot of misfortune has occurred here... You can see all the dangers of the Zone. Bloodsuckers, burers, controllers, dogs, and even chimeras thrive in this territory...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_5_dialog_81">
			<text>Yes, I believe that a lot more misfortune is still to come, I'll check out this info, though...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_5_dialog_82">
			<text>Thanks for the council. I hope we'll meet again...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_6_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello comrade. Is this your dinner time?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_6_dialog_1">
			<text>Yes, why do you ask?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_6_dialog_2">
			<text>Do you have anything to drink?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_6_dialog_3">
			<text>Unfortunately, no... I don't have anything...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_6_dialog_41">
			<text>Well, would you like some? What would we do without each other? I have already cracked open the bottle... Here, take a glass! What shall we drink to?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_6_dialog_42">
			<text>It's a pity, I don't have anything...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_6_dialog_5">
			<text>We will drink to such people as yourself who share good spirits! Pour a full glass! I want the full effect!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_6_dialog_6">
			<text>That's strong... Christ, it burns going down! Have you heard of any hidden loot stashed?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_6_dialog_71">
			<text>Well, Stalker, you have probably travelled all over all Zone... have you not? Do you know about the Dead City? The Mercenaries had a base there. I was taken prisoner by them about a year ago. I was taken there, but first they put a bag over my head and then hit it with a rifle butt to make sure I wouldn't know where they were taking me... When we arrived, they started to interrogate me. Well, I wouldnt give up any information... so they put me in a cage for the night. There were two other prisoners also in the cage. One was actually very similar to you. They both couldn't remember how they'd got to the territory. I noticed our captors looking at a map with certain points marked. I can still remember it clearly... In the morning, they dragged me out and bashed my skull with a rifle butt again. When I regained consciousness, I could tell we were in a car, but I had a hood on my head. We came to a stop and they dragged me out. They told me that I had one last chance to talk. Then, as luck would have it, an emission suddenly erupted... In the confusion, I made a run for it! I fell into a bog, and desperately tried to remove my hood. When I did, I found that I was in the middle of a stinking bog, but next to a carriage, so I climbed into it and waited out the emission. When I came out, I realized they had brought me to Agroprom... When I got back here, I told everyone my story, but nobody believed me...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_6_dialog_73">
			<text>I've only been here a week. Come back later, I'll see if I can find out something...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_6_dialog_81">
			<text>That's a hell of a story! It's a miracle that you're alive. We all need luck like that in the Zone...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_6_dialog_82">
			<text>Gut, vielleicht mache ich das. Man sieht sich.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_7_dialog_0">
			<text>What's wrong?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_7_dialog_1">
			<text>I've got the chills... I'm shaking all over...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_7_dialog_2">
			<text>Some hot soup or a bottle of vodka would cure that!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_7_dialog_3">
			<text>Some vodka would certainly do the trick...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_7_dialog_41">
			<text>Well, I can help with that! Would you like to share my bottle?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_7_dialog_42">
			<text>It looks like I'm out at the moment...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_7_dialog_5">
			<text>Ahhh, that's the good stuff, I feel better already. Thank you friend!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_7_dialog_6">
			<text>You're very welcome. Listen... have you heard anything about a hidden cache?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_7_dialog_71">
			<text>Well, I do know of one. But, there's a problem... It's located behind the Barrier. That's a dangerous place. I was doing some recon in the area of those big stones outside the Barrier. I was moving carefully around a boulder when I came face to face with an old comrade - who'd been dead for over a month! He'd become a zombie, so I had to put him down - it's always the right thing to do... In his backpack I found a PDA with a pair of caches marked on it. I cleaned one out, but I've no time to go search for the other one. You can have it...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_7_dialog_73">
			<text>Well, I heard that at the Agroprom, one can find a mountain of artefacts, but I think they're all gone. If I learn of anything else, I'll keep you in mind...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_7_dialog_81">
			<text>There's no dignity in ending your life life as a zombie. It's a fate nobody wants... Thanks for the info</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_7_dialog_82">
			<text>Well, I'll check back with you later...</text>
		</string>
<!--Created/Modified with S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Dialog Extended Editor by Marty Sheppard/ Version: 0.96i ( 2017/02/17) =!!= Last changed: 01.04.2017 02:39:57 -->
