<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 -->
<!-- Translated and corrected by Steve90k for fluency and ease of reading. Edited and proofed by Sword2012 for clarity, brevity, and consistency. 19 Jan 16 -->
<!--********************************-->
<!-- Sidorovich miniquest dialog start -->
<!--********************************-->
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_0">
		<text>Hey, you said someone left some loot for me, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_1">
		<text>Oh... Mmm, yes, here it is...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_2">
		<text>Thank you. I'll take it now, please</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_3">
		<text>Not so fast! I mean, I'm not trying to keep it from you. Of course it's yours. I kept it safe for you. I don't know if there's anything dangerous inside. My health's not so good these days, not like it used to be... So, that's a hundred rubles for keeping it safe for you. Fair price, okay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_5">
		<text>What? You make a charge for, what do you call it? Safekeeping?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_6">
		<text>That's fine. Here's your loot...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_7">
		<text>Are you serious? That's my property. Hand it over now, or I'll make sure everyone knows about the way you do business...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_4">
		<text>Sorry, I'm broke. I'll have to pick it up later...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_8">
		<text>Here, take your 'diamond'...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_9">
		<text>Are you threatening me? Who do you think will listen to you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_10">
		<text>Let's start with the newbies in the rookie camp. You can be sure they'll be a lot more careful in their dealings with you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_11">
		<text>How about the Military? Do you know what they do with illegal traders in the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_12">
		<text>You're seriously trying to screw over someone considerably younger and stronger than yourself?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_13">
		<text>I have certain 'friends' here. In powerful positions...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_14">
		<text>Look, they all know that if they don't buy something from me, when it comes in, someone else will instead. This is the Zone!\n They can't leave the Zone, because soldiers guard all the exits and, believe me, they search you inside and out before taking their share. To go deeper into the Zone they'll need ammo and weapons, and where can they get those except from me?\n So frankly, I don't give a shit what you say to them...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_15">
		<text>Ah, now I know you're new here. You look like you're Military, and had me concerned for a moment...\n Think about it, newbie. From where do you suppose I get all this equipment? All these firearms and ammo? Who do you think is getting most of the artefacts past the Cordon? Stalkers come and go, but I do more business with the Military than anyone else!\n But you can go to them, if you want, and tell them all about me. But please come back and tell me what they said. That is, if you can find a way to communicate from the afterlife...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_16">
		<text>Look, I'm a trader. One of the most established in the Zone. This is how we make a living. If it wasn't for us, nobody would be able to stay or move anywhere. Hey, if you're a mean SoB, then just say so! But I have no respect for those who try to settle their arguments physically...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_17">
		<text>Remember, friendship ends where money begins. Your so-called 'friends' don't bother me. They may be powerful, but if they're outside the Zone, they have no influence here. If they're inside the Zone, tomorrow they'll be gone, God help them... This is the Zone, remember that. The most powerful are those who've been here the longest...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_18">
		<text>Okay, one hundred rubles. And take your gift...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_19">
		<text>Thank you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_20">
		<text>Got it...</text>
	</string>
<!--****************************-->
<!-- Barist Repair dialog start -->
<!--****************************-->
	<string id="bar_trader_miniquest_0">
		<text>You have something for me? A guy left it with you, I hope?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_miniquest_1">
		<text>Oh yes... A small package. I'd almost forgotten it. Here it is... Do you want it now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_miniquest_2">
		<text>Yes, please</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_miniquest_3">
		<text>No problem, here you go...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_miniquest_4">
		<text>Thank you very much for looking after it for me</text>
	</string>
<!--********************-->
<!-- miniquest dialogs end -->
<!--********************-->