<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 removed replace - with _, removed "string_table" - aleks1970 -->
<!-- Translated and corrected by Steve90k for fluency and ease of reading. Edited and proofed by Sword2012 for clarity, brevity, and consistency. 07 Oct 16 -->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->
	<string id="Military">
		<text>Military</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Army">
		<text>Army</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_military_army">
		<text>\nThe Ukrainian government maintains the Zone's perimeter using its State Security Service troops, operating under the Ministry of Internal Affairs. The primary role of the Military is securing the borders of the Zone, to prevent unauthorized excursions into the Zone by Stalkers, and the distribution of artefacts to the outside world without government supervision. The Military had a strong presence within the Zone initially but, following the Zone's expansion, and the constant annihilation of military personnel by a variety of factions with their own agenda, further incursions into the Zone were put on indefinite hold. In practice, the Military is one of the most corrupt organizations operating within the Zone, ignoring smuggling operations in exchange for bribes, extorting money and goods from lone Stalkers trying to get in and out, and simply shooting them for sport\n \nSpetsnaz or 'Ukrainian Special Purpose Regiments' are elite Special Forces units that are deployed in the Zone in order to conduct rescue missions, special operations, and other assignments for the Ukrainian State Security Service. Although they lack the protection levels of Exoskeleton body armour, Spetsnaz possess superior training, advanced weaponry, and a fearsome reputation. They are most often deployed in squads or platoon-level formations, and may also employ aerial and mechanised support in the form of Mi-24 Hind gunships and BTR-70 APCs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Milstalkers">
		<text>Military Stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_military_milstalkers">
		<text>\nSoldiers who have undergone special training following their service in the Zone, or Stalkers who have voluntarily signed a contract with the Army. They are usually well-armed, and equipped with above average support gear. They are mainly employed to study the causes and effects of the explosion, and to map out the Zone. They work on their own, or in small detachments of up to five people. Believing themselves to be the only authorised personnel in the Zone, military Stalkers do not communicate with other Stalkers, and will often shoot them on sight. Highly skilled in combat, and very experienced in the ways of the Zone, these men are the Military's most valuable assets there</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Social">
		<text>Factions</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Bandits">
		<text>Bandits</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker_clans_bandits">
		<text>\nMembers of the criminal underworld who exist in the Zone for their own nefarious reasons - to make money by selling artefacts, to trade in weapons, or to simply hide from the law. From common thugs to serial killers, the Zone is full of these villains, most of whom find additional muscle and protection in numbers by belonging to a gang. Although it's normal for factions in the Zone to regularly fight among themselves, this criminal element poses a serious problem for all of them, especially lone and neutral Stalkers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Duty">
		<text>Duty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker_clans_duty">
		<text>\nA paramilitary group known for its discipline, and its members' adherance to a strict code, with 'Protecting the outside world from the Zone's dangers' as their primary objective. Duty is the only group that refuses to trade unique items from the Zone with the outside world, and all artefacts found are supposed to be handed over to the Zone's scientists. Most of the group's operations involve destroying mutants, which are pandemic in the Zone, and their regular raids will often save other factions from encountering serious trouble. Duty has long been at war with Freedom, although a tentative status quo exists to avoid constant casualties and re-recruiting</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Freedom">
		<text>Freedom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker_clans_freedom">
		<text>\nAnarchists and excitement seekers who declare themselves champions for free access to the Zone, and consequently find themselves in conflict with the Military, Duty, and military Stalkers. These so-called 'freedom-fighters' believe in sharing all information on the Zone with the rest of the world, and challenge the state's monopoly over the Zone's wonders and treasures</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Killers">
		<text>Mercenaries</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker_clans_killers">
		<text>\nSo clandestine and secretive is this faction that many don't even believe it exists - chiefly because its members do their job well, and leave few survivors. Many governments and organisations employ the services of mercenaries to deal expediently with any group or individual Stalker threatening their interests in an area. By the very nature of their work, Mercs who are still alive will be seasoned professionals. Well-armed, well-equipped, and well-paid, their services do not come cheaply, and to say that they demand a king's ransom for their services is not an overstatement, because they'll often be the ones called to rescue a king being ransomed, or who actually initiated the kidnapping... The location of their main base is a well-kept secret, suggesting that it is very deep inside the Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Loners">
		<text>Loners</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker_clans_loners">
		<text>\nStalkers who are not affiliated to any main faction. By definition, the name usually applies to smaller groups of Stalkers. Neutral individuals, most will happily trade or offer a variety of missions. They have no antagonism towards most other factions, and encounter little in return, but they've learned to defend themselves, often pre-emptively, against the Military, the Monolith, Mercenaries and, of course, Bandits. They tolerate the beliefs of Freedom, Duty and the Scientific factions, believing instead to 'live and let live'. While by definition they are not a recognised faction of their own, murdering a Loner will quickly earn the enmity of every other Loner in the Zone. Word spreads fast among this nomadic group, and if anything can pull them to work together, it's a common enemy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Monolith">
		<text>Monolith</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker_clans_monolith">
		<text>\nThis group displays most of the attributes of a religious sect. Its members believe in the all-immanent omniscience of a complex alien crystal, the Monolith, located in what they believe is the exact centre, and origin, of the Zone. Most Stalkers treat Monolith adepts with contempt, considering them lunatics. From its inception the group has striven to block all progress, from every direction, towards the centre of the Zone, in order to protect the sacredness of the Monolith from infidels and heathens. Rumour has it that the group has a large base deep in the Zone, but its location is known only to its members, each of whom would take its secret with them to the grave</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Scientists">
		<text>Scientists</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Mobile_groups">
		<text>Research Groups</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_scientists_mobile_groups">
		<text>Mobile Science Group</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Mobile_labs">
		<text>Mobile Science Lab</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_scientists_mobile_labs">
		<text>\nMobile Science Laboratories are armoured bunkers with small tinted windows made of hazard-proof glass. Incorporating reliable life-support systems with plenty of redundancy, these labs can function autonomously for several months at a time, while shrugging off damage from anything Nature can throw at them. These factors make them ideal for studying the inclement conditions found within the Zone. A bunker is usually delivered into the Zone by transport helicopter. To protect against 'contamination', lab staff rarely allow visitors past the external air-lock chamber, so very few Stalkers have ever seen the inside of one</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Zomstalkers">
		<text>Zombified Stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker_clans_zomstalkers">
		<text>\nCareless Stalkers who have suffered prolonged exposure to Psi-field emissions in Yantar and other heavily affected areas, including 'Blowouts'. These emissions will have irreversibly ruptured the neural pathways in their brains beyond recognition and help, cutting off their bodies from all they knew and loved, and effectively turning them into walking corpses that perceive everything as an enemy. With no sense of purpose, zombified Stalkers wander the Zone aimlessly, often reaching the perimeter. They are still able to use their motor functional skills, and hence their weapons, but they are quite lost to the world and themselves, and are usually heard mumbling incoherent and fragmented sounds as air continues to pass through their vocal cords. Eventually, when the destructive process is complete, causing all semblance of their former personality to disappear, they become what are popularly known as zombies - extremely aggressive to humans, and an even more serious threat in large, albeit largely uncoordinated, groups</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Stalker_clans">
		<text>Stalker Clans</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lastdays">
		<text>"Last Day"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker_clans_lastday">
		<text>\nLast Day - One of the first, and once the most powerful faction in the Zone, consisting of local residents, traders, scientists, and all those who remained in the exclusion zone after the first Chernobyl incident. For a long time they regarded themselves as the only legitimate inhabitants of the Zone, jealously guarding it and its 'gifts' against outsiders. These include the majority of clans and factions who threatened to abuse, plunder and research the Zone as if it was an alien being. About two years ago a Stalker named Ghost eliminated the leader of the clan, after which the group quickly fell apart. Unsure about choosing a new leader, many joined other groups. \nAccording to new information, the clan recently came together again at around the same time, and includes the former leading scientists of the so-called 'O-Consciousness' - those masters of the Monolith factions who were never religious fanatics. According to rumour, the clan developed serious connections outside the Zone's perimeter, and have become mercenaries and killers to accomplish their objectives. Their highly developed intelligence network is due to former members who temporarily transferred to other groups and factions, and its fighters are skilled, well-trained, and equipped with the best the Zone can provide. The size of their membership, and the location of their headquarters, are among the Zone's best kept secrets</text>
	</string>
