<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 unflawed sky -->
<!-- Translated and corrected by Steve90k for fluency and ease of reading. Edited and proofed by Sword2012 for accuracy, clarity, brevity, and consistency - 31 Oct 16 -->
<!-- Names changed as commented below - Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16 -->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16  -->
<!-- All lines reworked and proofed - Sword2012 - Small improvements 28 Feb 17 -->
	<string_table>
		<string id="tex_take_pushka">
			<text>While Fox sits here on his backside, getting drunk with the Doctor, I have to go and pick up his parcel from Prapor. This had better be worth it...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_atak_larger">
			<text>I need to return to the Cordon and find the old hunter, Sepator. That's all I know for now...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="saharov_about_klik_text">
			<text>Sakharov advises me to talk to Voronin about Fang's death</text>
		</string>
		<string id="voronin_about_klik_text">
			<text>So, according to Voronin, Fang was somehow crossed by the mercenaries. He advises me to talk to the informant, Snitch, who should have some information on those bastards...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="voronin_begin">
			<text>Voronin: The murder investigation proceeds...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="informator_begin">
			<text>Informant: We move a step closer...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="informator_about_klik_text">
			<text>Snitch wanted me to find Tirana's PDA for him before he'd tell me anything. I finally got it from that swamp dweller, Dan. In exchange, Snitch will arrange a meeting with LeHavre, which should help move my investigation along...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gavr_begin">
			<text>LeHavre</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gavr_about_klik1_text">
			<text>So much time and effort, and still I know practically nothing. This scumbag LeHavre is involving me in his personal dirty work, but it's necessary to stay with him for now - instead of taking his fucking head off. I just want to bring all this to an end...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gavr_begin2">
			<text>LeHavre. Continued...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="gavr_about_klik2_text">
			<text>LeHavre has sent me on an assignment - to find some documents. Strange documents they are, with scribbled notes in every available space. Even the attached map is covered with numbers, arrows, and times...\nInterestingly, as soon as I started searching for Fang's murderer, a shitload of foreign mercenaries come looking for me. I haven't a fucking clue what's going on, but I appear to have stirred up something... something... something in the back of my mind keeps trying to surface. Anyway, I've made a copy of the documents, just in case, and will show them to Freeman. I feel I've met him before somewhere, and that he knows something that can help me...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freeman_begin">
			<text>Freeman</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freeman_about_klik_text">
			<text>Through Freeman I've finally learned who ordered Fang's death - that bastard LeHavre. Now I just need to tidy up a loose end. You're a dead man stalking, LeHavre, and I've just written your funeral date in my diary...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ecolog_about_prizrak_text">
			<text>The Ecologist doesn't think that Ghost is dead. On his instructions, I went searching for Ghost's PDA. It's barely decipherable so, until the Ecologist can figure it out, I'll go have a talk with the Barkeep</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ecolog_talk">
			<text>Ecologist. First conversation</text>
		</string>
		<string id="prizrak">
			<text>The search for Ghost</text>
		</string>
		<string id="barmen_about_prizrak_text">
			<text>The Ecologist's suspicion that Ghost was not working alone has been confirmed by the Barkeep, who found a 'lookalike' for Ghost to cover his back if any shit happened, and was with Ghost in the lab. He also gave me an obsolete decryption device to try out. Maybe we'll finally read Ghost's diary...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="barmen_talk">
			<text>Barkeep conversation</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ecolog_about_prizrak2_text">
			<text>The Ecologist sent me for new decryption device, as we can't go any further without one. We could only decipher a small fragment of the message - 'Yakut'. If it's the Yakut I know, though, I'll go and talk to him...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ecolog_talk2">
			<text>Ecologist. Second conversation</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yakut_about_prizrak_text">
			<text>Yakut sent me to the Agroprom underground, but I've not found anything here other than Bloodsuckers and a bunch of Bandit shitbags. I'll need to talk to him again...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yakut_talk">
			<text>Yakut. First conversation</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yakut_about_prizrak2_text">
			<text>At last I've found it! The Ecologist was right. Ghost really is alive!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yakut_talk2">
			<text>Yakut. Second conversation</text>
		</string>
		<string id="prizrak_about_prizrak_text">
			<text>As I understand it, Ghost was hunted down by a certain group or organization. Their leader goes by the name of Beast. What kind of man gives himself a name like that? Whatever, I need to pay them a reciprocal visit. This Beast is about to become extinct...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="prizrak_talk">
			<text>Ghost. First conversation</text>
		</string>
		<string id="prizrak_about_prizrak2_text">
			<text>That butcher Beast is dead. Now I can go to the Monolith with a clear mind...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="prizrak_talk2">
			<text>Ghost. Second conversation</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sysh_about_prizrak_text">
			<text>My dear Owl. Please forgive me, but if you're reading this I'm probably dead. There is no shame in death, my friend. I want to tell you everything, and this will be the final payment of my debts\nThat fight at the Army Warehouses is not what you think. We were waiting for you, but a hit squad was waiting for us! Whomever Ghost crossed, the equipment and weapons used against us must have come from someone who really wanted him dead... The Ecologists had just returned, two of them wounded, and they'd set up a temporary camp. I was waiting, about fifty metres from them, when they called to me for help. Near the Red Forest! But it was my job, and I couldn't refuse...\nJust as I stood up, someone took a shot at Ghost from God knows where and, at the exact same moment, a Controller appeared behind us! Maybe the shot confused it, because as Ghost went down, it ignored me and went straight for for the Ecologists! The Controller hurled them all into their campfire, while a pack of blind dogs started to attack me!\nThere was an old woman dressed in red in the distance, well away from the dogs, and she was waving to me! It was so surreal, but her waving arm was like a warning flag to me, and pulled me from my panic. I ended up with injuries to my hands, arms and legs, though I managed to drive us to Pripyat. Ghost looked in pretty bad condition, so we stopped and started a camp fire. I'd just laid Ghost down to rest by the fire, when the 'white haze' came out of nowhere... that Controller had followed us! Fang and I ran in opposite directions and it went after him, so I doubled back and emptied the rest of my mag into it. But by the time I returned to Ghost, the remaining part of his mind had been taken, and our friend lay there lifeless...\nThat night, after 'the white haze', something new was born within me. Something very, very different. After a while the Doctor arrived and dragged me away. He sensed that my body wasn't all that was wounded...\nWe'd given everything for nothing! I'd risked my life for the Zone... for the sake of what? I realized then that every contract has a deeper contract hidden behind it...\nFor all the time that I rested at the Doctor's place, he never once spoke to me. Sometimes he went away, never telling me where. I'd pretend to be asleep, but in reality there was no energy left behind my eyes...\n
			A few days later I was able to sit up, and the Doctor asked me just one thing. Why did the Zone present itself to me? Why me, and for what? What did it need me to do? What does it want resolved? I couldn't give him answers, because the answers had left me. He told me he had to leave, but that we would meet again\nAlone, I searched for death within myself, knowing it was there and waiting for it to show itself... When it did not I willed myself to the Arena instead, taking on allcomers, hoping that someone, or something, would do what the Zone could not - turn me to offal, fit only for pigs. But it wasn't to be, and every match made me stronger and sharper. I hung around Rostok for several weeks. Everyone knew that Ghost had gone missing, but not one approached me... I spent some time training rookies, teaching them the ways of the Zone (Ha! one of my favourite students, Palyonyj, said I must have mutated extra eyes in the back of my head!) but each time I potentially saved a life I knew that, while I was still in debt, the Zone would never release me...\nLater I met Mole, but he left for the Cordon. I remained alone, and began to search for the one who'd ordered the hit on Ghost. I talked discretely to many people, followed leads, went undercover to seek out contracts and remuneration, and tried to figure out the payment I should make in return. I have yet to find it! Worse still, since that day in Pripyat, the old fear has returned, and I no longer know how to face it...\nSoon I will go to check out something. I have received an offer from Arhara... Maybe I will go to meet him...\nI'm sorry, my friend. It is so difficult, but so necessary, to tell you all this...\nYour friend through everything, Strelok</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sysh_talk">
			<text>Ghost's note to Owl</text>
		</string>
		<string id="voen_about_group_text">
			<text>Eintrag: 12.08... vergessen\n \nIch bin der einzige, der von unserer Gruppe überlebt hat. Die ganze Mission war ein totales Desaster. Ich schreibe diese Worte auf um nicht zu vergessen. Immer wieder entfallen mir Sachen oder ich kann mich nicht an einzelne Dinge erinnern. Es ist zum Verrückt werden. Hoffentlich schaffe ich es .. dorthin zu kommen um .. denen zu berichten was vorgefallen ist.\n \nWie war das... also.. Wir Eskortierten ein paar Wissenschaftler zu den Nördlichen Armee-Lagerhäusern. Dort hatten sie an verschiedenen PSI Feldern geforscht. Irgendwie Testeten Sie eine Vorrichtung die mit Hilfe Chemischer Zusätze vor den PSI Emittern schützen solle.. Alle waren gut drauf, "Nauchniki" hatte öfter mal eine Gesang stunden gegeben. Lustiger Typ, hat sich öfter auf eine Metall Kiste gestellt und fing an zu singen. Irgendwann bemerkte ich eine Patrouille die sich komisch verhielt. Keine Ahnung was die da machten. Aber in unseren Schichtplan stand nichts davon. Die Zwei waren offensichtlich vom Militär.. so wie die gekleidete waren. Hinterließen aber ein sehr gefährlichen Eindruck, vor allem der mit der Maschine Pistole. Naja..\n \nDie Wissenschaftler vermeldeten ungewöhnliche Aktivitäten in ihren Messungen. Die Spitzwerte bei den Messungen zeigten eine sehr hohe Aktivität. Wir sollte ein Paar Helme ausprobieren und diese in ein paar PSI-Feldern testen. Es war übel, aber das gehörte mit zu unseren Auftrag. Dafür hatten wir unterschrieben. Dennoch wenn ich vorher gewusst hätte wie das ist, hätte ich das nicht gemacht. Wir mussten uns ein paar Sachen merken, den Helm zu tragen wurde zu einer Last. Er wurde mitunter so schwer das das man versuchte, den Kopf auf den Schultern abstützte. Irgendwie wurde auch alles so neblig Gelb um einen. Als ob man einen  Schleier aus Milch vor seinen Augen hätte. ..Sieht wohl so aus, wenn man sich in einen Toten verwandelt.\n \nDiese Testroutinen verliefen alle Zwei Stunden. Nach ein paar Tagen, als ich für ein weiteren Test vorbereitet wurde standen plötzlich ein paar Typen vor den Wissenschaftlern mit vorgehaltener Waffe. Unsere Jungs hielten mit ihren gezogenen Waffen dagegen. Plötzlich ein Gegröle und ein Telepath erschien. Einige Jungs sind zusammengebrochen, die Wissenschaftler liefen in Deckung. Die Sicherung war schon nicht mehr gewährleistet, seit dem die Typen irgendwas von den Wissenschaftlern wollte. So hatte keiner den Telepathen bemerkt.\n \nDie Lage geriet außer Kontrolle. Der Schafschütze, von den Angreifern, nahm den Telepath im Visier und auch  die nicht zu unseren Jungs gehörten versuchten den Telepath zur Strecke zu bringen. Der Telepath hatte so eine Mentale Kraft das dieser, die Soldaten fertigmachte. Ich Versuchte zu entkommen und der Scharfschütze schoss mir in den Kopf, ich hatte den Helm aber die Elektronik wurde in beschädigt. Er hatte mich vor den Auswirkungen der Mentalen Fähigkeit des Telepathen geschützt. Aber nach dem Schuss bin ich gestürzt und in meinem Kopf Dröhnte dann die PSI Kraft des Telepathen.\n \nBevor ich zu Boden fiel sah ich den Scharfschützen und den Telepathen. Aus dem Blickwinkel sah ich noch unsere Jungs, wie die Getötet wurden. Einige haben sich selber erschossen. Bei einigen sah man das Blut aus dem Augen  sowie aus den Ohren, Nase und Mund laufen. Dann wurde mir schwarz vor den Augen.\n \nAls ich zu mir gekommen bin herrschte eine Merkwürdige Stille. Die Wissenschaftler, unsere Jungs sowie die Angreifer, alle tot. Ich hab ein paar ganz heftige Kopfschmerzen. Ich fing an alles aufzuschreiben, irgendwie fehlten mir Erinnerung an meiner Kindheit sowie an anderen Sachen. Verratzte mich erstmal und machte mich auf den Weg. Bei der "Müllhalde" traf ich auf ein Stalker. Durch meine Verwirrtheit nahm er mich auf und gab mir Proviant, Medikit's und eine halbe Flasche Vodka. Er beharrte darauf das ich mich ausruhen solle. Ich stimmte zu. Mein PDA habe ich bei einem Posten gelassen. Er enthält eine Kopie meines Tagebuchs sowie die Route. Danke an den Stalker "Ghost".</text>
		</string>
		<string id="voen_talk">
			<text>Notiz des Soldatan vom Tunnel</text>
		</string>
		<string id="nauc_group">
			<text>Vermisste Wissenschaftler.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandranen_about_group_text">
			<text>Yesterday, as usual, we set up an ambush, with my turn to be the wounded one. I lay down in that fucking road all day, but no one showed up. We'd have been better off just shooting the local dogs. Vmazali just sat there behind a rock, drinking vodka, like everything was normal, but then I noticed a Stalker by the road that leads to the Dark Valley. Usually we avoid Stalkers, and this one didn't appear to have anything of value. He wasn't even armed, for fuck's sake! But he was stumbling a bit and didn't look well. Is he playing us, I thought? No, he was obviously injured. At first I went over to join the others, but then this guy noticed my buddy and waved. We went over to him, and he offered us some bread and a few other things. He didn't seem to want to keep anything - he even gave us his PDA! Well, we thought it was our lucky day... until later on when we found Razderbanili, one of ours. Someone had strung him to a tree by his neck and cut his throat. What was scary was that he still all had his stuff on him, including his PDA... It said he was looking for that bastard, Borov. Well, we didn't want to hang around, so we took his loot and headed for Agroprom...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandranen_talk">
			<text>Wounded Bandit's PDA</text>
		</string>
		<string id="fraer_about_group_text">
			<text>Recording from yesterday... Damn, we boozed all day long, and the vodka ran out pretty quickly. So I went to Borov, to get some more from our stockpile. He told me to fuck off, so I left the base and headed off to Agroprom. I don't remember why... I really needed vodka, so I stopped these two morons with backpacks at the Dump. I had some vodka with them, and noticed they had a nice-looking PDA before they left for the base. Right, tomorrow I'm going to find it. One of the locals is bound to remember them, and where they went...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="fraer_talk">
			<text>Friar's PDA</text>
		</string>
		<string id="prapor_about_group_text">
			<text>I just received info from the Duty fighters at Cordon. They've caught this bandit, who insists that it was Friar who gave him the backpack he was carrying. They think it might be of use to me, so I just need to find ten Scientific medkits for a fair exchange...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="prapor_talk">
			<text>First conversation with Prapor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="prapor_about_group2_text">
			<text>I brought Prapor the ten Scientific medkits. In exchange he gave me a broken PDA. Great... Now I need to see the Barman. Maybe he'll know if someone can fix it...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="prapor_talk2">
			<text>Second conversation with Prapor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="barrem_about_group_text">
			<text>I don't know what to write... The trail has gone cold... Is this the end for me, too?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="barrem_talk">
			<text>Conversation with the Barkeep</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ara_about_group_text">
			<text>When I was in Rostok, I spoke with Gray. He told me many things of interest, including the fact that he and his group were working with the scientists at Radar and the Red Forest, but were afraid to go further. The Brain Scorcher was close by, so they settled in the Army Warehouses to wait for the scientists, but after three days they gave up and left. He reckons that those eggheads, who'd decided to research a place from which nobody has ever returned, had clearly not thought it through...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ara_talk">
			<text>Flash drive belonging to the mercenary Ara</text>
		</string>
		<string id="siv_about_group_text">
			<text>Our scientists told us of a group that were on an expedition. We weren't informed exactly where, so we camped in Rostok near the tunnel. We didn't have to wait long, because they showed up by the evening. Jean suggested attacking them there and then, since it was dark and they'd be tired. The location in our favour, too - narrow and open. But they had fifteen to twenty people and we had only five, so we followed them to the Red Forest. Then we got news of an emission, and the Brain Scorcher was nearby, so we hot-tailed it to the Army Warehouses and waited for them there, hoping they'd return soon\nIt became obvious that there was something really important for these scientists there. We waited a couple of days at the Army Warehouses, then went looking for them again. As soon as we found them, just pottering around, Jean decided to rush in and shot a couple of them, but a third one he hadn't spotted took him down with a single burst...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="siv_talk">
			<text>Flash drive belonging to the mercenary Gray</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sah_about_group_text">
			<text>Sakharov told me about the scientists' expedition to Radar. He believes that they all died. I need to check this out...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sah_talk">
			<text>Conversation with Sakharov</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ucen_about_group_text">
			<text>This was a heavy conversation. I'm used to seeing death every day, but seldom this close. How many good people will the Zone continue to take?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ucen_talk">
			<text>Conversation with the wounded scientist</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_short_sms">
			<text>Short text messages (SMS)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sms_new_dan1_text">
			<text>Gezeichneter, Zachar hier! Dan wurde getötet. Komm vorbei, wir müssen reden..</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sms_new_dan2_text">
			<text>Gezeichneter, Ich bin's Zachar! Dan ist Tot. Komm vorbei, wir sollte uns unterhalten.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sms_new_dan3_text">
			<text>Gezeichneter, Zachar hier! Dan wurde Tot aufgefunden. Komm vorbei, wir sollte uns unterhalten.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sms_new_dan4_text">
			<text>Gezeichneter, hier ist Zachar! Dan ist umgekommen... Das gibt boch Konsequenzen. Komm vorbei, so schnell wie möglich.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="nebo">
			<text>Clear Sky</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_dyak_help_need">
			<text>Clerik, the commander of the Clear Sky fighters at the entrance from Cordon, has asked for help to free their scout from the Bandits at the abandoned church</text>
		</string>
		<string id="box_kalmyak_name">
			<text>Box of Kalmyak's possessions</text>
		</string>
		<string id="box_kalmyak_desc">
			<text>Heavy steel box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="maz">
			<text>Kalmyak's ointment</text>
		</string>
		<string id="maz_desc">
			<text>Kalmyak's ointment. Neutralizes the radiation in a wound, and stimulates healing</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_kalmyak_need">
			<text>Kalmyak asked me to find his old backpack, and bring him the container inside. The problem is that a Teleport anomaly has formed near it...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_marsh_remont">
			<text>Vasily, the repairman at the Clear Sky base, is in too much pain to repair anything. His foot has swelled up badly, and he needs some of Kalmyak's ointment. However, it can only be obtained from Kalmyak himself...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_dyak_maz">
			<text>Clerik can give you three tins of Kalmyak's ointment, but requests a 'Soul' artefact in exchange</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_mozg">
			<text>Controller's brain</text>
		</string>
		<string id="red_mozg_description">
			<text>Brain of the Unique Controller</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mutant_krovosos_red_jaw">
			<text>Bloodsucker's jaw</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mutant_krovosos_red_jaw_description">
			<text>Blood-covered lower jawbone of a Bloodsucker</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mutant_burer_red_hand">
			<text>Red Burer hand</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mutant_burer_red_hand_description">
			<text>A red Burer hand. A rare item indeed...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_controller_hutor">
			<text>According to Sviblov, unusual mutant variations have been sighted recently. One of these is a Controller on a farm in the north-west, not far from the railway junctions. He asks you to bring him the brain of this Controller for research into the phenomenon...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_sveeblov_ferma">
			<text>Sviblov wants to organize spot checks on all large mutants, and needs a powerful weapon for this task. He asks you to steal a PKM machine gun from the Bandits camped on an abandoned farm. However, he doesn't want to provoke an endless and probably needless war with the Bandit faction, so asks you to do this job as an outsider, as discreetly as possible and without bloodshed. Before you go, however, you need to talk with Kashcheev, the Clear Sky scout near there...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mono_dead_doc_name">
			<text>Documents on the corpse of the Monolithian</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mono_dead_doc_desc">
			<text>Documents on the corpse of the Monolithian. A detailed map of the swamps, with odd markings on the map...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="televizor">
			<text>TV</text>
		</string>
		<string id="televizor_desc">
			<text>\nAnaloges Fensehgerät aus den 80ern.\nVersteht sich als Röhrengerät.  wobei sich der Begriff Röhre hier auf das Hauptbauteil, die Bildröhre bezieht. Diese ist ihrer Konstruktion nach eine Braunsche Röhre, benannt nach ihrem Erfinder "Karl Ferdinand Braun". Diese Röhre besteht aus einem unter Vakuum stehenden, trichterförmigen Glasbehälter, in dem je nach der gewünschten Helligkeit eines Bildpunktes mehr oder weniger Elektronen von der Kathode im hinten liegenden Bildröhrenhals nach vorn zur Anode (dem eigentlichen Bildschirm) hin beschleunigt werden und die dort aufgebrachte Leuchtschicht erregen.\n \nDie Hochspannung an der Anode wird in der Regel aus dem Zeilengenerator gewonnen und durch den Zeilentrafo auf je nach Bildschirmgröße 6.000 bis 33.000 Volt hochtransformiert. Die Bildröhre wirkt mit ihrer inneren und äußeren Aquadag-Beschichtung als großer Kondensator und behält die Hochspannung auch noch einige Zeit nach dem Abschalten des Gerätes und kann damit eine Gefahr darstellen. Aufgrund der geringen Leistung ist diese Spannung für Menschen im Allgemeinen nicht tödlich; es kommt aber bei einer Berührung zu schreckhaften starken Muskelbewegungen, die sekundär körperlichen Schaden und Sachschaden nach sich ziehen können. Deshalb sollten Arbeiten im Inneren von Röhrenfernsehgeräten grundsätzlich nur von geschultem Personal durchgeführt werden.\n \nIn der Frühzeit des Fernsehens (1930er und 1940er Jahre) wurde auch die elektrostatische Bildablenkung verwendet. Hier befinden sich zwei in einem Winkel von 90 Grad gegeneinander versetzte Kondensatorplatten im Hals der Bildröhre, zwischen denen sich bei Anlegen einer hohen Spannung ein elektrostatisches Feld aufbaut, welche den Elektronenstrahl ablenkt. Die mit annehmbaren Ablenkspannungen - so nur maximale Ablenkwinkel von etwa 40 Grad erzielbar sind, hatte sich später die elektromagnetische Ablenkung mit Ablenkspulen durchgesetzt, mit der Ablenkwinkel von über 110 Grad möglich sind.\n \nBei Farbfernsehgeräten gibt es drei leicht gegeneinander versetzte Kathoden für die drei Grundfarben Rot, Grün und Blau. Eine Maske in Form eines feinen Metallgitters knapp hinter der Mattscheibe sorgt in diesem Fall dafür, dass die Elektronen von jeder Kathode nur auf Fluoreszenzpunkte „ihrer“ Farbe treffen können. Die übrigen Elektronen bleiben in der Maske hängen. Da die meisten Elektronen daher den Bildschirm nie erreichen, muss die Beschleunigungsspannung in einem Farbfernsehgerät bei gleicher Bildhelligkeit viel höher sein als in einem Schwarz-Weiß-Gerät. Die fluoreszierende Schicht besteht in diesem Fall aus nebeneinanderliegenden kleinen Punkten oder Streifen der drei Grundfarben. Diese Elemente kann man leicht erkennen, wenn man den Bildschirm aus kurzer Distanz betrachtet.\n \nSehr beliebt bei "Retrogamer", das das Bild natürlicher aussieht.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mono_note_name">
			<text>Notebook des Monolithen</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mono_note_desc">
			<text>Personal notebook of the Monolithian. Not the hefty type designed for large pockets, but the small one carried by many Stalkers</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_kot_need_next">
			<text>Cat is concerned about the presence of Monolithians in the Swamp. He's asked you to find two of them who've been sighted in the area, and obtain information from them in any way necessary. These Monolithians won't be easy to find, and you'd be advised to ask around the base for info on their last whereabouts...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_need_televizor">
			<text>Chiston can help you find the Monolithians, but in return he'd like you to find him a TV set. Does he think he's going to get a decent signal here?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="wpn_awm_new">
			<text>Modified 'Iglomet' dart gun</text>
		</string>
		<string id="wpn_awm_new_desc">
			<text>Iglomet modified to shoot hypodermic tracking darts</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo_igl_new">
			<text>Tracking dart</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo_igl_new_desc">
			<text>A.50 calibre ballistic syringe containing a tiny tracking device in liquid suspension. The hypodermic needle falls away after impacting the skin, leaving the device deeply inside the body of the target</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_gigant_red">
			<text>According to Cold, a unique Red Pseudogiant has been spotted at Agroprom. He asks you to find this animal, and 'tag' it with a modified Iglomet that shoots tracking darts. On no account must you kill it! Just tag it and report back to him. He'll organize others to capture it...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="pda_francuz_desc">
			<text>PDA belonging to the Frenchman. Standard PDA carried by many Stalkers, but with a lot more interesting information...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="pda_francuz">
			<text>The Frenchman's PDA</text>
		</string>
		<string id="glushitel">
			<text>Tragbarer Funksignal-Störsender</text>
		</string>
		<string id="glushitel_desc">
			<text>\nEin Signal Störer der die Funksignale in einem Radius von 2km unterdrückt.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_borman_sniper">
			<text>Borman asks you to locate the Monolithian sniper who is killing his men, and put a permanent stop to his activity. According to Borman, the sniper has set up his position in the tall, unfinished building...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_borman_glushitel">
			<text>Borman has asked you to find the signal jammer that's currently intercepting and suppressing Freedom's radio signals, and take it to Miser to have it recoded. Then position it back where you found it, thus restoring Freedom's safe transmission channels and allowing them to intercept Monolith ones. The jammer is expected to be on or near the top of a tall building</text>
		</string>
		<string id="lekar_kalmyak_desc">
			<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+80\n%c[default]Medicine for Kalmyak. Using a recipe he learned from his grandmother, this rustic home-made antidote is highly effective in removing radiation from the human body</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_xalyava_nebo">
			<text>Sviblov has asked you to witness a transaction between Freebie and a group of mercenaries at an abandoned farm in Cordon. Under no circumstances must you be spotted, or the Mercs will cover their tracks - and we need that traitor Freebie alive...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_kot_agro_mono">
			<text>According to Cat, there's a group of Monolithians at Agroprom. He wants me to find out as much as I can from them...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="case_nebo">
			<text>Sviblov's case</text>
		</string>
		<string id="case_nebo_desc">
			<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+30\n%c[default]Sviblov's case. A radiation and shock-proof case designed to protect the flasks inside, and the carrier from its contents...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_brat_luis">
			<text>Zahar tells me that Brother Louis, one of leaders of the 'Avengers' from the Swamps, is looking for the Frenchman. So I need to find him first...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_francuz_start">
			<text>The dealer known as 'The Frenchman' has sought refuge at the Freedom base. I need to hurry before the 'Avengers' find him...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_kot_find_rabi">
			<text>If the Monolith are building something, the dealer Rabinovich will know. Zahar advises you to talk with Miser, as he knows they've done business together recently</text>
		</string>
		<string id="nebo_clear">
			<text>Anomaly Annihilator</text>
		</string>
		<string id="anigilator_anomal_zones">
			<text>Anomaly Annihilator. Designed to collapse and dissipate the energies of an anomaly, including Teleports. Instructions for use: Throw it into the center of the anomaly...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_nebo_kurier">
			<text>Sviblov has asked you to find the missing courier from Radar. The courier was on his way to Yantar, so it would make sense to start near the Brain Scorcher...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="price_upgr_marsh_remont_text">
			<text>List of upgrades for Vasily's suits:\n \n1. Adding night vision to the following suits (Classification: Clear Sky exoskeleton, Clear Sky scientific suit, Monolith black suit):\n-PNV 'Green' - 10,000Ru;\n-PNV 'Digital' - 25,000Ru;\n-PNV 'Sepia' - 15,000Ru;\n-PNV 'Halogen' - 20,000Ru;\n-PNV 'Cats Eye' - 30,000Ru;\n-PNV 'Psi-effect' - 25,000Ru;\n-PNV 'Moonlight' - 25,000Ru;\n-PNV 'White Night' - 30,000Ru;\n \n2</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_shadowman_zver">
			<text>Shadows has asked me to help the Stalkers at the tower camp outside the Red Forest to fend off a mutant wave. They're not prepared for this, and will be ripped to shreds. He's left a Winchester shotgun and cartridges in a bag on the second floor, in case of such an emergency. If I can save even one Stalker, my efforts won't have been in vain...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_shadowman_forest">
			<text>Shadows has requested help to defend the Stalkers against the mercenaries at the Limansk bridge</text>
		</string>
		<string id="price_grib_marsh_xolod_text">
			<text>For three mushrooms, Cold will give:\n-Five boxes of 7.62x25 mm for the machine pistol PPSH-41;\n-Three boxes of 7.92x57 for the Maschinengewehr 42 (MG-42) machine gun;\n-Three Army medkits;\n-Three Antirads;\n-Four boxes of 5.45x39mm;\n-Four boxes of 5.56x45mm SS109;\n-Three boxes of 9x39mm PAB-9</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_klyak_forest_doc">
			<text>Fang has asked me to retrieve a set of documents from the hunters in the Red Forest</text>
		</string>
		<string id="text_arc_denis_wound">
			<text>Fang has urged you to find his friend Denis, who went to the Red Forest alone to check out a stash in the abandoned mine. That was two days ago, and there's been no word from him. Please find Denis, and help him bring back what he found...</text>
		</string>
	</string_table>
<!--Created/Modified with S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Dialog Extended Editor by Marty Sheppard/ Version: 0.96i ( 2017/02/17) =!!= Last changed: 08.07.2017 20:41:53 -->
