<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.7 the doctor, line 451, 454, 484, rem. russian char. aleks1970, price_dan_prinesi_text, freeman_braad_one_2, Sidorovich,DeJames, something, 6 boar hooves, text outside block removed, ghost diary, land to miser -->
<!-- Names changed as commented below - Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16 -->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16  -->
<string_table>
	<string id="prinesi_hvost_0">
		<text>Sei gegrüßt! Ich habe hier ein paar Mutanten teile für dich. Interessiert?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prinesi_hvost_1">
		<text>Hallo Gezeichneter. Sicher. Warum nicht. Du kommst doch gut rum in der Zone und triffst wahrscheinlich auf jede Menge Viehzeug. Ich brauche immer wieder solche Mutanten Sachen. Ich beliefere einige Kunden die daraus Medizin erstellen wollen. Ich bräuchte:\n3x Schwänze von Mutierten Hund oder \n6x Wildscheinhufen.\n \nWenn du mir die Sachen bringst mach' ich dir ein guten Preis.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prinesi_hvost_2">
		<text>Hallo Dan, Hier. Wildschweinehufe. Die wolltest du doch? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="prinesi_hvost_3">
		<text>Hallo Dan. Ich habe hier ein paar Hunde Schwänze für dich.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prinesi_hvost_4">
		<text>Perfekt. Die sehen gut aus. Für die bekomme ich sicher ein guten Preis. Hier die Belohnung für dich.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prinesi_hvost_5">
		<text>Super. Hundeschwänze sind gerade richtig. Hier für deine Mühen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prinesi_hvost_6">
		<text>Ich hab' noch nicht genug beisammen. Habe ich genug, komme ich zurück.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fox_bring_0">
		<text>Hallo Fox, wie geht es dir?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fox_bring_1">
		<text>Wie soll's mir denn gehen? Die verdammten Hunde lassen mich nicht in Ruhe. Vielleicht hab ich ein besonderen Geruch an mir, vielleicht sind die läufig - was weiß ich...\n \nÜbrigens, Gezeichneter - du könntest mir ein Gefallen tun. Bei dem Wächter-Blockposten auf der Müllhalde wurde für mich ein Paket hinterlassen. Ein sehr gute Waffe.\n \nSei so gut, bring sie mir, ok? Damit hab ich mehr Schutz gegen diese Köter, und bei der Menge der Stiernacken, die sich hier in der Nähe aufhalten ist die Waffe mehr als sinnvoll. Ich würd ja selbst gehen, wenn ich wieder zu Kräften gekommen bin. Aber ich muss hier auf den Doktor warten und dann bei ihm erstmal bleiben\n \nFrag' den Feldwebel bei dem Blockposten, er sollte Bescheid wissen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fox_bring_2">
		<text>Kein Problem Fox. Ich werde den Feldwebel dort aufsuchen.\n \nBin dann bald zurück.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fox_bring_3">
		<text>Fox. Würde ich gerne machen. Aber dafür habe ich echt keine Zeit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fox_give_0">
		<text>Hallo Fox. Hier ist deine Waffe. Wahr ein bisschen Schwierig. "Prapor" beim Blockposten wollte die nicht einfach so rausrücken. Musste vorher noch ein Job für ihn erledigen. Das hat er erstmal ausgenutzt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fox_give_1">
		<text>Ich danke dir, "Gezeichneter". Auf dich ist echt verlaß. Sorry für die Umstände. So.. Sollen die alle jetzt nur kommen, dann kriegen sie den Arsch voll. Hier für deine Mühen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prapor_bring_jaw_0">
		<text>Hallo "Prapor". Ich bin hier um Fox zu helfen. Er selbst konnte nicht kommen. Dafür ist er zu angeschlagen. Er meinte du hättest was für ihn?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prapor_bring_jaw_1">
		<text>Ja klar... Bin ich hier die Poststelle? Einfach so geht gar das nun nicht. Bring mir ein paar Blutsauger-Tentakeln, dann reden wir. Als Lagerungsgebühr, sozusagen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prapor_bring_jaw_2">
		<text>Nicht grade anständig von dir, aber was soll's. Werde ich besorgen. Ich hab' Fox mein Wort gegeben, und ein Mann hält, was er versprochen hat. Gerade unter uns Stalkern ist das wichtig.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prapor_give_jaw_0">
		<text>Tag auch. Sparen wir die Fragen nach Gesundheit, ok? Hier sind dein Tentakeln. Dann schieb' mal rüber das Paket.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prapor_give_jaw_1">
		<text>Danke, "Gezeichneter". Sei nicht so sauer. Ich brauche diese Tentakeln, ich mache nämlich ein heilendes Likör daraus. Das erhält die Manneskraft auch bei hiesigen Strahlungslevel. Das Likör geht mir schon zu Neige, und ich bin ja nicht mehr der Jungste. Wir waren uns aber auch nicht sicher ob du es schaffen würdest. Jedenfalls hab' ich fünf Flaschen Vodka bei der Wette verloren.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_pda_tiran_0">
		<text>Sag' mal. So unter uns. Hast du ein paar Informationen für mich?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_pda_tiran_1">
		<text>Sicher das du mir reden willst?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_pda_tiran_2">
		<text>Hör zu. Keine Spielchen. General Voronin schickt mich. Erzähl mir einfach wer "Fang" getötet hat und wiso eigentlich. Ok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_pda_tiran_3">
		<text>"Gezeichneter", du bist ein bekannter Mann in der Zone, aber denkst du wirklich, das du deswegen einfach so, kostenlos, Infos von mir bekommen kannst? So läuft das nicht... Wenn du Infos willst - bezahle.\n \nIch sag dir was. In der letzten Zeit geht ein Gerücht um: jemand soll den PDA von "Tirana", dem Söldner-Anführer, gestohlen haben. Ob er noch lebte, oder schon tot war - keine Ahnung. Du verstehst, bestimmt, wie viele Daten drauf gespeichert sind und was diese Wert sind? Nach diesem PDA läuft in Moment eine richtige Hetz Jagd. Freiheit, Wächter, Banditen - alle wollen ihn in die Finger bekommen.\n \nIch weiß wo und wer diesen PDA hat! Wenn du ein Spaziergang machst und mir den PDA bringst, dann mache ich für dich ein Treffen aus. Mit einem wichtigen Mann, der wird dir alles erzählen, was er weiß. Und er weiß viel.\n \nNa, was ist?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_pda_tiran_4">
		<text>Hmm. Okay. Ich werde den PDA besorgen. Wer ist diese Person?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_pda_tiran_5">
		<text>Pass auf: In den Sümpfen gibt es ein neuen Laden Besitzer. Meine Quellen berichteten mir das er irgendwie in dem Zusammenhang steht und auch noch andere "Geschäfte" tätigt. Er besitzt auch diesen PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_pda_tiran_6">
		<text>Moment.. Dan? Er soll es sein? Ich werde Dan besuchen. Wenn du mich aber verscheißerst, so wird es dir leid tun.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_pda_bring_0">
		<text>Sag mal Willst du mich verarschen. Ich habe den PDA aber wie kommt es das die Söldner genau wussten wo und wann ich dort sein werde.\n \nKomm, schon rede.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_pda_bring_1">
		<text>Du hat ihn also bekommen? Respekt. Du hälst dein Wort. Nun beruhige dich. Überleg doch mal. Wiso sollte ich deine Position verpfeifen. Es gibt noch andere Gruppen und Einrichtungen die diesen PDA haben wollen. Ich denke das es ein paar Leute gibt die die Kastanien nicht gern selbst aus dem Feuer ziehen. Heuern stattdessen Söldner für solche Aufträge an. So sieht es aus, Bruder..\n \nNun hör mir aufmerksam zu. In der Freiheits-Basis in den Armeelagerhäusern triffst du dich mit LeHavre. Er wird in einer der Kasernen sein. Er wird dir alles über "Fang" erzählen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_pda_bring_2">
		<text>Was zum Teufel?!... Ein Söldner in der Freiheitsbasis? Wird die Welt jetzt vollkommen verrückt? Oder hab ich was verpasst?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_pda_bring_3">
		<text>Leise! Schrei nicht so, als ob du im Zaun feststeckst! Das ist ein gefährlicher Kerl... Er hat Beziehungen zur Außenwelt. Die meisten Waffen und Ausrüstung bekommt die "Freiheit" über ihn. Die waschen ihm die Füsse und trinken danach das Wasser.\n \nUnterschät das nicht. LeHavre selbst ist auch ein starker Kämpfer. Mit Drohungen oder Gewalt wirst du bei ihm nicht weit kommen. Viel Glück!\n \nÜbrigens, hier - nimm dieses Artefakt. Die meisten hier in der Bar halten mich für einen Aufschneider und so soll es auch bleiben... Erstmal. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_pda_give_0">
		<text>Hey, Dan! Es geht um eine verdammt ernste Sache, die uns beide betrifft. Ich weiß genau, das du ein bestimmten PDA hast, welchen ich unbedingt brauche. Mir kam zu Ohren das du auch noch in andere Geschäfte sehr Fleißig bist. Gib ihn mir - dann gehen wir in Frieden unsere Wege. Wenn nicht... ist deine Entscheidung.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_pda_give_1">
		<text>Ist ja gut, "Gezeichneter", reg dich ab, ich kenn' dich. Ich weiß, das du mich leicht fertig machen kannst, und da wird auch mein Exo nicht helfen.\n \nHier, nimm das Ding. Hat mir ein Kerl da gelassen, damit ich es aufbewahre. Ich war ihm ein Gefallen schuldig, und konnte nicht "Nein" sagen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_pda_give_2">
		<text>INFORMATOR_PDA_GIVE_2 WIRD NICHT BENUTZT</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_pda_give_3">
		<text>Mann, was für eine Erleichterung! Glaub mir, ich hatte gar nicht vor dich zu töten, aber ich brauche diesen PDA wirklich. Danke dir, Bruder, ich werde meine Schuld irgendwann doppelt begleichen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="informator_pda_give_4">
		<text>Gut, "Gezeichneter", das merke ich mir.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_take_first_0">
		<text>Bist du LeHavre? Der Informant schickt mich.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_take_first_1">
		<text>Oh! Der "Gezeichnete" ist da... Der Informant hat dich schon angekündigt, das du den oder die Mörder von "Fang" suchst. Ich kann dir dabei helfen, aber nicht umsonst. Du mußt für uns ein paar Aufträge erledigen, die nicht grade sauber sind, aber gut bezahlt werden. Eine Hand wäscht die andere und ich kenne deine Qualitäten.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_take_first_2">
		<text>Qualitäten? Du meinst Töten.. Das musste irgendwann ja so kommen. Sieht wohl so aus als würde ich ein Geschäft mit dem Teufel eingehen. Welche Finsteren Aufträge spuken dir in deinem verkorksten Schädel so rum. An was hast du gedacht?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_take_first_3">
		<text>Daran habe ich nicht gedacht. Vielleicht komme ich aber darauf zurück. Kommen wir zur Sache. Du hast dem Informant den PDA gebracht. Aus den gespeicherten Dateien geht hervor, das in unseren Reihen sich eine Ratte befindet. Und diese Ratte kein einfaches Mitglied ist, sondern ein Anführer. Direkte Beweise dafür gibt es natürlich nicht, deswegen kann ich noch nicht meine Jungs schicken um die Sache zu "klären". Es würden nur Schuldzuweisungen, gegenseitige Verdächtigungen und Krieg in der Gruppe dabei herauskommen.\n \nDu, als außenstehende Person, kommst da sehr gelegen. "Bolt" - so heißt die Ratte - er ist grad in der Nähe, mm Ende der Stra?e die zur Basis führt. Du musst sein PDA besorgen, dann haben wir klare Beweise für sein Verrat. Einverstanden? Eine gute Belohnung ist selbstverständlich.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_take_first_4">
		<text>OK, wie dem auch sei. Ich werd dir den PDA schon bringen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_bring_pda_0">
		<text>Hör mal, du Hühnerstall-Adler! Wo schickst du mich denn einfach so rein? Da gab's ja mehr Scharfschützen als Zombies in Jantar. Du hättest mich warnen könnnen. Hier hast du, was du wolltest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_bring_pda_1">
		<text>Deine Worte verletzen mich sehr... Ich bin nämlich ein sehr feinsinniger Mensch, weißt du. Du weißt doch selbst, das die Zone voller Ärger und Überraschungen ist. Egal, du hast die Sache erledigt, hier hast du was, um dir Vodka zu leisten. Geh, wohin du willst...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_help_one_0">
		<text>Mich laust der Affe.. Mensch?! Gordon Freeman, höchstpersönlich! Hat man dich aus City 17 verjagt? Ich hab da mal ein Gerücht gehört, das du nach einem Angriff und den Tod eines Wissenschaftler verschwunden bist. Warte.. Bist du noch bei Evlav und Black Mesa angestellt oder hat man dich aufgegeben?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_help_one_1">
		<text>...\n \n \n \nFragen über Fragen! Evlav? Dieser Geldstinkende Verein. Die haben die Zusammenarbeit aufgeben. Nach dem Desaster mit dem Combine Advisor wollte ich verschwinden. Dann wurde aber alles Schwarz um mich. Ich hörte Alex noch, aber ihre Stimme wurde immer leiser. Nach einiger Zeit bin ich, was du als den Kordon kennst, aufgewacht. Dort traf ich ein Paar Männer. Die brachten mich zu einem Mann den man Sidorovich nennt.\n \nDieser hat mir ein Führer besorgt. Er führte mich durch ein Tal, vorbei an einem See und an einem Fabrikkomplex. Wir hatten uns zwischendurch auch ein paar Feuergefechte mit den Söldner geführt. Erinnerte mich an den Kampf in Black Mesa. Er wollte mich zu einem Mann namens Sahkarov bringen aber.. In der Luft herrschte eine seltsame stille. Die wurde aber von einem Leisen brummen überlagert. Der Stalker der mich führte fing irgendwann an zu stammeln und zu murmeln. Ich versuchte ihn anzusprechen aber sein blick fühlte sich an als würde dieser durch mich durchgehen. Mich durchfuhr sofort eine Erinnerung an die Ravenholm Geschehnisse. Die Augen waren Glasig und schal und seine Haut fing an bleich zu werden.\n \nPlötzlich hörte ich das Gebrüll, aus einer Entfernung, auf mich zukommen. Ich Flüchtete in einen Tunnel mit Haufenweise Blitze. Ich kämpfte mich bis zum Eingestürzten Ende des Tunnels durch. Dort blieb ich erstmal eine Weile und ruhte mich aus. Das Gebrüll verstummte dann irgendwann.\n \nKopfschmerzen hatte ich die ganze Zeit über, verdammte Kopfschmerzen. Irgendwann bin ich dann wohl eingeschlafen vor Erschöpfung. Ich weiß gar nicht. Wie lange ich mich dort aufhielt. Gefühlt.. eine Woche, Ein Monat aber in Wirklich waren es wohl  nur Stunden. Letzten Endes wurde ich von einem Geschrei geweckt. Ein Monster mit Zwei Köpfen hat es in den Tunnel geschafft. Es war riesig und massiv. Diese Blitze machten dem Vieh nichts aus. Es kam mir so vor als ob es sich darin badete und gleichzeitig sich auflud.\n \nZum glück hatte es mich nicht bemerkt. Ich Schlich mich an dem Ungetüm vorbei und auch an den Blitzen. Durch die Kettenreaktion des Monsters konnte ich nun alles bestens erkennen. Dann lief ich. Habe aber meine Ausrüstung darin liegengelassen. Ich kam nicht mehr dran. Wenn du mal dort in der Nähe bist, dann schau doch mal ob du mir die nicht besorgen könntest. Darunter war auch eine Modifizierte Desert Eagle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_help_one_2">
		<text>Keine Sorge, Ruhe dich erstmal aus. Ich werde deine Sachen finden.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_bring_one_0">
		<text>Hey, Gordon! Na, gehts dir wieder besser? Hier ist deine Kanone. Gefällt mir, ein richtiger Elefanten-Killer aber ein Brecheisen war nicht dabei.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_bring_one_1">
		<text>"Gezeichneter"! Schön dich zu sehen. Ja, geht schon. Mich plagen derzeit noch Träume von dem G-Man aber mit Vodka geht das schon. Hier - dein Finder lohn. Ich habe ein Artefakt für dich...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_case_help_0">
		<text>Ich sehe, du hast dich schon eingelebt. Gefällt es dir hier beim Wirt? Pass aber auf und trink nicht zu viel auf Bruderschaft mit den Wächter da. Erzähl bloß nicht soviel von Black Mesa. Die könnten vielleicht auf komische Ideen kommen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_case_help_1">
		<text>Ich pass' schon auf. Jedenfalls sehr gute Truppe hier, sehr gastfreundlich. Aber könntest du mir noch ein Gefallen tun?\n \nAls ich mit dem Stalker unterwegs war der mich führte trafen wir außer Söldner auch auf einen Typen namens "DeJames". Ihm hatte ich ein paar unterlagen vorübergehend gegeben. Wir wurden dann irgendwann im Kampf getrennt. Nun habe ich aber hier von anderer Seite gehört das der Typ anscheinend ein Schwindler und Hehler ist und auch mit Infos Dealt.\n \nIch fürchte das er mich an die Söldner oder dem Militär verkaufen will. In der Akte befinden sich ein paar sehr brisante Unterlagen zu "Evlav" und ihrem Geschäft Modell "Maets". Dabei geht es um Online Kontrolle, Statistiken und Abhängigkeit sowie weiteren Illegalen Geschäft Methoden. Aber auch die Stilllegung um Aperture Science.\n \nDer Typ Soll sich irgendwo im "Wild Gebiet" aufhalten und wohnt wohl in so einem Mobilen Pappkarton.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_case_help_2">
		<text>Sicher, dafür bin ich der Mann hier in der Zone. "DeJames"? Noch nie von dem Typen gehört.\n \nBis später.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_james_speak_0">
		<text>Hey, du bist doch "DeJames"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_james_speak_1">
		<text>Bond... James Bond...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_james_speak_2">
		<text>Echt jetzt?\n \nMann.. Wer kommt als nächstes Erich Kästner?. Hör mal du besitzt was von Gordon Freeman - Ich dreh ab.. egal, rück raus die Akten.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_james_speak_3">
		<text>Mach die Flatter du Pisser. Ich lass mir doch nicht wegen so einem Dummbeutel wie dir, ein so guten Deal platzen. Jungs! Wir haben hier ein nicht willkommenen Gast. Begrüßn wir ihn auf unsere Art und Weise..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_case_bring_0">
		<text>Hey Gordon! Hier sind deine Unterlagen. Sei bloß vorsichtig mit wem du hier abhängst. Das ist nicht wie in City-17 wo man für eine Sache einsteht. Hier verfolgen die meisten ihre ganz eigenen  Kranken Ziele. Es gibt ein Parr Leute den man wirklich vertrauen kann. Die kann man aber einer Hand abzählen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_case_bring_1">
		<text>Ja das habe ich mittlerweile auch begriffen. Was ist passiert?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_case_bring_2">
		<text>Der Hatte dich verarscht. Er ist ein Söldner. Wie du schon gut befürchtest hattest. Der wollte dich aufliegen lassen. Dann hatte er noch ein paar Stinktiere bei sich. Die Lutschen nun an Blei-Bonbons in der Hölle. Hier ist dein Koffer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_case_bring_3">
		<text>Mann, so ein Scheiß. Vielen Dank. Hier.. warte, das habe ich für dich. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_doc_radar_0">
		<text>Nun LeHavre, was kommt als nächstes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_doc_radar_1">
		<text>Weiter geht es folgendermaßen, "Gezeichneter": ein "Monolither" sollte für uns wichtige Dokumente besorgen. Wir haben aber vor kurzem den Kontakt zu ihm verloren. Keine Verbindung mit seinem PDA mehr.\n \nDie letzte Nachricht kam an, als er am Hirnschmelzer war. Dann kam die Eruption, und ich denke, das er sich im Labor X-10 versteckte. Deine Aufgabe:\n \nFinden ihn und bringe die Dokumente hierher. Alles klar? Wir wissen ja, das du ein PSI-Helm von den Wissenschaftlern bekommen hast, der dich schützen kann.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_doc_radar_2">
		<text>Ok. Ich glaube zwar nicht, das eine Eruption für ein "Monolither" gefährlich wäre... aber ich werde euch die Dokumente bringen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_doc_radar_bring_0">
		<text>Ich hab eueren "Monolither" gefunden. Nur war er schon tot und, außerdem noch eine horde Mutanten.. Hier sind deine Dokumente.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_doc_radar_bring_1">
		<text>Mensch Gezeichneter! Hätte nicht gedacht das du es schaffst. Respekt. Da die Monolither ja alles sehr streng absichern. Lass mal sehen.. Ja.. die Dokumente sind es. Also, hier dein verdienter Lohn.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_flash_talk_0">
		<text>Freeman, wir sollten uns unterhalten.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_flash_talk_1">
		<text>Gezeichneter? Was gibt's?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_flash_talk_2">
		<text>Seit dem ich die Umstände des Todes vom "Fang" untersuche, tauchen auf meinem Weg immer mehr Söldner auf. Erst "LeHavre", dann "Bolt", dann haben ausländische Söldner versucht mich umzubringen.\n \n Sag, du weißt nicht zufällig, woher sie kommen und was hier vor sich geht oder? Ich habe für "LeHavre" ein Dokument besorgt und hatte mir eine Sicherheitskopie gezogen. Schau mal rein, vielleicht verstehst du mehr als ich, was da drin steht.\n \nObwohl ich so ein Verdacht habe, das du hier auch nicht einfach so rumhängst.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_flash_talk_3">
		<text>Gezeichneter, Ich hab hier meine eigenen Aufgaben. So... Interessant... Ich glaube ich fang an zu verstehen. Die Daten sind dennoch unvollständig.\n \nHör zu, "Gezeichneter". In dem Koffer, den du mir gebracht hast, waren auch Papiere und Dokumente von "DeJames". Es geht hervor, das bald ein supergeheimes Treffen der Söldner-Anführer ansteht. Es soll irgendwo im "Dunklen Tal" stattfinden. Auch ein gewisser "Blend" kommt zu diesem Treffen. Er hat wohl die fehlenden wichtigen Daten auf seinem Speicherstick. Die Söldner machen es oft so, sie splitten die Dokumente und teilen diese zwischen den Anführern auf, damit ihre Geheimnisse besser geschützt sind.\n \nWir brauchen diesem Stick, um weiter zu kommen. Und beeil dich, bald kommen da auch die anderen Anführer an, dann wird die Bewachung zu stark sein.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_flash_talk_4">
		<text>Ok, ich werde diesen "Blend" finden und den Speicherstick besorgen. Es wird uns hoffentlich helfen, endlich den Mörder zu finden.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_flash_bring_0">
		<text>Ich hab' Blend's Speicherstick. Hier.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_flash_bring_1">
		<text>Ok, lass mal sehen. Ach.. Sieh dir das an: Eine Söldnergruppe bestehend aus Ausländern hatte beschlossen den "Monolith" in ihre Gewalt zu bringen. Wofür.. Kann ich dir nicht sagen aber das verheißt sicher nichts Gutes.\n \nWeiter steht.. Dass sie ein Stalker namens "Fang" unter falschen Vorwand benutzt hätten um an seine Kenntnisse, was die Elektronik angeht, ranzukommen die sie wohl dringen benötigen. In seinem Profil was hier angelegt wurde steht, das er einer der wenigen ist, die es überhaupt ins Zentrum der Zone geschafft hätten .. und .. wieder rauskamen. Genauso ein Mann suchten sie. Da er sich eben sehr gut mit Elektronik auskannte wie auch mit Wissenschaftliche Arbeiten. Er soll mit einem Experten in einem.. Mobilen Labor in Jantar zusammengearbeitet haben.\n \nOh-ha, das wird dich interessieren. Hier gibt es eine Text Message zwischen einem Typen und "LeHavre". Demnach soll "Fang" wohl Verdacht geschöpft haben und als er versuchte hatte bei in ein paar Angelegenheiten Tiefer zu graben flog er auf. Daraufhin wurde er. . Eliminiert. Von einem Scharfschüztzen. Angeordnet wurde es wohl von "LeHavre". Er ist wohl auch der Kopf dieser Geschichte.\n \nGezeichneter? Das ist echt heißes Zeug. Das mit "Fang" tut mir leid. Schien wohl ein netter Kerl gewesen zu sein. Ach ja.. Hier das ist noch für dich.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_flash_bring_2">
		<text>Danke, Gordon. Irgnedwie habe ich schon vermutet das da was im Busch ist. Eins kann ich dir flüstern, der Typ ist fertig mit der Welt.\n \nBis später.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bland_flash_bring_3">
		<text>Viel Glück, Gezeichneter. Sei vorsichtig.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_braad_one_0">
		<text>Hey Gordon, wie sieht's aus?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_braad_one_1">
		<text>Wie eh' und jeh'. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_braad_one_2">
		<text>Ja, mitunter kann das Leben echt übel sein, kümmern wir uns aber erstmal um diese Blutsuager da draußen(*).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_final_dialog_0">
		<text>LeHavre? Weißt du zufällig warum ich hier bin?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_final_dialog_1">
		<text>Warte! Laß' uns erstmal reden! Trinken wir einen, ich hab hier noch eine Flasche echten Cognac liegen. Ist die Sache mit userer Basis im Dunklen Tal dein Werk?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_final_dialog_2">
		<text>Gieß ein. Ich hab jetzt alle Zeit der Welt. Du bist ja derjenige, der nicht mehr lange zu leben hat. Und ja, ich war das. Und ich gab' auch deinem Mitläufer, "Blend", die letzte Ölung. Ich hab jetzt alle Beweiße die ich brauche.\n \nAlso.. Auf "Fang" - Prost.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_final_dialog_3">
		<text>Ach ja.. "Fang"..  "Fang"... "Fang".....\n \nWir hatten mit ihm zusammengearbeitet ohne das er überhaupt eine Ahnung hatte. Wir ließen ihn im Glauben, das er Aufträge für die Wissenschaftler  erledigt. Wurde gut bezahlt und gaben ihm anfangs harmlose Aufgaben - Messungen, Artefakte sammeln, Anomalien Untersuchen.\n \nDas Hauptziel war aber immer der "Monolith". Wir suchten Wege, um zum "Monolithen" zu gelangen. Und du, sowie "Fang" gehören zu den wenigen, die dort waren und um die Möglichkeiten wussten, um dahin zu kommen. Er hatte irgendwann aber Verdacht geschöpft, hat rumgeschnüffelt wie ein Hund und wollte verschwinden. Tja.. und wie das nun mal ist, musste was getan werden.\n \nWillst du noch ein Schluck.. Moment.. Wie du dann sicherlich weißt habe ich ein Scharfschützen auf "Fang" gesetzt. Im Blutsauger Dorf bekam er dann ein Kopfschuss. Den Rest kennst du ja selbst. Du siehst echt nicht gut aus alle Ok? Irgendwie Bleich um die Nase...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_final_dialog_4">
		<text>Was..? Scheiße ist mir heiß.. Du verdam..mtes.. A-rschloch. Du hast.. Pis..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_final_dialog_5">
		<text>Du blöder Fixer.. Kuck mich an wenn ich mit dir Rede.. Los schau mir in die Augen. Du verfickter Stalker . Meinst du, du kannst hier reinspazieren und mich "LeHavre" killen. Ja seh' ich etwa so bescheuert aus. Da musst du schon früher aufstehen. Du solltest nie mit jemanden Trinken den du killen willst. Matchbirne.\n \nSchöne Träume du Arsch..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_finalend_dialog_0">
		<text>Aaa... So ein Arsch. Mein Kopf. Fuck.. Hört das den gar nicht auf. Man sind das Hammer Kopfschmerzen. Ich sollte zu dem Höhlenbewohner "Miner" gehen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_finalend_dialog_1">
		<text>Mann, Entspann dich, das war nur ein Schlafmittel. Ich brauch dich ja noch lebend. Hast du dich ausgeruht? Vergiss "Fang", mach dir lieber Sorgen um dein eigenes Leben.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gavr_finalend_dialog_2">
		<text>Wag es nicht noch mal sein Namen auszusprechen. Du hat ein Angebot, dann raus damit. Aber damit du es weißt. Du bist sowas von Tot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_priremont_dialog_0">
		<text>Hey Dan! Ich habe ein paar Mutanten-teile. Kannst du die umstauschen in Muntion oder Artefakte?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_priremont_dialog_1">
		<text>Im grunde schon.\n \nBesorg mir aber erstmal Vierzig PDA's. Dann sehen wir weiter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_priremont_dialog_2">
		<text>Wah? Willst du ein Elektronik Laden aufmachen? Na gut. Ich treib'  die teile auf. Sachen gibt's..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_repair_0">
		<text>Dan, ich hab hier Arbeit für dich, du mußt mal was reparieren.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_repair_1">
		<text>Dann lass mal sehen, was du da hast.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_repair_2">
		<text>.. Die Waffe im Pistolen Slot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_repair_3">
		<text>.. Die Waffe im Gewehr Slot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_repair_4">
		<text>Repariere den Anzug.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_repair_5">
		<text>Mann, das sind ja Preise, da dreht man ja ab! Nein, lass mal...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_repair_6">
		<text>Hier, alles wieder in Ordnung!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_repair_7">
		<text>Alles erledigt. Nimm mit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_repair_8">
		<text>Hmmm. Na gut. Aber wehe du vergißt mich...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_repair_9">
		<text>Nicht schlecht, du weißt wie man sowas macht.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_repair_10">
		<text>Kannst du noch etwas anderes reparieren?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_repair_11">
		<text>Sicher. Ich hab ja hier kaum Kunden...\n \nMeine Liste:\n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_bring_pda_0">
		<text>So Dan! Ich habe hier ein Rucksack voller PDA's. Warte... Da.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_bring_pda_1">
		<text>Warte.. kippe nicht alles den Tisch.. - mann.\n \nNagut, wenn du Mutaneile hast, kommen wir ins Geschäft. Jetz muss ich erstmal die ganzen PDA's wegräumen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_trade_buck_0">
		<text>Ok Dan? Was hast du so im Angebot?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_trade_buck_1">
		<text>Warte.. Dazu muss ich sagen das keiner in der Zone mit Mutanten Teile so handelt wie ich. Dazu zählen Hände, Füße, Schwänze, Augen, Krallen und so'n Zeug. Ich verhökere die Sachen nicht einfach so oder biete es Gratis an. Selbst nicht mal den Stalkern hier Vorort oder dem arroganten Sidorovich.\n \nDer nächste Händler, der damit Geschäfte macht ist "Raven" bei der Müllhalde. Aber selbst er macht nur in Mutanten Schwänze von Wirbeltieren.\n \nWenn du deine gejagtes gegen Geld eintauschen willst dann solltest du nach Jantar. Der Wissenschaftler im Forschungs bunker zahlt gut für Mutanten Sachen aus der Zone, da er diese für seine Forschung benötigt. Kannst es aber trotzdem bei "Raven" probieren um zu sehen was er so anbietet.\n \nAlso Gezeichneter, bei mir gibt es nur Munition und das kann ich dir anbieten\n2 Packungen 9x19mm PB1s-Muniton für 3 Augen vom "Fleisch"\n3 Packungen 45ACP Hydro-Shock Munition gegen 10 Köpfe von diesen Tuskano Ratten\n5 Packungen 5.45x39mm Panzerbrechende Munition für 4 Hände vom Telepathen. OK.. Plus ein Flasche Vodka.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_trade_buck_2">
		<text>Ich hab' Augen vom Mutanten "Fleisch". Gib mir die 9x19mm PB1s-Muniton.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_trade_buck_3">
		<text>Ich hab' Köpfe von "Tuskano's". Gib mir die 45ACP Hydro-Shock Munition.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_trade_buck_4">
		<text>Ich hab' Hände vom "Telepathen". Gib mir die 5.45x39mm PB Munition.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_trade_buck_5">
		<text>Hier ist deine Muniton. Nachzählen musst du selbst.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_trade_buck_6">
		<text>Das wird dem Kunden gefallen. Ich habe da gerade einen der sowas benötigt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_trade_buck_7">
		<text>Bruder, verstehe mich auch, Munition ist hier eine gefragte Währung. Panzerbrechende Munition. Und außer mir hat die nur Sidorovich im Angebot, also kriegst du nur die abgesprochene Anzahl.\n \nImmerhin kann ich noch eine Flasche Vodka drauf packen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_trade_buck_8">
		<text>Alles gut Dan! Ich werde dise Muntanten Teile gegen deine Munition eintauschen, sobald ich sie benötige.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_grab_helmet_0">
		<text>Dan, wo bist du mit deinen Gedanken?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_grab_helmet_1">
		<text>Hör zu, Gezeichneter. Ich bekam Informationen darüber, das in Kürze auf der Militärbasis im Agroprom irgendeine ungewöhnliche Ladung eintreffen soll. Was das genau ist? Keine Ahnung, aber die Basis wird nun stark bewacht. Ich kenne dich und du bist auf das Militär nicht gerade gut zu sprechen.\n \nIch schlage dir vor, uns bei dem Überfall auf die Basis zu helfen?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_grab_helmet_2">
		<text>Dan! Wenn das stimmt? Bei sowas sollten wir vorsichtig sein?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_grab_helmet_3">
		<text>Gezeichneter, für wen hälst du mich denn? Die Info ist sicher, Jungs würden nur noch auf dich warten, ansonsten ist schon alles vorbereitet. Wenn du nach Agroprom gehst, wird da auf dich "Arhara" mit seinem Team warten. Alles erfahrene Leute.\n \n"Arhara" selbst war mal bei der Freiheit. Bekam sich aber mit Lukash irgendwann in die Wolle. Darauhin startete er seine eigene kleine Indie Fraktion..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_grab_helmet_4">
		<text>OK, ich werde mich mit Arhara treffen. Dann sehen wir weiter.\n \nBis später.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_agro_helmet_0">
		<text>Bist du "Arhara"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_agro_helmet_1">
		<text>Ja und musst du der Gezeichnete sein?!. Moin. Etwas länger.. und wir hätten die Aktion ohne dich gemacht. Da du jetzt hier bist, erzähl ich dir wie das abläuft. Machen wir es kurz.\n \nWir gehen durch das Süd-Tor rein und beseitigen den Widerstand. Du gehst vorne durch den Hauptkomplex und nimmst den Wissenschaftler das Paket ab. Der Chef bei denen ist ein gewisser "Iwashenko". Wir vermuten das er dieses Packet bei sich.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_agro_helmet_2">
		<text>Hört sich gut an. Das wird einfach. Dann laß uns mal loslegen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_bring_helmet_0">
		<text>Dan, hier. Um diesen "Helm" ging es.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_bring_helmet_1">
		<text>Mensch, das ist.. interessant. Bin froh das du auf unsereer Seite bist Gezeichneter. Hier. Für dich. Ach.. "Arhara" fragte nach dir. schau bei ihm vorbei und ich sehe mir das hier mal an. Komme später vorbei. Ok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_help_0">
		<text>Hallo, "Arhara"! Dan hat mich gebeten bei dir vorbeizuschauen. Ist was passiert?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_help_1">
		<text>Es sieht so aus, "Gezeichneter": Einer meiner Leute ging in die Agroprom-Katakomben... Schon vor zwei Tagen, und ist immer noch nicht zurück. Du kennst es ja selber, da kriechen Mutanten rum, und Banditen sind da unten auch anzutreffen. Wahrscheinlich weilt er nicht mehr unter uns. \n \nLeider hatte er ein Laptop mit wichtigen Infos dabei, welche nicht in fremde Hände gelangen dürfen. Kannst du ihn dort rausholen?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_help_2">
		<text>Im grunde schon aber warum geht ihr nicht selbst? Schick doch einen von deinen Leuten...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_help_3">
		<text>So viele Jungs hab ich auch nicht mehr zu Verfügung, die Banditen und Mutanten sind in letzter Zeit so ziehmlich aktiv, da zählt jede Patrone und Waffe.\n \nVersteh' doch, ich darf meine Leute keinem Risiko aussetzen. Nicht jetzt. Auserdem du kennst dich besser mit den Katakomen aus als andere Stalker.\n \nHilf mir und ich werde dich dafür mit Munition bezahlen. Wir haben da einen kleinen Vorrat von den Soldaten. Den haben die mit uns geteilt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_help_4">
		<text>Ich finde den "Laptop", muss nicht sein aber Munition ist nicht verkehrt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_help_bring_0">
		<text>So, ich bin zurück. Wie ist die Situation?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_help_bring_1">
		<text>Wir stehen hier mächtig unter Druck um diesen Komplex zu halten. Hast du den "Laptop" gefunden?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_help_bring_2">
		<text>Ja, hab ich. Hier... Du hattest Recht, dein Mann ist tot, tappte wohl selbst in eine "Elektro Anomalie" als er, vor den Telepathen die da unten Hausen, flüchten wollte.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_help_bring_3">
		<text>Großartig, Danke Gezeichneter, du hast uns echt geholfen. Hier ist die versprochene Munition. Telepathen, sagst du? Shit, dann müssen wir unsere Position neu umdenken und eine Strategie einfallen lassen.. Danke für die Warnung.\n \nBis später.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_need_do_0">
		<text>"Arhara"? Du siehst nachdenklich aus?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_need_do_1">
		<text>Ich überlege grade was... Ich hab im Roten Wald, beim Radar, ein Rucksack-Versteck. Neben dem Hubschrauber, da ist noch so eine Metall-Box in der Nähe. In dem Versteck liegen verschiedene Kleinigkeiten, die könntest du als Bezahlung behalten. Aber das wichtigste - da liegt mein Notebook drin. Viele Dinge sind da drauf gespeichert und ich brauche ihn dringend.\n \nKönntest du den für mich holen? Oder warte mal, noch besser wäre es, wenn du das Laptop  bei meinen Bruder, "Yakut", ablieferst.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_need_do_2">
		<text>"Arhara", weßt du, was du da redest? Wie soll ich denn da durchkommen? Die PSI-Einwirkungen machen doch mein Hirn zu Brei. Und was für ein Bruder, wo sollte ich ihn, zum Teufel, suchen?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_need_do_3">
		<text>Geh doch mal zum Dan. Weßt du noch, wir haben im Agroprom diesen Koffer mit dem Helm erbeutet. Der wäre ganz nutzlich. Damit kannst du dich vor der PSI-Strahlung schützen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_need_do_4">
		<text>Stimmt.. Gut, ich treffe mich mit Dan. Mal sehen wie der Helm funktioniert?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_need_do_5">
		<text>Mach dir keine Sorgen, Bruder... Vertrau mir. Mein Bruder "Yakut"  findest du bei den Armee Lagerhäusern, er hängt in letzter Zeit in dem Stalker-Camp rum. Der Jetzige anführer ist "Wolf".\n \nBis Später.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_done_notebook_0">
		<text>Bist du "Yakut"? Ich hab hier den Laptop deines Bruders...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_done_notebook_1">
		<text>Gezeichneter! Du bist am Leben, verdammt! Ich hab schon fast die Hoffnung verloren... Und den Laptop hast'e auch dabei! Mein Bruder wird sich echt freuen das zu hören. Du hast uns echt geholfen, "Arhara" hat dich zurecht gelobt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_done_notebook_2">
		<text>Danke.. Du kannst aber einem echt Honig um den bart schmieren, Alter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_nauch_flash_0">
		<text>Hallo Dan! Jetzt wäre der Zeitpunkt gekommen den Schutz Helm zu testen. Hast du was darüber in Erfahrung gebracht?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_nauch_flash_1">
		<text>Junge, du hast ein Prototyp des PSI-Schutz-Helmes erbeutet! Er war zwar nicht auf die richtig eingestellt, aber ich hab ihn fast fertig justiert. Nur mir fehlen noch ein paar Informationen...\n \nHör' mal, du hast doch vor in das X-18 Labor zu gehen? Es gibt Berichte, das man in diesem Labor die Wirkung der PSI-Strahlung auf das menschliches Gehirn erforscht. Da gibt es bestimmt noch Daten darüber.\n \nWenn du im Labor irgendwelche Speichersticks oder Infos findest - bring diese mir bitte. Dann kann ich den Helm in Handumdrehen justieren.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_nauch_flash_2">
		<text>Dann gehe ich erstmal ins X-18 Labor. Ich muß dringend zum Radar, und ohne Schutzhelm kommt man da nicht durch.\n \nIch schau' was ich an Infos finde.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_nauch_flash_bring_0">
		<text>Grüß dich, Dan! Ich hab ein Speicherstick im Labor gefunden.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_nauch_flash_bring_1">
		<text>Lass mal sehen.. Aha.. So.... Genau! Das ist es, was wir brauchen. Warte, ich Konfiguriere noch die Einstellung am Schutz Helm zu enden.\n \nHier, fertig! Jetzt sollte er dich vor der PSI-Strahlung schützen. Aber da wir ihn nicht getestet haben, kann ich dir natürlich nichts garantieren...\n \nIch hoffe, es klappt. Viel Glück, "Gezeichneter"!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uceh_about_prizrak_0">
		<text>What's on your mind?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uceh_about_prizrak_1">
		<text>Listen, Marked One, about that corpse you found in the lab. Could you tell if it was really the body of Ghost? I have doubts that Ghost was lost. I don't think a professional like Ghost would have fallen to a controller. I will tell you something that very few people know, Ghost didn't come here alone. The stalker that was with him was almost a look-alike. We continually confused them. You after all hardly remember what Ghost looked like. Do you think its really his corpse in the lab!?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uceh_about_prizrak_2">
		<text>It could be someone else, what else leads you to suspect its not him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uceh_about_prizrak_3">
		<text>Before Vasilyev, and Ghost went into the Laboratory, we shared a small bottle the prior evening. We talked about the Zone, about the Monolith, but Ghost was mostly silent that evening. He had a look in his eyes, like a predator. He did say that all surviving members of Strelok's Group were being hunted down ... He said he came to Yantar for the solitude, as there remains but only a few people here. Too many Zombies, and Snorks to look out for. I asked Ghost if they were brothers, he told me that they had got acquainted recently at the Bar. You know what I think?, he wanted to make it look like he was dead. And there lies the other loner, not Ghost. Now everyone thinks that he is dead, and that makes it easier for him to hide</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uceh_about_prizrak_4">
		<text>Well, you could be right. Do you have any idea where he might hide?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uceh_about_prizrak_5">
		<text>Listen, Marked One, I have co-ordinates of a cache in Agroprom. I will send the location to your PDA. Ghost gave me these co-ordinates in case he didn't make it back. Marked One, go there and see if you can find some information on where he might be hiding</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uceh_about_prizrak_6">
		<text>Agroprom? I will go and see if I can find something</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uceh_first_prizrak_0">
		<text>Greetings, I have found it, there the diary was. Lying on the ground and its in poor condition so to read written text is difficult enough. The only thing, here, in one place about a person is written... 'You will find it in the Warehouses, near the base of Freedom'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uceh_first_prizrak_1">
		<text>Give it to me, the truth may lie within. Listen, Marked One, you should go to the Bar in Rostok and ask around, I will look over the diary, if I can read any more of it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uceh_first_prizrak_2">
		<text>It is fine, and most in the Bar it is necessary to me, to Barman business is, besides to buy something it would be advisable. I hope you can understand that</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barm_about_prizrak_0">
		<text>Greetings, Barman, have questions...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barm_about_prizrak_1">
		<text>Ask certainly, to you I will tell all that I know</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barm_about_prizrak_2">
		<text>Listen, you did not see Ghost? Speak, he was here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barm_about_prizrak_3">
		<text>Such business, Marked One, somewhere with one month ago or more, he was in the Bar and came to me, in general conversation concerns only me and Ghost, but... In general, he asked to find a 'master key', so to say with certain appearance</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barm_about_prizrak_4">
		<text>Barman, do not muddle, I know about the 'master key'... similar to Ghost! Further...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barm_about_prizrak_5">
		<text>Marked One, you understand, I am a businessman, and the information, like as, too the goods. Give so, bring to me one artefact of Simbion and I will tell you everything that I know</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barm_about_prizrak_6">
		<text>You are more of a 'Pusher' than a Businessman ... Fine!! I will go, and have a look...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barm_simb_prizrak_0">
		<text>Well 'businessman', I have brought you a Simbion</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barm_simb_prizrak_1">
		<text>Marked One, you, as always, please! It is pleasant to deal with you! In general listen, yes, he asked me to find the person more or less similar to it. A problem the extremely difficult, appearance at Ghost picturesque so I and itself did not hope that I can find, but day through two after ours with it of conversation, Dolg have caught the music, is not far from the Southern outpost, it somehow painfully suspiciously conducted itself(himself), as subsequently it has appeared, he did not eat three days it, spoke that the Bloodsucker has attacked it also it, escaping, all things has lost also a miracle he has reached the Bar. I in general, all the same, am said lies by it or not. The main thing that it as two drops is similar on Ghost. Well I have fed him, have given out which what need. Ghost Here has come, they about something have talked and have fallen down towards Yantar. Everything, is more I that, another did not see. And then I was reached by the information that Ghost has left in a lab and... Has not returned. Yes he asked, that I spoke to nobody, about a 'master key' so I hope, it remains between us. Yes has absolutely forgotten. Scientists asked you to come to Yantar, they have business for you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barm_simb_prizrak_2">
		<text>You know, I not from the Talkative. Oh these scientists, time to them you will help will not lag behind, but all the same, thanks</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uceh_second_prizrak_0">
		<text>Well, could read something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uceh_second_prizrak_1">
		<text>Marked One, such business, in General I try to restore make-shifts of a diary but if it is fair, results yet not impressing. Listen, you could not help us? We have departed to last emission protection. We have somehow repaired it, but it all the same works through time. We have ordered to ourselves new. But the helicopter is not present some days, on visible because of last emissions, to us on Yantar it is very difficult to reach by air. And we without the computer as without hands. And I would decipher Ghost diary faster</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uceh_second_prizrak_2">
		<text>I need a Computer System... can you help me find one?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uceh_second_prizrak_3">
		<text>There is one person, Arhara, he as offered that to us, but then it was not necessary for us also we have refused</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uceh_second_prizrak_4">
		<text>Well it is fine, I will try to find for Arhara...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_system_prizrak_0">
		<text>Hello, Arhara, was here at Scientists, speak at you is protection?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_system_prizrak_1">
		<text>Hello, Marked One, was yes Sly, I to its Duty have sold. So is not present it is more</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_system_prizrak_2">
		<text>To me that what to do? Where I protection will get?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_system_prizrak_3">
		<text>Well in general there is one place, laboratory X-18, there should be precisely</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_system_prizrak_4">
		<text>Again to a Burer on a visit to go? Well they do not differ hospitality. I all right will go, have put much. Good luck</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uceh_system_prizrak_0">
		<text>Hello, here protection, yes it was necessary to run about. I hope knowingly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uceh_system_prizrak_1">
		<text>Oh, Marked One, well you have gained us. And that to us have informed that the helicopter will be only in three days, and we has definitively departed. Look I the Yakut could read a name '... At... Warehouses'. Who it would be? Yes, here to you for the help, take cartridges for sniper</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uceh_system_prizrak_2">
		<text>Yakut? I know Yakut... I will have a chat with him...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_first_prizrak_0">
		<text>Yakut is doing quite well... Did you know Ghost?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_first_prizrak_1">
		<text>Well as to you to tell, I knew it once, but it, speak, was gone in laboratory X-16?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_first_prizrak_2">
		<text>Can and was gone, yes only some think differently</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_first_prizrak_3">
		<text>There is one place. Can you descend, you will look? Catacombs under Agroprom you know? And so, I assume that if it is live, could hide there somewhere</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_first_prizrak_4">
		<text>An Agroprom Vault you tell? Well all right I descend though if fairly not to be trusted who will want to hide in a monastery of bloodsuckers? Unless only the madman or insane and unbelievable. As I understand Ghost not that, another</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_second_prizrak_0">
		<text>Well the Yakut, is not present there Ghost, but I was met by the pleasant company from bandits, bloodsuckers, well and still there were there persons any strange, truth they met me unfortunately not with colors. More shortly the Yakut an ambush there</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_second_prizrak_1">
		<text>Yes, it is visible not one you you do not trust in death of Ghost. All right, I know one more place on the Radar. You know where an entrance in laboratory X-10? And so where there it should be. If and there it is not present, then I at all do not know than to you to help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_second_prizrak_2">
		<text>In the Radar? There fighters, probably, full now, well it is fine, I descend, I will check up</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_prizrak_0">
		<text>You it, Ghost. Yes, you are healthy all Zone have deceived</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_prizrak_1">
		<text>Strelok's mother fair. When you were gone, I have not believed that you were lost. So much together to worry, you always were the best among us. And a scent, you know did not trust also all here. I am glad to see you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_prizrak_2">
		<text>Questions has collected much, well here it is not so quiet, so tell though in brief how you managed to get out of laboratory? Yes me here met very 'amicably', and on Agroprom obviously someone waited. To whom have you salted?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_prizrak_3">
		<text>You know the narrator of me, but oh well. In general, the three of us went to the Lab: I, Vasiliev, well, 'Jimmy'. I myself did not know exactly get us off burner or not. Yes, and I went there to trick my persecutors. You probably already know about my 'master key'? There is a sin on his soul, still feel sorry for the guy, but act otherwise I could not. He did not believe that you're dead. There was no place in the Zone where I felt safe. But after the stunt with the corpse, I finally was able to do the quest. Through some of his people, I learned that you are alive. You probably know, there is a grouping of Avengers? Well, not what they do not Avengers, ordinary Mercenaries. Kill anyone they will order. However, there is a mystery. Rumor has it that such groups run by people from the clan of murderers Last Day. Did you know that on my youth, I slapped the former leader of ... According to unconfirmed reports - the clan got together again and now understand why they want to destroy me ... A horseradish hide from them, with no faction does not want to deal with, fear them, even Monolith try to pass them by. In general, I found out who is behind their head - Beast. If it is eliminated. it is possible at the time I was left alone. My boys recently told me that the beast and his right-hand oblique settled in the swamps - where they have a farm on the outskirts, apparently want to organize there something like the base ... I have sent there kids, but without you I am afraid they will not cope. Take it? Yes, it is important not only to kill him, but stick to get him there a list of all the victims, and certainly we in him. The approximate location of our people to throw off your PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_prizrak_4">
		<text>Ghost, your war my war, your enemy my enemy. So I am ready to hurt someone soon. I've seen people from the clan of the Last Day, so it seems, is not a fairy tale</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_prizrak_zver_0">
		<text>Greetings, Ghost, in general was possible for Beast to escape, here, by the way, a flash card, apparently, here the list of all of whom already... Or only gather. Likely I can be proud, I in the list the first, you the second</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_prizrak_zver_1">
		<text>Has run away... Well all right anywhere will not get to. For a flash card to you many thanks. Here take my personal Gauss, I have found it near to the Zone center. It has long enough lain in a Jelly Anomaly, and now it's simply super-gun. Rate of fire is increased several times and also check your pda, I put an mark for my valuable stash with my personal outfit...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_prizrak_zverfinal_0">
		<text>Well, Ghost, is known where this 'Beast' is?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_prizrak_zverfinal_1">
		<text>Yes, now we will precisely cover. In general he wants to surrender to the authorities. Has probably decided to hand over the secrets in exchange for a way out of the Zone. More shortly Streloks, is now in the Cordon, on the military man to a post. Protection there very serious, to one you not to consult. So you will be waited there by a small group. Children all veterans, skilled, do not refuse their help. Beast should have the list of customers, so find it and bring it to me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_prizrak_zverfinal_2">
		<text>I All right have gone, I hope he now will not escape from us</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_prizrak_after_zver_0">
		<text>Well that, Ghost, sad, is not present more Beast. Here, by the way, the list of customers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_prizrak_after_zver_1">
		<text>Yes Strelok you always were the best, here by the way take cartridges for sniper. Well the brother is time to you, the Monolith waits for you. Good luck</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_ograb_0">
		<text>Hello Yakut, the trouble has happened with me, I here have squabbled with LeHavre. So he has poisoned me in my opinion. A head till now the pig-iron. Yes has drunk brandy. Well so has regained consciousness, they probably have not noticed that I am drunk. Has looked round on fast in pockets, money is gone. Somehow with them has understood, then the Nectar of the Gods, and the things that are not present. Where they have got to? In the same place the base of freedom, turns out except scientists and to take not to whom?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_ograb_1">
		<text>I here on affairs went, to children on base so saw as steam of Mercenaries purely a backpack kg hundred, it is not less. They not through gate went, and the hole there is in a corner in a fence. As they bore it, for me till now a riddle. It is to any person not under force. And so wanted nuts on them, yes was not in time, it is sick quickly they skedaddle. And I think, what to me business to them, not mine, and figs with it. Now it is clear that they bore. Listen, descend here parking of Mercenaries at once behind village with bloodsuckers. There the base at them, can there the Bloodsuckers and will find. At the same time business good you will make, painfully to play pranks they lately became, a lot of our brothers of the stalker from their hands was lost. Here and so mutants flight from the center a rod so also they devils get the habit a robbery to be engaged. Yes it would be necessary to Lukash to tell that for affairs, it is direct not base, and a double-exit courtyard, Mercenaries as at home go. Though that from these scientists to take, as evening, so half of protection drunk, and the second smoked</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_ograb_2">
		<text>Well I to these devils that will set brains. Wait, I will return soon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_ograb_done_0">
		<text>Yakut Is healthy, I have taken away here Bloodsuckers, but they in a box lie, and it with the lock code. Can you open? Yeah, and - senior to those thugs was clearly not a Mercenary - he of the clan Last Day</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_ograb_done_1">
		<text>Wait, aha here hold. Last Day? You're not wrong hour? that group are gone. Maybe someone from Mercenaries pretending</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_ograb_done_2">
		<text>Also it is all? I here the Zone floor stand, on me any one hundred corpses, bloodsuckers the party bypass me, wild boars all legless go, and dogs without tails. Where? Where all mine of loots?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_ograb_done_3">
		<text>Yes calm down you, Marked One, you has killed all of them from whom now you will ask? But now with empty pockets directly to a Monolith</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rost_sysh_speak_0">
		<text>Greetings all in gathering?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rost_sysh_speak_1">
		<text>Hello, Marked One. There it is a lot of them and they the present animals. I am afraid it my last fight. I feel, me Ghost has taught to listen to the feelings, the good intuition, the brother, in a Zone is better than any detector, here I understand that it is not not necessary to me to go there, but I can refuse to Ghost. It to me three times rescued life, time apparently has come to pay off</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rost_sysh_speak_2">
		<text>Owls whence such thoughts? Anything we will break the brother. Well, we are put forward on the sly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_speak_sysh_0">
		<text>Ghost, it to you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_speak_sysh_1">
		<text>Bough Owls, to tears has touched. Yes that is a pity as. I to you on your PDA have sent, will read at your leisure</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tirex_speak_0">
		<text>Hello, Musics, Ghost has sent me, how are conditions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tirex_speak_1">
		<text>Yes all a way, protection truth too much, but, I think, we will consult</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tirex_speak_2">
		<text>Well it is good to smoke, we are put forward yes on the parties look, something to me not on myself somehow, painfully easy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_speak_helmet_0">
		<text>Doctor, such business, at me already is a helmet adjusted</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_speak_helmet_1">
		<text>Allow at you there is an adjusted helmet for the radiation? Whence it at you dear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_speak_helmet_2">
		<text>We Will tell so, I was given by its one person</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_speak_helmet_3">
		<text>You could not give it, I will look, I will compare to the operating time. Understand me correctly, dear Marked One, all the same we deal with this problem for a long time, and anyway our helmet will protect you better. We needed to make last gauging. And then I will give you a helmet already adjusted by us, believe, with it you though to Chernobyl will reach. Well as dear, you agree?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_speak_helmet_4">
		<text>Yes without problems, Doctor, here hold</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_speak_helmet_5">
		<text>Is not present, Doctor, I can not yet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_speak_helmet_6">
		<text>Thanks, here not the big gift from me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_proverka_0">
		<text>Yakut, I would like to talk to you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yakut_proverka_1">
		<text>Forgive, Marked One, I is now occupied. Freeman asked to come to it. Speaks affairs much, and Marked One of lines knows where goes, idles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_larger_protect_0">
		<text>Greetings. You Zahar? There is a job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_larger_protect_1">
		<text>Marked One, is one business, of risk are not afraid?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_larger_protect_2">
		<text>That, Zahar, has desired to joke? We here risk every minute, so one risk more... Do not pull tell</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_larger_protect_3">
		<text>Business not simple, but very important for us. My main assistant Dan from bogs has sent me the extracted trophies. For you, as well as for many, they do not represent interest are parts of mutants, and for us - a way to survive. Deliver them owe three hunters. They have stopped on rest at abandoned factory in Cordon, as while under the bridge where a post of military men cannot take place. There are data from Akim that on my people to prepare the attack. I have warned them, but it is not known, how many will be marauders... Has contacted Bes - that says that all its people are occupied - with bandits there is a territory repartition on Marshes. You the soldier skilled - will not help? You will find the senior - Sepator - he will explain all. If it agree - a gift for me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_larger_protect_4">
		<text>All right I descend on a cordon, I will help children</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_larger_protect_0">
		<text>Greetings. I from Zahar, to you in help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_larger_protect_1">
		<text>While all is silent, but not to be pleasant to me it. You, I see, have managed to pass under the bridge. What not to risk, if we will be in time - we will make so: we will go back on bogs, and you - take away a bag and Zahar transfer. I on a peak roof have thrown it - for reliability. Yes... And for service - take while my hunting bow with the night vision device and arrows to it, it is sensitive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_larger_protect_2">
		<text>It is good. I do not love superfluous blood. To bogs, I hope, will gather additionally. Here lines, in my opinion, we were late - visitors have appeared. Well, keep, musics...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sepator_ziv_0">
		<text>Uff... Was hot...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sepator_ziv_1">
		<text>Also do not speak... The skill of the hunter Was useful... Thanks that has helped. Take away a bag from a roof and carry Zahar. Tell to it that all is Okay, and I to Sidorovich on the way will come, I will smoke, yes to myself - on bogs I will go</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sepator_ziv_2">
		<text>Frets. I hope, still we will see. To smoke, by the way, harmfully. Though, it is better to smoke, than to breath our poisoned air. On ecology all nasal... only on the summits confused go...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_larger_done_0">
		<text>Greetings, Zahar, here, take the contents of the bag</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_larger_done_1">
		<text>Here thanks! I hope Sepator is live?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_larger_done_2">
		<text>Yes, safe and sound. Where he will get to</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_larger_done_3">
		<text>Has gained us fine, here take for work</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_larger_done_4">
		<text>Thanks, class Art!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_larger_done_5">
		<text>Is not present, it was lost... Was marauders Too much...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_larger_done_6">
		<text>It is a pity... The good Music was... Means, with protection it has not turned out. Well only one - the bag with parts of mutants is whole. Here, take - can be useful...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_larger_done_7">
		<text>Thanks...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_larger_done_8">
		<text>Here lines... In turmoil I at all have not looked, whether it is live...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_larger_done_9">
		<text>If it is live - that you should talk over with it, and after and we will communicate to you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_larger_done_10">
		<text>Has understood</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_znakom_0">
		<text>Hello brother. Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_znakom_1">
		<text>I'm Dan, of the 'Hunter' faction. We've organised small base here, where we buy up Stalkers' artefacts and mutant parts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_znakom_2">
		<text>Do you trade your goods with the bar?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_znakom_3">
		<text>We sell our mutant parts to Sakharov in Yantar, as the Bar doesn't pay a good price. You should talk with Zahar - he has set up our main base close to the Bar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_tade_art_0">
		<text>Zahar, do you buy artefacts?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_tade_art_1">
		<text>We buy up Artefacts for the scientists. Currently we buy 'Crystal' and 'Meat Chunk' artefacts. For three Crystals we will give you an Absolute Artefact, for three Meat Chunks we will give you a modified weapon. For one 'Gravi' you will receive three Antirads. Okay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_tade_art_2">
		<text>Zahar, I have three Crystals for you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_tade_art_3">
		<text>I have found three Meat Chunks, saved especially for you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_tade_art_4">
		<text>I need some Antirads. Here's a Gravi</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_tade_art_5">
		<text>Sakharov will be happy to see three Crystals</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_tade_art_6">
		<text>You always surprise me, how do you manage to find so many Artefacts? My blockheads only find Stone Bloods or nothing. Nothing this time?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_tade_art_7">
		<text>Gravi? here take some Antirad</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_tade_art_8">
		<text>This time my backpack is empty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_ask_help_0">
		<text>Zahar, what's wrong?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_ask_help_1">
		<text>Until recently, we once a week sent Artefacts to the scientists in Yantar. A group of Mercenaries has been ambushing my men trying to make these deliveries in the Wild Territory. Can you get rid of these Mercs?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_ask_help_2">
		<text>Zahar, these are your problems, why should I get involved?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_ask_help_3">
		<text>Marked One, you know my men are not good fighters. I'm afraid if we try to do it ourselves, my men will be wiped out. I went to Voronin and asked for help, but as always he answered: I can't spare the manpower. Help us re-establish a route to the Scientists</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_ask_help_4">
		<text>I will help you Zahar, I don't want to see you go out of business</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_ask_done_0">
		<text>Zahar greetings, the pass is free of Mercs now</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_ask_done_1">
		<text>You're a fine fellow, at last we can trade with the Scientists directly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_ask_done_2">
		<text>Zahar, you should organise an advanced post in the Wild Territory, so they don't return again</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_ask_done_3">
		<text>Yes that's good advice, here's your reward</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prapor_speak_group_0">
		<text>Well Prapor how's the service life?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prapor_speak_group_1">
		<text>Marked One, we caught a bandit trying to sneak through yesterday. We found a broken PDA in his backpack...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prapor_speak_group_2">
		<text>What's that got to do with me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prapor_speak_group_3">
		<text>Well you're the kind of person who likes to stick his nose into other people's affairs. It's yours if you bring me some scientific medkits</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prapor_speak_group_4">
		<text>How many?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prapor_speak_group_5">
		<text>Can you get me twenty, or is that too much to ask? Okay, I'll settle for ten...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prapor_speak_group_6">
		<text>Well you ask a big price for a PDA that doesn't work, 10 scientific first-aid sets? Well alright I will bring</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prapor_done_group_0">
		<text>Well Prapor I have brought the first-aid sets</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prapor_done_group_1">
		<text>Thanks Marked One, these are for my men. Voronin, the miser, doesn't supply us with these. I need to take care of my guys, you understand?. Here take the PDA, go to the Barman. He has two egg-heads in the back who can repair anything</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_speak_group_0">
		<text>Greetings Barman, who can repair this PDA?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_speak_group_1">
		<text>Yes I can arrange that, but you understand I need a favor first. Bring to me Artefact 'Chimera Tears' I've had an order in with Zahar for one for almost a month</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_speak_group_2">
		<text>Barman, do you think I'm stupid? For repairing PDA, 'Chimera Tears'? No! the best I can do is 'Fire Tears'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_speak_group_3">
		<text>Marked One, do not shout, all right give me 'Fire Tears' and we have a deal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_speak_group_4">
		<text>Alright, repair it while I'm gone. I will find your 'Fire Tears'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_done_group_0">
		<text>I have found the 'Fire Tears', here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_done_group_1">
		<text>Marked One, don't get angry. The Senior lecturer had a birthday party and too much Vodka was consumed and by accident your PDA was smashed into smithereens</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_done_group_2">
		<text>Is this a joke? There might be people in trouble or somebody needs rescued!. And your drunks destroy the information?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_done_group_3">
		<text>Marked One, I understand the guys did something stupid. I myself knocked them into the middle of next week. Here take a box of Vodka as indemnification</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_done_group_4">
		<text>Barman, do you think everybody is as selfish as you? Give the box of Vodka to the repairmen, maybe they will burn your bar down this time! This has been a big waste of time</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_speak_group_0">
		<text>Professor I should talk to you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_speak_group_1">
		<text>Yes Marked One, I'm listening</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_speak_group_2">
		<text>Professor some days ago I encountered the corpse of a military man. On that corpse I found a note, it mentioned an expedition to the Brain Scorcher</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_speak_group_3">
		<text>Marked One, I shouldn't even be telling you this. Approximately several months ago a group of scientists, with support from above, obtained a permit to search Lab X-10, which is located in the Radar. I, in every possible way, tried to stop them. Explaining that the territory was unstudied and chances of reaching the lab alive were unknown. I suggested that we first complete the study of lab X-16. To understand better how quickly PSI influences affect the brain and to design counter measures. But unfortunately they wouldn't listen to me. Weeks have past and nothing has been heard from them. I am inclined to think the worst</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_speak_group_4">
		<text>This is strange, Doctor, when I went to disconnect the Brain Scorcher I didn't find any group there, and saw no trace of these people. Well there were Monolithians, but they are fanatics not people</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_speak_group_5">
		<text>Its possible you didn't investigate all the bunker, for certain during that moment you had more important affairs. Don't you think that its necessary for you to visit there once again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_speak_group_6">
		<text>Likely you are right, Doctor. To understand what happened there, I should go and explore it once again</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_zaniat_0">
		<text>Doctor, I have some urgent business</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sahar_zaniat_1">
		<text>Forgive me Marked One, but I'm very busy. You've spoken to someone in the Scorcher? Here and well, we will talk when you return</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ucen_bunker_0">
		<text>Hello. To you it is bad? Take the first-aid set</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ucen_bunker_1">
		<text>Thank you, young man... cough blood, forgive I do not know what is your name, but I am afraid... cough blood... I am afraid it to me any more will not help. At me the backbone and many other parts of the body that I speak with you is broken... It from painful shock. Local bloodsuckers were very kind to me and have decided to leave me on 'sweet'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ucen_bunker_2">
		<text>Forgive me, Doctor, what with you happens?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ucen_bunker_3">
		<text>It is difficult To me to speak... khe-khe-khe. Our expedition should reach to burner and investigate it... Spits blood... Yes this France is able to insist... What was... khe-khe-khe... Mad idea, but he could persuade me and some others of the Board. Sakharov tried to dissuade us, but... Money... Spits and pants... A heap of money spent in this project and pride... Rattles, eyes are closed</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ucen_bunker_4">
		<text>Yes you all in blood, give I though I will try to stop blood</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ucen_bunker_5">
		<text>Already... Pants... Not help... Shoot down... Shoot down me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ucen_bunker_6">
		<text>I should ask</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ucen_bunker_7">
		<text>I Beg... Stop... Stop these... khe-khe I can not... Kill me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_informator_pda_give_0">
		<text>Greetings, Zahar, is a pity Dan</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_informator_pda_give_1">
		<text>It here has left one bag, PDA Tirana, speak it to you is necessary?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_informator_pda_give_2">
		<text>Yes the informant asked to extract for it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_informator_pda_give_3">
		<text>Well so drive 30000 and it yours</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_informator_pda_give_4">
		<text>Costly? certainly, well all right hold</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_informator_pda_give_5">
		<text>Lines I without money will approach today later</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_dan_bring_helmet_0">
		<text>Greetings, Zahar, yes here took the order From Dan and he has died</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_dan_bring_helmet_1">
		<text>You about the helmet? Yes give I calculate. Yes, Arhara asked to come to it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_dan_nauch_flash_bring_0">
		<text>Greetings... has found for Dan a flash card, and... In general of that to do I do not know</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_dan_nauch_flash_bring_1">
		<text>Yes give I will try, wait... So... Yeah... Here hold, Marked One, the adjusted helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_tainiy_hod_0">
		<text>Greetings the brother</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_tainiy_hod_1">
		<text>That the sad such?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_tainiy_hod_2">
		<text>Yes do not ask nasty and all. There, in the bunker, the person whom I have killed lies. He/she is the scientist, he to me has told that they tried to disconnect the burner, but is visible not destiny. The last I have settled</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_tainiy_hod_3">
		<text>And you trust them? You know for what they here Rushed? You know that searched here for LeHavre? To tell? Here there is a secret pass to the Monolith. They after all understood that it not to pass through Pripyat. There Monolithians like ants in an ant hill, and here time, and you already at a Monolith. Has understood that here it is necessary to all of them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_tainiy_hod_4">
		<text>Knew and was silent? As that it not absolutely friendly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_tainiy_hod_5">
		<text>Yes I did not know precisely, hearings went, well few times heard about this pass from people, and here now you to me have told also I about all have guessed</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_tainiy_hod_6">
		<text>And where to be this secret passage?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_tainiy_hod_7">
		<text>Yes that's just the point that I do not know. You know... Here that... Knowingly your LeHavre here sniffed up. Descend It, talk to Freeman. It seems to me, he should know. Most likely there should be a certain plan burner, I assume that it now at somebody from Mercenaries. Yes at me business one more to you is. As with the plan you will understand, come, we will talk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_tainiy_hod_8">
		<text>Frets I will talk to Freeman, perhaps the plan will be</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_tainiy_hod_0">
		<text>Hello, Freeman. Well how are you? About LeHavre heard?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_tainiy_hod_1">
		<text>Yes who did not hear, all Zone knows about it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_tainiy_hod_2">
		<text>Business is, but is strict between us. And so speak there is a secret pass to a Monolith, through burner on the Radar but to find this pass, the plan burner is necessary. You do not know, at whom this plan could be?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_tainiy_hod_3">
		<text>Listen, Marked One, in the first meeting with DeJames I saw at it a certain plan. I then did not understand much and did not know, but you know, memory at me good, especially visual. And so when you to me have brought my case, in it lay not only my documents, but also documents of DeJames. In them that is mentioned casually about what plan, also one mercenary on a nickname of Tamaz there is mentioned. As I have understood, it was someone like the foreman at LeHavre, and just through it and its brigade LeHavre liquidated objectionable to it people. One of these days I was reached by the information that the rests of a gang of LeHavre gather on a dump. Most likely Tamaz will be there. If there is a plan burner it should be at Tamaz. Descend there, check up</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_tainiy_hod_4">
		<text>All right I descend, if something I will find, I will bring to you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_tainiy_hod_done_0">
		<text>Well, Freeman, I have found the plan. Look, and I something not absolutely understand that</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_tainiy_hod_done_1">
		<text>Give I will look. Aha here... And thought. Here look, Marked One, you see here a room where the switch to be? Well and so you will come downstairs, well and there you will find in general</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freeman_tainiy_hod_done_2">
		<text>Thank you, Freeman, has again gained, from me kickback. Well all I have run, have put much</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_gold_art_0">
		<text>Well, Ghost, you as always are right. I have found a secret passage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_gold_art_1">
		<text>I and thought. Yes, Marked One, business to you is. It is necessary for me, that you have found rare enough Artefact. It is called 'Gold Chunk'. To find it is possible only near Chernobyl, most likely it is necessary to look in North Chernobyl (in a courtyard). Find me 10 pieces, and I will tell about one secret passage. North Chernobyl in the Sarcophagus and back. You will make?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_gold_art_2">
		<text>'Gold Chunk' you tell, all right I will look</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_gold_art_done_0">
		<text>Faugh, Ghost, has hardly found also truth a rare Artefact. Hold</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_gold_art_done_1">
		<text>Both! So quickly? The good fellow. Here look: I will note to you an entrance with North Chernobyl in the Sarcophagus in your PDA, and here pass from the Sarcophagus on North Chernobyl to be in a room with the Monolith. It is necessary to look a little. Well, good luck, my friend</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_tri_tainik_0">
		<text>Well, Ghost, affairs are made, it is possible and on rest?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_tri_tainik_1">
		<text>You Will have time to have a rest still, Marked One. Business at me to you is. Heard history about one Monolithian? Is not present? And so, there was one Monolithian, from scientists like which instead of praying to the Monolith hours kept diaries. Yes not simple, in them a lot of the valuable information on Chernobyl and that the main thing, on the Monolith! As if at it even the hypothesis was that this stone not a terrestrial origin. Well after you in the Sarcophagus to rustle have guided that, moreover and burner have disconnected, in Chernobyl the landing of fighters has landed at support from air. Well those have left a Monolith who on cleverer, Bloodsuckers what have collected to eat yes with secret tracks. Our hero too has set. But here something at it on road has occurred that it has not carried away the diaries with itself, and has hidden. My people have found it, yes have shaken properly, in general it has broken up, I will tell on truth, I wanted to catch for a long time these diaries, to me about them my person from a Monolith told. And so it has hidden them in three different places in Chernobyl, in a courtyard. You understand about what I will ask? Yes it should is necessary to descend and bring their these diaries to be 3 pieces. You will make?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_tri_tainik_2">
		<text>Eat, Ghost, and I have gathered for rest! Well it is fine, I descend. Well</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_tri_tainik_est_0">
		<text>Well, Ghost, was I there. Here hold 3 diaries as promised</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prizrak_tri_tainik_est_1">
		<text>Give I will look. Aha, interesting reading matter. Well, Marked One, business necessary has made, now and can have a rest. Good luck, you the brother!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="price_dan_text">
		<text>Dan's List:\n \n1. Cartridges 9x19 armour-piercing - 3 eyes of Fleshes;\n \n2. Cartridges 11.43x23 armour-piercing - 5 heads of Tushkanos;\n \n3. Cartridges 5.45x39 armour-piercing - 2 hands of the Controller</text>
	</string>
	<string id="price_dan_prinesi_text">
		<text>Dan's Offer:\n \n1. Repair work - for 40 PDA;\n \n2. A good award for 3 tails of blind dogs and 3 hoofs of wild boars!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_nebo_help_0">
		<text>Hello, who are you guys?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_nebo_help_1">
		<text>Hello Marked One, We are from the group 'Clear sky', this territory is considered ours</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_nebo_help_2">
		<text>I understand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_nebo_help_3">
		<text>Though the territory is considered ours, a lot of key points are held by strong groups of bandits. I sent one of my men to observe their camp nearby, but he has not returned. I fear he has been captured or maybe even killed. The men believe that our man is still alive and want to make a rescue attempt. As you can see we are few in number and I have a twisted ankle and can't lead the attack. You are an obviously skilled stalker. If you will lead this attack, I will be in your debt</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_nebo_help_4">
		<text>I will gladly help you, can you spare any ammo or medkits?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_nebo_help_5">
		<text>Our first-aid sets are few but take this ammo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_nebo_help_6">
		<text>I can use all the ammo I can get</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_nebo_help_7">
		<text>Here take this, good luck to you guys</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saha_nebo_help_0">
		<text>Are you Okay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saha_nebo_help_1">
		<text>Yes, I'm a little beat up but nothings broken...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saha_nebo_help_2">
		<text>How did you get captured?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saha_nebo_help_3">
		<text>I was watching the bandit camp and nothing was really happening so I decided to wash my socks. I put my weapon down and started cleaning when I heard a bloodsucker roar. It was after me so I ran, and in my panic I ran into this base and became a captive. The bandits were howling with laughter at me, it was quite humiliating</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saha_nebo_help_4">
		<text>Yes, well we need to get out of here before any more bandits arrive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_nebo_help_done_0">
		<text>I got your man out, he's safe now</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_nebo_help_done_1">
		<text>Here thanks, listen...if you go to our main base, please don't mention this</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_nebo_help_done_2">
		<text>And where's your base?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_nebo_help_done_3">
		<text>It's not to far from here, you go on a straight line past the church, then past a tower, and then you will see our outpost in a small farm, behind that is a portal, it takes you to our base. Wait, I will put it your PDA an approximate location of the farm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_nebo_help_done_4">
		<text>I understand, thanks. What about a reward?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_nebo_help_done_5">
		<text>I've nearly forgotten, here you are</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_vstrecha_first_0">
		<text>What's going on...?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_vstrecha_first_1">
		<text>One more thief caught, it was a good idea to set that trap. You think you can just walk in anywhere you like and take what you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_vstrecha_first_2">
		<text>Listen brother, in the Zone practically all houses are owner-less. If I knew this place had occupants I would not have touched anything</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_vstrecha_first_3">
		<text>This bog has become infested with thieves, you can't turn your back for a minute! ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_vstrecha_first_4">
		<text>Brother listen, I'm no thief. What do I have to do to prove it to you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_vstrecha_first_5">
		<text>Your going to have to do a job for us! or become frog food...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_vstrecha_first_6">
		<text>What job are you talking about?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_vstrecha_first_7">
		<text>Nearby is an Artefact container, we need you to retrieve it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_vstrecha_first_8">
		<text>So what's the catch? Mutants, Zombies, or Chimera?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_vstrecha_first_9">
		<text>It's nothing like that, an anomaly has formed a portal around the container. We need you to find a way to get it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_vstrecha_first_10">
		<text>How will I find a way?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_vstrecha_first_11">
		<text>Its not my problem</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_vstrecha_first_12">
		<text>Can you spare any cartridges or first-aid sets</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_vstrecha_first_13">
		<text>I wont go, sorry</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_vstrecha_first_14">
		<text>Okay then</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_vstrecha_second_0">
		<text>That was a little tricky but here it is, the 'container'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_vstrecha_second_1">
		<text>I didn't expect you to return. I thought you would run away</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_vstrecha_second_2">
		<text>I told you I was no thief, do you believe me now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_vstrecha_second_3">
		<text>Yes, I believe you. Here, this has all been a misunderstanding</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_znakomstvo_0">
		<text>Why do you live in the middle of the marsh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_znakomstvo_1">
		<text>Why?, I grew up not far from here. When all this madness, called the Zone, began I was conscripted into a local protection group. I had not long been married and was expecting my first-born. I was stationed on the perimeter, the Zone wasn't as large then. And here it comes... The letter, my wife has radiation sickness. My village was lied to by the government who told them it was safe to stay there. I have to go and see my wife, but the young officer denies my request. I lost my mind and grabbed my weapon and shot down all who tried to stop me. I walked into the hospital with my clothes covered in blood, the AK-47 in my hands. There my Grandma sat, and I ask 'Where is my Katka', and she points to the sign: 'Mortuary', I... I go in there. There she lies... So BEAUTIFUL</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_znakomstvo_2">
		<text>kalmyak please calm down</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_znakomstvo_3">
		<text>It was so quiet, and then, beside Katka, I found the baby so small, pink cheeks, and eyes same as me. I held his lifeless body to my chest and slumped into a corner and wept. Sat there for I don't know how long. The military Police came to arrest me, I didn't resist. I was taken back to the camp and locked in a cell</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_znakomstvo_4">
		<text>Then what happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_znakomstvo_5">
		<text>Next day a big group of Mutants attacked our section of the perimeter and broke through the defence. Gunfire everywhere, screams and roars, panic everywhere. The guards had fled, leaving me to my fate. My comrade Fedor came to my rescue and shot the lock open. He handed me a weapon and told me to run. Since then the Zone has been my home, I have nothing to go back to. Here I make ointments out of Mutant Glands and local plant life, there healing properties are amazing. If you ever need some I trade for vodka or cigarettes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_znakomstvo_6">
		<text>Life has not been fair to you kalmyak. The truth is, that's what brought me to your camp; to buy some ointment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_znakomstvo_7">
		<text>I will not tell you the recipe. Simply remember, it reduces radiation and stops bleeding</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_change_0">
		<text>Greetings kalmyak, I've come for some ointment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_change_1">
		<text>You have vodka or cigarettes? Remember, one jar of ointment, for 3 bottles of Vodka, or 3 packs of cigarettes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_change_2">
		<text>Here are the cigarettes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_change_3">
		<text>Here's some vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_change_4">
		<text>Well, maybe next time</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_repair_0">
		<text>Vasily, can you take a look at this</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_repair_1">
		<text>It needs a little work</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_repair_2">
		<text>Repair the first weapon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_repair_3">
		<text>Repair the second weapon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_repair_4">
		<text>Repair the armor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_repair_5">
		<text>I don't have that kind of money</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_repair_6">
		<text>Well here look as the newcomer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_repair_7">
		<text>How do you even wear this suit in this condition? I will need to change all the armor plates</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_repair_8">
		<text>It's quite good, I thank you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_repair_9">
		<text>Now it's even better, than when it was new</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_repair_10">
		<text>Can you take a look at something else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_repair_11">
		<text>Yes please that there at us:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vasil_first_0">
		<text>Are you the twin brother of Sidorovich?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vasil_first_1">
		<text>What!!, I've been in this Zone from the very beginning. And you can tell Sidorovich that one day I will feed him to the local marsh giant. Do you know who the first was to supply arms in the Zone? Me that's who! I was the first trader who could organise deliveries of everything, both products, and weapons, and medicines. Yes the Barman was my assistant. All business with the fighters was in these hands. But that Son of a dog managed to bribe major Serebrjannikova, and all who were connected with me departed. It wasn't long before this 'rat' had me pushed out of my bunker, yes-yes the same bunker where now this hamster lives. Together with people like Borov he had me thrown out onto the street. I'm still alive though, much to the disapointment of Sidorovich. But here there are kind people. I have survived, though I have a bad limp. But I will return someday and spit on his vile corpse!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vasil_first_2">
		<text>Vasily that's some story, I didn't mean any disrespect. Now that we have got that out of the way, do you do repairs?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vasil_first_3">
		<text>Yes this is my shop, but I can't get anything done in my condition</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vasil_first_4">
		<text>And what's wrong?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vasil_first_5">
		<text>My Foot aches, especially at night. The wound doesn't heal... So bad that it keeps me from doing my job</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vasil_first_6">
		<text>Well, can I help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vasil_first_7">
		<text>Yes there is a local man, kalmyak, who makes these fine ointments. Ive had some before, but now I'm in such bad shape that I can't make the trip myself</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vasil_first_8">
		<text>I will go and get the ointments for you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vasil_first_9">
		<text>Well, if you will get me 3 jars of ointment then I could start back to work</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vasil_second_0">
		<text>Greetings, Vasily, get ready to dance</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vasil_second_1">
		<text>Again you joke. I cant even stand up</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vasil_second_2">
		<text>Vasily, I don't joke, I have found what was promised. Here take 3 ointments as agreed</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vasil_second_3">
		<text>Well, for me, you will be my best client, I always without turn will serve you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_zamena_start_0">
		<text>Hello Clerik, why do you look so gloomy?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_zamena_start_1">
		<text>Five years ago I found out I had an ulcer, well I never got treated. I just took something for the pain and I could bear it. In the last couple of months it's gotten unbearable. The kalmyak gave me some ointment but it doesnt work on ulcers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_zamena_start_2">
		<text>What can I do to help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_zamena_start_3">
		<text>Bring to me a 'soul' artefact, its a known cure for ulcers. I will reward you with the kalmyaks ointment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_zamena_start_4">
		<text>I will try to help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_zamena_finish_0">
		<text>Clerik, have you forgotten about our arrangment?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_zamena_finish_1">
		<text>You mean about the ointment? I Remember. You have the artefact?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_zamena_finish_2">
		<text>Here it is</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dyak_zamena_finish_3">
		<text>Well thanks, heres 3 jars of ointment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_privet_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello, are you the leader of this faction?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_privet_dialog_1">
		<text>Well, for the last six months, yes I am. We are the faction 'Clear sky'. Our purpose is to study the Zone, but not like other scientists. More truly, we have different interests and a different vision of it's future</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_privet_dialog_2">
		<text>And in what way are you different? In my opinion, all the problems that the Zone poses to mankind are because of scientists</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_privet_dialog_3">
		<text>Yes, the majority, but not all. There are fanatics like the Monolith type. There are others, whos intentions are not clear... We are not fanatics, we don't pray to anybody, but also we have not come here to get rich. We really study the Zone, we don't answer to any goverment, that's the main difference. Its both our advantage, and also a disadvantage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_privet_dialog_4">
		<text>And so you have little faith in the people in power</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_privet_dialog_5">
		<text>Yes actually, but we are ready to co-operate with them. That's if they have the right intentions. But, I think, their scientific research is still focused on producing cheap electric power and even worse the production of new weapons of mass destruction. We, most of all, are afraid of that. In a Zone full of vicious mutants and deadly anomalies, Man is still the most dangerous</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_first_zadan_0">
		<text>So you absolutely don't communicate with other scientists in any way?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_first_zadan_1">
		<text>Well why should we? We support informal contacts to some scientists, in particular with professor Kruglov. We are not rich, and sometimes we don't have the necessary equipment. Here we do mostly field work. At a stage when a laboratory is required, we contact the scientists. By the way, do you want to work for science?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_first_zadan_2">
		<text>What kind of work?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_first_zadan_3">
		<text>Lately, we have observed a certain mutation among a species of mutant. We don't know how its all connected. We don't have any specimans for research</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_first_zadan_4">
		<text>What kind of mutant are you talking about?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_first_zadan_5">
		<text>In the northwest of the marsh we have found a different type of controller. It's necessary to get a part of this mutant. We need to examine its brain, I think you understand what needs to be done</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_first_zadan_6">
		<text>Well, I'm not against the work of science, give me the data and I will go search</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_first_zadan_end_0">
		<text>I brought the brain of the controller, you want to see it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_first_zadan_end_1">
		<text>Let's take a look... Yes, an unusual copy. Very large</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_first_zadan_end_2">
		<text>Thats the job done, what kind of reward do I get for dragging this big melon all the way across the marsh</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_first_zadan_end_3">
		<text>Yes certainly, certainly. Here, take this. I wanted to tell you, if you find any unusual mutant parts, with great pleasure I will buy them from you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_change_0">
		<text>Look, I brought something interesting for you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_change_1">
		<text>Let's see what you have...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_change_2">
		<text>A pair of red bloodsucker tentacles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_change_3">
		<text>A red burer's hand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_change_4">
		<text>Sorry, Sviblov, I don't have anything today</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_change_5">
		<text>Uh you, an unusual copy. Here, take in exchange</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_change_6">
		<text>The first time I've see such an interesting copy. Yes, this is for you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_weapons_need_0">
		<text>Sviblov, what's on your mind?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_weapons_need_1">
		<text>I want to start sending the men on regular patrols, but we lack the firepower to deal with large mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_weapons_need_2">
		<text>Do you have any ideas?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_weapons_need_3">
		<text>I do know where there is a PKM heavy machine gun. When my men patrolled near the abandoned farm the bandits, who have recently occupied the place, opened fire on them with the weapon. We are not as strong as we were before our unsuccessful attempt to break through to the Zone center. We lost our founder, Lebedev, and the majority of our veterans in that operation. Bandits have taken advantage of our weakness and control key points in the marsh. We somehow manage to hold this base and the approaches, also the 'Hunters' have helped us. If you can steal this machine gun it well help solve our problems. But I need you to do it with stealth</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_weapons_need_4">
		<text>So you suggest I remain unseen?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_weapons_need_5">
		<text>I have no love for bloodshed, we only use our weapons as a last resort. So try to get it without being noticed. One of my men already waits for you, talk with him. he will tell you all the details</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kashei_weapons_need_0">
		<text>Greetings, how are you doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kashei_weapons_need_1">
		<text>Greetings. You were sent by Sviblov? Good. There are seven in there - four outside and three in the building. You'll need to make your way inside, then look for a stash bag. That's where the weapon will be. Remember, no trouble, okay? We don't want to start a war...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kashei_weapons_need_2">
		<text>You're not going with me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kashei_weapons_need_3">
		<text>No. Together, we'd make too much noise...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kashei_weapons_need_4">
		<text>Okay, then wait for me here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_weapons_est_0">
		<text>I brought the weapon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_weapons_est_1">
		<text>What happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_weapons_est_2">
		<text>Things didn't go quite as planned. During the most interesting moment 'Hunters' arrived and a gunfight ensued. But I managed to get the machine gun</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_weapons_est_3">
		<text>I'm glad you were successful and came back unharmed. Here, take this as a gift</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_speak_about_kot_0">
		<text>Can I help you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_speak_about_kot_1">
		<text>Yes, I wanted to ask if you have seen any Monolithians? I mean here, in the swamps...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_speak_about_kot_2">
		<text>As far as I know, they are not present</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_speak_about_kot_3">
		<text>We have evidence that they are here, but don't know how they are infiltrating. They don't usually poke their nose south of the Radar. This really troubles me, these fanatics are devils</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_speak_about_kot_4">
		<text>What do you think they are up to??</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_speak_about_kot_5">
		<text>With these brainless fanatics anythings possible. They didn't come here for artefacts. Listen, theres a man I would like you to meet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_speak_about_kot_6">
		<text>Who?, tell me about him first</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dan_speak_about_kot_7">
		<text>His name is Cat, a smart guy who likes to keep a low profile, former KGB. He said he found something, I didn't press him for details. You should go and see what hes found. I will put his location on your PDA...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_first_speak_0">
		<text>Hello, are you Cat?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_first_speak_1">
		<text>Yes I'm Cat, has Dan sent you? I asked him to find someone with a bit of common sense, and he sends a rookie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_first_speak_2">
		<text>Watch your mouth! If you want to keep your teeth!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_first_speak_3">
		<text>Woah...camn down... sorry, I've been waiting here for Dan to send some help. I hope your ready to deal with a dose of high radiation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_first_speak_4">
		<text>What are you talking about?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_first_speak_5">
		<text>Dan spoke to you about the Monolithians? I was the first to have noticed something was wrong. The Monolith have become more active. At first they were sighted on the Agroprom, then I personally saw them in the Dark Valley. I've also tracked them directly to the Radar, I had to abort that recon operation as I got a bad case of radiation sickness. I was not ready for such a campaign. Since then my health has failed. Now I have seen them here, one of them has died in a highly radioactive Zone. We need to search the corpse for some information. Believe me, if these fanatics have conceived something, things could end badly for all of us</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_first_speak_6">
		<text>Why should I believe anything you say, you agents leave a trail of innocent bodies wherever you go. I think I should rise and leave or first put a bullet in your forehead</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_first_speak_7">
		<text>You are right, I served in the KGB. Enough bad things have happened to me. I had to disappear and where else better than the Zone. The only thing waiting for me out in the world is a bullet in the temple, or cyanide in my coffee, it all depends on the imagination of my 'friends'. The Zone is my home now, so that's why I want to find out what the Monolith are up to</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_first_speak_8">
		<text>Well, let's assume I believe you. What's next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_first_speak_9">
		<text>Well first of all we need to examine that body. I was observing the 3 Monolithians marking a map. They went in different directions, I followed one. He went through a radioactive Zone and was quickly overcome and collapsed. Like I already explained before I would go myself but for me it's certain death. My system just cant handle the trauma yet and I would be dead in minutes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_first_speak_10">
		<text>Alright, show me the place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_first_speak_11">
		<text>Let's go, only take your time, it's difficult for me to walk quickly. I will take you to the place, there will be a ruined house, in the ruins look for a corpse</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_second_speak_0">
		<text>Here Cat, I found a map</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_second_speak_1">
		<text>Let me see that. So it's a map of the bogs. Strange, I don't understand what they were doing. What are these marks for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_second_speak_2">
		<text>Well so?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_second_speak_3">
		<text>They have marked here one place, one more place in the southwest, here are figures, here are measurements - height, width and length. And here the rest... Alright, I now go to the bar at camp 'Clear Sky' to think about what we should do. Let's go, we will settle our affairs there</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_nebo_first_speak_0">
		<text>Well, Cat, have you received medical treatment?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_nebo_first_speak_1">
		<text>Yes, but here only Vodka rescues. You know that radiation influences the brain, earlier I would have quickly worked out those plans you found. Now my brain is constantly clouded with fog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_nebo_first_speak_2">
		<text>So, what will we do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_nebo_first_speak_3">
		<text>Well, actually, what we need to do is find the other two Monolithians, probably we can learn more from them</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_nebo_first_speak_4">
		<text>How will we find them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_nebo_first_speak_5">
		<text>Here on base 'Clear sky' they have the equipment that might help us find the remaining Monolithians. Go to the communications room and ask the officer if he can locate them, probably, they will be on their own network signal. When you find them, bring me any information you find and we will analyze it together</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tv_need_first_0">
		<text>Welcome, what is it you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tv_need_first_1">
		<text>I need to find two people, can you help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tv_need_first_2">
		<text>I understand, you want to trace them. Who do you want to find?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tv_need_first_3">
		<text>Two Monolithians. I have a PDA from a Monolithian, you can link the signal to the others?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tv_need_first_4">
		<text>Well well, I can help you, give me the PDA, but in exchange you should render me a service</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tv_need_first_5">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tv_need_first_6">
		<text>I am fond of electronics. I managed to get a TV set, but the picture tube has gone kaput. Could you get me another TV?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tv_need_first_7">
		<text>Where am I gonna find a TV? If I get you this TV, are you sure you can locate the people I'm looking for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tv_need_first_8">
		<text>I've done it before, so I think the second time will be easier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tv_need_first_9">
		<text>Alright, I will go and find you a TV</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tv_need_second_0">
		<text>Well, did you bring it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tv_need_second_1">
		<text>Yes, here take it. Not new, of course, but the Zone shops are closed</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tv_need_second_2">
		<text>Thank you, now let's take a look for those signals. I have picked up some suspicious signals. I have narrowed it down to five places, where there are signals. I can't be more precise than that, on the bogs strong radiation interferes. I will put in your PDA the co-ordinates of these places. Sorry, it looks like it's necessary for you to run about</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tv_need_second_3">
		<text>I knew it wasn't going to be easy, thanks anyway</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_nebo_second_speak_0">
		<text>Hello Cat, I found a notebook on one of the Monolithians</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_nebo_second_speak_1">
		<text>This is interesting, very interesting. They are planning to construct something, but I can't tell what it is yet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_nebo_second_speak_2">
		<text>What's next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_nebo_second_speak_3">
		<text>I need to study these notes some more. I'm sure you have other affairs to attend to, do you know the bar '100 X-ray'? I will meet you there later and we will discuss this further</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_barman_help_0">
		<text>Greetings</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_barman_help_1">
		<text>Greetings wanderer, have a rest. We are always glad to see good people</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_barman_help_2">
		<text>I am tired, its a long journey to reach your camp. Whats that smell? Something burning?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_barman_help_3">
		<text>Dammit!, I've burnt it again!... What will I feed the men?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_barman_help_4">
		<text>That's quite a stench... What were you cooking?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_barman_help_5">
		<text>The brothers brought in a wild boar, but the meat is tough and stinks when you fry it. The best meat comes from the Pseudogiant. Tastes sort of like chicken, but 100 times better. Listen, are you looking for work?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_barman_help_6">
		<text>Depends on what you want me to do</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_barman_help_7">
		<text>Its not a dirty job, youll just need to run around a bit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_barman_help_8">
		<text>Run around? I hope you're not going to ask me to go after one of those giant swamp monsters</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_barman_help_9">
		<text>I don't want you to kill anything. A few days ago some of the men saw a 'Red Pseudogiant' on the Agropom. These are very rare, and their meat... Mind you... even at the best restaurant you couldnt get something as delicious</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_barman_help_10">
		<text>What is it you want? You want me to slay this beast?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_barman_help_11">
		<text>I don't want you to kill him. I want you to mark him with this special sniper rifle that shoots a micro-transmitter needle. Then we will send out a hunting party, it will take several men to carry that much meat. So, just mark the 'Red Pseudogiant' and don't kill it. Then return here with the rifle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_barman_help_12">
		<text>I Hope you will pay well?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_barman_help_13">
		<text>Don't worry about that. Just take care not to kill him, the thought of that precious meat rotting away brings tears to my eyes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_barman_help_est_0">
		<text>Greetings, Barman</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_barman_help_est_1">
		<text>Greetings, my friend! I can see the location of the 'Red Pseudogiant' displayed on my PDA. I have already informed Dan, so we are looking forward to a good breakfast and supper for several days</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_barman_help_est_2">
		<text>Sounds much more appetizing than stale bread and old sausage. How about the payment?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_barman_help_est_3">
		<text>Certainly-certainly. Here you are</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_sniper_dialog_need_0">
		<text>Hello brother, who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_sniper_dialog_need_1">
		<text>Borman is my name. How did you reach here by yourself? Even groups of five men don't stand much of a chance of reaching this far north</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_sniper_dialog_need_2">
		<text>I have discovered paths that are not known by many stalkers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_sniper_dialog_need_3">
		<text>Regardless of that, if you reached Limansk you must be very skilled. Your help is needed here brother</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_sniper_dialog_need_4">
		<text>Whats going on??</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_sniper_dialog_need_5">
		<text>Here's the situation, we hold this side of the bridge and the Monolithians hold the other side. As you can see, the situation is far from stable, these damn mutants and zombies just keep appearing. Our main problem is this Monolith sniper, the Voroshilovsky marksman. This bastard picks off one or two of my men each day. Do you think you can take him out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_sniper_dialog_need_6">
		<text>What kind of reward will you give?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_sniper_dialog_need_7">
		<text>Well Brother, Ive got 10 packs of assorted cartridges I can give you, only</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_sniper_dialog_need_8">
		<text>Alright, I will try</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_sniper_dialog_est_0">
		<text>Greetings, Borman</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_sniper_dialog_est_1">
		<text>You don't cease to surprised me, how did your adventure go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_sniper_dialog_est_2">
		<text>Lets just say your problem has been put to rest</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_sniper_dialog_est_3">
		<text>Thank you brother, you saved many lives by ridding us of that bastard... Well here take these as I promised</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_glushitel_dialog_need_0">
		<text>Is there anything else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_glushitel_dialog_need_1">
		<text>Yes again your help is needed. Here these devils (Monolithians) jam our radio signal, so we cant communicate with anybody</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_glushitel_dialog_need_2">
		<text>Well Im not a radio engineer, what good could I do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_glushitel_dialog_need_3">
		<text>You have not understood, you need to find the 'muffler'. And here is the most interesting part. We will take the Monolithians small 'muffler' to the Miser, where he will make adjustments so that the 'muffler' blocks the radio signal of the Monolithians. Take the 'muffler' To Miser and then put it back where you found it. Then it will be their turn to suffer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_glushitel_dialog_need_4">
		<text>Not a bad plan, but where do I search for the 'muffler'?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_glushitel_dialog_need_5">
		<text>Its somewhere around the building on the hill. I cant be more precise than that. We are not rich here, but you will be rwarded</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_glushitel_dialog_need_6">
		<text>You have persuaded me, Borman</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scryaga_glushitel_dialog_first_0">
		<text>Greetings, shopkeeper</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scryaga_glushitel_dialog_first_1">
		<text>My old friend, why have you come? To buy something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scryaga_glushitel_dialog_first_2">
		<text>I come on business for Borman, you already know the situation?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scryaga_glushitel_dialog_first_3">
		<text>Yes, you mean about the 'muffler'?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scryaga_glushitel_dialog_first_4">
		<text>Here it is, a heavy lump of steel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scryaga_glushitel_dialog_first_5">
		<text>This will take me about five hours to adjust, come back then</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scryaga_glushitel_is_not_ready_0">
		<text>Well, is the 'muffler' ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scryaga_glushitel_is_not_ready_1">
		<text>Its too early, I said five hours</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scryaga_glushitel_is_ready_0">
		<text>Miser, is the 'muffler' ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scryaga_glushitel_is_ready_1">
		<text>Its ready, now let the Monolithians suffer. Take it back to where you found it, and send my greetings to Borman</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_glushitel_dialog_est_0">
		<text>Its done brother, the 'muffler' is in place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_glushitel_dialog_est_1">
		<text>You have gained many friends</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_glushitel_dialog_est_2">
		<text>Glad to help you and greetings to you from the Miser</text>
	</string>
	<string id="borman_glushitel_dialog_est_3">
		<text>Here, take this as promised</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_need_lekar_0">
		<text>Greetings Cat, you look terrible</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_need_lekar_1">
		<text>Im in really bad shape. It feels like I will die soon, thats no joke</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_need_lekar_2">
		<text>Can I help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_need_lekar_3">
		<text>I need something to extract this radiation poison from my bones. I've heard the kalmyak can make such a medicine...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_need_lekar_4">
		<text>Are you talking about the ointment?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_need_lekar_5">
		<text>There is another remedy the kalmyak can make. I also know he was fiends with the Hologram, he might know something also</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_need_lekar_6">
		<text>They have antirad here, it reduces radiation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_need_lekar_7">
		<text>My condition is too far advanced for antirad, I need something much stronger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_need_lekar_8">
		<text>Alright Cat, I will go ask for the medicine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_need_lekar_9">
		<text>What should I ask for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_need_lekar_10">
		<text>The kalmyak has a recipe, he can prepare a special medicine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_need_lekar_11">
		<text>Alright I will go</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_need_lekar_first_0">
		<text>Greetings, kalmyak</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_need_lekar_first_1">
		<text>Hello, have you come for ointment?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_need_lekar_first_2">
		<text>Ive come for medicine, but I need something special. Do you know 'Cat'? Well, the guy has a bad dose of radiation sickness that just keeps getting worse every day</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_need_lekar_first_3">
		<text>'Cat'!! A better name for him is rat! I know his past, how much innocent blood has he drunk?. He can die for all I care!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_need_lekar_first_4">
		<text>Brother do it for me, I really need his help finding out what the Monolithians are doing in the marsh</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_need_lekar_first_5">
		<text>Well, only for your sake then. But this medicine requires ingrediants that I don't have</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_need_lekar_first_6">
		<text>What do you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_need_lekar_first_7">
		<text>The artefact 'Night star' and ten 'feet of snorks'. All the other ingrediants I have. But there is one condition, to prepare the 'medicine', it has to be done in the early hours before dawn. Do not ask why, I will not tell. So, to bring the components and then you have until 5.00 am to pick up the medicine. If you don't come at this time, then we need to wait for the next day. Got it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_need_lekar_first_8">
		<text>I will go search</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_need_lekar_second_0">
		<text>Greetings kalmyak, here is the components you asked for</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_need_lekar_second_1">
		<text>Give them here. I need time to prepare the 'medicine', so go take care fo other matters. Come back in 12 hours, but don't hang around here or you get nothing</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_lekar_iz_not_ready_0">
		<text>Well is the 'medicine' ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_lekar_iz_not_ready_1">
		<text>You have come early, its not ready yet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_lekar_iz_ready_0">
		<text>Hello kalmyak, have you finished preparation of the 'medicine'?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kalmyak_lekar_iz_ready_1">
		<text>Here, its ready, Its radioactive so I hope you have artefacts or antirad to couter the effects during transportation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_est_lekar_holod_0">
		<text>Cat, here take this as soon as possible</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_est_lekar_holod_1">
		<text>Take what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_est_lekar_holod_2">
		<text>I brought the 'medicine', here take it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_est_lekar_holod_3">
		<text>Thanks Marked One, give-give it here. You saved my life, please accept this suit with strengthened protection against rupture. Here, its yours</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_est_lekar_kalmyak_0">
		<text>Cat, take this</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_est_lekar_kalmyak_1">
		<text>Take what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_est_lekar_kalmyak_2">
		<text>The 'medicine', you might spit a little blood but thats normal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_est_lekar_kalmyak_3">
		<text>You brought it? Here thanks, give-give it here. Here take this suit with strengthened protection against rupture. Here, its yours</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_need_lekar_0">
		<text>Hello</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_need_lekar_1">
		<text>Have you besome sick or just come for a rest? Accomidation is modest, but we are always glad to have visitors</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_need_lekar_2">
		<text>Its said that you are on good terms with Kalmyak?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_need_lekar_3">
		<text>Yes, but not good, sometimes he came to drink, and got drunk. During such moments he shared some recipes with me, about medicines to reduce radiation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_need_lekar_4">
		<text>Listen, could you give me this 'medicine', I need it for someone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_need_lekar_5">
		<text>Well, you understand, we are poor people...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_need_lekar_6">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_need_lekar_7">
		<text>The Artefact, 'Simbion' I have an order for one from Cold at 'Clear Sky'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_need_lekar_8">
		<text>I will try to get one</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_est_simbion_lekar_0">
		<text>Hello Cold, I have something for you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_est_simbion_lekar_1">
		<text>Yes!, a 'Simbion', thanks for the delivery</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_est_simbion_lekar_2">
		<text>No problem brother, I need some medicine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_est_simbion_lekar_3">
		<text>Ah yes, Ive had a message to have it ready, here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_change_0">
		<text>I Want to do some trading</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_change_1">
		<text>I have first-aid sets and grenades F-1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_change_2">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_change_3">
		<text>I will trade 4 grenades F-1 for 1 'Gravi' or 1 ' meat Chunk' or 2 'Quirk'. Five first-aid sets I will trade for 1 'Slug' or 2 'Sparkler' or 2 'stone Blood'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_change_31">
		<text>I have a 'Gravi'. Here you are</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_change_32">
		<text>I need grenades, heres a ' meat Chunk'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_change_33">
		<text>Heres two 'Quirk', give me some grenades</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_change_34">
		<text>Heres a 'Slug'. Give me some medkits</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_change_35">
		<text>I need some medkits. Here's two 'Sparklers'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_change_36">
		<text>Take these two 'Stone Blood' artefacts, and give me some medkits...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="holod_change_37">
		<text>Empty today, no artefacts to trade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_razborki_need_0">
		<text>Is there still a job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_razborki_need_1">
		<text>For you there is, your a serious guy. So this task is just for you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_razborki_need_2">
		<text>What needs done?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_razborki_need_3">
		<text>We lack heavy weapons, therefore we had to do some trading with Mercenaries. One of my men, 'Freebie', has been telling me he can get everything we need. He has set up a meeting with the Mercenaries, about arms supplies. But they have made a condition that, from our party, only two persons can attend. We have dealt with them in the past and they have not always been fair. Therefore I would like to ask you to 'observe' the transaction. To me the most important thing is 'Freebie' stays alive, and gets the weapon. From the very beginning I was against this transaction, but 'Freebie' insists that its a sure deal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_razborki_need_4">
		<text>So once again: I should cover 'Freebie' while he makes the deal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_razborki_need_5">
		<text>Yes you are right. 'Freebie' should not die, and the second condition - we don't want to be seen as violating the agreement, so you should remain unseen by the Mercenaries. The transaction will occur on an abandoned farm in the Cordon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_razborki_need_6">
		<text>All is understood, I will operate with stealth</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_razborki_est_0">
		<text>Lines, Sviblov, well you also have sent me, 'silently and peacefully' sit, aha always these words confuse me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_razborki_est_1">
		<text>That happens?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_razborki_est_2">
		<text>And I know? At first sat and all is silent bazaars, suddenly for weapons, well it was necessary to interfere, not say you is live 'Freebie'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_razborki_est_3">
		<text>Faugh you, have gone away, well the pancake felt... Eh! Well it is fine, here take something</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_agro_mono_need_0">
		<text>As our business, the Cat?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_agro_mono_need_1">
		<text>There is at me information some, it would be necessary to check up</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_agro_mono_need_2">
		<text>That there at you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_agro_mono_need_3">
		<text>Recently again group of Monolithians have noticed, on Agroprom. Listen, it is necessary to find them, it is necessary to understand the end-ends that occurs, here 'language' to us to get</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_agro_mono_need_4">
		<text>'Language' to get, it is good certainly, only here these people live and not surrender. All right, I will try</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gek_and_chuk_first_0">
		<text>musics, you who?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gek_and_chuk_first_1">
		<text>The Pancake the music, give all details then, here, mmmat, not safely, deduce us to the central complex, there the stalkers, here there about all and we will grind</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gek_and_chuk_second_0">
		<text>Well, give tell</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gek_and_chuk_second_1">
		<text>So this here to speak, we it... With the brother in spot-check were in the Dark valley, well and these devils madwomen we suffice and here. Speak dig a hole deep, metre on two</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gek_and_chuk_second_2">
		<text>What for a hole to dig?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gek_and_chuk_second_3">
		<text>So who freezed will understand these devils! We it, at first have thought that for us it we dig, I with fear in trousers nearly have not imposed that. And then I understand, Nakoy Lady it us here to conduct, to kill and bury here? Not, they though and freezed, but not stupid, there in a valley also have put. On kraynyak in anomaly corpses would throw</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gek_and_chuk_second_4">
		<text>Well and you that you think?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gek_and_chuk_second_5">
		<text>And what I think? It is live and is fine, at these assholes especially not forgot, to ask as for what, well it, to itself is more expensive. Though one of them something about towers told, any signal to transfer, alas they shun any music all believeth, yes so validly, 'IT' will be dissatisfied, 'HE' has told... Everything, more I know nothing</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_agro_mono_est_0">
		<text>Well, the Cat, could get I of 'language'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_agro_mono_est_1">
		<text>Tell</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_agro_mono_est_2">
		<text>I Have found Monolithians, truth was necessary to run about, an ash-tree a stub live they have not surrendered, but here with them was to steam captured, two brothers Chuk and Gek, they for them a hole for Repeater towers dripped. For what truth, brothers do not know. Yes Monolithians believeth all time about someone, unquestionably so, 'HE' has told, 'HE' has ordered etc</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_agro_mono_est_3">
		<text>Likely, their owner, heard I a legend about 'the Black Doctor', earlier I thought that it only a legend, and now...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_poisk_trader_need_0">
		<text>Well, a Cat, what ideas?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_poisk_trader_need_1">
		<text>There is one variant, truth muddy it is a little</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_poisk_trader_need_2">
		<text>Give, spread</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_poisk_trader_need_3">
		<text>There is a shopkeeper one, 'Rabinovich' klichut. Not, it not the Jew, it the Siberian thoroughbred, but a grasp business at it, God grant to any Jew. Supplies everything if only grandmas were, including these afflicted</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_poisk_trader_need_4">
		<text>The Monolith?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_poisk_trader_need_5">
		<text>Ugu. Tell it even the building crane to whom that could get, truth I in it not very much I trust. Fuck it here to whom is necessary. Well and so, this 'Rabi' almost the unique works with them, itself know as to them Related</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_poisk_trader_need_6">
		<text>Predlagash to find it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_poisk_trader_need_7">
		<text>At once I will tell, it will be difficult, truth is small hook, I know that it saw about two days ago on the base of Freedom. Talk to the Miser, it, basically, with it had business</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_poisk_trader_need_8">
		<text>Well, I know the Miser, perhaps I will split</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freetrader_poisk_trader_need_0">
		<text>Hello, Miser, how life daring?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freetrader_poisk_trader_need_1">
		<text>While the barrier is held all by a way, will be both vodka, and a herring and which that else...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freetrader_poisk_trader_need_2">
		<text>For the Person of one I search, your help, 'Rabi' klichut is necessary...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freetrader_poisk_trader_need_3">
		<text>'Rabi'... 'Rabi'... Something not values...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freetrader_poisk_trader_need_4">
		<text>'do not treat' me I know that you know, I in any way will not understand, what for you with it of business do? It supplies the Monolith, they then 'its' weapon kill you? Or money it is more important?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freetrader_poisk_trader_need_5">
		<text>Yes a nit it. Itself would shoot down, but I can not, I cannot, it is possible to tell 'roof' at it good, itself understand. We here long would not stretch, if not the help from 'Continent'. Give so, there was it here, has left yesterday where I do not know, look Modest, it it Accompanying, tell, yesterday in the evening Modest and has returned. Now in village thrown, well you know Gloomy? Well here they backs, at it and Zatusil</text>
	</string>
	<string id="joker_first_poisk_trader_need_0">
		<text>Hello the music where Modest to find you do not know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="joker_first_poisk_trader_need_1">
		<text>Oh blah, you hear the music is to drink that? I can not a head after the yesterday's...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="joker_first_poisk_trader_need_2">
		<text>Pogod now I will bring</text>
	</string>
	<string id="joker_first_poisk_trader_need_3">
		<text>Bear three, at me here the buddy where that, oh blah ... uk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="joker_second_poisk_trader_need_0">
		<text>Here, hold</text>
	</string>
	<string id="joker_second_poisk_trader_need_1">
		<text>Not-not at me hands shiver, pour itself. Has poured? Well, for the fallen</text>
	</string>
	<string id="joker_second_poisk_trader_need_2">
		<text>The Brother, Modest is necessary to me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="joker_second_poisk_trader_need_3">
		<text>Yes Wait you, give... Give still, here has gone, the darling has gone. Give on one?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="joker_second_poisk_trader_need_4">
		<text>I did not graze, affairs, the brother, do not wait</text>
	</string>
	<string id="joker_second_poisk_trader_need_5">
		<text>Well give, give for Modest, it the guy you know what, yes I, yes I for it to whom he likes...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="joker_second_poisk_trader_need_6">
		<text>Well all last give</text>
	</string>
	<string id="joker_second_poisk_trader_need_7">
		<text>About here, now most that. You about Modest asked me? He a little that has gone mad, we here yesterday is sensitive on a breast have accepted. Well appears we sit, warmly, well, in the asterisk sky, suddenly he jumps and speaks: - climbs a bough to whom I speak climbs, I you say see and so on. Aha and a finger there shows in depth of village. Well I look, there is there nobody. I speak: sit down Koljan, calm down, is not present there not a soul, on here still a little remains. Well he at first like has decided how to sit down, and then has suddenly jerked and there. More and more I it also did not see, and me overcame, well and I was chopped off. So if it is live Modest, search for it in village</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scromnyi_poisk_trader_need_0">
		<text>Who you so?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scromnyi_poisk_trader_need_1">
		<text>Who I do not know, but here because of whom I guess</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scromnyi_poisk_trader_need_2">
		<text>The Little man I search for one, Rabi klichut</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scromnyi_poisk_trader_need_3">
		<text>Yes I too would want, the nobility where it, a nit. We with the Joker have finished it to a barrier, and it to us of type - thanks of children, further I. Aha itself, whether you tell there is a person who for a barrier alone goes? A bough it, both our and your. There these morons Navernik waited for it. I think it towards Pripyat has jerked, at these fanatics a staff there so search for it in Pripyat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rabi_poisk_trader_need_0">
		<text>You Rabi? You can not answer, I know that you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rabi_poisk_trader_need_1">
		<text>You who?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rabi_poisk_trader_need_2">
		<text>And it you choose. You want, in a peacefully way we will disperse, and is not present so is not present</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rabi_poisk_trader_need_3">
		<text>That you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rabi_poisk_trader_need_4">
		<text>The information, what for and for what the Monolith is going to build transmission towers is necessary To me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rabi_poisk_trader_need_5">
		<text>But I here and, I the simple intermediary, me order, I extract, want also to you something I will get?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rabi_poisk_trader_need_6">
		<text>Do not drive the silly woman, all know that through you there are deliveries to the Monolith from 'Continent' so if they that have conceived that it should be known to you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rabi_poisk_trader_need_7">
		<text>About what you? What deliveries, I do not know anything. Yes, there was a business, has put the weapon to the Miser, it ask, really I do not say lies, but about any installations I know nothing</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rabi_poisk_trader_need_8">
		<text>Everything, the music, you have got me, or we with you now leave on meaningful dialogue, or I do not warrant for myself. You think I for this purpose were dragged to Pripyat that a fairy tale on night to listen?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rabi_poisk_trader_need_9">
		<text>But I...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rabi_poisk_trader_need_10">
		<text>You me have got All the swine, on knees</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rabi_poisk_trader_need_11">
		<text>All right-all right stand, to me have really ordered some towers and satellite Antenna. For what, well for what towers and companions are necessary? A signal to tell that for a signal I do not know, the order has arrived from 'the Black Doctor' who it I too do not know, I it and did not see never, I know that only its base where that in a Limansk, in Hospital...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rabi_poisk_trader_need_12">
		<text>When there should arrive towers and satellite Antenna?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rabi_poisk_trader_need_13">
		<text>Day through three-four... All I the dead man, I the walking dead person. Lag behind, lag behind me, me already all the same</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rabi_poisk_trader_need_14">
		<text>It is all?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_poisk_trader_est_0">
		<text>Well, the Cat, has found I our Rabi</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_poisk_trader_est_1">
		<text>As all has passed?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_poisk_trader_est_2">
		<text>Well, likely, successfully, I know where to search for 'the Black Doctor'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_poisk_trader_est_3">
		<text>In a Limansk? So Enachit, it not a legend</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_poisk_trader_est_4">
		<text>Is not present. I need to get to a Limansk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_poisk_trader_est_5">
		<text>I think, you should talk to Zahar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_poisk_trader_est_6">
		<text>And I will make, well wish my of good luck</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_need_perehod_0">
		<text>Hello Zahar, is necessary your help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_need_perehod_1">
		<text>What exactly?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_need_perehod_2">
		<text>It is necessary For me in a Limansk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_need_perehod_3">
		<text>In a Limansk? Well I can help, but also you to us help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_need_perehod_4">
		<text>That you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_need_perehod_5">
		<text>We through one person periodically Vypolyan orders from 'Continent', well and so have accepted not so long ago the big order on Arty, and the person through whom the transaction should take place, was gone. At it any problems were with avengers, you know them, with them it is better not to joke. Possibly, he most likely is in hiding. It is necessary to find it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_need_perehod_6">
		<text>Is clues?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_need_perehod_7">
		<text>You Know on bogs, there is a small base of avengers? Well and so, avengers have a certain caste 'untouchable', 'the brotherhood of ten' is called, it bratsvo and is a management of the avengers, one of leaders now just to be on the base of avengers on bogs. Call him is Brother Luis. Take it alive, he for certain knows that where our person. By the way, the intermediary klichut the Frenchman</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_need_perehod_8">
		<text>It is fine, I will try</text>
	</string>
	<string id="brat_luis_dialog_0">
		<text>I Welcome</text>
	</string>
	<string id="brat_luis_dialog_1">
		<text>Who you? Blah, you that have put all protection?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="brat_luis_dialog_2">
		<text>It was necessary, painfully it wanted to communicate to you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="brat_luis_dialog_3">
		<text>Not Zahar has sent to you? He will wait the. The Frenchman is necessary to you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="brat_luis_dialog_4">
		<text>It would be not bad</text>
	</string>
	<string id="brat_luis_dialog_5">
		<text>Late, we have found it earlier, but you can try to be in time, he-he, search for it on the base of freedom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="brat_luis_dialog_6">
		<text>Well, had pleasantly a talk, I hope, not last time</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_est_perehod_0">
		<text>Greetings, Zahar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_est_perehod_1">
		<text>Hello, Marked One, well as there our business?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_est_perehod_2">
		<text>I Was late Whitebait, Zahar, is not present the Frenchman, have killed him. Here it PDA take, it is possible it to you will help</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zahar_est_perehod_3">
		<text>Lines it is a pity the music, efficient was. Well it is fine. About transition to a Limansk: that path that I knew - a moss overgrown ... Vobschem, there is no it more... But there is hook one - there was such stalker - Fang called, he precisely knew road. Here only it is live or not - I not in a course, very long ago it did not see. To find out about transition, you should find Fang or at least to learn, whether it is live</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_need_kurier_0">
		<text>Hello, what for good reason at you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_need_kurier_1">
		<text>About, Streloks, you also are necessary to me. At us the courier was gone on a radar. Understand we for Sahara some interesting samples have prepared, have sent the courier. To the Radar all was normal, and there the signal was gone. Samples very valuable, and in the single copy, it is necessary to find the courier necessarily</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_need_kurier_2">
		<text>Yes I would help, but at me at problems</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_need_kurier_3">
		<text>That for problems?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_need_kurier_4">
		<text>Yes you understand, in a Limansk anomaly a teleport was formed, not to pass, not to pass</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_need_kurier_5">
		<text>Basically, I can help, give Bash on Bash. You will help us, we to you. I will give to you the angulator of anomalies, specially adjusted on teleportry, and you can remove this teleport</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_need_kurier_6">
		<text>Here a pancake, anything it is simple so do not do, it is fine on hands</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kurier_need_kurier_0">
		<text>Ohh... dude, what with you? Shitty you look</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kurier_need_kurier_1">
		<text>Hrenovo to me... kha-kha-kha... Wait... kha-kha-kha. Excuse blood and whips</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kurier_need_kurier_2">
		<text>You, probably, also are the courier from Sviblov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kurier_need_kurier_3">
		<text>Yes. Listen... Listen to me... kha-kha-kha. It is necessary... kha-kha-kha to deliver samples to Sakharov, it is very important. IMPORTANT, you understand. I. kha-kha-kha I can not any more</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kurier_need_kurier_4">
		<text>It is quiet Bratuha, now the first-aid set you will accept also all will be a way</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kurier_need_kurier_5">
		<text>You think I did not try, a shit I am feeling... kha-kha-kha. Listen promise to me to deliver this case to Sakharov?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kurier_need_kurier_6">
		<text>That for a case?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kurier_need_kurier_7">
		<text>Here it, there action... Really... kha-kha-kha important... The important...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kurier_need_kurier_8">
		<text>That the important?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saharov_need_kurier_0">
		<text>Professor, in... Take it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saharov_need_kurier_1">
		<text>It is quiet, here accept it, you should have a sleep a little</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saharov_need_kurier_2">
		<text>Prof...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saharov_est_kurier_0">
		<text>Oh Professor, a head plague</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saharov_est_kurier_1">
		<text>Anything, it is posteffect from soporific</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saharov_est_kurier_2">
		<text>I Hope you Explain to me, what for crap was in a case?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saharov_est_kurier_3">
		<text>The Pre-production model of a vaccine from a HIV of infections. If we appear are right, we can return millions people to life. Forgive that have forced you so to risk, but a case extraordinary. The substance while is strongly astable that leads to various reactions of an organism, up to lethal outcomes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saharov_est_kurier_4">
		<text>Well, Professor, it is necessary to warn, I hardly have not rejected a hoof</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saharov_est_kurier_5">
		<text>Here take here something, I hope it will redress our wrong</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_est_kurier_0">
		<text>Hello to sloggers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_est_kurier_1">
		<text>The Fine fellow, Streloks, has fine gained. You understand, it was the single copy... The Unique preparation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_est_kurier_2">
		<text>Yes do not justify, a stranger I for you, it is possible and to substitute me, and I will die such as I more will run ten</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sveeblov_est_kurier_3">
		<text>Not, the brother, you are not right, such as you units, and I very much appreciate you, believe. All right here take angulator. Remember, it is necessary to approach as it is possible more close to a teleport and to throw out angulator and if you will get successfully the teleport so to say 'will resolve'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_hosp_first_0">
		<text>What are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_hosp_first_1">
		<text>I couldn't send you in there on your own. Brought in some some back-up, former Spetsnaz</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_hosp_first_2">
		<text>Is there a lot of them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_hosp_first_3">
		<text>In the first room about eight to ten. And further...who knows?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_hosp_first_4">
		<text>Well brothers, I will go first. Then follow me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="black_doctor_dialog_0">
		<text>You must be the notorious Black Doctor?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="black_doctor_dialog_1">
		<text>And you are Strelok? The disturber of the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="black_doctor_dialog_2">
		<text>You probably already know that Maples has left you. Well it's time we met, can you tell me whats going on? It would be interesting to hear the information firsthand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="black_doctor_dialog_3">
		<text>He didn't leave, he has simply run away, he was frightened... He's a good scientist, a clever person, but the changing world scares him. I have all the time in the world, so Im ready to answer your questions</text>
	</string>
	<string id="black_doctor_dialog_4">
		<text>What are you planning?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="black_doctor_dialog_5">
		<text>Its all very simple. We are going to increase the size of the Zone. And of course, preserve it. But we wanted to accelerate the process</text>
	</string>
	<string id="black_doctor_dialog_6">
		<text>How?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="black_doctor_dialog_7">
		<text>We have developed a new Psi-installation that will allow us to reach the surrounding villages and even cities. Besides, we also have mobile psi installations</text>
	</string>
	<string id="black_doctor_dialog_8">
		<text>Wont the people who live near to the Zone undergo a Psi-attack? Whats preventing you from doing it now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="black_doctor_dialog_9">
		<text>Partly the originator of our problems is you. If not for your careless actions, we would by now have been able to deploy our portable repeaters. Our new Psi-installation demands enormous kol-va energy. We don't have such a kol-va energy supply. Certainly, our needs would have been met before the failure of the atomic power station. But now the reactor is destroyed, so it was necessary to try a different way. Besides there is also one more reason, its rather embarrassing... Our 'general' talkative friend, you didn't tell all</text>
	</string>
	<string id="black_doctor_dialog_10">
		<text>Maples or Rabi? Also what didn't you find out in time?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="black_doctor_dialog_11">
		<text>Except repeaters, we have ordered some independent generators and, if have received them, could start our installation on total power. And relay a signal in a radius of 200-300 km to begin with. But as I already stated that didn't happen because of you and the lieutenant colonel of FSB Kotova. So for now we are content with the portable Psi-aerials, and these are only for protection. Besides, as you already likely know, a spare variant of reception of the boundless power supply - too is in doubt</text>
	</string>
	<string id="black_doctor_dialog_12">
		<text>It's Cat?...REALLY!!!!, its impossible to trust anybody...the two-faced shit. So what happens now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="black_doctor_dialog_13">
		<text>I don't know how, but special services have learned, but not the details, of our plan. Also theres been an influx of agents. One of them your acquaintance, the Cat. And as a further result of your actions our counter-agents and some more people have been killed, the contract will terminate, cargo is destroyed. But never would they think that even children can be agents... As Maples has already told you - and this is an annoying truth - the girl has stolen from us an artefact without which it is impossible to produce an alternative energy source. My people are searching for her, but so far - unsuccessfully. Also I asked them to search, not kill</text>
	</string>
	<string id="black_doctor_dialog_14">
		<text>What further?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="black_doctor_dialog_15">
		<text>Further it's necessary for us to part. For some people the Zone is a source of harm, and for others its a second life. But I have not told you the most important part. I'm afraid that for now its just not the right time. You are awaited by a teleport - go downwards on a ladder - it will transfer you to the first compartment of the destroyed hospital. But before you go - a dream - I hope, it will bring some clearness in your consciousness</text>
	</string>
	<string id="black_doctor_dialog_16">
		<text>A Dream? But I don't want to sleep...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_after_doctor_dialog_0">
		<text>Well, your a double agent?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_after_doctor_dialog_1">
		<text>Strelok, calm down. Try to understand the situation. It was necessary to operate like that</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_after_doctor_dialog_2">
		<text>You couldnt be honest with me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_after_doctor_dialog_3">
		<text>You would have never began to help if you knew. Well tell me, what happened in there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kot_after_doctor_dialog_4">
		<text>You need to listen... I don't forgive lies, and the Zone will not forgive either. I'm not going to kill you, but other stalkers wont be as forgiving as me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_pre_upgreid_0">
		<text>Hello Vasily, an upgrade possible?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_pre_upgreid_1">
		<text>I Can attach to you a lantern under an eye, and also NVD to some suits</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_pre_upgreid_2">
		<text>All you joke, Vasily, on what suits you can attach NVD?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_pre_upgreid_3">
		<text>On grouping 'Sky' exoskeleton, on a scientific suit a Clear sky and on Black overalls of the Monolith</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_0">
		<text>Hi. I'd like to have night vision fitted to my suit, please</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_1">
		<text>Well, I can install anything up to 'White Night' NVD to any of the following suits:\nClear Sky exoskeleton\nClear Sky Scientific suit\nBlack Monolith suit. Which would you like?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_2">
		<text>I can install anything up to 'White Night' NVD to any of the following suits:\nClear Sky exoskeleton\nClear Sky Scientific suit\nBlack Monolith suit. Which would you like?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_3">
		<text>Let me check...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_4">
		<text>Are you saying you don't know what suit you're wearing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_5">
		<text>A Clear Sky exoskeleton</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_6">
		<text>A Clear Sky Scientific suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_7">
		<text>A Black Monolith suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_8">
		<text>Okay, you've got good taste:\n- NVD 'Green' - 10,000Ru\n- NVD 'Digital' - 25,000Ru\n- NVD 'Sepia' - 15,000Ru\n- NVD 'Halogen' - 20,000Ru\n- NVD 'Cats Eye' - 30,000Ru\n- NVD 'Psi-effect' - 25,000Ru\n- NVD 'Moonlight' - 25,000Ru\n- NVD 'White Night' - 30,000Ru\nWhich one?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_81">
		<text>Standard 'Green'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_82">
		<text>'Digital'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_83">
		<text>'Sepia'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_84">
		<text>'Halogen'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_85">
		<text>'Cats Eye'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_86">
		<text>'Psi-effect'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_87">
		<text>'Moonlight'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_88">
		<text>The best, please -  'White Night'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_89">
		<text>Sorry Vasily. Sidorovich has already taken all my cash...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_811">
		<text>On, a bast shoe, and who you still? Such crap only the bast shoe also could order</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_821">
		<text>I Look a money has saved up, it is necessary to tickle at night you a plumelet on a narrow path. Uh-ha-ha. On here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_831">
		<text>I Get on you take, well as you want, hold</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_841">
		<text>Jadren a long loaf and you there. 'Halogen' to it submit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_851">
		<text>In crystalization has moved? On 'Cats Eye'...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_861">
		<text>Podi has presoaked whom. Hold 'Psi-effect'...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_871">
		<text>And what for to you such NVD the good? Not for maids on bogs to peep ha-ha-ha? Hold the suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_881">
		<text>You look strangely at it how many. Barman on-has pressed?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_891">
		<text>Don't worry. Sidorovich won't be around forever...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_9">
		<text>Yes on your physiognomy proletarian, only a gas mask to put on, appreciate:\n- NVD 'Green' - 10,000Ru\n- NVD 'Digital' - 25,000Ru\n- NVD 'Sepia' - 15,000Ru\n- NVD 'Halogen' - 20,000Ru\n- NVD 'Cats Eye' - 30,000Ru\n- NVD 'Psi-effect' - 25,000Ru\n- NVD 'Moonlight' - 25,000Ru\n- NVD 'White night' - 30,000Ru\nWhich would you like?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_91">
		<text>Standard 'Green'...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_92">
		<text>'Digital'...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_93">
		<text>'Sepia'...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_94">
		<text>'Halogen'...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_95">
		<text>'Cats Eye'...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_96">
		<text>'Psi-effect'...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_97">
		<text>'Moonlight'...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_98">
		<text>The best, please -  'White Night'...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_99">
		<text>Sorry Vasily, too expensive...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_911">
		<text>How much for this crap?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_921">
		<text>Oh, well you the Barin, the poured out Barin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_931">
		<text>The Miser you. Heels of pieces has saved, and after all crap notable this NVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_941">
		<text>Pervayor of clever words of everyones 'Halogen-shmalogen'. Remember, there is a shit, and there is a thing standing. Here that you to yourself have ordered if and not shit it is close to this word</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_951">
		<text>On 'an ass of the bloodsucker'. Oh excuse, 'Cat's Eye'. Ours to you Sherlock</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_961">
		<text>And me still the bandit name? Here you are a bandit. Whence money, and? You are silent, yes? Gop-stop, we have approached from for a corner, gop-stop, you much on yourself took... Yes what hints? So the song was remembered</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_971">
		<text>Well a moustache, 'Moonlight' has put, in a bum of the peacock feathers Nasuval and the first guy on village</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_981">
		<text>Not, well tell to me, whence at you, stalkers, money? You thump all day long</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_991">
		<text>It is expensive? Yes you have gone. You to Sidorovich descend, here at it so is cheap!, that after it, at you even on a leaf of money will not be, shame the to cover</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_10">
		<text>Too by a head about a stone it has decided to be beaten? this the suit of madwomen has got on? And NVD to you that at night a stone with a belly of a shaggy burer not to mix? On appreciate:\n- NVD 'Green' - 10,000Ru\n- NVD 'Digital' - 25,000Ru\n- NVD 'Sepia' - 15,000Ru\n- NVD 'Halogen' - 20,000Ru\n- NVD 'Cats Eye' - 30,000Ru\n- NVD 'Psi-effect' - 25,000Ru\n- NVD 'Moonlight' - 25,000Ru\n- NVD 'White Night' - 30,000Ru\n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_101">
		<text>Standard 'Green'...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_102">
		<text>'Digital'...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_103">
		<text>'Sepia'...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_104">
		<text>'Halogen'...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_105">
		<text>'Cats Eye'...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_106">
		<text>'Psi-effect'...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_107">
		<text>'Moonlight'...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_108">
		<text>The best, please -  'White Night'...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_109">
		<text>Sorry Vasily, but I don't feel comfortable here. I need to go...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_1011">
		<text>In-in more you are not worthy. All the same you will die from... Vodka, an ear-ha-ha</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_1021">
		<text>Not, well Nakoy a shit you on the Zone gad at night? Better to the Cold, for holding a pile, yes canned food Radioactive to have a snack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_1031">
		<text>On hold. Silly you the people stalkers, run on the Zone all day long, and then all the same all your money to me, yes to the Cold get</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_1041">
		<text>Not, I such crap did not begin to carry. Take away Durian a head</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_1051">
		<text>On an eagle, here to you 'Cat's Eye'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_1061">
		<text>And me still the bandit name? Here you the bandit. Whence money, and? You are silent, yes? Gop-stop, we have approached from for a corner, gop-stop, you much on yourself took. Yes what hints? So, the song was remembered</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_1071">
		<text>Well everything, 'Moonlight' has put, in a bum of the peacock feathers nasuval and the first guy on village</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_1081">
		<text>Not, well tell to me whence at you, stalkers, money? You thump all day long</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marsh_remont_upgreid_1091">
		<text>I have bothered it. Oh, well it is direct the young lady muslin. Has bothered you will speak to the bloodsucker when it you on a dump will press at night, and at you from cartridges - only boots, and those rats chewed. An ear-ha-ha</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_zver_need_0">
		<text>Hello, we meet again</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_zver_need_1">
		<text>Thank the stars it's you Strelok, can you help us one more time?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_zver_need_2">
		<text>Explain whats going on</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_zver_need_3">
		<text>The hunters have just informed me that a big herd of mutants are heading towards our camp by the tower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_zver_need_4">
		<text>Do you have a plan?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_zver_need_5">
		<text>You are better with a weapon than any man here. In the tower, on the second floor, is a backpack that has our best weapon. Our best weapon should be in the hands of the best fighter. That way, more of us stand a chance of surviving</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_zver_need_6">
		<text>Well, I will try to protect your men</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_zver_est_0">
		<text>Holy shit!, Ive never seen so many mutants at once</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_zver_est_1">
		<text>Periodically, we get herds of mutants that pass through. Though this is the first time Ive seen so many at once</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_zver_est_2">
		<text>Well brother, Im not needed here any more. So I will go and take care of affairs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_zver_est_3">
		<text>Yes-yes thanks for the help. You can keep the weapon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_most_need_0">
		<text>Hello Brothers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_most_need_1">
		<text>I Welcome you stalker, Can you help us out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_most_need_2">
		<text>What is necessary?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_most_need_3">
		<text>There is a bridge nearby, and behind the bridge is the road to Limansk. But the bridge is in the hands of Mercenaries, so the road is blocked. Here men from different groups have gathered, we want to push them off the bridge</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_most_need_4">
		<text>Well and?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_most_need_5">
		<text>As you can see our group is small and they are twice our number. You've reached the Red Forest by yourself, so you must be a tough fighter. Will you help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_most_need_6">
		<text>Can you supply first-aid sets?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_most_need_7">
		<text>Help us and I will give you what we can spare</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_most_need_8">
		<text>Well Im going to Limansk, so you can count me in for this operation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_most_est_0">
		<text>That was interesting</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_most_est_1">
		<text>This is the fourth time we have had to take back this bridge. Mercenaries try to block it all the time. Why would someone pay mercs so much money to cut off our brothers in Limansk?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_most_est_2">
		<text>I don't know, these devils will do anything for money. You promised to share first-aid sets with me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_most_est_3">
		<text>Ah yes, these are army. Well, thanks for the help. I now go back to our camp by the tower. You have to go through the woods to get there</text>
	</string>
	<string id="xolod_need_grib_0">
		<text>Why so happy?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="xolod_need_grib_1">
		<text>I have a business offer for you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="xolod_need_grib_2">
		<text>What kind of business offer?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="xolod_need_grib_3">
		<text>Magic Mushrooms! Magic Mushrooms are what I trade for. I love them, well I have to share them with the guys</text>
	</string>
	<string id="xolod_need_grib_4">
		<text>Now I know why your so happy, tell me the offer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="xolod_need_grib_5">
		<text>For three mushrooms: 5 drums for the Pistol-machine gun PPSh-41, or 3 magazines for the MG-42 machine gun, or 3 army first-aid sets, either 3 antirad, or 4 packs of NATO cartridges, or 4 packs for AK-74, or 3 packs of cartridges for the Thunder-storm. Only thing is mushrooms carry a little radiation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grib_ghange_0">
		<text>Here you are, Cold. Mushrooms</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grib_ghange_1">
		<text>Let me see!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grib_ghange_2">
		<text>Here three pieces</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grib_ghange_3">
		<text>Oh, sorry. I thought I had some in there...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grib_ghange_4">
		<text>Which do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grib_ghange_41">
		<text>Give 5 drums for Pistol-machine gun PPSh-41</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grib_ghange_42">
		<text>Give 3 magazines for the Mg-42 machine gun...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grib_ghange_43">
		<text>Give 3 army first-aid sets</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grib_ghange_44">
		<text>Give 3 antirad</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grib_ghange_45">
		<text>Give 4 packs 5,45x39mm for AK</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grib_ghange_46">
		<text>Give 4 packs 5.56x45mm SS109 the NATO</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grib_ghange_47">
		<text>Give 3 packs 9x39mm PAB-9 for the THUNDER-STORM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grib_ghange_48">
		<text>No, perhaps I will eat the mushrooms myself</text>
	</string>
	<string id="green_need_doc_0">
		<text>Hello, stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="green_need_doc_1">
		<text>Hello guys, Im here on business</text>
	</string>
	<string id="green_need_doc_2">
		<text>What about?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="green_need_doc_3">
		<text>I was sent by Fang to pick up a document</text>
	</string>
	<string id="green_need_doc_4">
		<text>Eh...theres a problem</text>
	</string>
	<string id="green_need_doc_5">
		<text>What happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="green_need_doc_6">
		<text>A stalker aproached our camp and seemed normal, he passed around a bottle of vodka and we shared stories till we past out. When we woke up in the morning he had disappeared. Our backpack was stolen. In the backpack was almost all our belongings. We have had the same clothes on for two weeks. We barely have any cartrides left and our food is gone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="green_need_doc_7">
		<text>Where can I look for this stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="green_need_doc_8">
		<text>He talked about doing business with 'Cold', Barman on the Marshes. He says: 'I Will take my artefacts to Cold and get the best price'. So we believe he must have went to the marsh</text>
	</string>
	<string id="green_need_doc_9">
		<text>I will go to the marsh and talk with Cold and find out where your pack is</text>
	</string>
	<string id="green_need_doc_10">
		<text>If you find it, we will owe you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="xolod_need_doc_0">
		<text>Hello Cold, I need to speak with you</text>
	</string>
	<string id="xolod_need_doc_1">
		<text>Why have you come?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="xolod_need_doc_2">
		<text>Im looking for a stalker who might have passed through here recently, wanting to sell a backpack full of hunters gear</text>
	</string>
	<string id="xolod_need_doc_3">
		<text>I know who your talking about Marked One, 'Mitka Redemption'. One of the biggest thieves in the Zone. He came here trying to sell a backpack, but I knew it was stolen, and we kicked him off the base. Search for him near the cemetery that where his camp is located. I will not be surprised if he is dead already. He has stolen from too many people</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grab_need_doc_0">
		<text>Stojajajajajat!!!!!!!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grab_need_doc_1">
		<text>Brothers, easy! easy! whats going on with Mitka?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grab_need_doc_2">
		<text>What business do you have with this scum?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grab_need_doc_3">
		<text>Brothers, Brothers, let me have a few words with Mitka, in private</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grab_need_doc_4">
		<text>Pay up 50000ru and you can keep this rat for yourself. We cant even count how many times this son of a whore has stolen from us...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grab_need_doc_41">
		<text>Here, take the money. Now Mitka is free?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grab_need_doc_411">
		<text>Well he's your problem now, I wouldnt have payed a copeck to save his rotten hide. Partner in crime perhaps?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grab_need_doc_42">
		<text>Friend let me tell you something, if I was a bandit. You would all be dead right now and I would still have 50000ru in my pocket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grab_need_doc_421">
		<text>If he is still here when I count to 10, I don't know if I can control my trigger finger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grab_need_doc_422">
		<text>Our business is finished, now I will finish my business with Mitka. don't get in the way of that</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mitya_need_doc_0">
		<text>Well Mitka, you really owe me now</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mitya_need_doc_1">
		<text>Brother... oh brother, thanks so much, they... They were about to waste me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mitya_need_doc_2">
		<text>I took care of your problem with them. Now, where is the backpack which you stole from the hunters in the red wood?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mitya_need_doc_3">
		<text>I don't have it, bandits robbed me on the road and took everything, I barely got away with my life</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mitya_need_doc_4">
		<text>I don't have the time for this shit!, I will finish what they started if you don't start talking!...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mitya_need_doc_5">
		<text>Wait! Wait! I was mistaken, was mistaken... I have remembered. I have the backpack, its here...look...take it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mitya_need_doc_6">
		<text>Well you lieing dog. I should have waited till they shot you, instead of paying money</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_need_doc_0">
		<text>Hello Sidorovich, what for a parcel?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_need_doc_1">
		<text>Is shorter peasant one is, Mitjaem call, the pilferer it notable and the gambler. Well also appears to me has run into debt the sum round. I also did not hope from it to receive Duty. And here yesterday resorts, joyful such and me - affairs say at it on ointment, just about with all debts pay with. For now as pledge take, speaks, a backpack. Well, I have looked - there on a trifle, meal, cartridges, pair of artefacts. Of course, took better so, than absolutely than anything. And recently you remembered...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_need_doc_2">
		<text>Well and...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_need_doc_3">
		<text>You remembered, you at us the master to get into all affairs, and rucksak obviously stolen, well here and I think</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_need_doc_4">
		<text>Oh do not pull, Sidorovich, spread</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_need_doc_5">
		<text>I can sell to you this backpack More shortly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_need_doc_6">
		<text>How many?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_need_doc_7">
		<text>So we will estimate five... Plus the percent, total eight, is not present ten thousand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_need_doc_8">
		<text>For an old backpack? For pair cobble-stones and a stick of rotten sausage?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_need_doc_9">
		<text>Well I do not know, are long it is necessary to give. The backpack is necessary to you? It is necessary on eyes I see. Ten and copecks it is less</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_est_doc_0">
		<text>Sidorovich!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_est_doc_1">
		<text>That, has brought money?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_est_doc_2">
		<text>Is not present, it is simple in your mind's eye has come to look, perhaps you will change the mind</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_est_doc_3">
		<text>On, an Egyptian Vulture, choke</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_est_doc_4">
		<text>In, here it is another story, take away</text>
	</string>
	<string id="green_est_doc_0">
		<text>Greetings Strelok</text>
	</string>
	<string id="green_est_doc_1">
		<text>Hello brother, does this look familiar?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="green_est_doc_2">
		<text>Let's take a look, Yes!, it is our backpack. You are a savior indeed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="green_est_doc_3">
		<text>Excuse my haste, but I need those documents</text>
	</string>
	<string id="green_est_doc_4">
		<text>Yes-yes, of course, only they are not with us. We put them in another spot for insurance. It's not far from here go north from our cave and past the clearing and you will find an abandoned army tank in the woods. Near to it look for a backpack, the documents are in it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="klyak_est_doc_0">
		<text>Greetings, olden time</text>
	</string>
	<string id="klyak_est_doc_1">
		<text>Hello, Streloks, well docks at you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="klyak_est_doc_2">
		<text>At me. As I will remember your words 'Yes nonsense, trifling matter'... Here always I was confused with expressions of type 'trifling matter', 'small Halturka'... Blows from such affairs by usually big bum</text>
	</string>
	<string id="klyak_est_doc_3">
		<text>It happens, the Zone is unpredictable, all can be. Give them here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="klyak_need_denis_0">
		<text>Well interested in documents?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="klyak_need_denis_1">
		<text>You know a long time ago I worked for the Mercenaries. There was one person there that I worked with gathering intel in the Zone. But we didn't share all the information we gathered with the Mercenaries. We established hiding places and stored the intel on flash cards, a part of them directly on documents. After my quarrel with the Mercenaries, it was necessary to stash everything. Until a time I thought it would be safe to retreive them. I sent my old comrade to check up on one of these hiding places. But two days and he has not returned, and also his PDA is silent. Also I sent the Pilgrim long ago to check on a path to the Lost Village, and also no word from him</text>
	</string>
	<string id="klyak_need_denis_2">
		<text>What now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="klyak_need_denis_3">
		<text>We need to find my old comrade. If I am right, the documents contain important information. Meanwhile I will try to communicate with the Pilgrim</text>
	</string>
	<string id="klyak_need_denis_4">
		<text>I have had no news from the Panther about where to search for the girl who has abducted from O-consciousness, this situation also is not clear... Where though do I search for your comrade?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="klyak_need_denis_5">
		<text>In the Red Forest. It's not far from the house of the Forester, close to the wall. It's in an old abandoned mine, there I made a small hiding place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="klyak_need_denis_6">
		<text>I will look for him. What's his name?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="klyak_need_denis_7">
		<text>Denis, if he lives help him</text>
	</string>
	<string id="denis_need_denis_0">
		<text>Hello, are you Denis?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="denis_need_denis_1">
		<text>Thank you friend, did Fang send you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="denis_need_denis_2">
		<text>Yes, he sent me to save your ass</text>
	</string>
	<string id="denis_need_denis_3">
		<text>It's not the first time he has bailed me out of trouble</text>
	</string>
	<string id="denis_need_denis_4">
		<text>Do you have the documents?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="denis_need_denis_5">
		<text>The hiding place was empty! I only had time to check it then the controller got me. Hey, can you help me get to the local stalker base? It's not far but I'm too weak right now to make it by myself</text>
	</string>
	<string id="denis_need_denis_6">
		<text>No problem, you just follow me. I will try to keep a slow pace so you can keep up</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_need_denis_0">
		<text>Hello, I didn't expect to get any help. How did you know there was trouble?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_need_denis_1">
		<text>One of my men spotted a group of Mercenaries, and we decided to track them</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_need_denis_2">
		<text>Well, I'm glad that you did</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shadowman_need_denis_3">
		<text>It's nothing compared to all the help you have given us brother</text>
	</string>
	<string id="klyak_est_denis_0">
		<text>Bad news Fang, the hiding place is empty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="klyak_est_denis_1">
		<text>Shit! I can't believe it. Are you sure?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="klyak_est_denis_2">
		<text>Yes, there was nothing there. Denis said so... or do you think?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="klyak_est_denis_3">
		<text>No... Denis is a trusted friend. So who has visited us that could have known? Alright, have a rest but not too long. The Astrologer has sent an SMS for you to meet him in the Cordon at the rookie village. I communicated with the Doctor and told him to let the Astrologer know I'm alive. I'm not sure what this guy is up to but we need to be careful with him, he's a smooth operator. I want you to deliver this copy of my map to him</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
<!--Created/Modified with S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Dialog Extended Editor by Marty Sheppard/ Version: 0.96i ( 2017/02/17) =!!= Last changed: 10.07.2017 00:43:39 -->
