<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="st_antirad">
		<text>Antiradiation drugs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_antirad_descr">
		<text>A pack of pills with active ingredients that help expel radionucleoids from the body. The pills do not protect the body from new radiation, but only reduce the existing radiation dose.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bread">
		<text>Bread</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bread_descr">
		<text>No bakers have ever been identified in the Zone, but this bread is not contaminated and is actually quite edible. At least no complaints have been reported thus far.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_conserva">
		<text>“Tourist’s Breakfast”</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_conserva_descr">
		<text>Canned goods from an army ration depot looted by stalkers. Should still be good to eat, if you believe the best before date.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kolbasa">
		<text>Diet sausage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kolbasa_descr">
		<text>For better or worse, this sausage - a mix of chicken and soy substitute - is often a stalker’s breakfast, lunch and dinner in one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_beer">
		<text>Ukrainian Beer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_beer_descr">
		<text>Ukrainian beer. Another – beside vodka – popular beverage in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_beans">
		<text>Baked beans</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_beans_derscr">
		<text>Canned baked beans brought from the West. The kidney beans with tomato sauce may bring back nice memories for some people.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_chocolate">
		<text>Russian Chocolate</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_chocolate_derscr">
		<text>Russian chocolate. Very rare in the Zone and quite valuable even though its taste is nothing special. Brings back many fond childhood memories, which may help soothe the pain of living in the harsh and unforgiving conditions of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_raisins">
		<text>Raisins</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_raisins_derscr">
		<text>A pack of raisins. Rich and instant nutrition source, balances sugar in the blood.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mineral_water">
		<text>Sparkling Water</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mineral_water_derscr">
		<text>Sparkling water for thirsty Stalkers, it has some exhilarating effect when you're tired.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_medkit">
		<text>First-aid kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_descr">
		<text>Basic medical kit. Handy for treating various injuries - wounds, burns, poisoning and others.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_army">
		<text>Army medkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_army_descr">
		<text>A specialized medical kit for dealing with physical injuries and bleeding. Packed full of blood coagulants, painkillers, antibiotics and immunostimulants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_science">
		<text>Scientific medical set</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_science_descr">
		<text>A medical kit designed specifically for use in the Zone. The kit contains products for handling wounds, as well as expelling radionucleoids from the body. Prevents the development of radiation sickness and lowers the existing radiation dose.</text>
	</string>

<string id="st_corn">
<text> Can of Cream Style Corn</text>
</string>
<string id="st_corn_descr">
<text>Can of cream corn. Originally made in the Midwestern United States, cans of this soupy like mixture have found their way around the word. Cheap and filling, a can of Corn can last virtually forever and is immune to radiation.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_weed">
<text> Marijuana</text>
</string>
<string id="st_weed_descr">
<text>Marijuana is often used for its healing and psychoactive properties in the zone. Though not as good dedicated anti-rads and medkits, it is plentiful and cheap.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_vodka">
<text>Nemiroff Pepper Vodka</text>
</string>
<string id="st_vodka_descr">
<text>Orangish gold hue. Oily flax, slightly burnt and waxy apple aromas with a faint hint of citrus zest. A soft round entry leads to a dryish medium-bodied palate with vegetable oil, straw, and white pepper flavors. Finishes with a flax, sweet pumpkin spice, and hot pepper fade. A traditional and rustic flavored vodka.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_sausage">
<text>Sausage</text>
</string>
<string id="st_sausage_descr">
<text>Ground up meat stuffed into a tube and smoked. Its a filling meal, even if its origins are unknown.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_tomato">
<text>Canned Tomatoes</text>
</string>

<string id="st_tomato_descr">
<text>Canned Tomatoes are the only fresh vegetables available in the zone. Like other canned items, the tomatoes are immune to radiation and last for decades.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ration_ru">
		
<text>Russian IRP-B combat ration</text>
	
</string>
	
<string id="st_ration_ru_desc">
		
<text>Breakfast, dinner and supper all in one package. Comes with a polymeric box and is capable of curing all hunger.</text>
	
</string>
	
<string id="st_ration_ukr">
		
<text>Ukrainian combat ration</text>
	
</string>
<string id="st_ration_ukr_desc">
		
<text>The Ukrainian combat ration is based on a previous Russian version, consisting of commercially available cans and dried food items packed together in a sectioned box (resembles a takeout tray) made of very thin green plastic. Capable of curing all hunger.</text>
	
</string>
<string id="st_beans">
<text>Baked beans</text>
</string>
<string id="st_beans_descr">
<text>Canned baked beans brought from the West. The kidney beans with tomato sauce may bring back nice memories for some people.
</text>
</string>
<string id="st_beer">
<text>Ukrainian Beer</text>
</string>
<string id="st_beer_descr">
<text>Ukrainian beer. Another – beside vodka – popular beverage in the Zone.
</text>
</string>
<string id="st_chocolate">
<text>Russian Chocolate</text>
</string>
<string id="st_chocolate_descr">
<text>Russian chocolate. Very rare in the Zone and quite valuable even though its taste is nothing special. Brings back many fond childhood memories, which may help soothe the pain of living in the harsh and unforgiving conditions of the Zone.
</text>
</string>
<string id="st_raisins">
<text>Raisins</text>
</string>
<string id="st_raisins_descr">
<text> pack of raisins. Rich and instant nutrition source, balances sugar in the blood.
</text>
</string>
<string id="st_mineral_water">
<text>Mineral water</text>
</string>
<string id="st_mineral_water_descr">
<text>Mineral water from Ukrainian springs. Carbohydrated and with additional calcium.
</text>
</string>


	<string id="st_bandage">
		<text>Bandage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bandage_descr">
		<text>Bandaging material. Helps stop bleeding.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_energy_drink">
		<text>Energy drink</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_energy_drink_descr">
		<text>Often used by stalkers on long trips when no breaks can be afforded. The drink contains easily digestible carbohydrates, as well as drugs that stimulate the release of adrenaline into the blood.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector1">
		<text>“Echo” detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector1_descr">
		<text>This anomalous activity detector, with a built-in Geiger counter, produces an alarm signal when you approach an anomaly. It can also register the presence of artifacts and measure the distance to the nearest one. When closed, the device registers only radiation and anomalies. To switch to artifact search mode, raise the device’s front cover (antennae).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector2">
		<text>“Bear” detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector2_descr">
		<text>This anomalous activity detector, with a built-in Geiger counter, can also be used to locate artifacts. In addition to measuring the distance to an artifact, it can indicate its direction as well. When closed, the device registers only radiation and anomalies. To switch to artifact search mode, raise the device’s front cover (antennae).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector3">
		<text>“Veles” detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector3_descr">
		<text>A next generation detection scanner designed specifically for locating artifacts. Artifacts are shown on a special display, which makes them easier to find. The device comes with a Geiger counter and can be used to detect anomalies. When closed, the device registers only radiation and anomalies. To switch to artifact search mode, raise the front LED display.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cordon_case">
		<text>Silver case</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cordon_case_descr">
		<text>A small code-locked case. Contains very valuable information about trusted traders to offload artifacts to.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_fang_pda">
		<text>Fang’s PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_fang_pda_descr">
		<text>A pocket PC. Used in the Zone as a notebook, a navigation and communication device, and a voice recorder. Each PDA has a unique ID which allows it to be tracked.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_shukin_pda">
		<text>Lingov’s PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_shukin_pda_descr">
		<text>A pocket PC. Used in the Zone as a notebook, a navigation and communication device, and as a voice recorder. Each PDA has a unique ID which allows it to be tracked.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_recorder">
		<text>Dictation device</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cooler_docs">
		<text>Description of the cooling station</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cooler_docs_descr">
		<text>The folder contains a detailed description and troubleshooting instructions for a stationary cooling station, located on the factory’s premises.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_compass">
		<text>“Compass”</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_compass_descr">
		<text>A rare artifact - it’s been several years since one was found. The artifact can locate gaps in anomaly fields, effectively acting as a compass. It is believed that it can help one traverse the most complex anomaly fields completely unharmed. However, very few know how to handle it properly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_guitar_descr">
		<text>Seven-string guitar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_guitar_name">
		<text>Guitar</text>
	</string>

<!-- AMK Sleeping Bag start -->

	<string id="st_sleepingbag">
		<text>Sleeping bag</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sleepingbag_descr">
		<text>A portable sleeping bag.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_sleepingpills">
		<text>Sleeping Pills</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sleepingpills_descr">
		<text>Pills to make you instantly tired.</text>
	</string>

<!-- AMK Sleeping Bag end -->
<string id="mutant_flesh_eye_description">
		<text>The mutated, swollen eye of the Flesh acquired a number of strange characteristics, the most useful of which is the ability to regenerate the lens. The specifics of the process are hitherto unknown, although such discovery would most certainly revolutionize modern medicine. You can play your part in scientific development by selling Flesh eyes to scientists for their experiments.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_flesh_eye_description">
		<text>The mutated swollen eye of the Flesh-Mutant has gained some strange abilities. The most useful ist the ability to regenerate the lens itself. The precise process of this regeneration is still unknown, but if this was exposed, it would revolutionize the modern medicine for sure. You can help advancing medicin by selling them to scientists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_boar_leg_description">
		<text>Hoofs of Boars can be used for various medicins, for example antiradation serums. The cells of the outer skin layer regenerates so fast, that to a certain extent, it can not be harmed by radiation. If there still should get some radiation through, for example through an injury, then the radiation will be neutralised by the fat layer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_dog_tail_description">
		<text>The resitance of the mutated skin of Dogs in the zone agains electricity and chemical substances has been an interesst for sience for a very long time. This tail is almost free of fat and therefore particularly suitable for science purposes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_cat_tail_description">
		<text>The resitance of the mutated skin of Dogs in the zone agains electricity and chemical substances has been an interesst for sience for a very long time. This tail is almost free of fat and therefore particularly suitable for science purposes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_psevdodog_tail_description">
		<text>The resitance of the mutated skin of Dogs in the zone agains electricity and chemical substances has been an interesst for sience for a very long time. This tail inhabits viruses which make it even more resistant. Its characteristics have a resemblance to the rabies virus, which could be a reason for the hightened "trustiness". This tail is almost free of fat and therefore particularly suitable for science purposes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_krovosos_jaw_description">
		<text>The jaw of the Bloodsucker has a special gland, which produces an enzyme, that can dissolve skin and stops coagulation of blood. It would be a milestone to decypher the composition of this enzyme, but due to the dangerous donor of this medical importance, the progress is very slow.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_burer_hand_description">
		<text>Burers hands have multiple abilities, the most important is the hightend radiation resistance. It's still unknown how this happens to be exactly, but mayby you can change that by selling these to scientists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_zombie_hand_description">
		<text>The abilities of Zombies are still beeing explored. Until now, nobody could find something of mature importance, but you can support the scientists by selling the hands of Zombies in the interesst of science.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_snork_leg_description">
		<text>The feet of Snorks have multiple elastic tendons. This explains the unbelievable big jumps of this creatures. Scientists still seek for usefull possibility to use them, they would be thankful for every help they get.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_hand_kontroler_description">
		<text>Only very few survive the attack of a controller and still are in a condition to cut off one of its hands. Besides, there are few controllers to find in the zone, which makes the hands of a controller even more valuable for scientists. Until now it is only known, that controllers use their hand to enforce their psi abilities, put not why and how. Not only that, until now they didn't even find a real use for this hands, maybe they are just seeking for answers on the wrong place, even if the potential is great.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_face_tushkano_description">
		<text>Until now there is no special ability to be known of this mutants. The only difference to its relatives is its hightend bloodlust and better senses. However scientists try to find the origin of this mutation for a very long time. Help science find an answer to this most important mystery.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_poltergeist_glas_description">
		<text>The eyes of this mutant are desired because of the rareness and the special abilities of the Poltergeist. Many scientists think, that they could get the best results out of the eyes to transfer a Poltergeists abilites to another material. There are rumors that a scientist once managed to make his suit unvisible by using high ammounts of eyes. Shortly after he dissapeared. His collegues are told to have heard him scream, when he tried it on, then he dissapeared in an electric discharge. They believe that he changed to a such a creature himself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_psevdogigant_hand_description">
		<text>Its not only wanted as trophy by experienced stalkers, but also valuable for science. Pseudogiants produce their shockwaves that damage everything in reach. Scientists are trying for a very long time to use them for an impulse weapon, but because of the enormouse pressure on the "volunteers" every experiment ended with at least a ripped of arm.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_chimera_kogot_description">
		<text>The most dangerous part of Chimeras are still its two brains and its double organs which are moreover regenerating fast. Not to forget their unbelievable speed and hunting instincts. However, really interessting are simply its claws which are almost as hard as diamonds, but still biological. Through decyphering its components, it would be possible to produce a cheap but maybe ultimative armor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_csky_descr">
		<text>Patch of a member of Clear Sky. All patchs can be traded in for money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_csky_patch">
		<text>Clear Sky Patch</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_freedom_descr">
		<text>Patch of a member of Freedom. All patchs can be traded in for money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_freedom_patch">
		<text>Freedom Patch</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loner_descr">
		<text>Patch of a Loner Stalker. All patchs can be traded in for money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_loner_patch">
		<text>Loner Patch</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bandit_descr">
		<text>Patch of a Bandit. All patchs can be traded in for money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bandit_patch">
		<text>Bandit Patch</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dolg_descr">
		<text>Patch of a member of Duty. All patchs can be traded in for money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dolg_patch">
		<text>Duty Patch</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_army_descr">
		<text>Patch of a member of the Ukranian Military. All patchs can be traded in for money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_army_patch">
		<text>Army Patch</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_merc_descr">
		<text>Patch of a Mercenary. All patchs can be traded in for money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_merc_patch">
		<text>Mercenary Patch</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_renegade_descr">
		<text>Patch of a Renegade Stalker. All patchs can be traded in for money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_renegade_patch">
		<text>Renegade Patch</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_backpack">
		<text>Backpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_backpack_descr">
		<text>A sturdy military backpack equipped with a GPS tracker. You can leave it anywhare and be sure that your items will be safe from any harmful substances. Unfortunately, the backpack cannot protect your belongings from any potential looters, so keep in mind that leaving it in plain sight might not be the best thing to do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_backpack_take">
		<text>Take stash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_backpack_take_descr">
		<text>Unpack your stash and take it with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_player_stash">
		<text>Your stash</text>
	</string>
<!-- Added Helmets-->
	<string id="st_helmet_bubble">
		<text>Screen helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helmet_bubble_descr">
		<text>A light helmet with an airtight visor intended for protection from anomalies. Judging by the design, the helmet is made by the same Defense Research Institutes as the SEVA bodysuit. Its intended use may very well be in combination with military suits for operations in highly anomalous areas.\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Radiation Protection: %c[255,1,128,54]+10\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Chemical Protection: %c[255,1,128,54]+19\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Psychic Protection: %c[255,1,128,54]+14\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Bullet Protection: %c[255,1,128,54]+10%</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helmet_respirator">
		<text>E0-19 PBF Gas mask</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helmet_respirator_descr">
		<text>A Russian made regular plastic and rubber gas mask, used for filtering air for radioactive particles and poisonous substances. Widely used by rookies and veterans of all factions due to its universal functionality and availability. Does not provide any physical protection.\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Radiation Protection: %c[255,1,128,54]+5\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Chemical Protection: %c[255,1,128,54]+12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helmet_respirator2">
		<text>AM40 Gas mask</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helmet_respirator2_descr">
		<text>A Western designed and made plastic and rubber gas mask, used for filtering air for radioactive particles and poisonous substances. This design isn't widely used by most Stalkers due to its rarity, with the exception being the Mercenaries. It comes with a first generation night vision device. It does not provide any physical protection.\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Radiation Protection: %c[255,1,128,54]+5\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Chemical Protection: %c[255,1,128,54]+12\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Nightvision Device: %c[255,1,128,54]1st Generation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helmet_sphere08">
		<text>Sphere 08 helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helmet_sphere08_descr">
		<text>This helmet is the standard issue helmet of the regular Military Services deployed to the Zone. The helmet is designed to provide a squad leader with strategic superiority over the enemy via its many scanners and satellite communications devices, most which have not been installed in this particular helmet. Comes with multi-layered Kevlar protection and armored elements to protect electronic components. Includes a respirator and a second generation night vision device.\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Radiation Protection: %c[255,1,128,54]+7\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Chemical Protection: %c[255,1,128,54]+14\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Psychic Protection: %c[255,1,128,54]+8\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Bullet Protection: %c[255,1,128,54]+35%\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Nightvision Device: %c[255,1,128,54]2nd Generation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helmet_sphere12">
		<text>Sphere 12M helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helmet_sphere12_descr">
		<text>An aluminum/titanium helmet with a cloth exterior that comes with pockets for additional steel armor pieces and an armor face mask. The Sphere 12M is normally used as part of a combination that includes PSZ series Spetsnaz body armor. Quite popular in the Zone thanks to its respirator and built-in second generation night vision device, as well as providing the maximum head protection possible.\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Radiation Protection: %c[255,1,128,54]+7\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Chemical Protection: %c[255,1,128,54]+15\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Psychic Protection: %c[255,1,128,54]+8\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Bullet Protection: %c[255,1,128,54]+40%\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Nightvision Device: %c[255,1,128,54]2nd Generation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helmet_steel">
		<text>Steel helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helmet_steel_descr">
		<text>A desperately outdated steel army helmet that comes with an eye shield and first generation night vision device. Provides no protection against anomalies or radiation, but can deflect bullets. This helmet was never particularly popular in the Zone, except for use in brief armed conflicts between factions by Stalkers who couldn't afford better helmets.\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Bullet Protection: %c[255,1,128,54]+20%\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Nightvision Device: %c[255,1,128,54]1st Generation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mag_info">
		<text complex_mode="1" vert_align="l">Ammo List:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_amk_metka">
		<text>A GPS locator used to tag stashes for future retrieval.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="amk_metka">
		<text complex_mode="1" vert_align="l">GPS Locator Tag</text>
	</string>
</string_table>