<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="bandit_outfit_description">
		<text>Traditional bandit clothing - a leather jacket with armor pieces sewed in. The protection it provides is completely inadequate for the harsh conditions of the Zone. Does not hold any artifacts by default, but can be upgraded to hold one artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_outfit_name">
		<text>Bandit jacket</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_medium_description">
		<text>The "Panther" suit is the favorite dressing of those veteran Stalkers who made the choice to put their morality and friendship aside 
when entering the Zone. Often coming with a black coat and a tissue mask, mostly used as a mean to hide the owner's face, the bodysuit itself consists in a 
strong bulletproof, able of stopping all conventional kind of damages (bullets, projectiles, claws...), but extremely deceiving in anomalies, radiation and 
telepathy protection. Includes an operational night vision device, but requires few upgrades in order to receive the precious artifacts true bandits are all 
after.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_medium_name">
		<text>"Panther" suit"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_exo_outfit_description">
	<text>Used by only the most experienced bandits, this Exoskeleton offers less protection then other models. However, it is much lighter then other 
models and allows the wearer to sprint. Comes with no artifact containers, however it can be upgraded to hold three.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Bandit Exoskeleton</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_outfit_description">
		<text>A modernized version of the Duty protective suit, which provides good anomaly protection unlike the PSZ series suits. The built-in body armor is capable of stopping a pistol round. Does not hold any artifacts by default, but can be upgraded to hold up to two artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_outfit_name">
		<text>PS5-M “Universal Protection”</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_outfit_description">
		<text>An experimental sample of a military exoskeleton. Was never mass-produced due to the extreme cost and some design flaws. Small batches are nonetheless produced in underground facilities outside Ukraine. This is a third-generation exoskeleton, which corrects the mobility-impeding design flaws of previous versions and features stronger armor. Includes a container capable of holding one artifact, and can be upgraded to hold up to three artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_outfit_description">
		<text>The Bulat military armored suit is designed for assault operations in highly anomalous areas. Comprises a heavy military armored suit, a built-in compensation suit, and the Sphere-12M helmet. The suit’s armor is capable of stopping an assault rifle round. Does not hold any artifacts by default, but can be upgraded to hold up to two artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_outfit_name">
		<text>“Bulat” armored suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mp_exo_outfit_description">
		<text>This exoskeleton provides excellent protection against bullet and fragmentation damage at the cost of mobility. Vulnerable to armor-piercing rounds. Includes a container capable of holding one artifact, and can be upgraded to hold up to three artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mp_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mp_military_outfit_description">
		<text>This military armored suit is designed for assault operations. Provides outstanding protection against bullet and fragmentation damage without impeding mobility. Vulnerable to armor-piercing rounds. Does not hold any artifacts by default, but can be upgraded to hold up to two artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mp_military_outfit_name">
		<text>Military armored suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mp_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>This bodysuit is designed for research operations in the Zone. Comes with a closed-cycle respiratory module and a built-in anomaly field suppression system, which provides outstanding protection from anomalies. Extremely vulnerable due to low shield value. Includes a container that can hold up to two artifacts, and can be upgraded to hold up to a maximum of five artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mp_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>Scientific bodysuit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>This suit, produced by one of Kiev’s Research Institutes, provides a great alternative to other homemade stalker suits. It is a fine combination of an armored bodysuit, a closed-cycle respiratory module and an anomaly field suppression system. That, plus well-chosen materials, makes this suit a fine choice, with the price being the only drawback. Includes a container that can hold up to two artifacts, and can be upgraded to hold up to a maximum of five artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>SEVA suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="specops_outfit_description">
		<text>The Berill-5M is a Spetsnaz bodysuit, modified for use in the Zone. The suit includes PSZ-9a series military body armor with beryllium sputter and a Sphere-08 helmet. Designed for assault operations in extremely radioactive regions, it is ineffective in areas of high anomalous activity. Does not hold any artifacts by default, but can be upgraded to hold up to two artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="specops_outfit_name">
		<text>“Berill-5M” armored suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_outfit_description">
		<text>Made and manufactured by “do-it-yourselfers,” this stalker suit effectively combines light military body armor and a bodysuit of rubberized cloth. Despite the fact that the body armor is incapable of protecting the wearer from even pistol rounds, the suit enjoys great popularity due to its low cost and modification potential. Includes a container that can hold up to two artifacts, and can be upgraded to hold up to a maximum of five artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_outfit_name">
		<text>“Sunrise” suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>A reinforced stalker bodysuit made by Freedom craftsmen. Its standard military body armor in combination with plated zirconium elements yields good protection against submachine gun and assault rifle rounds and fragmentation damage at all distances. The suit’s dual-layered material combines specially treated leather with a fabric that contains asbestos yarn. The suit offers limited protection against various anomalies and radiation. Includes a container that can hold up to two artifacts, and can be upgraded to hold a third artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>“Guardian of Freedom” suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_light_outfit_description">
		<text>This lightweight stalker bodysuit is made by Freedom craftsmen. Its light military body armor is reinforced with Kevlar plating to offer protection from small arms fire. The suit’s fabric is treated with a special solution, which increases its resistance to anomalies. Includes a container capable of holding up to two artifacts, and can be upgraded to hold a third artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_light_outfit_name">
		<text>“Wind of Freedom” suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>This suit, produced by one of Kiev’s Research Institutes, provides a great alternative to other homemade stalker suits. It is a fine combination of an armored bodysuit, a closed-cycle respiratory module and an anomaly field suppression system. That, plus well-chosen materials, makes this suit a fine choice, with the price being the only drawback. Like all freedom armor, it has been lightened at the expense of protection. Includes a container that can hold up to two artifacts, and can be upgraded to hold up to a maximum of five artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>Freedom SEVA body armor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>Standard equipment used by Clear Sky assault squads. This body armor is able to stop a pistol bullet, while its integrated gas mask provides good protection from anomalous exposure. Includes a container capable of holding one artifact, and can be upgraded to hold up to three artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>CS-1 body armor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky_light_outfit_description">
		<text>This body armor was designed for conducting search operations in areas of low anomalous activity. Its higher quality materials result in greater durability. Includes a container capable of holding one artifact, and can be upgraded to hold up to three artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky_light_outfit_name">
		<text>CS-3a body armor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>An early Duty suit model. Became known for its built-in body armor and virtually no protection from anomalous exposure. Does not hold any artifacts by default, but can be upgraded to hold up to two artifacts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="cs_medium_outfit_description">
		<text>The CS-2s is designed for operations in areas with high anomalous and radioactive activity. Its higher quality materials result in 
greater durability. Comes equipped with two artifact containers and can up upgraded to five.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cs_medium_outfit_name">
		<text>CS-2s Medium body armor</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolg_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>PSZ-9d “Duty Armor”</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolgscientific_outfit_description">
		<text>The PSZ-9Md is a wonderful protective suit for the Zone, popular among Duty veterans. It combines excellent anomaly protection 
(thanks to the Curtain helmet with an integrated life support system and an anomaly suppression device) and a high quality PSZ-9d Duty suit, which grants 
quality protection from bullets, shrapnel and animal claws.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolgscientific_outfit_name">
		<text>PsZ-9MD Universal Protection</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolgexo_outfit_description">
		<text>An experimental sample of a military exoskeleton. Was never mass-produced due to the extreme cost and some design flaws. 
Small batches are nonetheless produced in underground facilities outside Ukraine. This is a third-generation exoskeleton, which corrects the mobility-
impeding design flaws of previous versions and features stronger armor. Duty has further modified these suits, they have greater protection at the expense of 
weight and speed.Includes a container capable of holding one artifact, and can be upgraded to hold up to three artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolgexo_outfit_name">
		<text>Duty Exoskeleton </text>
	</string>

<string id="exo_freedom_outfit_description">
		<text>An upgraded version of a regular exoskeleton. The use of lighter materials allowed the designers to reduce the suit’s weight and 
boost its durability. Includes a container capable of holding up to two artifacts, and can be upgraded to hold a third artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_freedom_outfit_name">
		<text>“Freedom” exoskeleton</text>
	</string>


	<string id="novice_outfit_description">
		<text>Common garb of a novice stalker. It won’t save you from bullets or anomalies, but it’s still better than nothing. Does not hold any artifacts by default, but can be upgraded to hold up to two artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="novice_outfit_name">
		<text>Leather jacket</text>
	</string>

	<string id="monolith_outfit_description">
	<text>Created by an unknown manufacturer, this suit consists of a splinter pattern urban camouflage radiation suit/battledress uniform with arm, 
elbow and knee pads of reinforced leather, a green tactical vest with carrying pouches and a mounting place for either two oxygen tanks, a backpack or a 
closed-circuit Curtain helmet life support system. The vest's protection is slightly worse than that of a PSZ-7a military bulletproof vest. Includes a container 
capable of holding up to two artifacts, and can be upgraded to hold a third artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolith_outfit_name">
		<text>Monolith Outfit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="monolit_heavy_outfit_description">
	<text>The suit is the pinnacle of personal protection technology. It is composed of three elements - a tactical helmet, a heavy armoured vest and reinforced jumpsuit. The tactical helmet encloses the entire head, covering the cranium with a thick armoured helmet, the face with a specially made gas mask with external filters and a cloth cowl covering the neck and ears. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolit_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>Monolith Heavy Outfit</text>
	</string>

</string_table>