<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 additional items, fixed typos, added 135 items, corrected text and strings aleks1970, det_art_super -->
<!-- Text editing as commented below - Sword2012 - 16 Oct 16 -->
<!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->
<!--;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;FOOD AND PROVISIONS;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;-->
	<string_table>
		<string id="medic_overdose">
			<text>Das war eine Überdosis!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="medic_several">
			<text>Kann nicht gleichzeitig mehrere Medikamente zu verwenden!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="medic_can_overdose">
			<text>Medikament kann nicht oft verwendet werden. Es besteht das Risiko einer Überdosis!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="medic_not_finished">
			<text>Die Erste Medizinische Behandlung ist noch nicht abgeschlossen!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="pivo">
			<text>Tschernigow Bier</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_pivo">
			<text>Keine Ahnung wer dieses Bier in die Zone gebracht hat, aber es wurde schnell zum Lieblings Bier unter den Stalkern ... Jetzt kann es bei praktisch bei jedem Händler in der Zone gefunden und gekauft werden.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="irp-b">
			<text>Militärische Rationen</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_irp-b">
			<text>Einmannpackung und Verpflegungsset. Speziell für das Militärpersonal das in der Zone den Dienst leistet. Mit der Zeit wurden die IRP-B Packungen unter Hand in der Zone hier und da verkauft. Es existieren verschieden Typen\n \nTyp I:\nFertiggericht 1: Ravioli mit Champignonsauce 300 g\nFertiggericht 2: Indische Reispfanne 300 g\nZwischenmahlzeit: Grießspeise mit Früchten 150 g\n \nTyp II:\nFertiggericht 1: Gulasch mit Kartoffeln 300 g\nFertiggericht 2a: Cevapcici mit Reis und Gemüse 300 g\nFertiggericht 2b: Ravioli in Champignonsoße 300 g\nZwischenmahlzeit: Obstsalat 150 g\n \nTyp III:\nFertiggericht 1: Hamburger in Tomatensauce 300 g\nFertiggericht 2: Südamerikanisches Gemüsechilli 300 g\nZwischenmahlzeit: Grießbrei mit Obst 150 gTyp IV:\nFertiggericht 1: Linseneintopf mit Mettwurst\nFertiggericht 2: Spiralnudeln in Hackfleischsoße\n \nTyp V:\nFertiggericht 1: Tortellini mit Schweinefleischfüllung in Tomatensauce\nFertiggericht 2: Reis mit Putenfleisch, Tintenfischringen und Garnelen\nZwischenmahlzeit: Obstsalat 150 g\n \nInklusive: Erfrischungstuch und "Panzerkekse"\n \nFür jeden STALKER ein Traum ... obwohl teuer</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mechta">
			<text>Packung(en) "Dream" Zigaretten</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_mechta">
			<text>Ein Stinknormale Zigarette wie sie die Tabak Industrie herstellt. Stalker gaben der Zigarette schon verschiedenen Namen:  "Märchen aus Wiener Holz", "Großmutters Kohle".</text>
		</string>
		<string id="voda">
			<text>"Kristall" Mineral-Wasser</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_voda">
			<text>Mineralwasser der Marke "Kristall". Stillt Perfekt den Durst und verbessert das allgemeine Wohlbefinden. Stellt auch Energie wieder her so dass man sich frische und erholt fühlt.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tuchenka">
			<text>Fleisch Konserven</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_tuchenka">
			<text>Fleisch Konserven vom "Armeelager". Stalker überfallen die "Armeelager" hin und wieder. Die erbeuteten Konserven werden dann beim nächsten Händler verkauft. Info: Das Haltbarkeit ist noch nicht abgelaufen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sardina">
			<text>Ölsardinen</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_sardina">
			<text>Ölsardinen sind in zum größten Teil in der Welt sehr beliebt. Einige Regionen bevorzugen jedoch die frische Alternative.  Es gibt verschiedene Methoden der herstellung.\n \nDie pazifische Sardine wird etwa 35 cm lang und normalerweise in Stücken eingelegt, im Gegensatz zur atlantischen Sardine, die nur etwa fingerlang ist und daher meist im Ganzen verarbeitet wird. Entsprechend denken Europäer bei „Ölsardinen“ auch an etwas ganz anderes als Amerikaner. Die Sardinen können auch enthäutet oder entgrätet werden und in mit Kräutern zubereitetem Öl eingelegt werden. Neben der klassischen Ölsardine sind auch andere Sorten, wie z. B. in Tomatensoße oder mit eingelegten Zitronenscheiben, im Handel verfügbar.\n \nZur Konservierung werden die Sardinen gekocht (bzw. gedämpft, gedünstet), kommen mit dem Öl in die Dosen, diese werden luftdicht verschlossen und anschließend in einem Autoklaven auf über 100 °C erhitzt. Dadurch wird der Inhalt sterilisiert und somit haltbar gemacht.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sholad">
			<text>Bitterschokolade</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_sholad">
			<text>Bitterschokolade ist Schokolade mit hohen Kakaoanteil. Andere Bezeichnungen sind "Herrenschokolade", "Edelbitterschokolade", "Zartbitterschokolade", "dunkle" oder "schwarze Schokolade".\n \nDiese Schokoladensorte schmeckt leicht bitter und ist dunkler und zumeist weniger süß als Milchschokolade und wird – im Unterschied zu Milchschokolade – in der Regel ohne Milch oder seltener mit nur geringem Milchanteil hergestellt. Der Kakaoanteil ist deutlich höher als bei anderen Sorten und somit in der Regel auch der Fettanteil. Je höher der Kakaoanteil der Bitterschokolade, desto herber und weniger süß ist der Geschmack.\n \nEinige Studien kommen zu dem Ergebnis, dass der Verzehr von Bitterschokolade aufgrund ihres hohen Gehalts von Flavonoiden wie Epicatechin das Herz-Kreislauf-System schützt. Darüber hinaus senkt der Konsum von dunkler Schokolade den Blutdruck.\n \nDie Studie In der Zone kommt zu dem Entschluss das die Schokolade sehr viele Antioxidantien beinhaltet und somit die Bildung der Radioaktiven Isotopen im Körper auflöst. Sehr weit verbreitet in der Zone.\n \nNach einer amerikanischen Studie, die von 1996 bis 2000 an 2291 Schwangeren durchgeführt wurde, kann der Genuss von Bitterschokolade das Risiko von Präeklampsie bei Schwangeren senken. Die Anzahl der Frauen mit entsprechenden Symptomen war dabei direkt negativ abhängig vom Spiegel des in der Schokolade enthaltenen Alkaloids Theobromin im Serum</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ogursi">
			<text>Marinierte Essiggurken</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_ogursi">
			<text>Es wird empfohlen die Gurken zusammen mit einem Wodka zu Genießen. Diese eingelegte Gemüse Kamm mal mit eine Zeit lang mit einer Lieferwagen Kolone in die Zone. Um die Lebensmittelgeschäfte in Pripyat und den umliegenden Stadtbereichen zu versorgen. Wurden jedoch oft Überfallen. Sole reduziert die Wirkung eines Katers ganz schön.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yantar">
			<text>(Amber) Yantar Schmelzkäse </text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_yantar">
			<text>Amber war tatsächlich ein preisgünstiger russischer Wettbewerber für den Schmelzkäse, der in den 50er Jahren von der finnischen Firma Valio Ltd. auf den sowjetischen Markt eingeführt wurde. Er wurde nach der lokalen Legende von der experimentellen und wissenschaftlichen Abteilung der Fabrik hergestellt.\n \nZum:\n"Binden der Freundschaft zwischen allen Völkern der Sowjetunion und der Welt."</text>
		</string>
		<string id="nuts">
			<text>Studenten Futter</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_nuts_descr">
			<text>Studentenfutter ("Pfaffenfutter" oder "Tutti frutti" ist der Ausdruck für ein Gemisch aus ursprünglich (im 17. Jahrhundert) Mandeln und Rosinen. Studenten sprachen diesen Zutaten Eigenschaften zu, die gegen einen Alkoholrausch wirksam sind. Auch anderes Trockenobst kann zugefügt werden, der Phantasie sind hier keine Grenzen gesetzt. Zu bedenken ist jedoch, dass viele Zutaten recht kalorienreich, wenn auch gesund sind. Beispielsweise werden ungesalzene "Nüsse" zugefügt, darunter Cashewkerne, Erdnüsse, Paranüsse, Walnüsse oder Haselnüsse. Wenn die Nüsse ungesalzen und unbehandelt sind, sind sie sehr gesund, denn sie enthalten für die Verdauung wichtige Mineral- und Ballaststoffe. Das Risiko von Herz-, Gefäß- oder Krebserkrankungen sollen die ungesättigten Fettsäuren der Walnüsse senken. Haselnüsse enthalten sehr viel Vitamin E, das Zellen schützen soll. Das Immunsystem soll durch Selen gestärkt werden, das in Paranüssen angereichert ist.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="olives">
			<text>Oliven</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_olives_descr">
			<text>Oliven sind reich, an einfach ungesättigten Fetten, Eisen, Vitamin E und Ballaststoffen.\n \nDie Olive ist eine mediterrane Steinfrucht. Sie ist wegen ihrer Bitterkeit roh nicht genießbar, aber nach mehrmaligem Einlegen in Wasser, bei dem die Bitterstoffe ausgeschwemmt werden, essbar. Echte Schwarze Oliven sind voll ausgereifte grüne (olivgrüne) Oliven. Oft werden jedoch grüne, mit Eisengluconat schwarz gefärbte Oliven verkauft.\n \n90% der Oliven werden zu Olivenöl gepresst.\n \nIm Handel erhältlich sind Oliven auch in modifizierter Form. Üblich ist dabei die Füllung der grünen Olive (mit Paprika, Mandeln) sowie das Einlegen/Marinieren der ganzen oder entkernten Früchte.\n \nIn Öl eingelegte Oliven sind ohne weitere Konservierungsstoffe relativ lange haltbar und werden auch nicht von Schädlingen befallen, was zumindest zum Teil ihre große Bedeutung für die mediterrane Küche erklärt.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="kolbasadmx">
			<text>"Doktor's" Wurst</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_dmx_kolbasa">
			<text>Der wohlschmeckendste Geschmack der Wurst wird durch traditionelle Technik, vor allem bestehend aus hochwertigen, fettarmen, Schweinefleisch und Rindfleisch, mit dem Zusatz von Eiern, integraler Kuhmilch und einem einfachen Strich Muskatnuss produziert</text>
		</string>
		<string id="absolut_vodka">
			<text>"Absolut" Wodka</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_vodka_absolut">
			<text>Absolut Vodka ist eine im südschwedischen Ahus seit 1879 produzierte Wodka- und Spirituosenmarke. Das Unternehmen ist eine Tochter der Vin & Sprit, die 2008 von deren Eigentümer, der schwedischen Regierung, für 5,6 Milliarden Euro an die französische Firma Pernod Ricard verkauft wurde. Der Wodka der Marke wird aus Winterweizen und Wasser aus einer eigenen Quelle hergestellt.\n \nAbsolut Vodka "Blue Label", 1879 	mit 40% alc.\n \nAbsolut Vodka Red Label 1879 mit 50 % alc., Produktion wurde inzwischen eingestellt.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="nemiroff_vodka">
			<text>"Nemiroff" Wodka</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_vodka_nemiroff">
			<text>Nemiroff ist eine ukrainische Wodkamarke, die aus der Stadt Nemyriw in der Oblast Winnyzja kommt.\n \nDie Destillerie, in der Nemiroff hergestellt wird, wurde 1872 von G. S. Stroganov gegründet. Nemiroff Wodka wird ausschließlich aus Getreide hergestellt.\n \nUnter der Marke Nemiroff werden verschiedene Wodkas vertrieben. Bekannt sind Nemiroff Ukrainian Wheat (weißes Etikett), Nemiroff Original (schwarzes Etikett), und Nemyrovskaya. Wie die meisten osteuropäischen Wodkas enthalten diese Sorten 40 Volumenprozent Alkohol.\n \nNach uralter Tradition und ausschließlich aus natürlichen Zutaten hergestellt.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="smirnoff_vodka">
			<text>"Smirnoff" Wodka</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_vodka_smirnoff">
			<text>Die Wodka-Brennerei Smirnoff wurde 1886 von Pjotr Arsenjewitsch Smirnow in Moskau gegründet und war die erste Brennerei weltweit, die Holzkohle zum Filtern benutzte.\n \nWladimir Smirnow übernahm 1910 die Firma nach dem Tod seines Vaters Pjotr Smirnow. Während der Oktoberrevolution wurde die Brennerei konfisziert und die Familie musste nach Konstantinopel fliehen, wo Wladimir eine neue Brennerei aufbaute. Vier Jahre später zog die Familie nach Lemberg; 1925 wurde eine zweite Brennerei in Paris eröffnet, die lateinische Schreibweise des Namens wurde zu Smirnoff geändert. Ende der 1930er Jahre wurde der Wodka in die meisten europäischen Länder exportiert.\n \n1934 verkaufte Wladimir Smirnow die Firma an Rudolph Kunett, der den Firmensitz in die USA verlagerte.\n \nMittlerweile gehört Smirnoff zu Diageo (einen Minderheitsanteil hält Alfa Group). Im Jahr 2012 wurden weltweit 26,3 Millionen 9-Liter-Einheiten abgesetzt, was die Wodka-Marke zur meistverkauften Premium-Spirituosenmarke der westlichen Welt machte.\n \nDieser Wodka ist der meistgetrunkene Wodka der Welt. Er geht öfter über den Tresen als jeder Whisky, Gin oder Rum. Ein weicher und vollmundiger Geschmack mit einem Milden, klaren und reinen Charakter.Jeder einzelne Tropfen wird in einem kontinuierlichen Dauerlauf dreifach destilliert und anschließend zehnfach gefiltert.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mineral_water">
			<text>Mineral Wasser</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_vodka_water">
			<text>Wasser, das Mineralien oder andere gelöste Substanzen enthält, die seinen Geschmack verändern oder ihm einen "therapeutischen" Wert verleihen. Der im allgemeinen aus einer natürlich vorkommenden Mineral-quelle oder Berg-Quelle gewonnen wird. Gelöste Substanzen im Wasser können verschiedene Salze und Schwefelverbindungen einschließen. Mineralwasser gibt es als Sprudel Wasser (Selters) oder ohne Sprudel (Stilles Wasser).</text>
		</string>
		<string id="energy_stalker">
			<text>S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Drink</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_energy_st">
			<text>Kräftiges Energiegetränk mit Methylxanthinen (einschließlich Koffein), Vitamin B und Kräutern. Andere gemeinsame Zutaten sind Guarana, Acai und Taurin, sowie verschiedene Formen von Ginseng, Maltodextrin, kohlensäurehaltiges Wasser, Inositol, Carnitin, Kreatin, Glucuronolacton und Ginkgo biloba. Kann hohen Zucker Wert enthalten. Der zentrale Bestandteil ist Koffein, wie in Kaffee oder Tee vorkommt.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="energy_non_stop">
			<text>"Non-Stop" Energy Drink</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_energy_stop">
			<text>"Non Stop" enthält tonisierende Substanzen wie Koffein und andere Stimulatoren sowie einen Komplexes gemisch an reichhaltigen Vitaminen. Es stellt die Energie nach langen "Joggen" zwischen dne Anomalien wieder her</text>
		</string>
		<string id="energy_ad_rush">
			<text>Adrenalin Kick</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_energy_ad_rush">
			<text>Kräftiger Citrus Geschmack mit einer einzigartigen Mischung belebenden und energiespendenden Elementen wie D-Ribose, L-Carnitin und Taurin. Einfach gut!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="energy_red_bull">
			<text>Red Bull Energy Drink</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_energy_red_bull">
			<text>Die Idee für taurinhaltige Getränke kam aus Japan, wo sie nach dem Zweiten Weltkrieg japanischen Piloten zur Steigerung der Leistung verabreicht wurden. Aus Thailand importierte der Gründer der Red Bull GmbH, Dietrich Mateschitz, später die Idee nach Europa. Bei einem Besuch 1982 in Thailand stellte er fest, dass ein Getränk namens Krating Daeng ihm half, den Einfluss des Jetlags zu überwinden. Er übernahm Name, Marketingkonzept und die Grundrezeptur, passte diese dem westlichen Geschmack an und ging damit 1987 auf den österreichischen Markt. Ende der 1980er Jahre wurde Red Bull vor allem durch geschicktes Marketing in der alternativen Jugend- und Club-Szene (Techno, Mountainbiking, Snowboarding) erfolgreich.\n \n
Von Beginn an wurde über gesundheitliche Gefahren sowie langwierige Zulassungsverfahren für einzelne Inhaltsstoffe diskutiert. Dadurch verzögerte sich die Marktzulassung in Österreich und später in Deutschland und anderen Ländern. Mitunter wurde dies in manchen Medien als Verbot kolportiert.\n \nEs entstand wiederum ein „Hype“ um dieses für den europäischen Markt neue Getränk. In Frankreich blieb der Energy Drink tatsächlich verboten, bis Red Bull 2008 das Taurin durch Arginin ersetzte. Die französischen Behörden stützten dieses Verbot auf angebliche Gesundheitsschäden durch den übermäßigen Konsum von Red Bull. Der Europäische Gerichtshof entschied 2004, dass das französische Verkaufsverbot nicht gegen die Warenverkehrsfreiheit verstößt.\n \nÄhnliche Verbote bestanden bis Anfang 2009 in Dänemark und Norwegen. Im Mai 2008 wurde ein Abkommen zur Wiederzulassung von Red Bull mit Taurin in Frankreich unterzeichnet und seit 15. Juli 2008 ist das originale Getränk wieder erhältlich.\n \n
Red Bull hat keine eigenen Produktionsstätten, sondern lässt das Getränk bei der Firma Rauch Fruchtsäfte in Nüziders[4] (Vorarlberg) produzieren und abfüllen. Für den Export wird Red Bull nicht als Konzentrat produziert, sondern fertig in Dosen abgefüllt auch nach Übersee exportiert. Für den amerikanischen Markt wird es von Rauch in der Schweiz abgefüllt, wo ein Werk in Widnau SG errichtet wurde. Dieser Standort wurde gewählt, um bei Handelsstreitigkeiten zwischen der EU und den USA nicht betroffen zu sein.\n \n
Dietrich Mateschitz war im Jahr 1982 während einer Dienstreise in Südostasien auf die dort bereits damals weit verbreiteten Energydrinks aufmerksam geworden. Daraufhin erwarb er internationale Lizenzrechte an der thailändischen Marke Krating Daeng. Zwei Jahre später gründete Mateschitz die Red Bull GmbH mit Sitz in Fuschl am See.\n \n
Seit Anfang 2006 besaß Red Bull auch 50% des Tiroler Transportdienstleisters Berger Logistik. Im Gegenzug übernahm Gerhard Berger 50 % der Scuderia Toro Rosso. Nach Beendigung Bergers Toro-Rosso-Intermezzos am Ende der Formel-1-Saison 2008 wurden die jeweiligen Beteiligungen jedoch aufgelöst.\n \n
Im April 2008 wurde die Produktpalette durch Red Bull Cola erweitert.\n \n Am 19. Mai 2009 wurde der Verkauf von Red Bull Cola in Hessen durch die hessische Lebensmittelaufsicht untersagt, da durch das Landesinstitut für Gesundheit und Arbeit des Landes Nordrhein-Westfalen in Red Bull Cola Spuren von Kokain nachgewiesen wurden. Das Getränk falle daher unter das Betäubungsmittelgesetz. Dem Verbot folgten auch die Länder Nordrhein-Westfalen, Thüringen und Rheinland-Pfalz. Red Bull Cola sowie andere Lebensmittel, die Cocablatt­extrakte enthielten, gelten allerdings sowohl in der Europäischen Union als auch in den Vereinigten Staaten als unbedenklich und verkehrsfähig.[2][3] Nachdem bereits das Bundesinstitut für Risikobewertung die Kokainspuren als unbedenklich bewertete, wurde das Verkaufsverbot am 24. August 2009 wieder aufgehoben.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="energy_non_stop_lite">
			<text>"Non-Stop" Lite</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_energy_non_stop_lite">
			<text>Im Wesentlichen das gleiche wie "Non-Stop" Energy Drink, nur ohne  zusätzlichen Zucker ... nicht so wirksam.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sok">
			<text>Saft</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_sok">
			<text>Vollmundiger, erfrischender Saft. Auf dem Tetrapak steht  "Multi-Frucht" und enthält alle Vitamine die eine Erwachsener für ein Tag benötigt. Es genügt ein Schluck und schon hat man wieder Energie, so dass man mit dem anstrengenden Tag weiter machen kann!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="syh_pay_gde_3">
			<text>Militärische Ration GDE-3</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_food_syh_pay_gde_3">
			<text>Einmannpackung Armee-Ration (GDE-3). Hergestellt in Amerika. Schmeckt besser als die Russische Variante. Wiegt auch weniger ..ist auch etwas weniger nahrhaft.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="syh_pay_spp5">
			<text>Militärische Ration SSP5</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_food_syh_pay_spp5">
			<text>Russische Einmannpackungs-Ration (SSP5). Diese Kompakte Mahlzeit wurde für sehr harte Feldbedingungen entwickelt. Nahrhafter als die NATO Version.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="pivo_baltika">
			<text>Baltic Beer</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_pivo_baltika">
			<text>%c[255,220,220,100]Stärke            : %c[255,1,255,1]8.0%\n \n
Baltika ist die größte Brauereigruppe in der Russischen Föderation. Sie wurde 1990 in Leningrad (Sankt Petersburg) gegründet und hat sich schnell zu einem wichtigen Wirtschaftsfaktor für die Stadt entwickelt. Ursprünglich war Baltika ein Joint-Venture der finnischen Getränkefirma Hartwall und deren norwegischem Partner Orkla. Baltika nahm 1990 die Produktion auf.\n \n
Baltika ist auch in Deutschland erhältlich und findet sich meist in russischen Supermärkten oder Getränkefachmärkten. Der Sitz der Baltika Deutschland GmbH befindet sich in Hamburg. Seit August 2011 wird die Sorte Baltika 3 auch von der Brauerei Königshof in Krefeld für Baltika Deutschland hergestellt, abgefüllt und von dort im mitteleuropäischen Raum vertrieben.
</text>
		</string>
<!-- MEDICINE -->
		<string id="antiseptic">
			<text>Antiseptische Pillen</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_medi_antiseptic">
			<text>%c[255,220,220,100]Gesundheitsschub : %c[255,1,255,1]5%\n
%c[255,220,220,100]Blutung stillen  : %c[255,1,255,1]90%\n
%c[255,220,220,100]Packungs Menge   : %c[255,1,255,1]1\n
%c[255,220,220,100]Nebenwirkungen   : %c[255,1,255,1]Leichte Ermüdung\n
%c[default]\n \n
Chemisches Mittel, das das Wachstum von pathogenen Bakterien und anderen Mikroorganismen zerstört oder hemmt aber für die Haut und die Schleimhäute nicht toxisch ist. Hilft bei Blutungen, Desinfektion für Wunden und verbessert den allgemein Zustand. Das Medikament ist schnell wirkend.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="zhgut">
			<text>Schiene</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_medi_zhgut">
			<text>%c[255,220,220,100]Gesundheitsschub : %c[255,1,255,1]0%\n
%c[255,220,220,100]Blutung stillen  : %c[255,1,255,1]100%\n
%c[255,220,220,100]Packungs Menge   : %c[255,1,255,1]5\n
%c[255,220,220,100]Nebenwirkungen   : %c[255,1,255,1]n/a\n
%c[default]\n \nVerschiedene Formen der Schiene wurden sparsam im Laufe der Geschichte verwendet, aber die Schiene gewann große Popularität als medizinisches Gerät während des französischen und indischen Krieges. Im allgemeinen bestehend aus zwei kleinen hölzernen Planken wurde die Schiene gewöhnlich um den Bruch mit Seil, Tuch oder sogar Rohleder während Grenzzeiten in der amerikanischen Geschichte gebunden. Bis zum heutigen Tag wird die Schiene häufig verwendet, um kleine Brüche und Brüche zu sichern.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="pervitin">
			<text>"Pervitin" (Methamphetamin)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_medi_pervitin">
			<text>%c[255,220,220,100]Erhöhte Ausdauer : %c[255,1,255,1]190%\n
%c[255,220,220,100]Reduziert. Hunger: %c[255,1,255,1]50%\n
%c[255,220,220,100]Packungs Menge   : %c[255,1,255,1]2 Tabletten\n
%c[255,220,220,100]Nebenwirkungen   : %c[255,1,255,1]Allgemeiner Zustand\n
%c[default]\n \nMethamphetamin, auch Metamfetamin oder N-Methylamphetamin (früher auch Pervitin) genannt, ist eine synthetisch hergestellte Substanz aus der Stoffgruppe der Phenylethylamine. Methamphetamin wird sowohl in der Pharmazie als Arzneistoff als auch missbräuchlich als euphorisierende und stimulierende Droge (umgangssprachlich Crystal Meth, Meth oder Crystal) verwendet.\n \nN-Methylamphetamin unterdrückt Müdigkeit, Hungergefühl und Schmerz. Es verleiht kurzzeitig Selbstvertrauen, ein Gefühl der Stärke und dem Leben eine ungewohnte Geschwindigkeit. Zu den Nebenwirkungen gehören Persönlichkeitsveränderungen, Psychosen und Paranoia aufgrund von Schlafentzug oder bei Prädisposition. Eine häufige Einnahme führt zu Gewöhnung und schleichendem Wirkungsverlust, der oft eine Dosissteigerung zur Erzielung der ursprünglichen Wirkung nach sich zieht.\n \nMethamphetamin gehört zur Substanzklasse der Amphetamine, der etliche weitere psychotrope Substanzen angehören, unter anderem Amphetamin und das in der Natur vorkommende Ephedrin. Es ist ein Stimulans und indirektes Sympathomimetikum, d. h., es regt die sympathischen Teile des vegetativen Nervensystems an.\n \nHerstellung, Besitz oder Inverkehrbringen von Methamphetamin ohne Erlaubnis ist in Deutschland und den meisten europäischen Ländern strafbar. In den USA fällt die Substanz seit 1970 unter das Drogenkontrollgesetz.\n \nInsbesondere während der Blitzkriege gegen Polen und Frankreich 1939/40 fand Methamphetamin millionenfache Verwendung. Unter den Spitznamen Panzerschokolade, Stuka-Tabletten, Hermann-Göring-Pillen und Fliegermarzipan diente das Mittel zur Dämpfung des Angstgefühls sowie zur Steigerung der Leistungs- und Konzentrationsfähigkeit bei Soldaten, Fahrzeugführern und Piloten.\n \n
In der Zeit von April bis Juni 1940 bezog die Wehrmacht mehr als 35 Millionen Tabletten Pervitin. Der damalige Reichsgesundheitsführer Leonardo Conti meinte am 19. März 1940 in seiner Rede vor dem NSD-Ärztebund im Berliner Rathaus:\n \n„Wer Ermüdung mit Pervitin beseitigen will, der kann sicher sein, dass der Zusammenbruch seiner Leistungsfähigkeit eines Tages kommen muss. Dass das Mittel einmal gegen Müdigkeit für einen Hochleistungsflieger, der noch zwei Stunden fliegen muss, angewendet werden darf, ist wohl richtig. Es darf aber nicht angewendet werden bei jedem Ermüdungszustand, der in Wirklichkeit nur durch Schlaf ausgeglichen werden kann. Das muss uns als Ärzten ohne weiteres einleuchten.“\n \nAls dann am 25. Oktober 1940 in der Münchener Medizinischen Wochenschrift (MMW) ein Beitrag erschien, in dem Pervitin für beinahe alles von See- und Bergkrankheit und verzögerter Rekonvaleszenz bis hin zu organischen Hirn- und Rückenmarkstörungen empfohlen wurde, sah sich die Reichsgesundheitsführung veranlasst, den Psychiater Ernst Speer als bekannten Kritiker des Medikaments mit einer Gegendarstellung zu berufen, die ebenfalls in der MMW erschien.\n \n
Ab Mitte 1941 war das Medikament durch das geänderte Reichsopiumgesetz nicht mehr frei, sondern nur noch auf Rezept erhältlich. Dadurch reduzierte sich der Einsatz der Droge merklich.\n \nVerwendung nach 1945\n \nBei Piloten war Pervitin für den Notfall vorgesehen, und der Verbandsatz der NVA enthielt bis 1988 Pervitin. Auch nach 1945 wurde der Wirkstoff vom US-Militär zur Leistungssteigerung eingesetzt, beispielsweise während des Vietnamkriegs. Im Sport soll Pervitin als Doping­mittel genutzt worden sein. Das Fertigarzneimittel Pervitin blieb bis 1988 im Handel.\n \n
Einsatz findet die Droge auch in „Chem-Sexpartys“ ? Sex-Orgien unter Drogeneinfluss. In Berlin liegt der Konsumentenschwerpunkt gegenwärtig (2016) in der homosexuellen Szene. Zwischen den Jahren 2008 und 2012 hat sich die sichergestellte Menge der Droge verzehnfacht.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="amfetamin">
			<text>Amphetamin (Phenylisopropylamin)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_medi_amfetamin">
			<text>%c[255,220,220,100]Erhöhte Ausdauer : %c[255,1,255,1]180%\n
%c[255,220,220,100]Reduziert. Hunger: %c[255,1,255,1]40%\n
%c[255,220,220,100]Packungs Menge   : %c[255,1,255,1]2 Tabletten\n
%c[255,220,220,100]Nebenwirkungen   : %c[255,1,255,1]Allgemeiner Zustand\n
%c[default]\n \n 
Amphetamin ist eine vollsynthetisch hergestellte Substanz künstlichen Ursprungs. Der Wirkstoff zählt zur Stoffgruppe der Phenylethylamine und dort zu den Weckaminen (Amine mit „aufweckender“ Wirkung).\n \n
Er wird derzeit in der Medizin als Arzneistoff zur Behandlung der Aufmerksamkeitsdefizit-/Hyperaktivitätsstörung (ADHS) und der Narkolepsie verwendet. Amphetamin hat eine stark stimulierende und aufputschende Wirkung. Wie alle Amphetaminderivate und viele Stimulanzien wirkt es appetitzügelnd und in hohen Dosen euphorisierend. Daher ist es insbesondere in der Drogenszene beliebt und unter Bezeichnungen wie Speed oder Pep weit verbreitet.\n \n
Amphetamin ist die Stammverbindung der Substanzklasse der Amphetamine. Zu ihr gehören etliche weitere psychoaktive Substanzen, unter anderem Methamphetamin und das in der Natur vorkommende Ephedrin. Amphetamin ist ein Stimulans und indirektes Sympathomimetikum, d. h. es regt die sympathischen Teile des vegetativen Nervensystems an.\n \n
Es existieren zwei verschiedene Isomere des Amphetamins: Dexamphetamin und Levamphetamin. Medizinisch wird oft reines D-Amphetamin verwendet, da dieses stärker wirksam ist als L-Amphetamin. Wird nur von Amphetamin gesprochen, ist meist ein Gemisch beider Isomere (D,L-Amphetamin) gemeint.\n \n
Amphetamin wird in der Bundesrepublik Deutschland in der Anlage III im Betäubungsmittelgesetz aufgeführt und stellt damit ein verkehrsfähiges und verschreibungsfähiges Betäubungsmittel dar; Handel und Besitz ohne Erlaubnis werden strafrechtlich verfolgt.\n \n
u den gesundheitlichen Risiken, die mit dem Konsum von Amphetamin einhergehen, zählen gesteigerte Aggressivität, Krämpfe, Zittern, Kreislaufkollaps, Herzrasen und Herzinfarkt. Bei einem Abhängigkeitssyndrom können Zerfall der Muskulatur, Nierenversagen, Gedächtnisstörungen, Schlaganfall, paranoide Wahnvorstellungen und Depressionen, Bewusstseinstrübung bis hin zu Koma und chronische Psychosen auftreten. Es kann zu einer Vernachlässigung sozialer Verpflichtungen (Familie, Schule, Beruf, Beziehung) kommen. Werden Amphetamine häufig geschnupft, kann es zu einer Schädigung bis zur Auflösung der Nasenscheidewand kommen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="medkit_elite10">
			<text>"Elite" Medkit</text>
		</string>
		<string id="medkit_elite10_s">
			<text>Medkit</text>
		</string>
		<string id="medkit_elite">
			<text>'Elite' medkit</text>
		</string>
		<string id="medkit_elite_s">
			<text>Medkit</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_medkit_elite">
			<text>Die "Elite" Medkit wurde Zonen Wissenschaftler speziell für die Arbeit in der Zone entwickelt von.
Das Kit beinhaltet: \n
  • 2 Alice-Clips und alle militärischen Schablonen \ n
  • 1 2 "x 4.1yrds Verbandgewebe \ n
  • 2 4 "x 4" sterile Schwämme \ n
  • 5 1 "x 3" Verbandstreifen \ n
  • 1 Feldbearbeitung \ n
  • 3 Knickerbänder \ n
  • 2 Ammoniak-Inhalationsampullen
  • 2 Schmetterlingsstreifen \ n
  • 1 Erste-Hilfe-Anweisungen \ n
  • 1 Dreifach-Antibiotikum 1 \ n
  • 1 "Tape \ n • 4 Alkoholtücher \ n
  • 3 Jodwischtücher \ n
  • 3 antiseptische Tücher \ n
  • 3 saubere Wischtücher \ n
  • 3 nach Bisswischen</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bandage_dmx">
			<text>Special Bandage</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_bandage_dmx">
			<text>Special dressing injected with an anti-radiation compound. Typically used used by the Military in order to treat wounds whilst on manoeuvres throughout the Zone</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tab">
			<text>Antipohmelin Tablets</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_tab">
			<text>%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Reduce hangover:%c[255,1,255,1] 95%\n%c[default]Tablets, completely relieving effects of alcohol. They enter the bloodstream special substances, which are somewhat reduce the concentration of ethanol. It was noticed that the constant use of data caps, their effectiveness is markedly reduced. No side effects were noted. The drug is fast acting</text>
		</string>
		<string id="radioprotector">
			<text>Radioprotector</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_radioprotector">
			<text>%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Duration:%c[255,1,255,1] 60 sec\n%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Protection:%c[255,1,255,1] +150\n%c[default]Radioprotector "Indralin-B190," was part of the personal kits power plant staff. Appeared as a substitute in the Zone too toxic cystamine hydrochloride FC1. Reduces the effects of gamma radiation on the tissues of a living organism. The drug D-190 provides life-saving nine out of ten irradiated in obtaining an absolutely lethal dose of radiation. It is advisable to use pre-emptively, before irradiation, since the drug is not instantaneous. The drug is long-acting</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_drug_anabiotic">
			<text>Anabiotic</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_drug_anabiotic_descr">
			<text>%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Duration:%c[255,1,255,1] 5 minute\n%c[default]An experimental drug designed to research groups operating in the zone. Underlying drug tetradotoksin, known as "zombie powder", causes complete paralysis of the central nervous system, which supposedly can help out the shelter to survive ejection. The drug has not been tested in field conditions and failed clinical trials, which casts doubt on its effectiveness, and raises questions about possible side effects</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_drug_psy_blockade">
			<text>Psi-block</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_drug_psy_blockade_descr">
			<text>%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Duration:%c[255,1,255,1] 60 s\n%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Psi-defense:%c[255,1,255,1] +240\n%c[default]Narcotic drug that blocks nerve impulses to an avalanche. Protects against psychic radiation exposure and the controller for a short time or completely eliminates this effect. An interesting side effect: after treatment there is a total blocking of any emotion. In the Zone is used to counteract abnormal fields of increased psy-activity; application outside the Zone does not exist</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_drug_coagulant">
			<text>Vinca</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_drug_coagulant_descr">
			<text>%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Duration:%c[255,1,255,1] 20 s\n%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Healing:%c[255,1,255,1] +30\n%c[default]Vikasol - a synthetic analogue of vitamin C. The main effect is to increase blood clotting. Demand among the stalkers, because it allows the body faster scar lacerations. It has a lasting effect</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_drug_yadulin">
			<text>Yadulin</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_drug_yadulin_descr">
			<text>%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Improvement of:%c[255,1,255,1] +45\n%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Reduce hangover:%c[255,1,255,1] 50%\n%c[255,238,153,26]  %c[default]Side effects: severe fatigue and a slight deterioration\n%c[default]The cheapest and widespread in the zone medical preparations for the accelerated healing of minor wounds and withdrawal from the body effects of alcohol. Were found side-effects shortly after taking the drug could dramatically worsen mood, or rolled over severe weakness. The drug is fast acting</text>
		</string>
<!-- OTHER ITEMS -->
		<string id="wpn_arm_binoc">
			<text>Army Binoculars</text>
		</string>
		<string id="wpn_arm_binoc_s">
			<text>Army Binoculars PNV</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_dmx_binocul">
			<text>Portable Army Field-Binoculars with an improved aiming grid. Also equipped with Night-Vision capabilities, which make this particular model well sought after throughout the Zone. Manufactured strictly for Military use oin the late 1980's, extensive field research has proven time, and time again that these Military Binoculars well outmatched their predecessor - the world-famous "Zeiss" Binoculars</text>
		</string>
<!-- NOT USED -->
		<string id="item_svarog">
			<text>Detector Svarog</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_svarog_info">
			<text>Detector artifacts Series "Svarog". This detector is the latest leading research institutes. Thanks to nanotechnology, the sensitivity of the detector is increased up to 1.5 miles. The presence of artifacts displayed markers on the map terrain. In addition to their location, the detector detects the types of artifacts, making this unit the best of all the series of detectors</text>
		</string>
<!-- AS OF YET UNUSED -->
		<string id="item_razgruzka">
			<text>Tactical Vest</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_item_razgruzka">
			<text>Convenience: 100\nStrength Class: 1\nWeight: 1kg\nThe 'Unloading Vest' is intended for the quick dispersal of ammunition, as well as individual means of emergency medical-aid. Contains ballistic panels to be used as an over-the-uniform multi-purpose Tactical Carrying Vest for serious incursions deep into the most dangerous parts of the ZONE</text>
		</string>
		<string id="timer">
			<text>Watch</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_timer">
			<text>Digital clock timer. Specially developed for special units of Russian Army. Shockproof and water resistant, can withstand immersion to 300 metres. Equipped with a timer and sundomerom. New Party were repeatedly stolen hours stalkers Scout warehouse database D-3 Special Forces colonel Bibik and sold wholesale traders in the Zone. Scout for these crimes was three times sentenced to death, but thanks to the notorious syndrome "Fear of Death," the stalker managed to survive the enforcement of sentences</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mine_1_name">
			<text>Mine</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mine_1_name_s">
			<text>Mine</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mine_1_description">
			<text>Blast Radius: 1 metre\n  Capacity: 20\n  Detonation Time: 10 seconds\n A mine used by the Military in order to defend a perimeter</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mine_2_name">
			<text>"Enhanced" Mine</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mine_2_name_s">
			<text>Mine</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mine_2_description">
			<text>Blast Radius: 3 metres\n  Capacity: 35\n  Detonation Time: 10 seconds\n An improved version of the Military mine with a larger blast radius capable of inflicting severe damage</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mine_3_name">
			<text>Electric Mine</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mine_3_name_s">
			<text>Mine</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mine_3_description">
			<text>Blast Radius: 6 metres\n  capacity: 60\n  Detonation Time: 10 seconds\n Developed by Military Scientists, this explosive device inflicts a severe "electric" discharge, causing serious damage to its victim(s)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_guitar_name">
			<text>Acoustic Guitar</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_guitar_name_s">
			<text>Guitar</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_guitar_descr">
			<text>A typical model, cheaply made in the Czech Republic, and brought into the Zone by an unknown Importer... many STALKERs like to have a little music to go along with their Vodka when relaxing near campfires throughout the Zone</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_harmonica_name">
			<text>Harmonica</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_harmonica_name_s">
			<text>Harmonica</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_harmonica_descr">
			<text>It is believed that these mouth instruments are being brought into the Zone by the same Importer that has managed to smuggle in the vast number of Acoustic Guitars seen all over the place at campfire's throughout the Zone</text>
		</string>
		<string id="wpn_smoking">
			<text>Cigarette</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_wpn_smoking">
			<text>A simple cigarette. The truth is... no-one actually knows where, and who makes these cigarettes</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_racya">
			<text>Portable Radio</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_racya_s">
			<text>Radio</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_item_racya">
			<text>Military issue hand-radio. Reception Radius is limited to 10 kilometres. Useful for communicating with others throughout the Zone, but it is anyone's guess who might be listening</text>
		</string>
		<string id="wpn_fuck">
			<text>The Finger</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_wpn_fuck">
			<text>Also known as: the middle finger, the highway salute, the bird (as in flicking, flipping or flying the bird), or to flip someone off, is an obscene hand gesture, often meaning the phrase "fuck you" or "up yours". Not adviseable to go around flipping people the "finger" if you don't want to get shot!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="fosfor">
			<text>Phosphorous Stick</text>
		</string>
		<string id="fosfor_descr">
			<text>A small stick made of phosphoric material, which is used as a source of light in darkened spaces. Does not require recharging, but over time the glow weakens</text>
		</string>
		<string id="car_key">
			<text>Car Key</text>
		</string>
		<string id="car_key_s">
			<text>Car Key</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_car_key">
			<text>A car key that seems to have been modified. Supposedly, it may fit some of the vehicles found throughout the Zone</text>
		</string>
		<string id="car_key_2">
			<text>Strange Key</text>
		</string>
		<string id="car_key_2_s">
			<text>Strange Key</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_car_key_2">
			<text>A key that seems to have many extra facets and a small military symbol on it. Looks like it might fit some of the vehicles found throughout the Zone</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bolt_detector_otclik">
			<text>Response Detector</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bolt_detector_otclik_s">
			<text>Response</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_bolt_detector_otclik">
			<text>Outdated model of the detector of abnormal activity. Reacts audible signal at the ingress of abnormal particles in a special chamber at the approach to anomalies, in addition, can detect the presence of artifacts and measure the distance to the nearest of them. The distance to the artifact is determined by supply frequency sound. Search mode artifacts include elevated cap antenna on the front panel. Due to simplicity of design is able to find only the most common artifacts</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bolt_detector_medved">
			<text>Bear Detector</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bolt_detector_medved_s">
			<text>The Bear</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_bolt_detector_medved">
			<text>The detector of abnormal activity of last generation. Equipped with radar anomalous formations and LED display for displaying the direction to the artifact, and is able not only to detect artifacts, but also to determine distance. Search mode artifacts include elevated cap antenna on the front side of the device. Unfortunately, some outdated list of artifacts was hard coded into the device</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bolt_detector_veles">
			<text>Veles Detector</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bolt_detector_veles_s">
			<text>Veles</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_bolt_detector_veles">
			<text>Detector scanner a new generation that is used by scientists. With three advanced camera location registration artifacts on the detector is displayed on a special screen. Is able to capture the radiation and the presence of anomalies. Search mode artifacts include elevated indicator-board on the front side of the instrument, in this mode is able to detect all known science artifacts</text>
		</string>
		<string id="helmet_stalker">
			<text>Mask</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_helmet_stalker">
			<text>Radiation protection = +60\nA standard gas mask designed to filter the air of radioactive dust and toxic substances. Widely used by both novices and veterans of all armed groups because of its functional indispensability. Not equipped with protection from bullets, shrapnel and mechanical effects</text>
		</string>
		<string id="radiation_detector">
			<text>Research dosimeter</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_radiation_detector">
			<text>The device is accurate measurement of radiation in a unit of Bear. When you turn on full scans of the owner for radiation. Used mostly by scientists, but sometimes you can find the mother of stalkers</text>
		</string>
		<string id="m_dmx_box">
			<text>My stuff</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_m_dmx_box">
			<text>Backpack with my belongings</text>
		</string>
		<string id="silencers_box">
			<text>Bag with silencers</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_silencers_box">
			<text>The bag, which contains all types of silencers for weapons</text>
		</string>
		<string id="zombie_antiradiation">
			<text>Antiradin Device</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_zombie_antiradiation">
			<text>This device is intended to protect humans from radiation emitted by zombie. Device in a backpack completely absorbs radiation, which subsequently accumulates in a special container made of similar material, which covered stalker's containers for artifacts. "Antiradin" - expensive, but very useful thing in areas of high PSI activity - in fact most often it can run into a zombie</text>
		</string>
		<string id="device_warning_module">
			<text>Decoder Module</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_device_warning_module">
			<text>Decoder Module, connected to the PDA. Catches warnings from stalkers. Allows decoding PDA stalkers and withdraw money from them. After all the money in the Zone - electronic</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mine_detector">
			<text>Mine detector</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_mine_detector">
			<text>Compact self-scanning minesweeper. Warns of finding mines beep. Radius sustainable detect mines seven metres</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_ammo_flame_transfer">
			<text>Generator flame mixture</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_item_ammo_flame_transfer">
			<text>This device allows you to create a mixture of colloidal gas and gasoline, which can then be used in a flamethrower. To generate the flame mixture must have a gas cylinder, a gas canisters and most flamethrower. After using the generator, Flamethrower is fully charged</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bolt_box">
			<text>Box with screws</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_bolt_box">
			<text>A small box inside of which is ten most common bolts</text>
		</string>
		<string id="device_torch_bad">
			<text>Broken Flashlight</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_device_torch_bad">
			<text>These lanterns are often out of order. Expiration date not specified. You may need to buy a new one</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_car_repair">
			<text>Automotive repair kit</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_item_car_repair">
			<text>Set of tools to almost completely restore the technical condition of the car. Use the set follows directly from the car</text>
		</string>
<!-- Quest items -->
		<string id="item_doc_x8">
			<text>Aleksandrov's Diary</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_item_doc_x8">
			<text>Our laboratory work did not stop after the second explosion, also, it is not involved in the creation of a "live" weapons in contrast to other laboratories. We have been tasked so - to create a compact, stand-alone weapon. Whom is the so-called Cube Shadow. The technology was invented by his creation of a single subject, which we found in an expedition near the fourth power unit of Chernobyl NPP. This course consisted of an unknown substance, which was stronger than steel in a few thousand times... And not only that all the interesting properties of matter - there were other.\nFour years later, created the first prototype of Cuba shadows. I will not tell its working principle and features, except to say that the cube can "suck" the life energy of every creature and send it to the owner...\nCube of Shadows is the latest development in the history of the laboratory X-8. In fact because of him and began to create something weird. In the course of the next test in the test room explosion. More precisely it was like a very loud bang... I just was not far from the place. Going into it, I saw the bodies of their colleagues - as white medical gowns... All of them were dead... And standing in the middle of a ghost. Most, if I may say so, the real, the ghost!..\nI slammed the door in terror trial in the hall, knowing that it will not help... After that, give the command to evacuate. At this point, as an evil light was extinguished. Could be heard running, screaming, the new "bangs"...\nAs a result, the lab got a total of nine people, including me, and five soldiers. Others did not have time...\nI had to return to his apartment and wait for the decision of the authorities about the incident...\nAll the same, the fact remains - it was after the trial began, Cuba Shadows are strange things... Perhaps, the phantom was placed in the energy sector in Cuba and testing freed... I have to learn this subject sret...\nI've decided. I will take all necessary and sent to the laboratory</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dmx_military_map">
			<text>Map of Army Warehouses</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dmx_military_map_s">
			<text>Army Warehouses</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_dmx_military_map">
			<text>An old map of the army warehouses. Apparently was made before the second explosion at Chernobyl. On the map, in some places there are a few notes without names.\n \n"To see insert the card into the slot pistol"</text>
		</string>
		<string id="fake_cube">
			<text>Cube Shadow</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_fake_cube">
			<text>Qualitatively made mock Cube shadows. Most likely it should look like a real cube</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dmx_pripyat_map">
			<text>Map of eastern Pripyat</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dmx_pripyat_map_s">
			<text>Eastern Pripyat</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_dmx_pripyat_map">
			<text>Place on the map marked the evacuation of the laboratory personnel X-8. Marker placed on the building of the BWC "Jubilee".\nOn the back of the card can be seen worn in some places record: "... for speed unlock doors before evacuating the code was changed to a very simple, consisting of a single digit - 1."\n \n"To see insert the card into the slot pistol"</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mudrec_instruments">
			<text>Repair Tools</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_mudrec_instruments">
			<text>A good set of tools. Apparently, the carefully chosen experienced master "for themselves, native." Despite the years, the entire instrument is well preserved</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_doc_x8_2">
			<text>Documents from laboratory X-8</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_item_doc_x8_2">
			<text>The documents indicate the technical characteristics of an antenna-radiator and how they differ from predicted. Apparently it is in X-8 developed a plan to create a radiator "Rainbow" (aka Brain Burner). On the reverse side is marked - it shows that this documentation is designed in the laboratory X-10</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_certificate">
			<text>Identity soldier</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_item_certificate">
			<text>Document certifying that the holder is on the Zone and is in its legal</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bipsizon_ogse">
			<text>"Psihodelin"</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_bipsizon">
			<text>Strange chemical concoction made specifically for abnormal conditions within the Zone. Protects from psi-radiation and the incapacitating influence of Controllers for a short duration, and has been known to be able to disable their influence completely. Developed exclusively for Sciuentific Division Leaders conducting field tests inside of Zone's perimeter. Invented by a Dr."Bibik Voenstalov" and given the codename "Xanth-83". Extremely rare</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yod_ogse">
			<text>Preparation A-190</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_yod">
			<text>Preparation A-190 (190-kilodaton) has been identified in several multidrug-resistant (MDR) cell lines that show decreased drug accumulation without expression of P-glycoprotein. It is not clear whether this 190k protein is involved directtly in drug efflux. Recently, a gene for a putative transporter protein, MRP (multidrug resistance-assiciated protein) has been sequenced and localized to chromosome 16. The protein encoded by this gene contains a 7-amino-acid sequence present in the synthetic peptide used to generate the antiserum recognizing the 190k protein.Purpose:The study was undertaken to clarify the relationship of the 190k protein to MRP gene expression in non-P-glycoprotein-containing MDR cells of the large-cell and adenocarcinoma cancer lines</text>
		</string>
<!-- THE ADDITIONAL DESCRIPTION TO SUBJECT MATTERS OF SALT !TB3D not in 134-->
		<string id="mushroom">
			<text>"Magic" Mushroom</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_mushroom">
			<text>%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+10\n%c[default]"Amanita Muscaria" ( commonly known as the "fly agaric" ) is a poisonous and psychoactive basidiomycete fungus, one of many in the genus Amanita. Native throughout the temperate and boreal regions of the Northern Hemisphere. Known for the unpredictability of their effects. Depending on habitat and the amount ingested per body weight, effects can range from nausea and twitching to drowsiness, cholinergic crisis-like effects (low blood pressure, sweating and salivation), auditory and visual distortions, mood changes, euphoria, relaxation, ataxia, and loss of equilibrium. It was referred to as the 'Flesh of the Gods', or 'Food of the Gods' because those who ingested it believed that they were in direct communication with the Earth and the Universe when they consumed this Fungi. The Fly-Agaric was commonly used by the Druids and other "Magic" users. It was considered too powerful for those not trained in the higher levels of the mind</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mushroom2">
			<text>Holucengenic Mushroom</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_mushroom2">
			<text>2   Purple A special mushroom that has mutated due to the affects of close proximity to rare artefacts</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mushroom3">
			<text>Radiated Mushroom</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_mushroom3">
			<text>3    Green A special mushroom that has mutated due to the affects of close proximity to rare artefacts</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mushroom4">
			<text>Power Mushroom</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_mushroom4">
			<text>4    Red top A special mushroom that has mutated due to the affects of close proximity to rare artefacts</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mushroom5">
			<text>Wealth Mushroom</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_mushroom5">
			<text>5    Blue fluoro top. A special mushroom that has mutated due to the affects of close proximity to rare artefacts</text>
		</string>
<!-- !TB3D -->
		<string id="bolt_descr">
			<text>Bolt 32h100. A Stalker's best friend</text>
		</string>
<!--	Duplicated from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970	<string id="bolt_descr">		<text>Bolt 32x100. Stalker's best friend</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="rover_bot_stancion">
			<text>Station for a mobile robot</text>
		</string>
<!-- !TB3D -->
		<string id="cigara">
			<text>Cuban Cigar</text>
		</string>
		<string id="cigara_s">
			<text>Cuban Cigar</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_cigara">
			<text>Cuban cigars are rolled from tobacco leaves found throughout the country of Cuba. The filler, binder, and wrapper may come from different portions of the island. All cigar production in Cuba is controlled by the Cuban government, and each brand may be rolled in several different factories in Cuba. Cuban cigar rollers or "torcedores" are claimed by cigar experts to be the most skilled rollers in the world. Torcedores are highly respected in Cuban society and culture and travel worldwide displaying their art of hand rolling cigars. These are a rare find in the Zone... and can be worth a lot of Rubles to the right buyer</text>
		</string>
<!--	<string id="cigara">		<text>Cuba Cigar</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_cigara">		<text>This Cuban cigar. In the Zone gets smuggled. According to this, local merchants to sell cigars can be bought and they can not be the same. Tobacco natural, strength and flavor excellent. Complementing the picture beautiful form of cigars, which makes smoking a real pleasure when you consider that we are in the Zone</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="fake_cigara">
			<text>This needs to be fixed</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sandwich">
			<text>Sandwich</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sandwich_s">
			<text>Sandwich</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_sandwich">
			<text>A very basic sandwich using any available meat, or sausage product. The bread doesn't seem to be too stale to eat... will satisfy hunger for the time being, or until something more nutritious comes along</text>
		</string>
<!--	<string id="sandwich">		<text>Sandwich</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_sandwich">		<text>The most common sausage sandwich. Prepared in advance, so that you can eat on the go, without a knife uncovered and not digging in his backpack in search of food ingredients</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="beer_a">
			<text>Zone Beer</text>
		</string>
		<string id="beer_a_s">
			<text>Beer</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_beer_a">
			<text>Apparently, this beer is brewed right here in the Zone somewhere. No-one seems to know where, but no-one seems to complain about it either</text>
		</string>
<!--	<string id="beer_a">		<text>Beer</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_beer_a">		<text>Beer of local production. Composition of the course has been written. A good way to get drunk to the blue tomato</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="flaska">
			<text>Flask</text>
		</string>
		<string id="flaska_s">
			<text>Flask</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_flaska">
			<text>A flask filled with clean, spring water... possibly just re-filled from the "Crystal" brand water found throughout the Zone</text>
		</string>
<!--	<string id="flaska">		<text>Flask</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_flaska">		<text>Flask, filled to the edge of water from a pure spring. Cleaner water in these places do not find</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="sweetness">
			<text>"Alenka" Chocolate Bar</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sweetness_s">
			<text>"Alenka"</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_sweetness">
			<text>First produced in 1966 in Moscow's Red October Factory following a Kremlin directive to create a new brand of milk chocolate, "Alenka" became a sign of the good times... and a favorite snack of several generations to follow. Ingredients: sugar, dried whole milk, cocoa oil, ground cocoa, emulsifier lecithin E322</text>
		</string>
<!--	<string id="sweetness">		<text>Bar of chocolate</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_sweetness">		<text>A delicious chocolate bar. Soybeans in excess, the presence of natural cocoa is doubtful. Well satisfies hunger and positive effect on brain activity</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="box_cigara">
			<text>Box of Cigars</text>
		</string>
		<string id="box_cigara_s">
			<text>Box of Cigars</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_box_cigara">
			<text>A box of Cuban Cigars... worth a lot of money in a place such as this!</text>
		</string>
<!--	<string id="box_cigara">		<text>Cigar Box</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_box_cigara">		<text>A box with Cuban cigars. Very expensive thing</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="balalaika_a">
			<text>Balalaika</text>
		</string>
		<string id="balalaika_a_s">
			<text>Balalaika</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_balalaika_a">
			<text>A stringed instrument of Russian origin, with a characteristic triangular body and three strings. The balalaika family of instruments includes, from the highest-pitched to the lowest, the prima balalaika, sekunda balalaika, alto balalaika, bass balalaika and contrabass balalaika. The earliest mention of the term balalaika dates back to a 1688 BC Russian document.The term became widely used in Ukrainian language documents from 1717-1732. According to one theory, it is thought that the term was borrowed into Russian where, in literary language, it first appeared in a poem by V. Maikov "Elysei" in 1771</text>
		</string>
<!--	<string id="balalaika_a">		<text>Balalaika</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_balalaika_a">		<text>Normal balalaika. A wonderful Russian folk instrument. In the Zone, too, lacks the masters of playing</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="det_artefact_indy">
			<text>"Response" Artefact Detector</text>
		</string>
		<string id="det_art_indy_info">
			<text>The "Response" Detector was developed by the Zone's Scientific Community. It was the first model of Detector to surface within the Zone. Detection radius is limited to 40 metres, and the presence of an Artefact is distinguished only by a simple sound. Further developments of this model have led to far more effective devices, which can be difficult to obtain both inside, and outside the Zone's perimeter</text>
		</string>
<!--	<string id="det_artefact_indy">		<text>Detector artifacts</text>	</string>	<string id="det_art_indy_info">		<text>This is the first detector artifacts, designed by local craftsmen. The device is ineffective because it does not reach over and 40 meters, and the presence of an artifact is recognized only an audible signal. But in its time, with the help of this device has been found so many artifacts</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="det_art_ultra_super">
			<text>"Svarog" Artefact Detector</text>
		</string>
		<string id="det_art_ultra_super_s">
			<text>"Svarog"</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_det_art_ultra_info">
			<text>The last known invention to come out of the Scientific Research Institute. Using advanced "Nanotechnology", this sensitive detector can detect Artefacts from as far away as 1.5 km, and displays such finds on the user's map. Besides their precise location, this excellent detector can distinguish the type of Artefact found. This alone, sets it apart from all other models. "Svarog" - ( Old Slavic mythological God of the sky, the father of the sun and fire )</text>
		</string>
<!-- Duplicated string id's from "string_table_arhara.xml" and the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" files.TB. you should choose only one string id and delete the rest - aleks1970 -->
<!-- before was "det_art_ultra_info" id(which was also duplicated), but now have new string to match "items.ltx" file - aleks1970 -->
<!--	<string id="enc_det_art_ultra_info">		<text>Artifact Detector Series 'ULTRA'. This detector is the latest created by local scientists. Thanks to nanotechnology, the sensitivity of the detector is increased to one hundred meters. The presence of Artifacts displays markers on the map. In addition to their location, the detector detects the types of Artifacts, which makes this unit the best of all the series of detectors to hunt for Artifacts. Activated when in the pistol slot</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_det_art_ultra_info">		<text>This is an improved version of the detector artifacts, past upgrades among scientists. Added map of the area with the output label on it. Range increased to 70 meters. In connection with the reasonable price and improved performance, its use is considered preferable</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="detektor_amorf">
			<text>Isomorphic Detector</text>
		</string>
		<string id="detektor_amorf_s">
			<text>Isomorphic Detector</text>
		</string>
		<string id="detektor_amorf_info">
			<text>Detector able to detect items containing particles of an Alien power and display these items on the map within a radius of fifty to sixty metres, also beeps. It is also possible to locate Artifacts. Activated when in the pistol slot</text>
		</string>
<!--	<string id="detektor_amorf">		<text>The detector is isomorphic</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="detector_elite_john">
			<text>Ultra Detector</text>
		</string>
		<string id="detector_elite_john_s">
			<text>Ultra Detector</text>
		</string>
<!--	<string id="detector_elite_john">		<text>Detector Holograms</text>	</string> -->
<!-- DOCUMENTS AKIM -->
		<string id="doc_garbage">
			<text>Old documents from the Dump</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doc_garbage_s">
			<text>Old documents</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_doc_garbage">
			<text>Documents found at the Dump. Some sort of Scientific formula.... written in an incomprehensible language. By the looks of it - could quite easily be the senseless scribblings of a lunatic</text>
		</string>
<!--	<string id="doc_garbage">		<text>Old paper from the landfill</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_doc_garbage">		<text>Documents found in the Garbage. Formula, write a foreign language. By type - ravings of a madman</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="doc_agro">
			<text>Old documents from Agroprom</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doc_agro_">
			<text>Old documents</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_doc_agro">
			<text>A stack of documents found in the Catacombs beneath the Agroprom Institute. Some sort of formula written in a language I don't understand. Very strange indeed</text>
		</string>
<!--	<string id="doc_agro">		<text>Old paper with agricultural industry</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_doc_agro">		<text>A stack of documents found in the catacombs of agricultural industry. Formula, write a foreign language. By type - not very much like the previous</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="doc_x18_1">
			<text>Old Document - Part I</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doc_x18_1_s">
			<text>Part I</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_doc_x18_1">
			<text>Documentation found in the Dark Valley. Appears to be the first part of something more in depth</text>
		</string>
<!--	<string id="doc_x18_1">		<text>The old document. Part I</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_doc_x18_1">		<text>Documents found in Dark Valley. By all appearances this is the first part</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="doc_x18_2">
			<text>Old Document - Part II</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doc_x18_2_s">
			<text>Part II</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_doc_x18_2">
			<text>The second part of a series of Documents to be found in Laboratory X-18</text>
		</string>
<!--	<string id="doc_x18_2">		<text>The old document. Part II</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_doc_x18_2">		<text>The second part doumentov found in the laboratory X-18</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="doc_x18_3">
			<text>Old Document - Part III</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doc_x18_3_s">
			<text>Part III</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_doc_x18_3">
			<text>The third part of a series of Documents to be found in Laboratory X-18</text>
		</string>
<!--	<string id="doc_x18_3">		<text>The old document. Part III</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_doc_x18_3">		<text>The third part doumentov found in the laboratory X-18</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="doc_x18_4">
			<text>Old Document - Part IV</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doc_x18_4_s">
			<text>Part IV</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_doc_x18_4">
			<text>The fourth part of a series of Documents to be found in Laboratory X-18</text>
		</string>
<!--	<string id="doc_x18_4">		<text>The old document. Part IV</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_doc_x18_4">		<text>Last quarter of doumentov found in the laboratory X-18</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="doc_x16">
			<text>Old Document from Laboratory X-16</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doc_x16_s">
			<text>Old X-16 Document</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_doc_x16">
			<text>Documentation found inside Laboratory X-16. A series of Scientific Formulas written in a language I do not understand. Apparently this is the last portion of a series of Documents which make up some sort of Report on Secretive Experiments throughout the Zone... It is signed by a one 'Benjamin Linus' of the Dharma Initiative... what does this mean?!.... and, who/what is this Dharma Initiative I keep seeing all over the place!?</text>
		</string>
<!--	<string id="doc_x16">		<text>Old document from the X-16</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_doc_x16">		<text>Documents found in the laboratory X-16. Formula, write a foreign language. Apparently this is the last part of the documents found</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="pda_info">
			<text>Broken PDA</text>
		</string>
		<string id="pda_info_s">
			<text>PDA</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_pda_info">
			<text>A typical PDA, which in the zone a lot. Besides - a non-working and bruised. It is seen that the former owner was with him, not very thrifty. Activate the PDA can not be due to a broken screen. Flash cards do not. So fuck anything</text>
		</string>
<!--	<string id="pda_info">		<text>Broken PDA</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_pda_info">		<text>A typical PDA, which many in the Zone. Besides - a non-working and bruised. It is evident that the former owner was with him not very frugal. Insert a PDA can not be due to a broken screen. Flash card no. In general, nothing can fuck</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="hand_teleporter_arhara">
			<text>Defective hand teleporter</text>
		</string>
		<string id="hand_teleporter_arhara_s">
			<text>Defective teleporter</text>
		</string>
<!--	<string id="hand_teleporter_arhara">		<text>Faulty manual teleportator</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="hand_teleporter">
			<text>Hand teleporter</text>
		</string>
		<string id="hand_teleporter_s">
			<text>Hand teleporter</text>
		</string>
<!--	<string id="hand_teleporter">		<text>Hand teleportator</text>	</string> -->
<!-- Documents on the Hood -->
		<string id="bloknot_pantera">
			<text>Panther's Notebook</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bloknot_pantera_s">
			<text>P. Notebook</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_bloknot_pantera">
			<text>Panther's personal notebook. It contains several indecipherable phrases, and the following code: 25190456... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
		</string>
<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970	<string id="bloknot_pantera">		<text>Panthers Notebook</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_equipment_bloknot_pantera">		<text>Personal notebook Panthers. It was written a few sentences and some code: 25,190,456. To view a document, insert in pistol slot</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="dosye_zvez">
			<text>The "Astrologer" file</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dosye_zvez_s">
			<text>Astrologer Profile</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_dosye_zvez">
			<text>A file containing information on the "Astrologer"... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
		</string>
<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970	<string id="dosye_zvez">		<text>Astrologer Profile</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_equipment_dosye_zvez">		<text>Quick profile on Astrologer. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="foto_kukla">
			<text>Photo of a Doll</text>
		</string>
		<string id="foto_kukla_s">
			<text>Photo</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_foto_kukla">
			<text>An old photograph of a child's toy doll... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
		</string>
<!--		Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970	<string id="foto_kukla">		<text>Photo Doll</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_equipment_foto_kukla">		<text>Old photo normal infant dolls. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="pilot_zapiska">
			<text>the Pilot's Letter</text>
		</string>
		<string id="pilot_zapiska_s">
			<text>Letter</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_pilot_zapiska">
			<text>The Helicoptor Pilot's letter... which contains some very important information... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
		</string>
<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970	<string id="pilot_zapiska">		<text>Letter to the pilot</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_equipment_pilot_zapiska">		<text>Letter from a helicopter pilot with important information. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="foto_chaes_truba">
			<text>Photo of the Pilot</text>
		</string>
		<string id="foto_chaes_truba_s">
			<text>Photo</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_foto_chaes_truba">
			<text>The photograph of the burned helicoptor taken by the Pilot. In it, the large pipe alongside the burned helicopter can be seen clearly... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
		</string>
<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970	<string id="foto_chaes_truba">		<text>Photo Driver</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_equipment_foto_chaes_truba">		<text>Photo taken a helicopter pilot. It is visible to a large pipe with the burning helicopter. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="foto_aver_mono">
			<text>Group Photo</text>
		</string>
		<string id="foto_aver_mono_s">
			<text>Photo</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_foto_aver_mono">
			<text>Photograph of the group that burned the helicoptor... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
		</string>
<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970	<string id="foto_aver_mono">		<text>Photo of</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_equipment_foto_aver_mono">		<text>Group photo, fired on the helicopter. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="foto_aver_zvezd">
			<text>Photo of the group "Leader"</text>
		</string>
		<string id="foto_aver_zvezd_s">
			<text>Photo</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_foto_aver_zvezd">
			<text>Photograph of the Leader of the group that burned the helicoptor... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
		</string>
<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970	<string id="foto_aver_zvezd">		<text>Photos of the leader</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_equipment_foto_aver_zvezd">		<text>Photos of the leader who fired on the helicopter. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="chaes2_karta_kluk">
			<text>Photo of the NPP</text>
		</string>
		<string id="chaes2_karta_kluk_s">
			<text>Chernobyl</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_chaes2_karta_kluk">
			<text>Photograph of the northern side of the Chernobyl NPP. There is a mark on it possibly indicating the way to the southern side of the NPP... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
		</string>
<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970	<string id="chaes2_karta_kluk">		<text>Chernobyl Photo</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_equipment_chaes2_karta_kluk">		<text>Photo northern region of Chernobyl. It marked a rough passage on the other - the south side of the Chernobyl NPP. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="kreditka">
			<text>Credit Card</text>
		</string>
		<string id="kreditka_s">
			<text>Credit Card</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_kreditka">
			<text>A Credit Card issued from the Bank of America with a $5000,000 limit on it!... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
		</string>
<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970	<string id="kreditka">		<text>Credit Card</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_equipment_kreditka">		<text>Credit Card Bank of America in denominations 5 mil. USD. To view the credit card insert in pistol slot</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="razved_karta">
			<text>Map Fragments</text>
		</string>
		<string id="razved_karta_s">
			<text>Map Fragments</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_razved_karta">
			<text>Old scraps of a map containing directions, or coordinates of some sort... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
		</string>
<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970	<string id="razved_karta">		<text>Scrap maps</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_equipment_razved_karta">		<text>Old scrap card with the coordinates of the transition. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="karta_peschera">
			<text>Cave Map</text>
		</string>
		<string id="karta_peschera_s">
			<text>Map</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_karta_peschera">
			<text>Old map of the caves... somebody has scribbled some possible directions on it... hard to decipher... maybe the way out of here?!... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
		</string>
<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970	<string id="karta_peschera">		<text>Map of Cave</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_equipment_karta_peschera">		<text>An old map of the Cave. It shows all the moves and tunnels. There's also a label with the outputs of the Cave. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="recipi_bpb">
			<text>STALKERs Note</text>
		</string>
		<string id="recipi_bpb_s">
			<text>STALKERs Note</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_recipi_bpb">
			<text>Unidentified STALKERs' note... there appears to be information here regarding being able to modify certain Artefacts!?... sounds interesting... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
		</string>
<!--	Duplicated string id from the "string_table_enc_equipment.xml" file - aleks1970	<string id="recipi_bpb">		<text>Note stalker</text>	</string>	<string id="enc_equipment_recipi_bpb">		<text>Note an unknown stalker. There is information on the modification of the artifacts. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>	</string> -->
		<string id="stukach_book">
			<text>Informant's Notebook</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stukach_book_s">
			<text>Notebook</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stukach_book_desc">
			<text>Notebook belonging to the "Freedom" informant. It contains information about modifying Artefacts... can be viewed by placing it in the first weapon slot:</text>
		</string>
<!-- from the "string_table_enc_equipment" file - aleks1970		<string id="stukach_book">		<text>Notebook informer</text>	</string>	<string id="stukach_book_s">		<text>Notebook informer</text>	</string>	<string id="stukach_book_desc">		<text>Notebook informer group of Liberty. There is information about the new artmod. Insert in Pistol slot to view</text>	</string> -->
<!-- from the "sak_strings" file - aleks1970		<string id="stukach_book_desc">		<text>To view: insert the Laptop into the first slot.\nPavliks laptop. Besides some boring financial records, it contains a recipe for 'Artpreobrazovaniya'</text>	</string> -->
	</string_table>
<!--Created/Modified with S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Dialog Extended Editor by Marty Sheppard/ Version: 0.96h ( 2017/02/01) =!!= Last changed: 10.02.2017 01:28:58 -->
