<!-- ?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"? -->
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4 seperated from arc_string_table, lukash -->
<!-- Names changed as commented below - Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16 -->
 <!-- Corrected many generic punctuation, in-game and US/UK spelling errors - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16 -->
  <!--  Teile der Tagebücher von Wlad AMK/NS -->
<string_table>
<string id="kontroler_diary_1_part_1">
	<text>%c[255,220,220,100]29. Juni 198..(Jahr gelöscht)\n%c[default]Heute brachten sie uns hierher. Gerüchten zufolge sollten wir unterirdisch gehalten werden... Dreckskerle! Hatte ich doch lieber die härteste Strafe auf mich genommen... Doch uns hat sowieso niemand gefragt – wir mussten alle nach ihrer Pfeife tanzen. Und dann tauchten diese "plötzlich enthüllten" neuen Akten auf, sowie neue Paragraphen im Gesetzbuch über die politischen Häftlinge. Und als dieser Glatzkopf anfing seine gefühlsduseligen Reden uber "freiwillige Hilfe fur die Wissenschaft" zu führen... Alles verfluchte Scheißkerle! Niemand hatte je eine Wahl – entweder Erschießung oder hierher, ich weiß nicht einmal wo genau wir hier sind.... Na schön, schauen wir mal, was das hier fur eine Wissenschaft ist.\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]12. Juli\n%c[default]Sieht aus, als hätte ich mich geirrt!! Sie gaben uns nicht nur zu essen, sondern auch gesonderte Zellen! In Wahrheit werden wir rund um die Uhr beobachtet... Dafür gewähren sie uns alle möglichen Wünsche, mir wurden z.B., nachdem ich darum gebeten hatte, augenblicklich Bleistift und Papier gebracht, dem Nikolsky haben sie gestattet Lieder seiner Lieblingsrockgruppe zu hören! Was für ein Idiot er doch ist, he-he. Wären nicht die Aufnahmen, hätte man ihn niemals für die Spekulationen drangekriegt. Interessant ist nur warum er, ein Spekulant, mit uns politisch Gefangenen zusammengebracht wurde?\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]1. August\n%c[default]Nach fast zwei Monaten beginnt sich langsam alles aufzuklären. Wir sind alle verloren... Diese Hundesöhne stellen hier schlimmere Experimente an, als Hitlers Ärzte in den KZ's. WIE IST SOETWAS NUR IN UNSEREM LAND MÖGLICH!!? Heute haben sie Nikolsky nach ihren sogenannten "Experimenten" zurückgebracht... Sie zerrten ihn vorbei an meiner Zelle, da hob er kurz seinen Kopf, schaute mich an... MEIN GOTT!!! Das waren keine menschlichen Augen! Was haben sie nur mit ihm gemacht? Er hat mich nicht angesehen, nein, er sah DURCH mich hindurch, er sah IN mich!!! Aus seinem Mund floss Blut.... Der Fleck auf dem Fußboden direkt vor meiner Tür...\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]2. August\n%c[default]Ich habe fast die ganze Nacht nicht geschlafen... Schreie sind durch die Wände zu hören, sie klingen nicht menschlich... Ich bat den Wachmann um etwas zu trinken, unglaublich, aber mir wurde tatsächlich ein Wodka im Plastikbecher gereicht, ähnlich wie sie es in den Flugzeugen auch tun. Er bat mich, davon niemandem zu erzählen... War selbst nicht in bester Verfassung. In Andenken an dich, Nikolsky. Soll deine Seele zur Ruhe kommen, auch wenn dein Körper noch in der Nachbarzelle schreit.\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]24. August\n%c[default]Das war's. Nun bin ich an der Reihe. Heute haben sie mir den Kern meines Experiments erklärt. Irgendein "Generator" wird mich solange bestrahlen, bis sie eine Veränderung bemerken. Auf die Frage, was passiert, wenn ich vor der Veränderung sterbe, entgegneten sie, dies wäre nur eine "unwesentliche Störung des Experiments". Daraufhin habe ich mich auf einen von ihnen gestürzt, wollte ihm die Schlüssel abnehmen... Wie mir der Schädel brummt... Der Wachmann, der mir den Wodka gab, brachte mir einen Verband – um die Wunde nach dem Knüppelschlag zu stillen. Den Verband nahm er mir wieder ab, damit es niemand bei mir findet. Trotzdem ist er ein guter Kerl. Wolodja ist sein Name.10. September\nDas Schreiben fällt mir immer schwerer. Meine Finger lassen sich kaum noch biegen... Sind fest wie Stahl – vor drei Tagen habe ich die Schüssel mit dem Essen zerbrochen. Und anscheinend hab ich den Aluminiumlöffel zerbissen – kann mich nicht mehr erinnern... Morgen dann wieder der PSI-Strahler – so heißt das gute Stück im Hauptsaal... Ich bin als einzigster übrig. Nikolsky hat noch Glück gehabt – er schrie nur zwei Tage vor seinem Tod. Die meisten meiner anderen Genossen quälten sich erheblich länger... Ich bin der Letzte... Sie sagen – ich bin nicht so wie sie, ich bin besonders...\n
	\n%c[255,220,220,100]13. September\n%c[default]Nicht länger ein Mensch. Besser, stärker. Ich bin gross. Ratte. Sie gaben mir eine. Ich mag Ratte nicht. Ratten. Ich mag sie nicht. Wollte zubeissen. Hab ich nicht zugelassen. Zwang sie an der Decke und Wänden zu laufen. Ohne die Hände zu benutzen. In ihrem Kopf dachte ich ans Laufen und sie lief, wohin ich wollte. Dann hörte ich auf zu denken und sie fiel von der Decke herab. Ich kam näher und dachte, sie soll sich nicht bewegen. Bin auf sie getreten. Mag keine Ratten. Sind dreckig. Sie standen und schauten zu. Zelle klein. Aber ich bin gross.\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]1. Oktober\n%c[default]Ratten. Sie geben mir viele Ratten. Ich zwinge sie alle zu laufen und zu fallen. Und noch einen Hund. Ist auch wie Ratte. Ich denke für ihn und sehe, was er sieht. Mag Ratten nicht. Mag Hund. Ich dachte für Hund Ratten zu essen. Und Ratten sich nicht zu bewegen. Und der Hund ass. Lecker... Schade, dass ich kein Hund bin. Ich bin gross.\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]13 Oktober\n%c[default]Sie wissen nichts mehr über mich. Sagen, sie haben alles studiert. Sie sind naiv. Ich war in ihren Köpfen, habe gesehen. Sie haben mich nicht gesehen. Wolodja... Einer von ihnen. Ist schwächer. Er hat Mitleid. Hat mir Gutes getan. Ich nehme ihn zuerst. Werde für ihn denken, Zelle zu öffnen. Dann denke ich für ihn, er soll den Zweiten töten, der schwieg. Dieser ist stark, schwer in seinen Kopf zu sehen. Alle anderen schwächer. Nicht wie Wolodja, aber schwächer. Die, die Aufzeichnungen gemacht haben und studierten – schwach. Sind Anführer. Aber schwach. Ich nehme sie alle. Sie sind wie Ratten und wie Hund.\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]20. Oktober\n%c[default]Im Wald ist es besser. Hier gibt es Pilze. Ich erinnere mich, habe irgendwann Pilze gegessen. Und sie erinnern sich auch. Aber sie sagen nichts mehr. Sie brüllen und weinen. Aber Wolodja nicht mehr. Er ist keine Ratte. Ist besser. Ich war hungrig. Lecker... Sie denken, ich bin gross. Ja. So ist es. ICH BIN GROSS.</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_2_part_1">
	<text>%c[255,220,220,100]29. Januar\n%c[default]Heute brachte der Briefträger einen Umschlag. Darauf befand sich ein Stempel des Kiewer Forschungs-Instituts für Neurochirurgie. Als ich es öffnete, fand ich die Antwort auf meine Anfrage, ich zitiere: Sehr geehrter Anton Anatoljewitsch. Wir haben ihre Dissertation gelesen, ebenso wie eine Reihe Ihrer Artikel über die Entwicklung der Wissenschaft im Bereich der Neurochirurgie, insbesondere den Artikel über die "Wirkung der PSI-Strahlung auf den menschlichen Organismus und dessen Möglichkeiten". Wir möchten Ihnen auf dem schnellsten Wege mitteilen, dass in einem von unseren Labors neue, qualifizierte Fachkräfte gesucht werden, und wir würden uns darüber freuen Sie in unseren Reihen ... (nicht mehr lesbar...)\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]16. Februar\n%c[default]So, endlich sind wir im Labor. Seltsam, aber ich kann mich nicht mehr an die Fahrt hierher erinnern. Im Grunde war ich vor der Fahrt ausgeschlafen, doch als wir in den Bus stiegen und außerhalb des Institut-Geländes waren, wurde ich sehr schläfrig und schlief schließlich ganz ein. Das Letzte, woran ich mich erinnern kann, ist das mein Gesprächspartner, ich glaube Michael, mir über seinen Vortrag auf der Berliner Wissenschaftskonferenz berichtete. Interessant, wie lange sind wir gefahren? Eine Stunde? Zwei? Innerhalb des Laboratoriums habe ich noch keine Uhr erblicken können. Ich habe komplett mein Zeitgefühl verloren. Ist es jetzt Tag oder Nacht? Losgefahren sind wir um 6 Uhr morgens. Ich denke, wir sind nicht weit vom Institut entfernt, wahrscheinlich irgendwo am Rande von Kiew. Vielleicht in einem benachbarten Städtchen. Bald wird unsere Gruppe erste Instruktionen erhalten und wir können unser Labor begutachten.\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]17. Februar\n%c[default]Gestern bekamen wir im Hörsaal Instruktionen zur Arbeitssicherheit. Wie es einen ermüdet... man kommt sich vor wie ein Student bei der Vorlesung. Fasst dies nicht an, lasst die Finger von dem. Als ob sich das bis heute noch niemand gemerkt hat. Gerade eben wurde bekannt gegeben, dass das Treffen der Neuankömmlinge im Hörsaal stattfindet. Aller Wahrscheinlichkeit nach, werden dort Dias gezeigt und dann eine Führung gemacht.\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]18. Februar\n%c[default]Die Führung war äusserst beeindruckend! Das Labor ist riesig und enthält modernste Ausrüstung, anscheinend ist noch jemand anders an der PSI-Strahlung unserer Gelehrten interessiert. Aber etwas hat uns im Labor hellhörig gemacht. Unabhängig davon, dass es in einem Labor reinlich und sauber sein muss, sah hier alles ein bisschen zu geleckt aus. Es macht den Anschein, dass vor unserer Ankunft Putzfrauen des Hotels "Metropol" angekarrt wurden und das sie, wie üblich, alles bis in die kleinste Ecke sauber gemacht haben..\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]23. Februar\n%c[default]Wir dachten, wenigstens heute würde man uns gestatten hinauszugehen und etwas frische Luft zu schnappen, aber weit gefehlt. Wie ich herausfinden konnte, werden wir von einem Zug Soldaten bewacht. Obwohl ich nicht begreifen kann, wieso man uns überhaupt bewacht. Und vor wem? Ich dachte, wenigstens an einem solchen Feiertag, der jedem Militär nah geht, werden uns die Soldaten gestatten für ein paar Minütchen hinauszugehen, doch sie waren gleichgültig.\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]4. März\n%c[default]Heute ist mein erster Geburtstag, den ich nicht wie gewohnt zuhause verbringen werde, sondern im Kreise meiner neuen Familie. Die Kollegen haben mir bereits am Morgen gratuliert. Auch wenn sie mir keine Geschenke machen konnten, aber das ist ja verständlich, wie sollen sie schon in völliger Isolation von der Außenwelt etwas kaufen? Ich weiss immer noch nicht, was hier meine Pflichten sein werden. Von unserem Vorgesetzten Gubarew Witali Semenowitsch habe ich erfahren, dass schon bald die ersten Leute gebracht werden, die sich freiwillig den Diensten der Wissenschaft zur Verfügung gestellt haben.\n
	\n%c[255,220,220,100]10. März\n%c[default]Heute haben sie die ersten Freiwilligen gebracht. Mein Gott, das waren ja gewöhnliche Gefangene. Es fällt mir schwer, sie als Freiwillige zu bezeichnen. Welch einen Freiwilligen bringt man schon in Ketten?\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]16. April\n%c[default]Es ist bereits ein Monat vergangen, nachdem wir die Arbeit mit den "Freiwilligen" begonnen haben. Die Aufgabe unserer Abteilung liegt darin, die Ausrüstung vorzubereiten. Nach der Ankunft der Häftlinge wurde uns der Zugang zu einem Grossteil der Laboratorien untersagt. Wir treffen die Gefangenen nicht einmal. Schön wenigstens, dass die Versorgung mit allem Nötigen gewährleistet ist.\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]19. April\n%c[default]Mein Gott, wo bin ich hier nur reingeraten? Verflucht sei der Tag, an dem ich der Verlockung eines möglichen Karrieresprungs gefolgt und hierher gekommen bin. Heute ist etwas im Labor vorgefallen. Wir wurden auf einer Etage eingesperrt und zwei Soldaten mit Maschinengewehren wurden zu unserem Schutz abkommandiert um den Anschein zu erwecken, wir würden beschützt werden. Wir haben nichts gehört und das hat uns noch mehr erschreckt. Wir bemühten uns, wie auch zuvor, unsere Arbeit zu erledigen um den Anschein zu erwecken, dass nichts geschehen wäre, doch vergeblich. Uns war klar, dass unten etwas passiert. Es wäre besser gewesen, ich hätte die Wahrheit nicht erfahren! Selbst in Objekten der höchsten Geheimhaltung verbreiten sich schnell Gerüchte. Eines der Versuchsobjekte (Ich kann sie nicht länger Freiwillige nennen! Wem lüge ich etwas vor? Mir selbst?) war nicht länger steuerbar und nahm entweder eine Geisel oder fing an einige Mitarbeiter zu kontrollieren. Wie sich zeigt, werden wir nicht nur von Soldaten bewacht, sondern... (Die Seite ist ausgerissen...)\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]16. Mai\n%c[default]Es scheint, als würden all meine Briefe und Bitten, mich von meinem Posten versetzen zu lassen, gar nicht wahrgenommen werden oder sie verlassen das Laboratorium nicht. Ich kann hier nicht länger arbeiten. In mir kommen immer öfter Gedanken über einen Anschlag oder Sabotage hoch. Ich bin zu allem bereit, nur um diesen Ort so schnell wie möglich wieder verlassen zu können. Ich habe mich sonst nie vor geschlossenen Räumen gefürchtet, aber ich fühle, dass mit jedem Tag eine ähnliche Phobie in mir wächst. Als ich meine Arbeiten über die PSI-Strahlung verfasste, hatte ich einen ganz anderen Einfluss im Sinn, der sich mittels geringster Dosis von Strahlung auf einen bestimmten Bereich des Gehirns ergab. Doch diese Schlächter setzen die gesamte Hirnregion einer solch grossen Bestrahlung aus, dass das kein normaler Mensch aushalten kann. Ich hörte, dass derjenige, der die zwei Wissenschaftler kontrollierte, bereits der zweite Mutant war. Erst der zweite. Der erste ist 3 Minuten nach Beginn der Mutation im Gehirn gestorben. Sein Kopf ist wie eine Walnuß geplatzt. Begreifen sie wirklich nicht, was sie da tun? Diese Häftlinge, sie waren doch schließlich auch Menschen... Was passiert erst, wenn ihnen diese armen Schlucker ausgehen? Wen bringen sie dann hierher? Obdachlose? Und weiter? Nein, ich muss um jeden Preis hier rauskommen und der ganzen Welt die Wahrheit berichten!\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]21. Mai\n%c[default]Gott, ich werde noch ganz verrückt! Mir kommt es vor, als würde jemand in meinem Kopf festsitzen! Ich begreife nichts mehr. Manchmal bekomme ich heftige Anfälle von Kopfschmerzen, dann wechseln sich diese mit Lärm ab. Bisweilen höre ich auch irgendwelches Piepsen! Es hält für einige Sekunden an und dann gehen wieder die Kopfschmerzattacken los! Haben die komplett den Verstand verloren? Haben sie etwa wirklich begonnen, die eigenen Angestellten der Strahlung auszusetzen? Welche Dosen wenden sie an? Ich habe noch nie von solchen Nebenwirkungen gehört!\n
	\n%c[255,220,220,100]29. Mai\n%c[default]Verdammt! Verdammt! Verdammt! Zwei Tage halten sie uns schon hinter Schloss und Riegel. Ich höre, dass draussen jemand umherstreift, doch niemand antwortet auf unsere Schreie. Bald gehen uns unsere Essensvorräte aus. Gestern hätte jedes Stockwerk frische Lebensmittel erhalten sollen. Einige Kollegen haben erste Panikanfälle, wir versuchen dann sie zu beruhigen, aber es gelingt uns immer weniger. Die Anfälle brechen fast jedes Mal neu aus, wenn wir um Hilfe rufen (testen sie etwa unsere Reflexe aus, oder was?).\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]30. Mai\n%c[default]Das Essen ist ausgegangen, uns bleibt nicht mehr als 2 Liter Wasser... der am meisten entfernte Raum, den wir zu einer Toilette umfunktioniert haben, gibt auf der gesamten Etage einen solch penetranten Gestank von sich, das es schwer fällt zu atmen... Wir haben versucht die eiserne Tür aufzuschlagen. Haben dazu einen massiven Tisch zerbrochen, doch wir haben die Tür nicht aufgekriegt... Draussen können wir niemanden mehr herumschleichen hören, und das ist noch beängstigender. Wir wissen nicht, wann sie das Licht abstellen, das alles mach uns immer mehr Angst...\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]31. Mai\n%c[default]Der Geburtstag eines unserer Kollegen. Als wir hineingingen, um ihm zu gratulieren, baumelte er an einem Strick. Wir versuchten noch ihn zu reanimieren, doch er hing schon zu lange und unsere Bemühungen, sein Leben zu retten, waren vergeblich. Nach einer Weile vermissten wir auch Michailow, der zur Toilette gegangen war. Als wir nachschauten, fanden wir ihn auf dem Boden liegend. Aller Wahrscheinlichkeit nach ein Herzinfarkt. Beide Kollegen wurden im selben Raum zusammengelegt.\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]Datum unbekannt\n%c[default]Im Labor wurde das Licht abgeschaltet, auch die elektronische Uhr, die uns Datum und Zeit anzeigte, leuchtet nicht mehr. Ich schreibe blind. Kann keine klaren Gedanken fassen. Wir haben damit abgeschlossen, dass wir alle dem Tod geweiht sind und uns hier niemand suchen wird. Ich habe nun endlich begriffen, wieso es während der Führung so sauber war und warum das Labor soviele unbesetzte Stellen hatte. Das lag nicht an der Schaffung eines neuen Flügels oder darin, dass das ein noch junges Projekt war. Es lag daran, dass wir von vornherein Todeskandidaten waren. Genau wie auch die vorherige Gruppe von Wissenschaftlern. Sie sind ebenfalls bei den Experimenten gescheitert und alle umgekommen. Es haben nur diejenigen überlebt, die das Experiment leiteten. Diejenigen, die immer aus allen möglichen Situationen sauber herauskommen... Mein Großvater nannte solche nur Stabsratten! Und er hatte verdammt nochmal recht. Nur wir sind hier die Ratten... Versuchsratten... Menschen, die aus freien Stücken zustimmen, sich für die Wissenschaft zu opfern...</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_3_part_1">
	<text>%c[255,220,220,100]Beschlagnahmte Briefe die verboten sind und wieder zurück an Schütze Petrenko ging\n \n%c[default]Geliebte Mutter!\nIch schreibe dir nun nach 2 Monaten Dienstzeit! Ich bedauere dabei kein bisschen, mich für den Kontrakt in der "Zone" gemeldet zu haben. Unsere Kompanie wurde in der Forschungseinrichtung namens "Agroprom" untergebracht. Während der Dienstzeit habe ich bereits meine ersten Befehle erhalten, gestern habe ich meinen nächtlichen Dienst begonnen. Der Dienst selbst ist hier nicht besonders staubig, Schikanen sind nicht vorhanden, so wie der Oberleutnant Chadschinow hier für eiserne Disziplin sorgt.\n \nMach dir keine Sorgen wegen der Strahlung, 86 wurde die Einrichtung komplett gesäubert und von radioaktiven Partikeln dekontaminiert. Die Strahlung auf dem Gelände überschreitet nicht die Norm, aber außerhalb beträgt sie etwa 200-300 µSv/h. Richte Peter aus, dass ich ihm, sobald der Kontrakt endet, irgendein Souvenir mitbringe. Hier gibt es einige interessante Sachen, die man Artefakte nennt. Es gibt welche, die radioaktiv sind und solche, die dich selbst während des Aufenthalts in der kontaminierten Zone vor Strahlung schützen können. Einige unserer Jungs haben sogar versucht, sich selbst einige dieser Artefakte zu erschaffen. Dazu muss man irgendwelche Zutaten auf eine bestimmte Stelle werfen, Anomalie genannt, nach einiger Zeit wird daraus dann ein Artefakt mit einzigartigen Eigenschaften. Mein Zettel ist schon fast voll, ich weiss nicht, was ich dir sonst noch schreiben soll. Mach dir keine Sorgen um mich, Mama! Noch 10 Monate und ich komme nach Hause!\n \nIch verspreche dir alle 2 Monate zu schreiben. Öfter geht es nicht. Außerdem ist das schon der zweite Brief, den ich an dich schicke, und du antwortest nicht. Dein Sascha.\n%c[1,208,60,1]Grund: unabsichtlicher Versuch der Verbreitung von militärischen Geheimnissen, Propaganda über die Zone.\n \n
	\n%c[default]Grüß dich, Kostik!\nSeltsam, das du meinen Brief erst so spät erhalten hast. Ist wahrscheinlich bei der Post verloren gegangen und konnte 'ne Zeit lang nicht gefunden werden. Ich freue mich, dass dir das Foto gefallen hat, das ich dir geschickt habe.\n \nLetztes Mal hab ich doch tatsächlich vergessen zu erwähnen, wer da mit auf dem Foto ist. Wenn du von links nach rechts schaust, steht da am Anfang Petja Brovun, dann kommt Saschka Petrenko (er ist erst seit kurzem bei uns, nur 3 Monate), rechts stehe ich, wie du sicher erraten hast und vor uns sitzt Vitalik Dmitriev. Er wurde gestern ins Lazarett gebracht. Er, Leutnant Subko und Unteroffizier Netschajew waren gerade auf nächtlicher Streife rund um das Institut-Territorium. Und dann musste es ja passieren, ein Blutsauger aus dem Sumpf fiel sie an. Der Mutant hat sich als ziemlich flink erwiesen, Vitaliks Aussage zufolge. Kam nachts aus dem Gebüsch gehuscht, packte sich Netschajew und verschwand ebenso schnell wieder zurück. Ist nach kurzer Zeit wieder herausgesprungen und hat sich an Subko festgekrallt. Vitalik Dmitriev ist zwar nicht grade einer von der feigen Sorte, aber sowas hat er auch noch nicht gesehen, wie direkt vor seinen Augen aus einem lebenden Menschen die Seele ausgesaugt wird. Hat sich tierisch erschrocken. Ist wieder zurück gerannt, hat unterwegs sogar den Helm verloren. Der Blutsauger hat ihn aber doch noch in der Nähe des Tores eingeholt. Oh Mann, wäre nicht der Graue Anton, ich weiß nicht, was mit Vitalik passiert wäre. Aber unser Scharfschütze oben im Turm trifft sogar einem Eichhörnchen ins Auge, genau wie dem Blutsauger, ja selbst einem Tushkano würde er die Nase abschiessen, er verfehlt nie sein Ziel. Ich weiss selbst nicht wie es ihm gelungen ist, aber er hat den Blutsauger erledigt, ohne den Kameraden zu treffen!\n \nSo eine Geschichte war das. Der ist wohl im Hemd geboren worden, nicht anders zu erklären! Morgen schicken sie uns neben Kordon auf Patrouille, die Stalker sind dort ziemlich frech geworden, haben im Stacheldraht Löcher geschnitten und gehen dort ein und aus wie es ihnen passt. Ich erwarte deine Antwort, Kumpel! Und entschuldige, das ich dir solche Neuigkeiten erzähle, aber in unserer Zone gibt es weder Politik, noch Wirtschaft. Also muss ich solche, ja fast schon Krimi-Nachrichten schreiben. Witjok\nP.S. Ich habe immer noch den Verdacht, dass unsere Briefe vor dem Abtransport gelesen werden. Wahrscheinlich ist das auch der Grund, weshalb du nicht alle Briefe erhalten hast.\n%c[1,208,60,1]Grund: unbeabsichtigter Versuch militärische Geheimnisse, sowie vertrauliche Informationen, an eine dritte Person zu verbreiten.\n \n
	\n%c[default]Grüß dich, Brüderchen!\nHab deinen Brief bekommen und wollte dir gleich zurückschreiben, solange ich noch Freizeit habe. Bei mir läuft alles gut, ich diene wie alle anderen. Nur die Gesundheit macht mir ein wenig zu schaffen. In letzter Zeit war ich anfällig gegen alle möglichen Virusinfektionen, wie diese Grippe, die hat mir im Winter schon keine Ruhe gelassen. Die Ärzte sagen, das kommt daher, dass ich während meiner letzten Patrouille von einer Anomalie verstrahlt wurde. Aber ich glaube ihnen nicht.\n \nDiese Stalker verbringen Stunden in der Nähe der Anomalien, sie fürchten sich nicht mal davor neben ihnen zu schlafen, wenn sie Artefakte kochen, und ich war gerademal eine Stunde neben dem "Vortex". Ich denke, ich habe es deshalb, weil sie mir Ende Herbst etwas gespritzt haben... Es kamen irgendwelche Wissenschaftler, wir nannten sie untereinander nur "Eierköpfe" (die haben einen lustigen Anzug). Diese Jungs suchten sich nach einem unbegreiflichen Prinzip Leute aus, darunter auch mich, und haben an denen Impfungen, wie sie es nannten, durchgeführt. Danach brachten sie uns jeden Tag zum Doktor, um uns zu untersuchen, fragten uns nach unserem Befinden und fütterten uns sogar besser als die anderen. Vor kurzem wurden zwei aus unserer Impf-Gruppe von diesen Eierköpfen mitgenommen.\n \nIch weiss bis heute nicht, wofür. Aber die beiden beklagten sich über häufige Kopf- und Rückenschmerzen. Vielleicht wurden sie zur weiteren Behandlung abtransportiert? Es ist nur seltsam, weil das Lazarett hier am modernsten in der gesamten Zone ausgestattet ist. Wäre denkbar, dass sie uns etwas verheimlichen. Aber ich werde nicht so schnell aufgeben, ich habe einen starken Organismus und werde nicht so krank werden wie sie! Ich verspreche es, Brüderchen! Richte der gesamten Verwandschaft meine Grüße aus. Ich hab es nicht mehr solange, noch 3 Monate und mein Kontrakt geht zuende.\n%c[1,220,60,1]Grund: unabsichtlicher Versuch, ein streng geheimes Experiment und weitere Informationen an dritte Personen zu verbreiten.\n \n
	\n%c[default]Hallo Mama!\nIch schreibe dir gleich nachdem ich von einer Patrouille zurückgekehrt bin. Ich habe hier gerademal einen Monat gedient, aber ich bereue meine Entscheidung schon jetzt. Mutter, ich habe heute zum ersten Mal einen Menschen getötet. Auch wenn mich diese Leute, die hier herumlungern, nicht gerade an Menschen erinnern, die ich aus unserem Dorf gewöhnt bin. Sie ähneln mehr seelenlosen Maschinen, die bereit sind für einen funkelnden Gegenstand zu töten. Sie sind wie Elstern, sammeln alles was glänzt und schlecht gesichert ist. Sie sind sogar fähig, sich selbst zu zerfleischen, nur um an einen funkelnden Stein, eine Flasche Wodka, ein Granatenbündel oder ein paar Turnschuhe zu gelangen.\n \nDas sind keine Menschen mehr. Sie sind schlimmer als die Wölfe, die ich mit Vater gejagt habe. Aber dieser Stalker... Er hatte mehr Menschlichkeit in sich, als alle unsere Kameraden zusammen. Ging verwundet in Richtung von Kordon, schleifte sein Maschinengewehr nur mit Mühe hinter sich her. Wir dachten zuerst daran ihn passieren zu lassen, aber unser Leutnant gab ihm den Befehl, seine Waffe fallen zu lassen. Hat sich wohl einreden wollen, dass dieser sie ja doch nicht mehr braucht. Doch dieser Typ schaute uns dann plötzlich mit einem schmerzverzerrten Blick an, mit einem Schmerz der ihn innerlich zerriss... er bat uns, ihn zu retten, ihn von diesen Schmerzen zu erlösen. Victor Tichonyk meinte zu mir, er würde wahrscheinlich von Innen heraus mutieren, hätte höllische Schmerzen und es wäre besser, ihn lieber nicht durchzulassen. Aber der hat wahrscheinlich den Unteroffizier gehört, und versuchte sein Gewehr hochzuheben und auf uns zu richten. Der Leutnant gab uns den Befehl, ihn zu erschiessen und ich habe ihn, wie alle anderen Soldaten, ins Visier genommen und abgedrückt.\n \nIch weiss nicht, warum ich geschossen habe. Ringsum gab es nämlich genug Schützen. In wenigen Sekunden haben wir einen menschlichen Körper in einen blutigen Kadaver verwandelt. Einige unserer Neulinge baten den Leutnant darum, sich den Stalker ansehen zu dürfen, aber allein von der Vorstellung, wie er vom Nahen aussieht wurde mir übel. Der Leutnant lächelte nur und sagte, "dass alle normalen Menschen beim ersten Mal so reagieren".  Den Neuen, die ihn von Nahem sehen wollten, sagte er, sie würden noch in ihrer weiteren Dienstzeit genug Gelegenheiten bekommen, noch schlimmeres zu sehen. Danach wollte ich alles hinschmeissen und wieder in unser Dorf zurückkehren.\n \nIch vermisse wahnsinnig deine Piroschki, mit frischer Milch von den Kühen am frühen Morgen. Aber du weißt ja selbst, wie wir das Geld, das ich hier in der Zone bekomme, benötigen. Mit dem Geld können wir deine Operation bezahlen. Damit schaffen wir es noch rechtzeitig deine Krankheit zu heilen, bevor sie richtig ausbricht. Ich küsse dich, Mutter! Und mach dir keine Sorgen um mich! Ich bin stark und halte es schon aus!\n%c[1,198,20,1]Grund: Zibenko Valentina Alekseewna lebt nicht länger unter folgender Adresse: Dorf Polanskoje, Haus Nr. 35.</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_4_part_1">
	<text>%c[255,220,220,100]Erster Tag.\n%c[default]Heute gehe ich zum ersten Mal in die Zone, für einen kleinen Raid! Die ortsansässigen sagen, ein Raid - das wäre ein Raubzug nach etwas wertvollem. Der Mann, der mir den Auftrag erteilte, erklärte mir, wenn ich lernen will hier zu überleben, wäre ein Raid zu wenig. Aber dieser wäre eine Prüfung. "Steinblume"... Interessant, was genau ist das? Er hat mir ein unscharfes Bild davon gezeigt, ich habs aber nicht wirklich zuordnen können. Irgendwelche Linien, ein Aufblitzen... Flammen in verschiedenen Farben. Aber er sagte mir, wenn ich dieses Ding finde, kann ich es nicht verwechseln. "Steinblume"... Oh Mann, ich komme mir vor wie ein verdammter Anfänger. Egal. Er hat mir gutes Geld versprochen und sagte, es gäbe noch einen Bonus, wenn ich schnell mache. Dieser Typ scheint eine lokale Autorität zu sein - woher hat er sonst all diese Dinge in seinem Bunker?\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]Zweiter Tag.\n%c[default]Ich bin noch am Leben. Das ist das wichtigste – vor ein paar Stunden hätte es auch anders ausgehen können. Kann sebst kaum glauben, dass ich es geschafft habe... Irgendein Mistvieh, so groß wie ein Panzer, kam aus nem Talkessel und fiel aus dem Schatten über mich her. Wie konnte ich nur so schnell mein Gewehr ziehen??? Das ist er – der militärische Drill... Und ich dachte, die zwei Jahre wären nutzlos gewesen. Wenn ich zurückkomme, stelle ich die größte Kerze für die Gesundheit meines alten Feldwebels auf. Obwohl es hier in der Nähe wohl kaum ein Kirche gibt... Na gut, dann trinke ich einfach auf seine Gesundheit – er lehrte mich das Schießen, dieser Lumpensack... Das Gewehr werde ich aber nicht länger schultern. Mit der Knarre im Anschlag fühle ich mich sicherer, auch wenn es ein wenig unbequem ist.\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]Dritter Tag.\n%c[default]Ich hab's gefunden!!! Es war genauso, wie der Typ im Bunker gesagt hat!!! Die Blume... Sie ist wunderschön, ich habe noch nie so etwas Schönes gesehen!!! Ich habe es lange in den Händen gehalten, und sie strahlte... So sehen sie also aus – die Artefakte. Es tut einem fast schon leid, sie wieder abzugeben – ist schließlich mein erster Erfolg. Also gut, wird Zeit zurückzukehren.\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]Sechster Tag.\n%c[default]Üble Sache. Hab fast keine Munition mehr, und ich habe mich anscheinend verlaufen. Der Platz kommt mir bekannt vor, ich erinnere mich an diesen Hügel, diese drei Bäume neben dem Brunnen... Aber irgendwas scheint verändert zu sein, als ob... Ich weiß nicht. Und auf dem Rückweg werde ich noch zusätzlich von allen möglichen Viechern angegriffen. Meistens nur Kleinvieh, aber ziemlich flink – hab sämtliche Magazine verschossen. Ist nur noch Schrot übrig, fünf Patronen. Wenn mich was Grösseres als ein Hund anfällt – bin ich fällig.\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]Sechster Tag, abends.\n%c[default]Noch ein riesiges Mistvieh hat mich angefallen! Hat auf mich in einem Hinterhalt gewartet!! So wie in der Nacht, als ich hierher kam! Ich werde nie wieder diese Fratze und seine Reisszähne vergessen... Merkwürdig, aber dieses Tier sah aus wie ein Eber. Nur riesiger, mit vielen Reisszähnen, hab's nicht geschafft sie zu zählen. Oder vielleicht ist mir das in meiner Angst nur so erschienen? Weiss nicht. Er griff mich so schnell an, ich war ganz starr vor Angst, als wäre ich gelähmt!! Ich konnte nur zusehen, wie er auf mich zu rannte, als plötzlich... Als wäre es auf eine unsichtbare Barriere gestoßen – wurde das Viech hoch in den Himmel geschleudert, fing dann an sich zu drehen, und dann... Mein Gott, das hätte auch ich an seiner Stelle sein können! Also sind die Gerüchte im Lager über diese Anomalien wahr. Verflucht, wo bin ich hier nur gelandet!?\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]Siebter Tag.
	\n%c[default]Morgens kam es mir vor, als hätte ich einen Menschen gesehen. Wahrscheinlich eine Halluzination – hier kann es doch keinen unbewaffneten Menschen in Jeans geben... Ja, und sein Kopf war ziemlich gross. Vielleicht kommt das von der Steinblume – meine Hände sind ganz rot geworden, Hals und Rücken jucken fürchterlich. Möglicherweise ist es radioaktiv? In den Augen verschwimmt alles... Und dieser Lärm in den Ohren, wie Stimmen... Wahrscheinlich hab ich mich vergiftet... Es wäre besser, wenn ich schneller ankommen würde. Wo bin ich nur?\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]Siebter Tag. Abend.\n%c[default]Es fällt mir schwer zu sprechen... Dieser Mensch... Er folgt mir, die ganze Zeit schon... Einmal habe ich sein Gesicht gesehen. So nah, dabei war er weit weg. Wie kann das sein? Es lärmt in den Ohren... Er spricht so, das ist seine Stimme, wie ein Windgeräusch... Und ein Pfeifen... Nein, er ist kein Mensch, er... ist anders... Er weiss, wo ich mich versteckt habe... die Hände gehorchen mir nicht...\n \n%c[255,220,220,100]Letzter Eintrag.\n%c[default](Rauschen, Knacken) Lass mich...(Lärm)...ich...muss nach Hause...Dunkel...sehr dunkel...Grosser, lass mich gehen...Oder sterben...besser so...er...erlaubt nicht, zu gehen...Pistole hab ich...Patronen...eine...wenn es mir nur gelingt...lass mich gehen...nein...bitte nicht...stör mich nicht...das war's...(Schussgeräusch. Rauschen. Knacken. Abbruch der Aufnahme)</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_5_part_1">
	<text>%c[255,220,220,100]Bericht Nr. 25-19-12u.\n \n%c[default]Ich hab's geschafft!! Ich fahre in die Zone! Alle aus dem Labor haben mir heute gratuliert, sogar der leitende wissenschaftliche Mitarbeiter Kovalew. Ungeachtet dessen, das er mich nicht mag, kam er rüber, schüttelte mir die Hand und sagte: "Ich gratuliere, Genosse Pankov!" Hat unaufrichtig gelächelt – war wohl zuviel verlangt. Trotzdem bin ich glücklich! Ich werde nun selbst die Orte sehen, aus denen wir die meisten Objekte fur die Untersuchungen erhalten. Vielleicht schaffe ich es sogar noch, meine Dissertation dieses Jahr zu beenden!\n \nVor Ort ist es ganz anders, als ich erwartet habe. Die wissenschaftlichen Apparate sind mir größtenteils unbekannt. Semenow – der Assistent des Laborleiters und stellvertretender Leiter des ML-4 (Mobiles Lager) – sagt, das sie direkt vor Ort hergestellt wurden und sich in ihnen einige örtliche Artefakte befinden. Unfassbar, wie weit die Wissenschaft hier in der Zone fortgeschritten ist!\n \nHeute war ein schwieriger Tag. Wir haben es nur mit viel Glück geschafft, uns vor dem sich einschaltenden Reaktor in Sicherheit zu bringen. Semenow nahm Messungen der Strahlungsintensivität vor und ich leitete sie per Funk an Kruglow weiter, einem weiteren leitenden Forschungsmitarbeiter, er kam mir ein wenig eingebildet vor..., als plötzlich der Geigerzahler voll ausschlug. Mit etwas Glück konnten wir entkommen. Die Erde bebte, als ob unter der Fabrik ein Vulkan ausbricht! Welche Anlage nur ist dazu imstande? Wie mächtig muss sie sein!? Semenow meinte, ich sollte den Hügel hinaufklettern und das Fabrikgelände mit dem Fernglas auskundschaften, wenn ich verstehen will was hier so vor sich geht. Interessant, wofür eigentlich? Oder hat er sich nur einen Scherz erlaubt?\n \n
	Zum ersten Mal habe ich wirklich Angst. Ich habe Semenows Rat befolgt... bin mit einem Feldstecher auf einen hohen Baum geklettert und mich umgesehen, was sich im Inneren des Fabrikgelandes abspielt... Oh Gott, dort sind ja Menschen!!! Sie laufen im Kreis, fast so wie Nachtwandler! Einige von ihnen haben Forscherkleidung an, wie es aussieht, sind einige verletzt... Was ist mit ihnen? Warum kommen sie nicht heraus? Ich muss mir uberlegen, wie ich ihnen helfen kann. Heute sind Semenow und Kruglow weggefahren, sagten, es dauert nicht allzu lange. Schade, das heißt ich muss alleine gehen. Ich muss mehr Medikits einpacken, für die Forscher dort drinnen. Und vielleicht eine Waffe. Obwohl ich bisher nur in der Schießbude geschossen habe, mit einem Druckluftgewehr. Ach was soll's, fur alle Fälle.\n \nIch stecke in einer Falle, unweit der Fabrik, auf dem Dach irgendeiner Werkhalle. Unglaublich, aber die Leute werden von einem Monster kontrolliert, einem aufrechtgehenden Zweibeiner!!! Diese Parodie eines Menschen tragt Jeans! Es fällt mir schwer zu schreiben – anscheinend wirkt sich die PSI-Strahlung auf meine Koordination aus. Gut, das der Reaktor jetzt nicht aktiv ist – ich hab's selbst überprüft. STOP. Woher kommt dann die PSI-Strahlung? WAS GEHT HIER VOR? Wäre es möglich, dass dieses Monster PSI-Wellen generiert? Nur gut, das er mich nicht gesehen hat... Ich muss ihn erschießen... Wichtig ist – das ich ihn in den Kopf treffe, wenn ich vorbeischieße – bin ich tot. Zombies (leider kann man diese Stalker und Forscher, die um ihn herumschleichen nicht anders nennen... Was fur ein Horror...) sie schießen, wohin er ihnen zeigt, wenn ich ihn nicht sofort töte, machen sie aus mir einen Sieb. Aber ich muss es versuchen. Das ist meine Pflicht, fur all die unglücklichen Gestalten neben ihm... \n \nAn den, der das findet und liest... \n \nIch bin verwundet. Kann mich nicht bewegen – das Projektil traf mich genau in die Wirbelsaule... Trotz aller Schmerzen schreibe ich, es ist wahrscheinlich, dass ich schon bald mein Bewusstsein verliere – wenn ich Glück habe... Leider bin ich ein beschissener Schütze – habe das ganze Magazin verschossen, und alles daneben. Ich höre, wie das Monster zu mir aufsteigt. Ich habe wenig Zeit. Er braucht mich nicht lebend, da ich verwundet bin – ich sah, wie er einen Zombie aß, als sich dieser mit seinem Bein in einer Lüke verfing und es sich brach... Hoffentlich geht es schnell... Ich fürchte mich. Lebt wohl. Ich habe für diese Menschen alles getan was ich konnte.\n \nAssistenz-Mitarbeiter Pankow</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_6_part_1">
	<text>%c[255,220,220,100]Tagebuch von Swetoslaw "Schisser" Dedenko\n \n%c[1,208,210,100]13. April 2010\n%c[default]Was zu fressen wär nicht schlecht... Keine Kohle, also fahre ich in die Zone. Schwierig ohne Moneten... Das wird der erste Tag sein, der Tag der Ankunft, ab dann nur noch ohne Datumsangaben...\n \n%c[1,208,210,100]Tag 7.\n%c[default]Bereits eine Woche... Zeit vergeht hier schneller als außerhalb der Zone. Jetzt ist das keine Zone mehr, sondern eine „ZONE“.\n \n%c[1,208,210,100]Tag 12.\n%c[default]Zusammen mit dem ""Grauen", dem "Ganoven" und dem "Lahmarsch" machen wir uns auf zur Mulldeponie... Mitten durch den Posten...\n \n%c[1,208,210,100]Tag 13.\n%c[default]Verfluchte Banditen... Haben mir in den Arm geschossen... Am Unterarm... Scheiße, wie das schmerzt... Ich hasse sie...\n \n%c[1,208,210,100]Tag 15.\n%c[default]Fotzen!... Sie haben ihn getötet... DIE HABEN DEN "LAHMARSCH" GETÖTET!!! Ich bring sie alle um, ohne Gnade und Reue... \n \n%c[1,208,210,100]Tag 20.\n%c[default]Die Wunde ist geschwollen, tut höllisch weg, ich muss in die Bar, vielleicht können die mir dort helfen... Scheiße, tut das weh... Proviant ist fast alle...\n \n%c[1,208,210,100]Tag 21.\n%c[default]Wir haben irgendein... Artefakt gefunden. Strahlt Wärme aus, der Zähler vom "Ganoven" schlägt leicht aus, die Wunde hat aufgehört so stark zu schmerzen... Das ist gut...\n \n%c[1,208,210,100]Tag 25.\n%c[default]Haben es bis zum Wächterposten geschafft, die haben uns zuerst nicht reinlassen wollen, doch als sie die Wunde bemerkten, haben die ganz schnell das Tor aufgemacht.\n \n%c[1,208,210,100]Tag 26.\n%c[default]Der Lagerarzt sagt, dass man zu Sacharow muss, um die Medikamente zu bekommen, er hat sogar fur einen Führer gesorgt, das Artefakt mussen wir leider den Forschern überlassen. Schade, ist wirklich bezaubernd... Halt, was ist mit mir? Ich geb ihn ab und das war's... \n \nDer "Ganove" arbeitet jetzt fur den Wirt, aber der "Grauer"... es gibt keinen "Grauen" mehr...\n \n%c[1,208,210,100]Tag 30.\n%c[default]Sacharow hat mir die Medikamente gespritzt, ist schon fast wieder verheilt. Das Artefakt hat er an sich genommen, hat sich als sehr selten rausgestellt... Ich arbeite jetzt fur sie, die haben mir sogar einen Forscheranzug gegeben. Jetzt werden wir zum hiesigen Laboratorium gehen. Wie heißt das Ding noch mal, ach, genau! X-16!\n \n%c[1,208,210,100]Tag 32.\n%c[default]Grauenhaft... irgend so ein Scheißding unter der Erde... Strahler... Die Zombies sind jetzt hier... gruselig...\n \n%c[1,208,210,100]Tag 60.\n%c[default]Ein Schnork hat mich gebissen... Seltsam, aber ich fühle keinen Schmerz! Habe nur Hunger auf... FLEISCH!\n \n%c[1,208,210,100]Tag 62.\n%c[default]Rrrrr... Nahrung... essen... RRRR... FLEISCH! Rrr... Oh, wie schlecht... kan nicht mal meer richtig schhreiben... ab jetzt nur noch Aufn-rr-ahmen mit einem Diii-iktierrr-rgerät!...\n \nTag 63.\n \nA-u-r-r-r... e-e-s-s-s-e-n! Essen... u-r-r-r</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_7_part_1">
	<text>%c[255,220,220,100](START DER AUFNAHME)\n \n%c[default]...ein Dreckskerl ist das, aber egal, ich kann ja nicht den ganzen Krempel zu Sidorowitch tragen, kenne aber keinen anderen Hehler. Fur die Munition sollte das Geld noch reichen.\n \nDie Bar – ist die Oase der Zone. Ständig gehen welche ein und aus, Banditen und Monster gibt es fast nicht – die Wächter verscheuchen sie, ist ja praktisch ihre Basis.\n \nSo... Noch ein Gläschen hinterher – und dann ein kleines Schläfchen. Die Stalker wollen aber zur Arena, und sich das Schauspiel reinziehen...\n \n Tja, wieder ein trüber Morgen. Obwohl, wie sagt man so schön – Stalker saufen nicht – Stalker kurieren sich aus. Ich erinnere mich noch gut an ein Gespräch mit so 'nem Kerl, "Glatze" glaub ich... Erzählte was von einem Werk in Jantar, dem Lager der Eierkopfe am See, und wie viel Geld sie fur einfache "Steinblumen" hinlegen. Wenn du mit einem seltenen Artefakt ankommst, sind sie sogar bereit, dir das letzte Hemd herzugeben. Was soll man schon machen, sind eben Forschungsfanatiker... Es gibt aber auch einen Nachteil – den PSI-Reaktor. Selbst hab ich noch keinen Zombie getroffen, aber wenn man mit den Veteranen redet, die dort waren – ist das kein schöner Anblick.\n \n"Glatze" erzählte, er hatte sich mit einem Stalker angefreundet, der sogar seinen Plünder mit ihm geteilt hat, im Kampf seinen Rücken gedeckt, und in der Bar zusammen Wodka getrunken hat, und ihm vor einer Woche auf dem Weg von Jantar begegnet ist (ist angeblich alleine auf einen Streifzug gegangen). Er meinte, er ging wie aufgezogen, geradewegs, fast in eine Anomalie hinein. Murmelte irgendwas vor sich hin, sein Sturmgewehr hinter sich herziehend. "Glatze" hat ihn gerufen, aber der Freund hat nur mit einem Feuerstoß reagiert, bis sein Magazin leer war. Da hat "Glatze" begriffen, dass sein Kumpel sein Hirn in Jantar gekocht hat und zu einem Zombie geworden ist. Kurz gesagt, musste er seinen Kollegen mit den eigenen Händen umbringen...\n \nTraurig... In Wirklichkeit ist das Zählen des Geldes, nach dem man seinen Nahrungs- und Munitionsvorrat, sowie die Medikits wieder aufgefüllt hat, noch viel trauriger. Wie auch immer, morgen breche ich in Richtung Jantar auf.\n \nDer Wirt sagt, das es einen Weg durch eine Eisenbahnkreuzung, oder wie das heißt, nach Jantar gibt ... Naturlich gibt es dort auch eine Menge Anomalien – ich sollte also besser mehr Bolzen und Muttern mitnehmen.\n \nGlück gehabt! Bin bis zur Brucke gekommen, die auf dem Weg nach Jantar liegt, ohne einem einzigen Söldner zu begegnen. Ehrlich gesagt musste ich einen großen Umweg machen, weil am Güterwagen ein Blutsauger rumschnuffelte. Gut, das ich ihn rechtzeitig bemerkte. Als ich unter der Brücke war, ist mir doch glatt der Kiefer runtergefallen – den ganzen Durchgang hindurch waberte die Luft, wie von einem erhitzten Metalldach an einem heißen Sommertag. So viele "Brenner" hab ich noch nie gesehen! Fast eine Stunde hab ich gebraucht, um durchzukommen, hab 'ne Menge Bolzen verbraucht, Drecksanomalien. Dafür hab ich mir Artefakte eingesackt – 3 Feuerbälle und 5 irgendwelche birnenähnliche Dinger. Jetzt mach ich ein kleines Raucherpauschen, sitze im Schatten, die Strasse... VERDAMMT! Wen hat es denn jetzt hierhin verschlagen??...\n \n So ist es also, dieses Jantar... Eine riesige Halle auf dem Hügel, Sumpf mit einem abgeschossenen Heli, der Forscherbunker, auf dem ich es mir gemütlich gemacht habe – und Stille. "Glatze" hat nicht gelogen – dem wissenschaftlichen Leiter, Sacharow, glaub ich, sind fast die Augen rausgefallen, als er meine Beute erblickt hat. Nahm all meine Artefakte und hat mir einen Riesen Batzen Kohle zugesteckt, hab noch nie für einen einzigen Raid soviel verdient! Hat mich aber nicht in den Bunker gelassen, von wegen Quarantane und Strahlung – na ja, was soll's, auf dem Dach, dem Hubschrauberlandeplatz, kann man auch ganz gut entspannen.
	Only scary here. Quiet, only snorks roam the bushes, and zombies... I first met this on the way to Yantar, when I made a halt at the road. In the black kombeze dolgovtsa, left side burned, as if in a fire or fell into the hot flew, hobbling gait, because one foot is dislocated or broken. I wanted to wait when it will pass, and this bastard somehow sensed where I zatiharilsya and shmalnula PE-EMA. I had to soak, but until I told him Bosko has not carried a shotgun, he still tried to get up - a lot, you rat. Terrible sight.\n \nIt's time to move back to the bar. 'll Get on there than the thread-standing, can the 'Abakan' enough, and kombez change does not interfere. Bald meeting - affixed to a tip about scientists thanks to him.\nTaak... There's someone with gorochki down, Wait a look, that for the...\n \n(a loud low-frequency hum)\n \n... MMAT! WHAT ??!\n \nStep. Step. Road.\nNext. Forward.\nHube... Hub... swag...\nBar. Bar...Man...\nbartender. Barryga...\nStahl... ker...\nstalker.\n \n(bang, shout: 'Stop, you stalker! Put down the barrel! ')\n... became... STAAALKER!\n \n(sound distortion shutter)\nMOCHIIIIII!\n(long machine gun fire)\n \n%c[255,220,220,100](end of record)%c[default]</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_8_part_1">
	<text>... there is no beginning, the record is hopelessly spoiled...\n \n... Waffles, fat bitch. Someday I 'll nail them. Ugly bastards, they said that the blue Kosoy today blew nonsense in the ravine and nichrome not on duty. As always oblique, that's bitch. Shit...\nNow taschus with this washed-up idiot waffles (do not forget to slap on the quiet, blue say patrol) to look for a stalker. Mad, Cheshenny... I do not remember how to. Blue said in order to collect the package should be, too, is fag. Sam would go and take away...\n--- \nPancake, today went through Agroprom fucking ugly place, the boys said that here to fuck the military, and we found only one body. Fastened to the branch... Someone tried so highly of his implant. We must say that the kid would come, look, funny stuff. Waffles all whining that leg rubbed, told him - that would not save sneakers, but not the same wafer smartest.\n--- \ n've broken screen PDA, now I can only listen and speak. Waffles, bitch, laugh... Well, I did bang it soon, do not pull this same bitch back?\n--- \nThat's no waffles... hell, I thought it bang, but fate decreed otherwise. While we slept we crept to the leech. Shit, that's disgusting monster. He rushed to the wafers, the world of his vile soul, and harassed him as Fido warmer, and he yelled, fuck... so yell that I almost went crazy. Barely escaped...\nAnd where am I now? House somewhere and no dick is not clear. Where to go?\n--- \nShit... I'll definitely be back, but when I come back uroyu bitch Tolstoy, Alexei fag, but can still and blue. Devil's house, where I knew that there den tushkanov? Barely escaped, now in some woods...\n--- \nOnly to return. Irony... That stalker... we cut and he looked at me and said I do not come from the Zone... hell, his eyes...\n--- \nNow, under a snag, fuck... As soon release said PDA, and then as luck would have no shitty hollow.\n---- \n(noise emission)\nWhat a headache... and those eyes, stalker forgive me if you can, I will fuck... back and pray for your soul...\n---- \n(... start recording spoiled... noise emissions)\n... hell I will not survive this day... terrible headache... Curse on your head Blue... I must be back...</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_9_part_1">
	<text>06:00\nAh... It is time to get up... Hmm, yes, I said Tolia, should not have been the fifth bottle! How's your head splits... Damn, sorry, no such Arta, that took off a hangover!\n \n06:48\nPancake, yet almost no money! At the plate is not enough! That's because Tolik bastard, take a bottle, take... Well! Heard, Sidorovich wants something on the farm to find, we ought to go ask me there nychka because, at the same time it found out.\n \n07:02\nI asked from him about this farm... Greet need me, you know, the eye of the flesh, although I have heard from other stalkers of such orders, but he ran for the first time... well at least not the brains, but it would trephine (or as it is there) I had to do. Well you can already gather.\n \n07:15\nAbout! Met the Academic Andryukha (and we heard that he's not kicked the bucket) he immediately found a den pseudodog. It speaks for its tail can give money, and good! In general, I agreed with him, together dog arrived.\n \n07:29\ndecided to go through the ATP, although they say that there were entrenched crooks, but it can, slipped and did not notice...\n \n07:53\nOof! Well at least Andryukha PB was, or he would set fire to us! That's because you rat! I sat so that it immediately and you will not notice!\n \n08:06\nWell, that tunnel, I see this dog is settled, look how many bones lying! Even scared somehow, never seen these pseudodog, blind firing, and these...\n \n08:27\nThis is because scum! I sat and waited in the tunnel when we'll go! Oh, sorry for Andrei, he was a good stalker... Well, I have a tail, must now walk to the village.\n \n09:13\ndecided to bypass the ATP, go just to the north, above what would warriors did not notice... Damn even a headache.\n \n09:28\nE-me! Controller! Here! Can not be...\n \n09:35\nYes, it... Exactly he eats something, and can not get around...\n \n09:43\nfigured out I've got nychka a locomotive, there stick of dynamite. Before him not dokinu, but can divert attention, can manage to get around.\n \n09:45\nFuh! I walked! Pulled, of course, not very... see damp, but oh well... distracted and \n \n09:46\nHmm... What if...\n \n09:48\nYes! I got! Hit!\n \n09:50\nWow... fill up the Controller of Toza with the first shot! Not everyone can boast of! What's this? PDA?\n \n09:53\nM-da... That's how is. Area...\n \n10:43\nYes I must! Without adventure reached. Sidorovich reptile such, the tail gave the total some 7500 hryvnia! Well, at least patrons poured.\n \n11:20\ntold about the controller, no one believed... He, he But when returned to listen to a recording device, once all was hushed, that the same! Well, today all, man can not both be taken!\n \n09:27\nSomething I was worn out... so woke up late... Bliiin! Fighters have the guard changed, and there was a neighbor! We'll have to pay for the transition, the devil...\n \n10:39\nHe came to the mound without incident, paid in 2500 for the transition, there bloodsuckers!\n \n10:51\nXe, and grunts there running around. But what's this? Bandits! As they were here! Thus, while there? Ooops! Cabana... Two... Four... Six... But how many are there? Twelve! The devil must go!\n \n11:25\nM-yes... I'm sitting in a tree... all bandyukov ate, I have not noticed...\n \n15:43\nThese creatures are gone. Ohohia... All served! Hmm...\n \n15:52\nWell, that's farm... Oh, well, I go...\n \n16:10\nYes, sir, here they staged a den! Oh! And here is the mumps... Dead... Well, now where's my knife? Damn cut uncomfortable... This is what's the buzz? Your mother did! Cabana! Aah! AT! MORE! Creature...</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_10_part_1">
	<text>From the diary of an unknown stalker.\n \n13.04.12 6:00\nM-yes, again... How much area had heard about her, but in reality it... she... can not even express in words all the feelings when you see it! Today, decided to come back to Agroprom. It is said that after the release of there a lot of artifacts, and even bought a map of the dungeon Institute.\n \n8:50\nAmazingly, no one and nothing met (knock, knock touch wood!). He stopped at the dump, at the hangar. Inside, find someone's corpse, probably a beginner - there is not automatic, and the double-barreled shotgun (by the way in good condition, must be tucked away, can I will take away the next time). In the vicinity there is no one, well and good.\n \n11:00\nWell, I had almost come. Hmm, and artifacts at not so much vapor 'flower' and 'Gravi' . Now, only the plant and left all hope, and even ammunition and a map in debt taken (so Sidorovich controller took! Although such a monster fuck who would win, he himself had a ram's horn was seized and still make to buy something, damn!)\n \n12:45\nclimbed onto the roof, as in time! Downstairs was bloodsucker! That's because skunk sitting in ambush, went to the building and all the Khan would be me! Well that was a grenade with him... As well, she nailed it! All mug intact, so I can cut the tentacles, at least some money.\n \n13:00\nThat bastard! He then turns dining room! He counted four corpses. Found Eureka (last name he still had some famous... but! Semetsky!), Was a good guy... And we thought he went to Moscow, to his friend the writer. Ah, another good stalker killed...\n \n14:00\nWell, that's dungeon... damn still had to buy a night vision device! And so with a flashlight can not see anything.\n \n14:15\nSomething quiet... a feeling that there is someone walking on a regular basis (have heard that there is a cache group! and even though she went to the leader of the burner and back!)\n \n14:30\nFound 'Hedgehog'! Well at least something worthwhile.\n \n14:35\nDamn! Another bloodsucker! Well I managed to shoot. Strangely, he looked at the duct, as if waiting for something.\n \n14:40\nHa! And these rumors are true about hiding! There is a staircase and... hell banner!\n \n17:10\nHow it hurts! They set a trap to all stalkers to keep it out there... And I'm a fool Popper, thought of nothing! Hmm, well that is not F-1, and will not be lying here, and rest in heaven... While I'm in a state that can not climb the stairs...\n \n17:50\nThis is the end, I crawled and got into the 'Jelly' , I have all the hands in this...\n \n18:00\nI do not see anything... But no, I see the light! Yes, the light...</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_11_part_1">
	<text>Diary of the experiment \n \nProject: APEC \nTop Secret. Only for official use.\n \nExperience 143\n \nObject: \nWhite male 33 years old.\nHeight - 180\nWeight - 100 kg.\n... was taken to a research center under the personal supervision of Professor Selezneva...\n(... part of the document spoiled water...)\n... document attached transcript: \n \nFirst Day \n17.00\nObject a man, 33 years old. He suffers from severe daunizma. Understand human speech. Obedient.\nI entered the object serum L14-OS. We observe the process.\n \n20.00\nAfter the initial diagnosis...\n(... part of the document a broken water...)\n \n21.30\n(... part of the document is not...)\n... external signs: redness in the elbow and knee bends, as lymph nodes... Object complaining of feeling unwell. Increase the dose of serum. Added some substance from the draft Berserk (under my own responsibility).\n \nSecond Day \npersonal writing: \nObject calmed down after yesterday. I was able to explore the recently begun to show outward signs of change. I hope this experiment will succeed. The object name is Vitaly. He came to us [information not be disclosed. Cross out censorship] is very obedient object. Dad thinks I am. He, he Let's see how my 'boy' sings on.\n \n10.32\nhmmm... I think my idea about [information not be disclosed. dipped censored] from Berserk was a good idea. The object is extremely active and almost no sleep.
                Today, a complex of primary physical tests.\n \n10.54\namazing! Phenomenal. Wit... er... The object has become much stronger. During the experiment, he raised the barbell weighing 150 kg. To experience it was 80... (...Part of document missing...)... Object cleverly moves the Swedish wall, even upside down... (... Not quite a big part of the document...)\n \nDay 14\n10.00\nobject can not see the light of hospital lights. We must seek advice from knowledgeable experts on the subject. I do not know what it is, or may be nervous eye effects of large doses of drugs.\n \nWhile the mask gave him written off guard. The object is pinned on his head and is worn on the ward. It turned out pretty... fun. Associate Ivianiec said that since they were running elephants in the army.\n(Ask the manager to replace Ivantsov, my lab clowns do not have to)\nProperty has become even stronger. Anginal unwarranted aggression, I think to reduce serum concentrations of (inaudible). I'm afraid now it will not be able to retain and five nurses.\n \n14.00\nexamination revealed a significant increase in the elasticity of tendons. The object can not be dislocations, despite the fact that he often falls from a great height. I think the material on his tendons enough for a thesis. [Remark verifies: Sidortsova have to isolate the end of the experiment] \n \nhead ordered to take an object mask, object growled and squealed, nurses could barely cope with it. (I do is to increase security, today they are no longer sufficient)\n \nDay 15\n10.30\nall day today will conduct experiments jumping... (... Blurry water...)\n \n18.00\nThe object is to pass through the jumping distance of almost 18 metres! This... (... Most of the documents is not...)...\nIndividual entries: \nHead, Professor Schultz ranting and raving. Vitaly and before the experiment was not very 'gifted' , and now finally unconscious. Yes... Today, he threw another trick, I could not make out machine. Yes we did he do yesterday explained!
                  \n \nIt does not even. Only grunts or growls. The object did not want vylazit the ward, lured out of his mask. I had to give him his favorite toy.\n12.10\nspent the last inspection of the object.\n400 contractions of the heart muscle in a minute. But his heart drives the blood as reactive. Very elastic tendons. Bone seriously saturated by calcium. The frontal bone thickening twice.\nThe object is not honoring the pain does not notice the wounds... (... A piece of paper chewed and not readable...)...\n \nIndividual entries: \n... Schultz said that the experiment is almost fails, object (does not turn the language to call it Vitalik... no, this is not he more...) is completely controllable, yesterday on our walk, he gnawed a medic and tried to escape. Barely caught... (... End of the document is not...)</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_12_part_1">
	<text>Notes Byvaly \n \nJune 3, 2010\nI'm sitting at the bar. Beside me, my partner, Yakut his nickname. A good stalker, experienced. On the table, vodka, canned food, sausage, hlebushek... Well, that is rich Bartender... eats from the soul, tomorrow raid...\n \nJune 4\nWell, it's time and way. Immediately next to the bar base Duty, Duc Sergeant Vasilyuk gave us allowance at full rate: food, barrels of good - I have a Colt and AK-108 with personal belongings: optics, there podstvolnik, silencers, etc. Yakut took the Emku sixteenth and Beretta, personal belongings, too, slapped, gave ammunition, new overalls, with night vision, flashlights, toilet paper... yes, in case the boar near you vzbryknet, and you do good in the pants)) Sometimes it happens, not a stalker with a wet spot in the middle come.\n... We went to General Voronin in the barracks, he told us the problem set - to reach the military depots, where freedom is based, they say, if anything, they perekantovatsya (general when he said, as much frowned - but do not love each other the duty of freedom), then through checkpoints to reach the radar and into the cellars of some down - Che-there off. Dali headphones which, they say, from the radiation will help... Well, let's go and pray...\n \nJune 4, after 4 hours \nWell, that's fun... sitting in a little hut or something, to have decent storage... should have a sleep, the beast last straw... met a pig, nehily such hundredweight four probably... bitch, knocked off his feet, as many pole stolen... Yakut his skull crumbled Emkoy while I writhed under this huge edifice... It had passed then... will soon be dark, you should sleep...\n \nJune 5\nSlept badly, outside some screams could be heard, though guts out of someone alive fetched... br-rr, horror... go have a couple of hours, until all is quiet...\n \n... after 9:00\ncame to warehouses, svobodovtsy were hospitable... sitting at the campfire, boys poisoned tales, beauty... Yes that's the way horseradish was... went through some little village, Duc sat there half a dozen blood-suckers, all in one house, bitches, checkers that I have played... hardly ever leave, at daggers drawn pyryalis, they at the bullets chhat... I have a torn arm, Yakutia hit in the stomach... bastards, what strengths, overalls in tatters blows... still licking its wounds, it came... as it is, damn it... Well, in the tram that... a controller, in. There is, as we noggin spinning, all the noise, floating... as I did with optics off - do not remember, I remember that my pistol from the holster flew somewhere... I'm as much priohrenel...
                  \n \nJune 7\nvisit, time and honor to know... the guys from the Liberty we patched, pereobmundirovali, chuck Doda, food... good guys... with the outpost contacted, they said so we missed... sure have. Before checkpoint hour walk... Well, in a way...\n \n... 4 hours \nat checkpoints shit happened - like an animal on the side chesanet... epta whom I am there but not seen - snorks, zombies, wild boars, bloodsuckers, a couple byurerov (two of these monsters to death with bricks scored the guys to tears, sorry) - but our flame throwers out of watering, stinks horror... In the end, Ito... (Page torn)... scribe as much as. Yes, this is a terrible place - radar. Around her forest, trees curves, as if in the center of a huge crater. Around this eerie, pipets, just the slightest crunch - and the heart in the heel... fighters from Monolith 'met' - and horseradish understand, sort of like the normal kind and no... ammunition and food on the sly to an end, and here it dropped on PDA - release soon... in a bunker huddled, waiting...\n \nJune 9\nFucking emissions, all plans are ruined. So fonilo on the street, that two days in a hole sticking... (A piece of page is lost)... Bitch, I monolitovets wounded in the arm... Oh, how painful... Yakut intact, but something with him then... some, he became restless, and then at the very some voices in my head... although we have near the entrance to the antenna, a helmet sight not omnipotent... cartridges for machine ran out, had to take LR 300 at Zombar... horseradish gun, the AK is better... bitch, what's this? Ah, well, filth, zhrite grenade!...\n \nJune 10\nDamn, how bad... how shitty... Yakuta killed... Who was it? Healthy such carcass (boar resting), so stamped, if it weighed two tons Yakuta literally smeared, such a fountain of blood spurted... I was lying in the bushes... features of ammunition, two grenades and a pistol with two clips... blah, all covered with blood... mind some chaos, noise, voice... hear the roar, there's snork somewhere creeps... I sense, I Khan \n \nJune 11\nI can hardly write... will soon release, there truhnulo once, I drove out of the bushes and... hell, I can not stand... Are we going to rot here... (Torn)... I try to write faster to me pret Zombar... hear his infamous urine-and-and... I thought... you go with me... of the last forces pulled out a grenade...\n \nhell, started Select Click...</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_13_part_1">
	<text>today raised the alarm - say, a landing operation. Ran out of the barracks - bruised knee! Bitch! how can I now I'm able to jump? bliiiin! need to go Lopatychu will.\n \nsank fly... er... progresses to a point. The knee hurts more and more, and here and bench, bring it in different directions on my foot my knapsack dropped, suuuka, kill viper!\n \nturned out to be landing on the agricultural industry, there stalkers suspicious activity lit... and we have there next base, that's Nachgar and scared Malets... Another would be: he has six offices contractors - Pervogodok, and his side run hither twenty hardened stalkeryug that happen that, in hamsters them tear...\n \napproach the point. Down on the road, two stalkers, one saw us - as chesanul! I swear, the master of sports standard blocked!\n \nlanded, shot stalkers... Well fucking beast! them there were only ten people do not know where he scored 20, but ten men broke 2 landing offices literally chunks. Well, thank God, we overcame them. However, one leader seems to have managed to slip away into the complex.\n \nsurrounded the complex with the kids, decide who will enter first. Vasil went poshmonat stalkers, artifacts, shmartefakty... (Shot with a shotgun). Damn! Vasil doshmonalsya hike, but somewhere there is haunting remnants of a stalker! OPA! See it! (Another shot shot, the sound of a brief exchange). Damn... pliiiinaaaaa... ahhh... I... I was wounded... fraction... to... stomach... aaaaaa... hell... it hurts... put all of our... hell... stalker... it goes here... no. No! do not! (The sound of shots from the ACA) nnneeee... nnnnaaaaadddddaaaaaaaaaa...</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_14_part_1">
	<text>Log scientist \n \nApril 12, 17.53\nguinea ? 283 died without regaining consciousness. Time after the procedure - 2 hours 53 minutes. Cause of death - brain hemorrhage in the area of the left temporal lobe.\n \nApril 13, 10.31\nguinea ? 289. Procedure - radiation emitter Kaymanov. Frequency - 3600 GHz. Wavelength - 0,305 nm.\nPrior to the procedure introduced experimental drug 3NKZP1 volume of 2 cu. see \n \nApril 13, 11.30\nbegin to show signs of exposure. The body begins to cover bugroobraznymi tumors, mostly in the joints and the temporal and occipital parts of the head. Mental state of guinea - passive reaction to external stimuli was observed.\n \nNote: apparently, the radiation of the frequency and modulation proved to be successful.\n \nApril 13, 12.41\nThe external signs of mutation appear brighter. Noticed a strong increase of the cerebral cranium. The skin cracks and exudes a foul-smelling discharge. Expression has been observed in the form of telekinesis, moving small items - pens, pencils, etc.\n \nApril 13, 14.35\nin the experimental starting to show signs of aggression. When I try to make measurements of the electric radiation of the brain, guinea tried to attack the young laboratory Kuznetsova NI Security was able to hold him until the above-mentioned laboratory worked hard experimental sedative.\n \nApril 13, 16.34\nguinea becoming more aggressive. Using a progressive and permanent telekinetic abilities, he throws in the staff different things, ranging from pens, finishing with chairs.\n \nNote: I was given instructions to remove all the furnishings in the room with cameras.
                  \n \nApril 13, 19.12\ntelekinesis in experimental developed so that when you try to approach his cage, he pushed and struck the wall assistant Aleksandrova SN \n \nNote: guinea becomes dangerous. Me was ordered on the Elimination of guinea ? 289.\n \nApril 13, 19.38\nattempt to eliminate failed. Guinea just shot two security guards from their own weapons. At the same time he opened his cell, using their abilities. The third surviving bodyguard managed to lock him in a block 'Z' .\n \ncausing a large number of protection for the elimination of guinea...\n \nApril 14, 00.03\n... he killed all... now I'm locked in a grocery store block 'D' . When the connection with the laboratory will be lost, it may take 24 hours before the surface will be sent a search party. Hopefully, I can demon... [Record torn]</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_15_part_1">
	<text>Day 341.\nNow we finally calibrated emitter. This Caymans - an ignoramus! How was it possible to produce such a crude device! So much material is wasted! Do not worry, soon the authorities promised a fresh batch. They promised political, it's good, they are much more suitable, higher intelligence...\n \nDay 345.\nExcellent! Wonderful! Property ? 74 already endured three sessions! The survey showed a significant increase in the temporal lobe. Looks like I still shines NOBEL PRIZE! The day after tomorrow comes Lena. I'll show her my results. She would be overjoyed!\n \nDay 346.\nThis is a great day. The object is able to control small animals. However, short-lived, and only in the immediate vicinity. Continuing exposure.\n \nDay 347.\nI showed my work Lena. Demonstrated object number 74. She said that I was - a monster! What in fact people! And she - a scientist! The same sentence of death, as she does not understand that this is just stuff!
                  \n \nDay 349.\nAnother emergency. It seems that the mutations are faster than expected, otherwise we would be prepared. And this, Yakhontov, idiot! I've ordered not to approach closer to the object of three metres. Especially during the experiment! As a result, the object took him under their control. I noticed something strange in his behavior, and suddenly realized that I was trying to order not to notice this! Just think about this result, I have not even dreamed of! I had to order the immediate elimination of the object number 74. What a pity! What are the prospects?\nLena at the sight of this spectacle happened hysterics. She was crying, asked me to send her away, I'm a fascist, that between us all over. It's over? Everything is just beginning! He ordered it to inject a sedative and put under surveillance.\n \nDay 352.\nhas now been three days.\nLena does not want to see me. How so? A wedding in the fall? I'm not live without her! Let him sit still in the hospital, and I'll think how to make it change the decision.\n \nDay 361.\nIt seems I have depression. Nothing can do the work falls out of the hands, yesterday, the object number 75 the same fate as predecessor.\n \nLena keep proud silence, but through the glass I can see how she was crying...\nWhat do I think?\n \nDay 363.\nI got it! After processing the radiator can I order Lene change their decision. One must be very careful that mutations are not irreversible. I was the first time in many years, afraid. But for her sake I am ready for anything. Today, the same night the first session. You also have to figure out how to do without assistants...\n \nDay 366.\nSubordinated wonder what I'm doing three nights in a row, locked in the main hall. I had to think of work secrecy.\n \nSensations strange, until stabilization using drugs to stop the external changes.\nLena almost did not eat anything, has become a shadow of itself. We must hurry.\n \nDay 368.\nI can hear the thoughts of other people. Even the wrong: I feel them. And I can guide them, while weak, but still a few sessions...\n \nBy the way, suggestibility all different. Lena - the strongest, I hardly hear. Poor need to go through.
                  \n \nDay 370.\nlooked in the mirror. Badly. While the order all not to notice how I changed. I'm good I can do it. But Smirnov... It is not good happened. He had a very high threshold, after Lena, of course. I pushed too hard. He began... I can not find the term, the brain in a fog... I saw his eyes, moved his hands... and when released - he died.\n \nDay 371.\nNormal food is disgusting. I eat raw meat. Tasty.\nin control of all in the laboratory. Two of the post had to take full control. Tomorrow check, not that they have seen...\n \nDay 372.\ntook a commission. Needless to check my achievements! When going to the same, he'll tell you everything.\nIt is a pity that two had died, my experience is not enough...\n \nTomorrow I'll go to Lena.\n \nDay 373.\nShe died.\n \nI went in, and she screamed. I said that's me. She stopped and crouched in a corner.\n \nI went, and she died. Horror. In that I became \nI held her hand and looked. For a long time. I was hurt. Why? I am nobody hit him.\nYes, and how I can now hit? I did this... How... King?... King?... I remember the words, but what they mean...\nOnly the images... How? Boss? Okay! Boss! I know what it means</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_16_part_1">
	<text>Diary dolgovtsa VLADIMIR flew \n \n27April\nI have taken a loan! That is, no, not so. And so - in debt! Now I must prove that it is not for nothing official rations. Still, I was here is no big calling. I, as they say, himself came. I was given a real, brand-new 'Abakan' with telescopic sight and grenade launcher, and another suit, painted in the colors of our group. Long could not stop looking at myself in the mirror at the bar. Then there was a drill, dinner, drill, dinner... The commander caught serious. Even the name he had such a terrible - loud. Dmitry Petrovich loud. Well, he drove us... in the evening I began to feel that I hate him. Although, okay. He's not with us so evil rides. Still, I myself came here. Oh, okay, speaker blowing collection of... then Finish, as will be possible.\n \nMay 1, \nWe stand on guard at the exit from the wild areas. I do umyknul minute - pochirkayu bit. Pooh, curves and Sanya look askance at me and joke. Like, nerd. Themselves are, see how you are. Let me tell you about their friends. Of the four of us formed edakii 'detachment' . 'Quad' - in dolgovski.\nPooh - is a round bumbling fool who tries to pose as an intellectual. Although Silushka him not to take - only a horseshoe bend. Commander solemnly handed him the PKK official and four tape cartridge. He now portrays himself from Rimbaud - tied the bullets, machine gun slung over his shoulder and looking menacingly into the distance, swung round spectacles on his nose.\nthe curve - or worse. Tall, skinny alcoholic with a constantly red-eyed, melancholy eyes and unceasing allergies. All the time, sneezing, itching, and said his nose, because of what looks like an interpreter Valadarski. He's a sniper. Loud (which Dmitri Petrovich) said that it hurt well he shoots and no less solemn than Pooh, handed him a tattered SVD.\nWell, Sanya - a single story. Sanya - this is not addressed, and the same moniker yak and all of us. Outwardly you look - not at all remarkable stalker. Age - 30-35 years. But. He is one experienced all of us together. So loud without thinking twice appointed him as our commander and gave him 'Enfield' with a silencer and podstvolnikom. More Sanya suit different from ours - he has a helmet with a visor of tinted glass, which completely hides the face. Croot and-a thing. At least, menacing looks.\nNow we are sort of inseparable team. So, I scream our - probably something espied - go and see.
                        \n \n2 May\nFuck, do not understand how he's still alive. For us yesterday with the wild territory of a sack - horror. Some sort of creature was broken nafig gate and rushed at us. Some major mutant, like wild boar, but only with two heads and a faster and more powerful. Pooh immediately opened fire with his machine gun, managed to shoot down creature on the fly, and Sanya has finished tvaryugu from his pistol (he had, by the way, 'Desert Eagle' - a terrible thing). He said that such a mutant, called 'Chimera' ... ugh... We've been thinking all. But it's no such luck. After about fifteen minutes from the break on us fell upon such a pack of blind dogs, half with psedosobakami what I ever saw. Special 60. Pukhov gun again, was very much into the subject, he could not even aim. Crooked deftly throw a grenade - only scattered clumps of enemies. Sanya were shot mostly pseudodog. Well, I just had fired into a crowd of monsters. So much blood and corpses, I've never seen. It is good that a couple of minutes just the right, three more quad for help. We rescued this wave. Phew... The entire blog is now in krovische monsters. Sprayed, you know.\n \n6 May \nYes, long time since I did not take in hand treasured notebook. And all of a sudden stroke of luck - Colonel gathered quads for the raid on Yantar - clean from zombies. Environmentalists sent a message that, say, a zombie afterwards came - brick has nowhere to fall. Well, we agreed. Zadolbalo drill and guard duty - the job done right! Clean the area from the mutants! Ugh!\n \n7 May \nWe collected our things - set off. Again, wild territory. Not feel there to stomp, but what to do - need. We walked up the aisle with the territory of Duty. On the wall of a huge banner, which they say does not go there - 'parvut. In pieces. But, as they say - should be.
                        \n \n8 May\n \nWe have reached. It was a complete ATAS... Not counting the bloodsucking and Bandos. Especially spoil the life of mercenaries - Merck, refers to them as Sanya and dogs. Both were attacked several times, but we somehow strayed and even survived an ambush in some abandoned house. But Geiger counter there is cracked, without ceasing, and we were soon forced to retreat outside. While Sanya talked to Sakharov, we climbed on the tank - look around. Awful place, oppressive. Crooked got his gunshot apparatus, lay on the roof and began to methodically shoot zombies. Predominantly - unarmed. Sly, cattle, heh. After a half hour left Sanya and said that we if we shoot zombies on the coast and around the bunker, then get five mowers on a helmet. If we reach the x-16 and postrelyaem them there, then the price has risen three-fold. On the helmet. Scientists themselves for two weeks leave the bunker, leaving only one officer. He will give us money.\n \n9 May\nWe shot them, probably more than a hundred. And they do not end there. Filth. Hate. Pooh yesterday bitten snork. His time shot, but still the wrist he Pooh bitten through.\nNight. I can not sleep. Pooh, poor, terrified screams. His wrist was swollen and festered. Nauchnik threw up his hands, they say, can not do anything. Bitch. We live, by the way, in one of the huts behind the bunker. They were there two, but we and one missing. Although I do not believe so. Move further out to this idiot whining from us!...\nGod, that's me... perhaps it's me because of overwork. Okay, try to sleep.\n \n10mApril\nscary headache. It seems that rolls inside a lead balloon. Mlyayaya... Interestingly, all of our well... Apparently, the pressure fell. Happens. Today, when getting out of the barracks, Krivoy tsepanul butt jamb and accidentally pulled the trigger. The bullet flew within a centimetre of my head. I hate him. I remember him, although he is very apologetic. I know it is specially... He wanted to kill me!\n \nDamn, what a nightmare. Ugh. Now kill the zombies were incomparable pleasure, unable to vent anger at least for someone. One so plaintively say, 'Mom-ah...' when a bullet he carried a half a head.\n \nI shot and laughed. I probably never did laugh... barely calmed down.
                        \n \n11 May \nToday Krivoy Sanya fought, Pooh could barely separate them. His wrist had already turned blue, and he could not move his fingers. We washed the wound with vodka and bandaged. Injected anesthetic. It seems he felt better.\ntension. Krivoy, Sanya and Pooh almost always silent. They are obviously up to something.\n \nshoot the zombies and snorks, almost to the X-16 reached. They returned to the barracks and went to sleep.\n \n12 May\nThey are up to something against me... I saw how they look at me... I hate... but I did not do anything to them...\n \n13 May\nnight I did it. I went to the barracks, where they sat and played cards. They even smiled and greeted me. Two-faced creature! Why do they so?\n \nThey still thought I was joking when I raised the gun... And I laughed and pulled the trigger. They cried and begged me not to kill them... They said they did not understand... They said I was crazy... I? Crazy?! Ha-ha! Brad!\n \nI shot until I ran out of bullets in the horn...\n \nAnd then... I do not remember... I remember that I hollowed at the door of the bunker and asked them to open and shouted that I kill the enemies... that's not my fault that their were my 'companions' ...\n \n14 May\nSitting around the bunker. Walk around zombie... I... I suddenly realized what he had done. I killed their friends. Those who shared with me shelter and bread, which covered my back...\n \nI sobbed and wailed so that even a zombie feared to approach me... I am a monster... I hate myself...\n \nThis is the last entry... hard for me to write... hands are shaking... I can not see very, Tears filled my eyes... I feel like something pressing on my brain... Where my beret?... It must stop this... this... muche... tion...</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_17_part_1">
	<text>Day 1.\nLord, how can I happened to that? In the middle of the length and breadth trodden Agroprom run into the controller! It is not the first year the Zone has already tread. Or trampled ' No While I was still alive, must be fought... Well though, that for some reason I can say. Recorder is set to include the sound of my voice, batteries have enough time. Maybe my writing at least someone can help...\n \nSo, in order. My name is Vitaly Andreev in the fourth year of the Zone I, a veteran single parent. Once was in freedom, but that was years ago. Today... I do not remember the date! Me? I do not remember any dates! Even my birthday! Well, let today be the first day. In the morning at the Agroprom would wait ejection in the destroyed railway tunnel. Due to the large number of anomalies where the detector had not determined who was hiding controller. I even did not have time to raise the weapon... It is believed that the man who fell under the influence of the controller is not capable of intellectual activity, and is a regular zombie. At least, people who survived after the death of controlling their creation, do not remember anything... My body is totally controlled It, but I keep a clear mind, I can talk or even move his head a little. At his... Stae? Detachment? Group? Well, let it be a group. In his group, except for me, three more zombies varying degrees of preservation, a pair of dense marsh and 6-8 dogs. Specifically about the dogs can not tell, they are constantly running around, but hard for me to twist my head to count them... Talk to me, too difficult, so enough for today.
                        \n \nDay 2.\nDeco hungry. And drink. 'I never thought that zombies can have such desires! Interestingly, he feeds his servants? Or, when people kick the bucket, the new recruits? The dogs I saw, ate jerboa. Finally withdrew from their seats. We move to the swamp.\n \nParticipated in His... Or ours? Hunting. Dogs rescued from a pair of dense swarms of monsters fatter, and I shot them. Or he shot them? But how? He got no weapons... From me? Controller of me shot two dense... Funny sounds, do not you?\n \nI've been a damn thing I can not find it funny! You would take my place! What am I doing? A minute ago he was ready to tear all hands... It seems his influence still affects... Where am I going? What? Neeeet! I will not have it! Radioactive raw meat! Neeee...(Indiscriminate gurgling, passing in squelching).\n \nThen we drank water from the radioactive swamps. Now I'm just a living corpse. But I can fairly say.\n \nDay 3.\nToday we ran into the military.\nAnd he a good tactician - rushed forward dogs and zombies, while their soldier was falling, I went closer and laid him.\n \nI had to eat human flesh. I do not like warriors, but not as much... Wow, I can still joke... Only the humor is very much black turns out... Interestingly, I have not slept for three days, and do not want to! Although some pluses in my situation. Only his head begins to ache.\n \nDay 4.\nDo you understand why he is busy with the flesh in the group. They are in fact no good there! But today the whole day production was not, and we ate one. Interesting organization NZ. In the evening came across the same two flesh, and he captured both. But the group has begun a strange confusion, and we ate another. Confusion immediately stopped. It seems he can not control too many things. By the way, he sleeps. Not long, but at this time, control a little bit weaker. I was the creature holding fast, but a dog yesterday, managed to escape.
                        \n \nDay 5.\nIt seems colder. It seems that because I do not feel the temperature. But in the morning frost on the grass lay. I began to feel the group. If you concentrate, I can even see the eyes of someone from them. Damn, what is happening to me? Today, again, killed a man. A simple personal stalker, and I do not feel anything. I did not care.\n \nI understand that while he was asleep, I can not control someone from the group. While very little, dog - easy, zombies - heavier. They seem to be his nervous activity is left, so you have to monitor their every move. That's because an ambush! In other control can and is - no...\n \nDay 6.\nIt seems he feels something. Today came up to me and stared into his eyes. Pretended tables. Something must be done. Now night. He fell asleep. I know what to do.\n \nCome on, dear, go syudaaa... Another small step. So, now take my rifle... An idiot, I said take it, but do not leave... So... Raised... Shutter cocked, well... Now, quietly, quietly... here just five metres. And take care not to damage the infection! I love you! Excellent! Now lift the weapon... Upgraded... Yes, right in the temple... And meeedlenno pull down... (Sound of the shot). Uraaaaaagggrrrhhhh... Hey, where are you? Well all back! Look, ran... Esssst... I want esst... In the swamp at night saw ssstallkeraa... Slaadkoooeee myayayasooo...\n \n(More unintelligible gurgle and growl, recording breaks)</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_18_part_1">
	<text>Brothers!\n \nToday during the prayer came to me Monolith! I almost went blind and prostrated himself before the great radiance of the Divine!
When I dared to raise their eyes, then saw that the glow of the Perfect faded, and his voice became softer in my soul. Tears gushed from the eyes and the rage came into my heart when I heard his words:
Faithful to me! - Said he: my enemies close and become more!
Great - I cried: Tell us who they are and we will crush them with their faith and the strength of your weapons!
After a silence of eternity, which struck me as torture, he uttered: 'I know your strength, and I see that your hearts are burning ruthlessness to my enemies, and you are ready to sacrifice their lives for me.
I brighten my soul, Monolith did not turn away from their children and believes in us!
But my enemies too much even for my faithful.
What can we do about the Great? How can we destroy the infidels? - I thought, but dared not interrupt the thoughts of the Divine.
Perfect heard my thoughts and replied: I know a way that is suitable for the faithful of the faithful of mine.
I am prepared to listen, trying not even to breathe, that would not stop his voice.
Find me some of the most loyal of my children and let them wait for the embodiment of my anger at the top of my house.\n \nBrothers!
\nMonolith ready to give strength to us. Embodiments will be waiting for: Nail, Black Pasha evil.
These elected Chad, Monolith will wait on the roof of the fourth block, while emissions</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_19_part_1">
	<text>Notes Yakuta

\n \n13.06.09

\n- I sit in the bar... hell, something needs to be addressed. Money is ending, but clothing was not the same - an old AK often wedge, shabby suit. And with work, as luck would calm - do not have anyone Nitsche, snickering, bastards... s-eh-eh, I'm going to Voronin, General dolgovskomu, we can have him CHE... Well, another glass...

\n14.06

\n- Well, was at Voronin. I said to Yantar to walk there from scientists working completely, but short of hands. Damn, so far away and the place is not sugar - a hotbed snorks and zombies, many stalkers there were killed. On the other hand, nowhere to go, want to eat like a wolf... Voronin has helped - rearm, and medkits and food supplied... If all succeed, must be put down. Well, in a way...

\n16.06

\n- finally can pipets. The germs so much adventure to find his ass. Only went to the territory - here bloodsucker for stealing boxes. I wanted to hide, but fuck it - spotted. Poper at me, I gave one part, another - zero attention. I barely managed to pull a knife but his jab in the skull - a little bit more, and scrambled eggs... Oooh, next to a pack of dogs ran - automatic recharge forgot, managed only two shot - ferrule end. One with a gun put, the other does in the heat under your ass kicked with his legs - yet ochukhivayemsya, I strangled the last, leaped into the bitch's throat would break. Fuck it, I loaf of bread grated. Well, the one which gave pendalya, managed to head off armaturinoy break - the good, the iron plant enough. It was true, and good - has found an artifact, such as Crystal. Good thing, scientists can shake off a certain amount. But already for half a kilometre to go to the lake Yantar ran into byurera - thing that is. I shot him, of course, only he got me a couple of bricks... blah, still hurts to horror, right in the pole attached... Okay, good rest, it's time to move on...

\n19.06

\n- rested among scientists. After being wounded in the chest. Prior to the bunker scientists have steps left, as I Zombar vypersya. I have not had time to utter a word - he is in me a pistol with three bullets put. I swam in the eyes of all, the pain excruciating, her legs gave way and I fell... vaguely remember when I heard some screams, the rattle of the door bin... then more shots, Snuffles cry Zombar... then... hell, a damn do not remember, probably lost consciousness. Jumped into the bunker, bandages, a young guy sitting next to a scientist. He took me out. A good guy, we chatted with him. He, therefore, not very interested in science, but like all mysteries disassemble. Zone A Well it's a solid neponyatka, here it is for scientists and went. I asked him about a job, said job of work there, dirty, true, but what is - at the lake Khrenova cloud snorks gathered, it is necessary to remove them from there. Here is rest cautious and forward...

\n21.06

\n- Well, the lake, I cleaned out. I am for this, Sakharov, chief among scientists there, grenades supplied in order for trouble not to climb briskly. It was fun to see how snorks throws in different directions. I even a single bullet did not spend. Sakharov was rewarded, as it is, money given decent, I gave him another artifact showed Tuk he almost jumped with joy, said this to him and not enough. And for his money rolled sugar. I was about to leave, but he asked to stay, said his hands need work, a hand in the laboratory, promised to pay, not elegant, of course, but in the zone all representations pennies are good...

\n16.07

\n- almost a month. All the while he worked at the Sakharov subsidiary - then bring it, go there. Well and good, I was even smarter, so much sugar knows everything... In the evening the conversation turned to the factory, which stands on a hill, somewhere in the hundred yards from the bunker. Sakharov said at the plant has an underground laboratory with some psy-emitter, they say, because of this and a lot of Zombar haunting Yantar. Another said that there is a prototype of protection from radiation and that he wanted to explore the installation, which is there. There just are not willing to go down and cut down the radiator. Sakharov and his scientific organization is ready to fuck off mad grandmother for the radiator... features, offering tempting, but dangerous as... In the underground so rubbage usual... But what if the prototype did not survive the radiation and I turn into a zombie... no, I will not... I still went crazy...

\n18.07

\n- I thought two days on the words of Sakharov and the chase that he was willing to pay. Broken down, walked over to him and told him to say, I'm ready to go into the catacombs. He replied that he had come to us at night is a stalker and agreed to go too, so I go with a partner. My name is Vasya, shows that an experienced stalker, not one year zone tramples. Sakharov has supplied us for a full program - issued superpuperzaschitnye suits, brand-new assault rifles and pistols, ammunition, prototypes of radiation, medical kits, food, etc, etc, etc, radios and recorders... Recorders are not just granted, I only then realized that - in the catacombs, we could easily die, and those successors who may come after us, this infa on tape can be useful. Yes, perspektivka opens cheerless. And the hell with it, do at least something worthwhile in his life...

\n19.07

\n \n(More blog is in audio format) - to move through the territory of the plant... (As the machine-gun fire could be heard cursing and running mate) your mother, well, Zombar here... on, bitch, for you!... Fu-u-x, no one yet, we go further... won two front... Here, zhrite, bastards! Uh, epta, almost got... So, judging by the map, that's the entrance to the building, it should be a staircase to the basement... until all pure... down... on the stairs met the bloodsucking, showed his middle finger and kicked a asshole, and he die... just strange... kidding, beat him with rifle butts... we are in the basement, hell, as dark and scary, night vision, of course, done his job, but now the fear is not going away... hell, some voices... noise, Vaska, too, probably the radiator gives the effect of... BL * Gy, E * YOUR MOTHER! (Roar) BITCH RECEIVED! AT! (Long queue)... Hell, Bastards! FUU, uh, two snorks out of the darkness leapt straight at us, here are bastards! Damn, pants wet! That pancake... blah, well before the attack near... go ahead, go up a ladder... that's radiator mmat what he huge... at the top of some huge bulb, what is it... bl * qk, know komments, here suchary (urine-and-and 'mixed with fire and mats stalkers)... Vasya RIGHT-AA! CAUTION MMAT! NOT-ooo! BITCH, stop bitch, got it! YY-Y-er-AAA! (Hear the crunching and wailing zombies)... blah, hardly ever leave... a scum Vaska grabbed from behind by the throat and dragged him, I told her the butt of starling... hyyhh... made... hyyyhhh... fuhh, much as breathe... fhuuuhh... we are at the top, that switch... disable... MMAT WHAT IS IT? The earth trembles!... There, no longer... during and in the flask like a brain... FUU, disgusting... taak, slipping away through the tunnel should be... Again noise... but it does not install, we did it just cut down... hell, probably the controller... noise louder... we are going little by little... so, here's the passage... AAAA, no-o-ooo! Vasya, avast! NEEE! You Presho right in a Fruit Punch! Do NOT! PROKLTYATE!... Mmat, I think, the controller caught Vaska and ordered him to go to the anomaly... I'm still hiding... I heard a screaming wildly Vaska, literally dissolving in acid... Damn, what a nightmare (hear the sound of vomiting)... hear steps... it goes here... Well all, bitch, Get a grenade... (Heard an explosion and groan)... aha, I caught a bitch... not even wetted... blah, from Vaska and not a trace, only a pool of blood... Well all the hell I saw it all, it's time... AAAAAAAA (hear the sound of a falling body)

\n While I can say... ha, ha... here is another... controller... ahem... Bitch, well, who had taught him to use the weapon... He comes up to me... it... to... glhyyy... ugh... Nooo!... not... ho... aayayay... maaachiiii... (More incomprehensible noise, recording breaks)</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_20_part_1">
	<text>Day 1

\n \nI'm in the zone. And what about her saying so? It looks ordinary field with broken roads, which is complete in some provinces. Occasionally you can see piles of construction debris from standing around with signs 'radioactivity. Stalker conductor, who agreed to take me through the checkpoint to the camp newcomers, said that it will still remain from the first crash. Now late in the evening, so the guide says to go directly to Sidorovich we will not - he does not like the later reviews. Well, okay. The conductor said I would sleep in any house. When he reached the camp I see six houses with broken windows. From two of them were only part of the core. Near the fire sat for seven people, something animatedly discussing. At my direction, they do not even look. I decided not to intrude, and lay down in the nearest house, his backpack under his head, and fell asleep.

\n \nDay 2

\n \nI was awakened by a bright light in the face. Today was a sunny day, as yesterday, explained the conductor, a rather rare phenomenon for the zone. Usually there overcast and rain, often acidic. Wearing a backpack, I went to Sidarovich. He lives in the basement than it resembles a bomb shelter - huge heavy doors on the street and thick security door on the course in his 'den' .
Sidorovich was fat man about 50 years, with a bald head. He sat back on me, so I could not see his face. When he heard the door slam, he asked without turning around:
\n- Khabar brought?
\nI immediately remembered that swag here called the extracted artifacts, and all that goes on sale merchants.
\n- No, - I answered honestly.
\n- So what the hell are you here brings you here? - Still not turning around, asked Sidorovich.
\n- I'm new here...
\n- Really? - Sidorovich finally deigned to turn to me and I could see his face more attentively - mustache, little pig eyes and red nose.
\n- Yes. I only arrived yesterday.
\n- Hm. Who brought you here?
\n- Stalker nicknamed Cutter.
\n- carver, carver... yes I remember this. And he usually does not cause fools, so I have a job for you, so tell your baptism in the Zone, heh, heh. And this is what the job - bring me the tail pseudodog. Of the weapons given to thee a knife. Misc fetch once myself. I'll pay you for it... well, let's say, 500 MNT. Agreed?
\nThe fact that I told the carver, I learned that the first task in Sidor better to take - this is a very strong impact on your reputation. But it also lecture in the livestock area, I learned that from pseudodog alone will not risk to leave even experienced stalkers, what can we say about me. Moreover, the psevdopsy singly do not hunt. But do nothing, and I am under the watchful gaze Sidorovich agreed.
\n- Loading.
\n- Well, nice. Here's your knife. PDA, as I see you have, so do not get lost. Let's Go.
\nI turned around and opened the door.
\n- Stop! - I stopped. - Yes, I joked about pseudodog. Consider the test you passed. Go to Wolf, he's here watching over newcomers. He will give you the PM and a pack of cartridges. How to talk to him, come to me, I'll give you the job. By the way, as you call it?
\n- Anton Zaitsev.
\n- Ah, no, we do not accepted. Can you imagine what drove some idea. And though... will be called the Cross. Or Anton Cross, if you are so fond of the name. And now march to Wolf, and let me calm finish.

\n \n[Many pages missing, some muddy, and they can not read]

\n \nDay 63.

\n \nNow I'm in a bar '100 Rads'. Of the equipment I have LR-300, the next version of the American M-4, Colt, two grenades, three bandages and first aid kit. The money is there, I just just a job - regular cleaning of the mutants.
This time was a pack of blind dogs. In order not to look for trouble, I crept up to him and threw into the midst of a flock of two grenades. An amusing spectacle - to see how fly discarded blast dogs. The surviving puppy, I just shot out of a brand-new LR-300. Considering the number of killed my dogs (and this proved to be problematic - some of them was a bloody mess), I went for a reward.
The bartender greeted me cordially - unlike Sidor, who sullenly inspected brought my swag.
I reported on the destruction of 15 blind dogs. The bartender sighed, and told me as a fee 'Fireball' , a bottle of vodka, bread, a pot of stew and tonic.
The drink I drank once, but a bottle of vodka I had stored for later - because of supply problems antirads, it is very expensive, so people started to stock locally produced vodka.
Finally, Barman said that 'the duty announced an additional set in their ranks and I would have been happy there.
I said I'd think about it, though long ago decided everything for himself: 'Debt' - it's not for me. I thought to go to the Military, to 'Freedom' . Seasoned stalkers were told that the people there are happy, relaxed, and always happy to see new visitors. Perhaps, tomorrow and go.
Here's a Christmas tree, paper ends. A new there - here she deficit. We'll have to record on tape.

  \n \nDay 64.

  \n \nAs I yesterday and decided, I went to artskladam.
In the Zone was as always cloudy. Before I reached the base without incident - in the way no one met, except that two 'Electros'.
Before the entrance to the base I was stopped in a strange stalker armor. The massive armor plates covering the entire body, feet and hands were visible hydraulic boosters, united into a single system 'joints.
He asked me what I'm doing here and why he was there. I replied that I wanted to join them. Stalker immediately moved and freed the passage, saying that I should go to a two-story house with a guard.
The very basis of freedom is a typical picture for the settlements in the zone - scattered piles of construction material. Standing beside the main building of the monument broke in half - top lying on the ground. It seems that the local inhabitants of particularly do not care.
Income before security guards, I told them that I want to join, and they do not hesitate to let me, stating that he must go to the second floor, to Lukash.
To the second floor, I saw a very Lukash and two guards, dressed in the same armor that svobodovtsa at the entrance to the base. Along with these giants, Lukash looked dwarf. I greeted him and explained his purpose of arrival:
  \n- My name is Anton Cross, you can simply cross. I would like to join you.
  \n- Yes? And how do we know that you're not a spy 'Duty'?
  \n- I dislike them.
  \n- This is for words, dude. But in reality... In general, this: go down one floor below to Miser. He will give you the job. Run - conquer the respect and reputation we have, get a new kombez and gift. Agreed?
  \n- And what kind of job?
  \n- And that's your own Miser says. Even the outfit will help if you have it tight.
\nI am descended from Lucas to Miser.
Miser was a short, intelligent-looking man with a mustache and glasses.
I approached him and said that Maine has sent Lukash. Miser slyly looked at me and said:
  \n- Okay, dude. In the village, not far from here, bred bloodsuckers. Yes, yes, they. As you already understood, your task - to remove these creatures. In this respect, and receive a gift from me - a rare artifact, 'Crystal' is called. I see that the weapons you have no skill, so give me your Volyn here, and I'll give you in return SG-550, weapons powerful and reliable. With him these bastards where it will be easier to knead.
In a village in the evening not poke your nose - there in the evening not only bloodsuckers prowling around, but some - who are worse. You'll have to wait until tomorrow. And now you can walk and relax, but within, of course. Oh, and here's another dude - not meddle in the swamp, not only that there is a minefield and radiation, so even in a small house sits crazy jerk and shoot anyone who will get to it under review.
\nHaving said all that, we got it I was out.

  \n \nday 65

  \n \nI woke up at 11 o'clock. The sky was always overcast.
The village I saw from afar. Even away from her evil exuded an aura of death. But doing nothing, and I went to their homes.
Come down to houses, I pick up on the roof of one of them and start looking look right to me monsters.
Yeah, that's one. Lifting and tselyus him straight in the temple - it is their weak point. In the gold! Legs bloodsucking faltered and he fell to the ground.
At the sound of gunfire and ran the rest of creation. I hid behind a chimney, so they would not have discovered. Bloodsucker has come to slain colleague. Here is the chance! Look out and throw them under the feet of two grenades. There were two deafening explosions. Look out again and see now - bloody clumps scattered in a radius of five metres from the explosion. One of them chopped off his legs, but he is still alive. I came up, I get the Colt from its holster and three shots ceasing his ordeal.
Everyone must go. I notice that - something wrong - the sky is red, begins to hear a low rumble. Oh, damn! Eject!
Headlong run to the nearest house, jumping into the basement...

  \n \nDay 66.

  \n \nI do not know what's happening to me... During the ejection head gripped like a vice. Now I could barely move - my body could hardly listen to me. And I want to eat... meat... raw meat... I want MEAT!</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_21_part_1">
	<text>February 26

\nConeheads assholes. What did they do that have experienced stalkers like me need to explain the mission. Zadolbal have this sugar. Would put it in psevdovezhlivost in psevdozadnitsu psevdogiganta. Okay, leg snorks him to bring both legs snorks. But first, sleep...

\nFebruary 27

\nI'll go for a walk in his foot this hrenoviny a mask. Damn, I think a zombie is usually less... Never mind, Tear! Take that, stupid bastards!

\nFebruary 28

\nDamn, already zadolbalsya find these snorks! Hiding, pancake... They mock what? Hmm, there was a little idea...

\nFebruary 29

\nam Sakharov leg zombies. I will say 'snork hit the anomaly, so that the properties of the limb may differ' Maybe with a double to take charge of the 'anomalous leg' Let's see...

\nFebruary 31

\nin the zone of the country there!

\nMarch 2

\nHa-ha-ha, this moron bought into! Can I buy... hmm, 'stone that I'm not on the road found a cut from the kidney sginuvshego in the hot bloodsucker' Although the right, in my case and there are more important...

\nMarch 4

\nSakharov zadolbal. He had an erection on the leg snorks what? The last time I take this stupid job...
A walk-ka I'm in a marsh. Quiet here. Distance zombies roam... What is this? I heard a splash... Here it is, an infection! It hurts, yes? Scum! No, do not die! Legs are you now useless. I would have stayed to see how you'll croak in the jaws of some chimeras, but a little hurry...
Well, mission accomplished... Or not. Wait a minute, here's another... And two... and there... and over there yet... snorks course hunt in packs, but not so smoothly... And this noise in my head... Exactly!...

\nMarch 5

\nbarely survived in the massacre of snorks... I saw on the hill in the distance, the controller... How cleverly he thought of everything... He flung a grenade at him, but do not think that hooked. I hate zone...

\nMarch 6

\nSakharov gave the responsible (as he believes) the job - to protect a small group of scientists. There would be at this time to the fallen helicopter... I will not again go through a swamp... death there... he... He's waiting for me, I know

\nMarch 7

\nAt the egg heads off to the turntable. A strange premonition... Zombies almost gone, couple strongly nevduplyayuschih wrecks do not count... Like all well-formed... I do not like this. Started buzzing in the ears... I'm sure it was him. Scientists do not believe, they say they say this area, radiation, anomalies... Jackass...

\nBut tomorrow is a holiday... International Day of these, as they... 'Female human' as scientists call them... We should have bought all vodka...

\nThat's a helicopter. One of them ploheet... Worried... Something serious will happen soon...

\nBotan paid employment. This, which poplohelo looks worse and worse... Mom remembers her... OH NO!
Scientists with cries fell upon me. I explained to them that the poor controller took... We decided to leave, while intact...
Cunning beast in jeans seemed to feel that we're going... headache intensified... Hello, Jan. 1... Now the rest is the same hrenovnya... I see you...

\nZombie has more. Everywhere strange wheezing, probably bugs. Go to the moral willpower... Scientists will not last long... Damn, what are you crazy? ' The cattle, nearly armor not bitten through! Now his intestines can decorate the Christmas tree... heh, scientists minus one...

\nreturn soon... Scientists are somehow suspicious slowly... THIS LOOK! Automatic fire... I'm alone again... Hm, the controller is the wily predator... He is a dangerous man...
It is hard to go, I can not make out the road... The noise just unbearable... This snorks?... No, the tree... I have one... in this zone?... No, he's still here... I find it... I'll kill you... break... will kroshiiit... Machi... I'm saying?... oh, mother... Damn! A sip of vodka and calm down! Like let up a little... No, I am getting one of them! I can not be those who hate...

\nHey, you bastard, you looking at? You think you won?...
  \n \nHa ha... a Springboard... this anomaly always amuses me... Hello, predator... and goodbye...
  \n \nAs well... Consciousness is pure... I will not be controlled... I'm free! I paryu, I'm flying, I am weightless, but only for a few seconds...</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_22_part_1">
	<text>...

  \n \n(record not available)

  \n \nthe 13th day
\nWhy did I go into the dark valley, because the landfill was so good... That's because the bartender, it took him to get some documents from one of the bunkers.
I stumbled on the bandits, long skirmish, there aren'ta lot of ammunition... I found some notes and plans for the dead 'kids' .
One of them resulted in a pipe sticking out of the ground. Near a bubbling Fruit Punch, I hope nothing is spoiled. Uh, you... some clips to my arms, eating and first aid kit.
Taak, this note is no longer needed. F)
Shot a couple of crows for fun. No one did not seem to hear.

  \n \nthe 14th day
\nFuuh, how much did these hooligans was in this building. Nitsche, like Bron'ka still hangs well, although the hole is already decent.
He filled many machines that barely move. I'll have to drop the dump shake off all the good green newcomers.

  \n \nthe 15th day
\nIt seems nothing I bought all the way, running into a flock tushkanov. Hardly had time to throw down everything and climb up a concrete block near a stop.
The devil! Still, one creature to bite my leg managed. Used kit. A strange in her appearance... Well, okay, apparently helped.

  \n \nthe 16th day
\ntook all the trash in a landfill, pushed this inexperienced idiot... Hahaha, now there is little money on ammunition.
By the way, must still obtain the documents for the bartender, and then swear to be.

  \n \nthe 17th day
\nThere's something rumbling in the stomach. We ought to have a meal... No, definitely something with the things from the cache is not a gangster. The remnants of food thrown out, the taste disgusting.
Gotcha gangster beginner, died quickly. Still, bullets and even silly, but fly fast.

  \n \nthe 18th day
\nHow strangely began to feel themselves and the chin itches constantly, as if no lice infested, still need to be clipped beard.
I found a large building with a crane. Like here on the description is unknown laboratory must pay a visit. I hope that the problems will be small.

  \n \n19-day
\nAll, it's time to tie with stalking... Spent almost the entire supply of ammunition to the bandits, even grenades left. Seems someone experienced jettisoned.
Here's a pancake, top of these monsters is also an RPG shmalyayut... Well, quite oborzeli... We must wait until night, when they fell to sleep. By the way I see a small trailer
north and something like a conveyor belt. Sorry dosimeter croaked after my fall on the ground. Well, nothing... Vodka deryabnu and go to sleep, maybe blow over...

  \n \n...
\nI'm sorry I probably slept there: head is aching, itching and aching, something like even firmer steel. He broke the knife with one hand, when, as usual, played them.
Still, a strange thing this radiation, you never know what it all ends...
That evening, although it is unclear... all in some strange contours delineated... probably drunk or bodunischa, it's time to go pay a visit to our brother gops.

  \n \nthe 20th day
\nNo, well this mess... bandyukov I flunked, but the fact that the top, had some trouble - mothers turned. But near the brick chimney has found dozens of clips for his Abakan.
It seems that the flux: teeth ached for several hours. Dumb place this laboratory... only went so once some devilry going on in advance.

  \n \n...
\nThis is because snorks infection jumpy... Well I have a bit of shooting, hit in the head immediately.
AAA... a bastard still crept back and managed to claw slash on the back... Damn, it hurts the same. Well, nothing like their hooves make a lot of money.

  \n \nthe 21st day
\neat so there was... move deeper into the terrifying. Today, almost did not get a stool in the forehead... Maybe even sleep in the elevator...
Someone at the bottom heavily walks... lower jaw barely moves, has reduced pain... No, you must throw away up to heal a little, but then somehow I feel strangely

  \n \n22nd day
\nafraid for myself... unable to recharge the machine, his fingers in fright pulled the bolt, along with the contents.
Bumped into byurera did not think I'm that smart in terms of uvorachivaniya of bricks.
Flooded while intact on the surface.
I had to soak milksop bare hands... How appetizing he caruncle...
I try to keep myself in hand, armor is barely alive... trying to finally get out of this nightmare...

  \n \ntwenty-third day... machine not... food, no... there is almost no armor... and even that throw, it is still pointless. How to pass through the radiation field do not know.
\nhead ached so that it seems the bottom half is about to fall off. Well while dragging his backpack, although all that was left a couple of some legs and strange stones.
I think I'm numb... Legs like the taste of anything, stones thrown, they nafig me.
Oh, found the bandit did not even notice as ran up to him... Figa behold I sprinter... Inundated with a pair of punches... Here select podamsya a maniac... otherwise it can not be called.

  \n \nthe 24th day
\nBrrr Hrrr tasty body and blood of some kind... not thought of hunger because changing tastes... Wandered into the kind of crap with upright... like the inscription on the house
Flammable... xs what... ought to go into the house opposite and meal... Well, at least by the body yesterday...

  \n \nthe 25th day
\nAaaarrhrhhhh that with my chin... I am now probably similar to Cthulhu... devil in my head just thinking about the blood... What am I?
I quickly... I am strong! I am well... I see the booty... To hell with the note... now I'm... I... and figs with him... I want blood!</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_23_part_1">
	<text>20.04.2012.
  \n \n09:37

  \n \nToday, my group landed in the plant in the Gaza Yantar. Scientists want us to cut off the installation, emitting some sort of field, due to which people turn into a zombie. For the protection we were given special helmets. Landing is scheduled for 10:40.

  \n \n20.04.2012.
\n10.53

  \n \nThe helicopter flew away. We are near the entrance to the plant. Helmets are working fine, only the head for some reason it hurts. Moving to the main building.

  \n \n20.04.2012.
\n11:27

  \n \nThere is strong resistance from the zombie. No casualties reported. Destroyed about twenty (20) zombies. There are signs of mutants of the third class. Request support from the air.

  \n \n20.04.2012.
\n11:57

  \n \nShit! Spinner has covered! Flew by, gave a volley of bunks and crashed somewhere in the factory! Probably covered with radiation. The head is very sore.

  \n \n(time not specified)

  \n \nAll flies to hell! Three people opened fire on their own. Four were put. We are left with three. We must get out of here!

  \n \n(time not specified)

  \n \nUdaltsov and Nefedov died. I am alone. On his head as if hit with a sledgehammer. I can not go. They are coming. But...It can not be! This Udaltsov and Nefedov! A lot of them! I will not give up!
(Sound of the shot)</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_24_part_1">
	<text>Cordon...
  \n \nWhew! Finally, the end of this damned uchebka, all these preparations... especially drill. On the parade ground in all weathers
you walk a measured pace, but for what? As if all my life I will participate in the parade, heh, heh, well, I do not.

  \n \nmy first day...
\nThis is the whole day at the cordon, they say, it's not the worst place in the Zone, so too, and the word-then what... 'Zone'!
During the day quietly, just somewhere in the distance shots and grandparents say it again, or bandits attacked a lone stalker
they would all freebie, the crowd at one of which would be selected, or someone from the beast to fight back. They say that sometimes approach the gate,
have to shoot these bastards. Rather would with his AK to shoot, and then uchebke a couple of times on the fire went out.
Okay it then, NAV should be mom to write a letter, it is true about all kinds of mysteries of nature writing will not, do not know, maybe grandparents
Tales been told to me, about all sorts of mutants, about the anomaly, the release of some sort, although in appearance were serious. I noticed the elderly
all vodka consumed, type in the prophylaxis of radiation, shitty! We know them, these goals, 'preventive'!
In uchebke sergeants, also in the evenings all kinds of 'banquet' rolled, and then the company system, on the evening 'puncture' Stand up!
So they find a cigarette 'fashion' , the money they 'just barely' not enough to continue the celebration, find them all! Although burst. I thought all! 'Hello arrived' - here the same, I hope batter will not.

  \n \nEvening...
\nSome Daisy into my head, all nonsense. And the 'old' all sit drinking, where they climbs. I do not know, but I think so, or
in fact, but for the whole day I did not hear the singing of birds, only crows circling in the sky all. Sunset, nice-how!
Aha. Fuck! Che was, but...? Perhaps a wolf howl. Santa laugh, what they say here wolves, it pseudodog. Heh-heh, they laugh
How would I know who it was howling, I'm urban, and that the dogs are, figs knows. I'll go get ready for bed,
tired after the first day. Ha! Like no Che did. Beds me standing at the window, opened the window, and then bit stuffy in the barracks.
Fuck! Martyn contract soldier who is a 'young' he called, he is somehow, and more vodka asked to bring. Where it here in the sticks you find it!

\nMorning...
\nSuch sleepless nights I have ever had. Santa singing by singing, then someone from them what it is not divided. Ass, in one word.
All night long, then a howl, then laughter, then some groans, and even staged a fire.
It is said of mutants were shot, what fuckin mutants, either reading too much science fiction, or vodka census. All through the night under a blanket lying, creepy... but what fuck spine, elephants in the skin running! My pal Lehi lucky he was in Special Forces airborne, and I... in the ass! That's where I got!
This afternoon, the first time the post will go on the tower! They said the most important post! Cleaned his AK, but UEFA to clean it, I do not even shoot out of it. Neither Che, I shoot out of it yet! Let's see what sort of mutants, I'll fix it... no, I like her, but, vendetta
for my 'quiet' night!

  \n \nIn the post...
\nclimbed the tower. Cool! My first post! At the dinner eaten up pile, Whew! Smoke a cigarette or something, although the statute and can not
but if no one sees, it is possible. On the horizon, everything seems quiet. Beauty! No office, and Lafayette, it is true the night I stop please.
Nitsche, get used to it... Shit! Che is the Che for the firing! It's like Kiruha the other tower waters. Between the trees a stalker, or a bandit, too, shoots. That bastard! I'll Wait a him! That's because scum, he is still somewhere grenades scored! NAV, I will take it on the fly, do not leave... Ay! Mom, it hurts, I can not breathe, that is... Blood Blood Why so, since this is my first post was a cold, why? Why? He's still shooting? That bastard, shoots, with-page-relativistic...</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_25_part_1">
	<text>20.04.1986

  \n \nWell, finally! New house, new city, which is what I like, requires labor! Pripyat... Good apartment, bedroom. Even a little furnished.

  \n \n22.04.1986

  \n \nWe moved the whole family. No city - paradise! Park beautiful - the whole evening with his wife were sitting. Tomorrow I'll go get the NPP, the benefit of education can not be 'second class' workers.

  \n \n25.04.1986

  \n \nawful! He was so engrossed in work that did not write for three days! Also yesterday, got in trouble - breaking his leg. Fell down the stairs. He held the handrail, and he (uh, these workers - hacks) began to fall. So I grunted to him. The leg being torn apart from the pain. Thankfully, the doctors rushed in time

  \n \n25.04.1986 (Night)

  \n \nThe foot is almost no pain. But I feel bad, not terrible. Something will.

  \n \n26.04.1986

  \n \nNow 4:00 am. There was terrible! Night vytsepili out some soldafony. They say: 'on paper' . Tucked into the keyway and indistinctly muttered one of them: 'The accident at the nuclear power plant, just shut up.' Now I'm going on the bus. They're taking off somewhere. Everyone is silent... With me another fifteen. All of them - workers at the plant. What is it?... Despite my injury I was sitting on a wheel ', so the leg being torn apart from the pain...

  \n \n26.04.1986

  \n \nI do not understand... (Spattered with blood and written inaudible) and the bus rolled over... Closed fracture turned into an open, somehow reached into the kit in a backpack military, now... (Splash of blood) tourniquet on his arm. Wow, at first did not notice that his hand hurt!

  \n \nDate Unknown

  \n \nI woke up in the basement, his head - in the gel, near incomprehensible harnesses, parts of a machine. Terrible... My leg is free from residues of plaster and bandaged... As if so will help. And my head hurts. Strange how something, the pain is, then no...

  \n \nDate Unknown

  \n \nwoke up with a terrible headache, with me again, something someone did... The head is scratched, near incomprehensible device... to understand

  \n \nDate Unknown

  \n \nIt is not know how many days have passed...
Today found a number of rations (stick of sausage, bread, some kind of strange thing to me - round, like a tin)
He tried to deal with that... etc... Damn, I forgot the word! What with me. In general, I tried to understand and as soon as I pressed a key combination (the devil! I forgot how! But the keys are only three) head came on a terrific pain. Lost consciousness.

  \n \nDate Unknown

  \n \nI think I forget his name.

  \n \nDtaa nevizsten

  \n \nSgeodnya gave kshuat. I byuos. I byut Tcom on gloove. I Jouyet en OmSU Muda...

  \n \nDaiip

  \n \nA... Ma - ma. Tat Tat</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_26_part_1">
	<text>13.05.2012

  \n \nMet with escort in Kiev. Tomorrow we will cross the border. Recently, I began to feel that I have never in my zone I will not enter! But no, tomorrow is my dream fulfilled. The guide gave a long silver stick. He says energy accumulates. It seems that such things are called artifacts.

  \n \n14.05.2012

  \n \nGot outfit: tight leather jacket, PM, sixty rounds of ammunition, sleeping bag, backpack, flashlight with a rubber, gas mask and dosimeter. Like that! And with a still of the house took two sticks of sausage, a box of dried apricots, pure water (Who knows, fonyaschyuyu something?)and other necessary things to everybody.
No go - I write. The guide said we will go through a mine field, I'm afraid...
Uh-O! They crossed! My heart in my chest made flip probably still going... Horror. Well, we crossed the field, he gave me to the village brought the stalker in the house left. He says, Meet here with someone - it will go. Well... Force no. So take out of the backpack sleeping bag - I'll write more tomorrow

  \n \n15.05.2012

  \n \nwoke up, went out. Sat down with the guys at the campfire, talked, drank a bottle with them for five... Porassprashivali they me what's going on in the world... Chat in general, agreed - tomorrow I will tour. Mutants show and artifacts, and these... their... anomalies. Max (here it is me, and lead) told me tomorrow at the shop Sidorovich (the local dealer... they say - a decent miser) will wait

  \n \n16.05.2012

  \n \nSend... Resembled little. I saw pseudodog. Impressed... skin covered with sores and eye some evil, red. He showed me an anomaly 'stepping stone' and it seems just as her flesh (and this is generally a strange mutant) flew. She shook and the sky exploded. Then Max me a bag of bolts slipped and said that I threw bolts - a way to check anomalies.
Max me now not far from the tunnel some left. Around the empty... The tunnel UAZ is. Hmm... I wonder why stalkers do not ride in cars? I'll have to learn from Max.
It seems that the barking nearby. It is necessary to look around. Wow! What a pack of dogs! And to me the motion...
  \n[END OF MESSAGE]</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_27_part_1">
	<text>Record 1

  \n \nTomorrow Jora seasoned go into a pass. We go into the woods just north of Military. Jora got this military helmet fastened inside the small copper mesh. Under the helmet wants to put some crap from the foil and wire. The whole bar above him whinnying. Apparently the roof a man moved. Ah, that zone does to people... Since taking a 'Beretta' a couple of grenades and 'Storm' is, 'Duty' last week gave for the salvation of their quad. We leave in the morning.<!-- Changed 'Zhorik' to 'Jora'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->

  \n \nRecord 2

  \n \ncame out before dark, before the Military arrived without incident. On the way to the barrier fell asleep bloodsucker, fell two shots from the 'Beretta' .Meters for 200 of the barrier heard terrible cries, Jora said that he knows the workaround. Let's go a little farther east. We stopped at the edge of a forest for the trees Pripyat. Let's go west, to the copse where I last saw some concrete garbage and 'Hot' eternal.<!-- Changed 'Zhorik' to 'Jora'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->

  \n \nRecord 3

  \n \nWhen they reached the road they saw two men left, like the 'Monolith' . Lay in a roadside ditch, did not seem to notice. When Stoned went racing across the road and went through the forest. Noticed zombie Jora it with 'Vintorez' clapped like no one heard. At Zombar found some documents, there is no time to deal, in a bar for a look at what they are. We stopped at the tree from which the 'Burning Down' hangs. Good hanging, we are not seen.

  \n \nRecord 4 (apparently made much later than the rest)

  \n \nMonitor Dmitry today showed me a little of the Truth! He told me about halo Monolith... His story gave me strength that was left me in this impious place. The words wrong, which we keep in captivity in a basement bunker of the forest, planted in my soul the greatness of his doubts, but now I have no doubt! Coach explained to me that is incorrect, with whom I came to this forest - worthy to be called a minister of the Monolith, so magnificent I just put it on the path of truth. Wrong is - an enemy of the Shining, and therefore must be destroyed. Mentor Dmitry noticed my doubts when I asked, 'Why kill the alien, because we had been of the same clan before my enlightenment, perhaps, better to wait for another? But the coach said that if the greatest wrong is not opened his eyes once, then this is His will.

  \n \nRecord 5.

  \n \nI fulfilled his wish! Wrong shouted before his death, cried on deception, attempted to dissuade me of the truth of my faith. But I was adamant. Mentor Dmitry will be proud of me because I have fulfilled the will of the Shining. I already know that only the elect of our brothers are Akolitami it, only those who knows not doubt his strength. Hopefully, I will have the patience to complete this sacred way, and someday see His brilliance... And now I must return to the post in the bunker and to report to mentor the triumph of justice. All things wrong, I had brought with him a lot of them along with clothing, but Monolith gives me strength. I hear your call, of Perfect!

  \n \nRecord 6

  \n \nI again sent to the test. Mutants living in the woods, blocked my path. But I know - he once again wants to make sure my loyalty to his faith! I will go through everything. I have used all their skills, but proved that I am worthy to be called His servant. To survive in battle with the mutants, I had to use some items of clothing incorrect, killed me yesterday. And Mutants quivered in an unequal battle, because he fought on my side! I survived, on the Great!

  \n \nRecord 7.

  \n \nWhere can I... I do not understand where I am... Some forest... And the name... I can not remember my name! On my flak jacket and helmet with sewn letters 'Jora', but I do know that it - not my... Where I took it? And how to get to people?<!-- Changed 'Zhorik' to 'Jora'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->

  \n \nRecord 8.

  \n \nOh, no... That I killed Jora... His friend... (Hear the cry). Why I do it?? He also asked them to leave him alive, to spare... He tried to say that I am mad psi-unit, as it... Burner... ? Yes Now I know what it is. Clearly, where are all the new Monolith, and where so many are disappearing lone stalkers who have decided to get to the north. Luckily, I was wearing his helmet in a battle with mutants - I do not remember this, but after reading their records, I was horrified! I was one of Monolith! I was crazy! And maybe now??<!-- Changed 'Zhorik' to 'Jora'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->

  \n \nRecord 9.

  \n \nNo, I'm okay. Must be chosen inversely, I must tell how you can protect yourself from radiation! Scientists will probably explain this delay and foil in the helmet Jora... If only through the post Monolith pass...</text><!-- Changed 'Zhorik' to 'Jora'- Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16-->
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_28_part_1">
	<text>Introduction
\nYour team is sent to the object X-18.
\nSomeone opened the door at the complex.
\nOn arrival, your group should be divided into three parts.
Their tasks are as follows:
\nThe first - the penetration of the compound, with the discovery of other people, objects destroyed.
\nThe second - to take a position on the surface, in the building and cover around it. If you find extraneous, objects destroyed.
\nThe third - to take up positions in the area of closely spaced bridge to cover the most likely route of the enemy.

  \n \n* Further recording obtained by decoding the linguistic program, the owner of the CPC votes to transfer information group commander, for some reason the record was not automatically deleted *

  \n \nI have that again, the commander of the first group? Not well, lucky me... There are set aside nagging Comrade Captain.

  \n \nfor the landing ready.

  \n \nTo the right of the entrance to the building covering a man found dead, judging by their clothing, apply to the bandits. The corpse of a fresh gunshot wounds.

  \n \ncame into the room. It was found a few more people, all the corpses without rigor mortis, all belong to the bandits. Apparently their opponent was a man. He shot quite accurately, but not military, most likely some kind of stalker.

  \n \nget down to the entrance of the object. Discovered the corpse of another gangster. Status and time of death is approximately equal to that of the upper.

  \n \nThe front door facility is open to the plowing. Damage to the doors do not seem to have included was the key. I received an order to capture the newcomer, but his inability to capture, hold destruction.

  \n \nAccording to the schemes that we have only one way out, decided not to go down, and gain a foothold on this floor. The examination revealed a floor large number of anomalies Class 'Hot' . Also found two badly burned corpse of corpses, the description would fit in being 'Snork' . Also found dead in a suit scientist. The scientist discovered the CCP, recently it has been withdrawn information including the code of the door leading to a lower floor. The positions chosen. We are waiting for a 'guest' .

  \n \nThere is a movement upward, one person, my conclusions are correct. It moved slowly, cautiously.

  \n \n...We lost!... I believe that the detention facility's impossible!... DESTROY THE OBJECTIVE!

  \n \n* Based on the sensors, the owner has received many wounds, voices dropped to a whisper.*

  \n \nPancake, exx, after all of the Zone I did not go. She bastard. Simply...</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_29_part_1">
	<text>Entries bandit.

  \n \n(the top torn off )... find and kill that louse!

  \n \nAnd in general - I was wrong to listen to Tolstoy. He was also a monster, brought called on Salvage! Promised something, you bastard, promised! Actually, what? It's not us it on fraerka roe, and brought it to us, oh well would you fraerok... The Wolf turned out to be worse than the guard at Volokolamsk... As he calculated the Old Grey? He just came up in the hands of a damn no! Asked to smoke, but what in response? No hello, no sorry, no rut lohovskogo - just a knife in the throat. So much Fraher. Apparently a former cop, for all that shabby. Ehhh, what I do here prikanal something... Sitting in a hole he could now, vodyaru jam tarts and feel, so no, canned fool... And how well it all started...

  \n \nbegan and the truth - as in a fairy tale. After a second spell in gaol (for example, sat on the little things. Especially, myself, heh, heh... Otherwise it would have surfaced about the collector - and would have covered a year or two, but not small, but good. During the arrest, the NDA...) returned home to his boys, in the yard darling. Beauty! And so goes - not yet sat down, did not see the house well, and should sit - and on you, paradise, and not the yard! Guys who anyone could do. Kolyano Kachka killed, though. In the disassembly useful, but there Tale Timy Black harnessed, but against Kolyano... Well, he is guilty - those kids only an idiot now, high lifts. While I was sitting, they are generally entered into force, rose. Trample down, they say, even the gypsies - but those cops were purchased, nobody is seizing control of... Other pals - Vasya Bruise - planted, but not for trifles. As lawlessness. When drunk (klikuhu he did not himself have given life to bruise and is) not that girl lapnul, but it turned out that her daughter, or sister of a packed. At paw who should have given the prosecutor's office, that's no Vasey. Well at least not for an unpopular article, or he really bad on the area would be lived. According to article 159 was closed, however, to its fullest. I once knew - whinnying half, that's a must, bruise - and for fraud! Yes, he punks cards lost! What do you mean cheat... Another pal, although he was always muddy, and we are not mates with him apart, and got cool. What to do - even I did not catch up, but he tachila such that potbellied beavers, and they do not have. I thought I did not even know me, but it is the opposite! He came up, he handed crab, 'with the arrival of you, bro!' said a restaurant called, on both. We sat a good idea, but when I looked at the menu, the price, Che has become something dumb, Babble then I was not particularly. And Sanya says - bro, no market, you there parilsya, and I grew fat here, so take a walk, do not think treat. About how. I it at the moment even bought - it hides UEFA something... But what made me get it? The smell of the prison, or worn-out sneakers ' And it won as it turned out.

  \n \nAfter a couple of days san came again. He says: 'Do you want to, well, get up, like, better than me?' - And I told him straight what I say, dark. Come on, brother, directly, does not suit me at lohah walk to me as a child threw up. He opened his mouth as much, did not expect. And he said, 'Oh, and I in you, so I was not mistaken...' Why me wrong? Well, he explained what was happening.

  \n \nWhile I was sitting, he nadybal channel black, utter crap some research. Yes nadybal so that it now shines Degree! Type, there are rare items from the Ukraine through it only in the institutions are, where they Botany our four-eyed under the microscope view. A Sana'a for a fee of hard cash! But more and theirs thanks, and in such nerds everywhere have hairy arms, so I switched on. It turns out, Sana'a itself somehow these dumb thing, artifacts, find, but you can pass. And where they are? And here was all like in the alley between the Sign and Marx, all of the concepts. There are those guys hrenoviny to Salvage greedy. And bear to sell them. Just do not always convey. Here Sanya and invited me to take the smart kids, but under the Chernobyl hit the road. Trip, said as he squints so bad... You'll find, said there is a place a huckster, Tolstoy, they call him, also sitting, for banditry true. He will enlighten your chaps and where to go and someone to wait, and then to collect them. And then I said, you'll pass, too, by Tolstoy. Godick there to fish, Ddlokhov potryasesh - for life in the gold will be. Well, I agree.

  \n \nI arrived, two people with him took. Tolstoy was a huge, bald, sweaty freak. I have about it beforehand bratvy learned - from the boundless, spun. But What are they doing - Sanya promised to help, and Bubble hunting, as much as possible in the movie houses where such a square, which pretended authority, in the train brings the thief: 'You thief, a gentleman of fortune! stole, drank, in jail! '- this is where morality was such that the type of life you have, the thieves, boring, and her romanticism is calling you, especially so, with a sneer, that sort of came to himself. Fraerskoe movies, comedy, and the thought sunk into my soul... So I had to for the sake of Salvage for the future of the nits general ponyatki search, though sickening. Well, he told us it would be easy at first gave. Meet, says it is necessary, one boy. He broke down tsatsek nemeryano, there are different, the names do not remember, all the sea some: Medusa, Fish... Crap, in short, yes me and the drum, what is there. The main thing - when the amount of fat called, it will give us for the fact that this shpanets naryl - all I could to not to show that these attendants are not kept in the hands of old, even after the collector of the deceased. It merely passed - Gray lay down on the road, like a wounded, but moaned that over half a kilometre heard about it, but shpanets probably sick of people not used to seeing - to help lomanulsya, but so that the bushes crackled. Well we met. Kostya's head and I in the kidneys. Although I do so for the species - after weighted knucklebone Kastsyan kid is a pass-long stay, but not to the understanding of my side stand, when it's done. I did have them type in the main, that's what! Thick seeing stuff that was dragged in a backpack, almost wrought with happiness. 'And what with the kid?' - Asks. And what with him... Resting, and said so. 'How?' He was then a living? ' Oh crud, I think, yes I Mokrushnikov in life is not recorded, once only was, and even then I'm not that collector... So about that nobody knows who they were and everything had fallen on the spot, one I'm alive, collector before his death, all shot, all of our gang, but I did not notice.

  \n \nshort, stout buhtet began, by saying that his witnesses are not necessary. And if so screwed up again, he would do away with us. Well, I was thinking we'll see who gets away with and when, but at this time to parse not reached. He gave us a second order, creature sweaty... Fraher, said there is one. Famous stalker. Who, I ask? What a 'stalker' such Che is this crap? But Tolstoy said - so the local hunters name, which can shmalyat protein in the eye, but a nose for the artifacts have - these were from fish yes Medusa. In short, local raiser. The fat of his talks with someone catches it, and, in short, U-raiser something nadobyval that the price does not yet have. The unique thing is kind. Well CHE... Job understandable.

  \n \nBut here we made a mistake with the little kids. That is a little something I and the boys on the full ogrebli. Although, as a look - im a lucky can still... And I'm here alive rot and decay. Fraher this just a former cop, Old Grey stabbed in the throat - so we do not beat, they are at the heart of mochkanuli to, but once on the ground, jumped on his back, and the weapon from behind the jump took. Shit, I'm such a movie just seen... Kostyan fool, and pushed him... What's going against the Kalash edged with something? ' Neto Kastsyan now. Well, I'll hide how was, and lay there until a square, damn, how could there be a square, mentyara that his pockets were rifled kids. Gray was like still alive was bubbled UEFA something... Finish it this ghoul. While he has not helped any molded like, with his throat slit something. Well, this is kind of wanted to go, I think - again I was gone, but I must! At this point, sneeze, as punks, as Snivel last! Mentyara did not even look for me - threw a grenade, tvaryuga... Hooked me, boys... So soon and I to you. There and we'll settle for my herd, but for your stupidity... Khrenova UEFA something... Our yard sorry I will not see... Beautifully there...</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_30_part_1">
	<text>There is still time.\nsergeant slices sector for shooting, instruct staff, welders - in the center...

\nCartilage! Your sector - from the power line poles to concrete slabs. Landscape heavy swamp, they are not held. Work will single. Work out goals, endure the fire right.\n \nThe next sector of the plates to the bridge - Fuchs and rustle, will change each other. Fuchs, begin to shoot, when the rustle appear tracers. Rustle, recharge and wait tracers Fuchs.\n \ncheese! Your sector - from the bridge to the lake. There are two frying, so it will be quiet. Looked for Fuchs.\n \nWe Lt. duplicate left and the central sector.\n \nAll, guys. We look forward to...</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_31_part_1">
	<text>blog Monolith (from Pripyat)

  \n \n[START RECORDING]

  \n \n13.07.2011
\nThat's it!
Yesterday I called Lucas, said to collect belongings and immediately move to the barrier to Capua. They patted our Monolith pretty: the wounded have to base, lie for, and the dead - bury it away, so that no beasts stared at svezhatinku (we have to be completely happy only bloodsuckers out of the village is not enough!). I thought that would punish for yesterday, but no, type 'has high confidence' , blah...
Well, let - better than the barrier than in the cooler or the cook assistants.


  \n \n14.07.2011
\nin the morning got under way. I go to the detachment of the same 'elected' . I had to lay the hook on the hills, and then on the lawn near the swamp pig romp, but the earth is sometimes trembling. Andryukha said it psevdogigant. I saw this from afar, but how such a carcass through the barrier went unnoticed - no idea... So he was met by a minefield, you bastard! Nahr us a 'tank' in the rear.

\ncame to the location. So jolly was here! In spines passages metres wide and 5, two trench razvorochany, krovischa everywhere...
Cap said that before the monolith monsters sack, but a little too organized, though under control - first dog, heads 20-30, the flesh, and snorks psevdogigant. Matthew Fink, vice Capa said that if orders do not, then everything would have fallen here before the approach Monolith. First shot psevdopsov who managed a bunch of dogs, snipers drove the raft (those eyes on polmordy, the most vulnerable spot). Psevdogiganta drove grenades, and through the bushes lomanulsya back where you came.
And then, they did not even muster a yes losing count went Monolith...


  \n \n16.07.2011
\nlate yesterday restored barrier. We are with Andryukha sent me to a funeral command, here I first saw the fanatics Monolith. Guys like guys just kombezy some others, but three others in spacesuits, and outside tubes, rods, hinges. Matthew told me that it was 'ECWA' , or exoskeleton. Man it can load lug 200 pounds, without straining, or what gun to take the more impressive, such as the RPG. The only thing bad ekzy - by bullets and shrapnel almost save.


  \n \n18.07.2011
\nFifth Day on the barrier. It seems all is quiet. You should be happy, but my heart restless. In the Zone just did not happen, and even more so that's a lull. After dinner in our trench to come back in Cap and told me to come back tomorrow to the base. Says Lucas took away my collection, and around the Warehouse dolgovtsy began to appear, it is possible to raid to capture our database.
It is a pity, of course, the guys leave, suddenly turned from radar that-popret thread, but... order...
Yes, and quieter still in warehouses.

\nEvening. Something stirred beasts. Not whether someone from the radar?


  \n \n25.07.2011
\njust learned today's date... mmat! I'm just a week ago was at the barrier at the warehouse was going to come back, but here is...
In general - I am among Monolith.
I was locked in a kennel, but returned all my things (except the weapon). Even allowed to keep a diary. I'll try to remember what happened.

  \n \nThe next day, after I ordered to return to Captain Lukash, in the early morning attack began Monolith. This time they were alone, not counting the 'waves' of three dog, but a pair of wild boars, expelled from the rookery. At first, we held, and even tried to counterattack. But from behind the rocks on us hit RPG! Probably, the detachment fanatics ekzah approached.
The front edge of the Barrier, along with barbed wire just scattered explosions. The boys began to retreat in all directions. A couple of times zhahnulo near our trench. I have seen us running Matthew, as he hid in a nearby trench, then - an explosion, and when all was settled, the place was just swirling dust and pieces of glowing camouflage...
Then I broke down and ran back over the hill. I saw the downed helicopter and took off for him, but bury his breath.
And there is a Geiger counter began to crack, as if now melted - radiation! Went round the helicopter since, so an extra dose not grab it, and saw the hill people in kombezah, Monolith. Dahl turn without thinking, but suddenly noticed how the side is something translucent to me moved, but for a couple of metres 'something' was manifested in the bloodsucker!
Caught unawares, I stumbled on the slope, fell and I fell on top of the monster. I tried to shove him or reach out to the machine, but where there...
Suddenly I heard above a certain sound, like a whistle. I think so anyway, yet the controller awakened. Here bloodsucker rose sharply and angrily growling, ran away, hiding behind trees.
Above me hung four in kombezah Monolith. Then - flash in the brain, and all...

  \n \nI came to the cold, because he was lying on some boulder. Nearby visible section of concrete fence and gatehouse. Campfire Monolith sat with bowed head and rhythmically swaying. Yes, and mumbled something mournful, apparently, prayed his monolith. Then rose, and one (commander) came up to me, kicked in the ribs and jerked by the collar and forced to stand. Behind brought three more prisoners. The detachment commander fanatics loudly declared that we had the chance to serve as a monolith and thus atone for their sins. He said that as a result of a successful attack Barrier captured and will soon be eliminated as unnecessary, as servants of the Monolith will move to new lands, bringing light to all the stray. Then we were lined up in a column, and led on the road.
After some time we were ordered to stop, took the guard defense, and then from behind the rocks jumped snorks. While the fanatics were shot monsters, one of the prisoners jumped up and ran toward the red trees. When he almost ran up a huge boulder behind which the forest, a shot rang out. The commander looked Monolith (nobody but me and did not notice the escape), deposited on the ground saw the body and proudly said that, they say, our snipers are always on the alert.


  \n \n26.07.2011
\nWe are led to some kind of bunker. The commander went to talk with one-hour long wrangled, pointing at his watch, the sky, we hear the word 'radar' , 'improving' , 'Tunnel' , 'Pripyat' . He came back, said something to our protection. We drove to a hefty armored door, which had already begun to slowly swing open. Inside was a branch railway with the trucks, such as mining. We were seated in three cars, each sat down with the guard. Suddenly I felt a prick in the arm and after a few seconds to lose consciousness...

  \n \nI found myself in a dimly lit room at the foot of high, m 4, motley heap of rubbish, which was covered by several fires. Judging by the rustling of the darkness was so little space, such as the gym. I was kneeling near and saw his comrades in captivity. In the lit bonfires round out a man in a robe and hood on his head, started something monotone mumble, gradually raising his voice and changing the rhythm. On all sides of the darkness grew the roar of the crowd praying Monolith. The roar penetrated the brain, yet who quit of sleeping pills. Suddenly, the air suffused flavor, kind of like grass. I have all swam before his eyes, fires broke out and burned brighter and a lot of illuminated lights. It was a monolith.

  \n[END OF RECORDING]</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_32_part_1">
	<text>Okay, listen, guys.
  \n \nI go, I mean on the road near the warehouses, and then again Freedom fanatics udelyvala. Chose quieter place, took the binoculars, I saw - some corpses everywhere...
I think - so, if all things are pure, then monstryaki close somewhere too quiet around. Well, I think, so help me Zone, I go down to the battlefield, and remember that Lech attendant, heard about this? said that he would go to the barrier to the free help, he charged them, something should have been, probably, and yet, he appointed me to meet here, an artifact to give. I could hear someone moaning. Kalash reloaded just in case and went to look who it is. I go up, e-my, it's Lech. Quickly bandage him where I can, but understand that it would save him for only a doctor. Then he groaned, and some time later was able to say:
  \n- Bones, go, ha, ha, hence, more alive you will, here, ha-hka...
  \n- What's here? Rest, yes dorasskazhi.
  \n- Here leech somewhere sharitsya, be careful. There he is, there, for sure. Similarly, he also shoot, shoot!
\ntwitched, then Kalash, tselyus, shoot, though in reality I only imagined it, Sidor, bastard, slipped clip idle. I think I do now. I got out PDA, trying to call Max, he here somewhere of some operations there, he could deliver a companion to the doctor. While summoned, it managed to get close sucker is very close. I turned around and saw his face, so terrible, in front of him. I manage to think that we ought to somehow escape, but the body itself in the direction rushed. Felling should urgently. From Lehoy nothing could be done. I ran, but bloodsucker runs noticeably faster than me. What's the end I came, I think. Suddenly entot monster stumbled on some piece of iron, and instead to get me in the back, managed to smash my leg only. I'm trying to crawl, but what's there. Suddenly, his face tilted up to my face, tentacles disgusting move, let alone stinks something which, words can not convey. Suddenly he begins to lurch and falls down at me, I hear the cry: 'OAG is still alive?' Of the latter, the forces trying to scream, but does not go, I say: yes, still!
Max is rushed. With the Doctor. I asked the doctor:
  \ N-What Lehoy?
  \ N-All, too late, dead Your Lech, thinking of myself!
  \ N-How dead? When?' Who? How? - Try to jump up, but falling.
  \ N-Silence, and even the second leg break.
\nshort, able to take me to the doctor, go on do not remember.
I wake up, I think it did as far as I lay there?
Suitable doctor and says: Okay, stalker. Good luck to you. In a certain sense.
  \ N-It's like that? - Ask.
  \ N-leg had to be amputated - said - Max has agreed with the screws to the one you sort of prosthesis made. Well, I think I still rotations. Then, when learned to move on this artificial leg, looked to the screw, and asked - what you say thanks? He sent me to the Lukash, boss,
and he says to me, we're saved, now work it out. Nothing in the free zone is not done.
  \n \nIn short, now I'm in the ranks of Liberty. Bloodsuckers not afraid of already learned how to kill quickly. So our boss sent me to the village to the east of the base. Now there is my outpost</text>
</string>
<string id="kontroler_diary_33_part_1">
	<text>Wind noise in my ears.\n \nmadness.\n \nSmell cool slightly clarifies the chain of thought. Waiting, patience... proud loneliness...
This work requires too many sacrifices. For me, it does not work - calling and curse rolled into one... I was in her grip like a slave. But, I chose her... harsh life imposed. They say that if a person can not be, then nothing would make him... - Nonsense, though it is true...
  \n \neyes remember everything you need... affected by years of stupid training.
  \n \ninseparable from his eyes 'ant' hands like clockwork, put handy tools. Harmless toy without important details...
  \n \nLike a beast, rely on intuition and instincts... - Point at the bottom... seconds before its appearance. Heart pounding, sinking... lead breath. Finger betrayed emotion. At the right time has made the desired action. The familiar sound slows down time... - Dot stopped moving, became red... The smell of blood... Panic at the bottom. Shares of seconds... fallen sleeve and its still ringing.
  \n \nlaceration, conscience... it is not... no emotion... emptiness... loneliness...
  \n \nheart pounding, sinking,
\nshot in the head,
\nLead breath
\nelse is sand...
\nThe smell of gunpowder and lubricants
\ndepreciated sleeve and its ringing.
\nEndless excuse
\nAnd the broken law...
\ncolor of red blood
\nin black and white background.
\nJust quietly and without pain
\ndying star in the sky...</text>
</string>
</string_table>