<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.6 commented out mutant parts, changed Devil to Bes, 880 max to prapor, 1137 Tolia to Tolik, minor edits,several edits, moved bar_dolg_ivancov_start_41 and bar_dolg_petrenko_start_5 to stable_dialogs_bar, YURICK to Yurek, The Doctor,life heart 41-11, artmod_873_dialog_0, removed some hard returns, artmod_821, 841, 851, 661, 511, enc_artmod_medusa_galant_text,new PKM ammunition box and descr. line:172 aleks1970, artmod_322_dialog_4, removed '-' -->
<!-- Stats rationalisation by GlowWormToo - 16 Jun 16-->
<!-- Edited by Sword2012 up to Line 1012 (though translations still required) - 16 Jun 16 -->
<!-- Names changed as commented below - Sword2012 - 31 Oct 16 -->
<!-- Partial reworking of text - Sword2012 - 12 Dec 16-->
<!-- 9 / 48 artefact descriptions from Lines 1942 to 2011 still to do - Sword2012 -->
<!-- Dialogues from Lines 1013 to 1818, and 2012 to 3329 still to do - Sword2012 -->
	<string_table>
		<string id="freedom_dinamit_0">
			<text>Die Jungs an der "Barriere" sagten, du suchst einen zuverlässigen Mann?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_dinamit_1">
			<text>Ja, suche ich. Meine Kumpels haben den Übergang ins Dunkle Tal fast fertig, aber wir brauchen mehr Dynamit. Ich weiß, das im Anfänger-Lager im Kordon es welches gibt. Kannst du es besorgen? Für die gemeinsame Sache, und du gehst auch nicht leer aus.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_dinamit_2">
			<text>Gut, ich versuche es.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_dinamit_3">
			<text>Sorry, ich habe noch andere Dinge zu erledigen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_dinamit_have_0">
			<text>Hey, ich hab Dynamit mitgebracht.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_dinamit_have_1">
			<text>Fein, lass sehen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_dinamit_have_2">
			<text>Vorsicht.. Du hast keine Ahnung, wie es ist, dieses Zeug  mit sich rumzuschleppen. Schlimm ist in der nähe von Anomalien. Ich bin froh, es loszuwerden - das ist sicher ...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_dinamit_have_3">
			<text>Danke dir! Also, schau mal, hier, hinter den Boxen wollen wir den Durchgang machen, du kommst dann beim kleinen See im Dunklen Tal raus. Aber behalte das für dich .. Ok.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="freedom_dinamit_have_4">
			<text>Kein Problem das mach ich und Danke ...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_leader_start_dialog_15001">
			<text>Hallo, Gezeichneter. Wir warten schon auf dich. Hast du das Dynamit?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_leader_start_dialog_15002">
			<text>Ja. Entschuldigen die Verspätung. Ich musste damit vorsichtig sein ...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_leader_start_dialog_15003">
			<text>Wunderbar, gleich werden die Jungs den Weg durchsprengen und wir können uns frei bewegen. Hmm, klingt gut - Freiheit macht den weg  frei - also, die Koordinaten hab ich dir hochgeladen, so kannst du auch den Weg benutzen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="mil_leader_start_dialog_15004">
			<text>Wow, gut gemacht Ich bin beeindruckt.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="find_af_dummy_glassbeads_0">
			<text>In den Dokumenten, die "Ghost" bei sich hatte, stand was über eine neue sichere Route...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="find_af_dummy_glassbeads_1">
			<text>Sie haben einen scharfen Blick. Ja, stimmt. Aber Sie müssen uns noch ein Gefallen tun. Wir machen hier Experimente mit seltenen Artefakten. Um weiter zu kommen brauchen wir das Artefakt "Mamas Perlen". Haben Sie schon von gehört!?\n \nBringen Sie uns dieses Artefakt, dann werde ich ihnen über diese Route berichten.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="find_af_dummy_glassbeads_2">
			<text>Ich versuche es zu finden.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="find_af_dummy_glassbeads_3">
			<text>Zurzeit Schlecht, ich bin unterwegs zum Monolithen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="find_af_dummy_glassbeads_have_0">
			<text>Guten Tag, ich hab das Artefakt "Mamas Perlen".</text>
		</string>
		<string id="find_af_dummy_glassbeads_have_1">
			<text>Kann ich..? Schauen wir mal.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="find_af_dummy_glassbeads_have_2">
			<text>Natürlich. Hier ..</text>
		</string>
		<string id="find_af_dummy_glassbeads_have_3">
			<text>Ja... genau das, was wir brauchen. Danke.\n \nSchauen Sie bitte hier, auf der Karte. Bei Agroprom gibt es einen sichern Pfad, der genau hierher führt. Sehen Sie?\n \nAber den Rückweg kennen wir, leider - noch - nicht. Das Militär in Agroprom hatte wohl diese Dokumente, wo dieser Weg beschrieben wurde, aber der Aktenkoffer  wurde von einem Deserteur gestohlen - soweit ich gehört hatte.\n \nTrauen Sie sich zu, diese Dokumente zu finden?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_scientist_find_case_0">
			<text>Sie denken.. diese Dokumente über diese neue Route sind immer noch in Agroprom?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_scientist_find_case_1">
			<text>Ja, genau. Meines Wissens nach, sind sie nicht bei anderen Zonenhändlern aufgetaucht. Auch nicht im Kordon oder auf der Müllhalde...\n \nAlso, wenn sie diese Route kennen wollen, dann würde es Sinn machen in Agroprom zu suchen. Ist ja nicht weit, und den kurzen Rückweg zu uns kennen Sie doch bereits.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_scientist_find_case_2">
			<text>Gut, ich versuche den Koffer mit den Dokumenten zu finden.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_scientist_find_case_3">
			<text>Nein, ich werde mich weiter zu dem Monolithen durchkampfen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_scientist_find_case_4">
			<text>Sehr schön! Ich erwarte Sie dann.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_scientist_find_case_5">
			<text>Tja, wenn Sie dann mal Zeit haben - kommen Sie vorbei.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_scientist_find_case_have_0">
			<text>Ich grüße Sie, Professor. Ich hab die Dokumente.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_scientist_find_case_have_1">
			<text>Lassen Sie uns mal nachsehen, was wir da haben.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_scientist_find_case_have_2">
			<text>Hier, bitte.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_scientist_find_case_have_3">
			<text>Ja, das ist das, was wir gesucht haben. Hier sind auch die Markierungen für den Weg nach Agroprom. Aktualisieren Sie ihre Karte, bitte.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="yan_scientist_find_case_have_4">
			<text>Danke, Professor!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_halfdead">
			<text>Mongol</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_bandit_trader">
			<text>Sehne</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolgovazyi_repair_0">
			<text>Ich grüße dich. Machst du hier Reparaturen?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolgovazyi_repair_1">
			<text>Ja. Flicke hier die Anzüge wieder zusammen. Kann auch deine Sachen überholen. Sei aber gewarnt - das ist alles nicht billig, je kaputter - desto teurer. Was soll's denn sein:\n </text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolgovazyi_repair_2">
			<text>Repariere die Waffe im 1.Slot.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolgovazyi_repair_3">
			<text>Repariere die Waffe im 2.Slot (Primär Waffe).</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolgovazyi_repair_4">
			<text>Repariere den Anzug.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolgovazyi_repair_5">
			<text>Verflucht, das Geld ist aber wieder knapp. Ich komme mal später.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolgovazyi_repair_6">
			<text>Gleich... Wird alles in einer Minute...\n \nSo,fertig, nimm mit!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolgovazyi_repair_7">
			<text>Tja, Gezeichneter...du wurdest ja ganz schön durchgeschüttelt. So...irgendwo hatte ich doch Panzerplatten. Ah, da sind die. Hier rein und hier... Ufff.\n \nSo! Wie neu!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolgovazyi_repair_8">
			<text>Hmmm. Spitzen-Arbeit. Hör mal, wo hast du das gelernt? Schweigst wie ein Grab, was? Na ja, egal...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolgovazyi_repair_9">
			<text>Ausgezeichnete Arbeit, das ist mir dieses Geld wert.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolgovazyi_repair_10">
			<text>Kannst du noch was reparieren?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolgovazyi_repair_11">
			<text>Sicher, kein Problem\n.\n:</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dolgovazyi_name">
			<text>Lanky</text>
		</string>
		<string id="bar_docent_name">
			<text>Dozent</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stranger">
			<text>Einzelgänger</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-pkm">
			<text>-- WIRD NICHT BENUTZ --</text>
		</string>
		<string id="wpn-pkm_name">
			<text>-- WIRD NICHT BENUTZT --</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x54r_box">
			<text>%c[221,255,193,255]Munition\n%c[255,255,255,210]Kaliber® : %c[1,168,255,210]7.62x54mm Rand\n%c[255,255,255,210]Waffen®® : \n%c[1,168,255,210]- PK (Pulemyot Kalashnikova)%c[default]\n \nDie 7.62x54mmR ist eine Standardmunition der russischen Streitkräfte für Gewehre und Maschinengewehre. Die auch Mosin M1908/30 genannte Patrone ist seit mehr als 120 Jahren ununterbrochen in Verwendung und damit die dienstälteste Militärmunition der Welt.\n \nDie Entwicklung dieser Randpatrone begann im Zarenreich zu Ende des 19. Jahrhunderts im Zuge der Beschaffung von neuen Infanteriegewehren für die Kaiserlich Russische Armee. Die Wahl fiel im Jahr 1891 auf das Gewehr M1891, das aus den Entwürfen des Russen Sergei Mosin und des Belgiers Leon Nagant hervorging.\n \nIm Jahr 1908 wurde das Rundkopf- durch ein Spitzgeschoss ersetzt, 1930 die Patrone von sowjetischen Konstrukteuren in ihrer Leistung optimiert und wird seitdem als Mosin M1908/30 geführt.\n \nRandpatrone:\nDie ursprüngliche Form samt Patronenrand blieb bis heute erhalten. Die letzte andere Randpatrone, die .303 British, wurde nach dem Zweiten Weltkrieg nach und nach durch moderne randlose Munition wie die 7.62x51mm NATO ersetzt. Im Gegensatz dazu stieg die Verbreitung der Mosin-Patrone eher noch, da sie nach 1945 in allen Warschauer Vertragsstaaten Standardmunition des Militärs wurde. Sie fand auch Eingang ins Arsenal der chinesischen Streitkräfte, die vielfältige Versionen russischer Infanteriewaffen fertigten.\n \nDie 7.62x54mmR gibt es mit verschiedenen Geschossen. Bis zum 2. Weltkrieg war das Bleikernvollmantelgeschoss Standard. Es existieren Stahlkern-, Panzer-, Panzerbrand- und Leuchtspurgeschosse sowie Präzisionsmunition für die Verwendung in Scharfschützengewehren wie dem SWD.\n \nFür die PK (Pulemyot Kalashnikova) gibt es sie in 100er Trommelmagazin oder 200er Trommelmagazin Magazinen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x54r_100_s">
			<text>Munition: 7.62x54mm Rand (100 Trommel)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ammo-7.62x54r_250_s">
			<text>Munition: 7.62x54mm Rand (250 Trommel)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-p90">
			<text>-- WIRD NICHT BENUTZT --</text>
		</string>
		<string id="wpn-p90_name">
			<text>-- WIRD NICHT BENUTZT --</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_military_stalker">
			<text>Fähnrich Sherstuk</text>
		</string>
		<string id="repair_item_outfit_desc">
			<text>\n \nReparaturkit für behelfsmäßige Instandsetzung der Schutzanzüge und Lebenswichtigen Dingen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="repair_item_outfit_name">
			<text>Reparaturkit RIA</text>
		</string>
		<string id="repair_item_weapon_desc">
			<text>\n \nReparaturkit für behelfsmäßige Instandsetzung der Waffen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="repair_item_weapon_name">
			<text>Reparaturkit RIW</text>
		</string>
		<string id="repair_box_desc">
			<text>\n \nKoffer für Reparaturkits.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="repair_box_name">
			<text>Werkzeugkoffer</text>
		</string>
		<string id="wpn-saiga12c">
			<text>-- WIRD NICHT BENUTZT --</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_weapons1_saiga12c">
			<text>-- WIIRD NICHT BENUTZT --</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak47">
			<text>-- WIRD NICHT BENUTZT --</text>
		</string>
		<string id="device_pda1">
			<text>PDA</text>
		</string>
		<string id="device_pda1_s">
			<text>PDA</text>
		</string>
		<string id="device_pda_npc">
			<text>Miliär PDA</text>
		</string>
		<string id="device_pda_npc_s">
			<text>Miliär PDA</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_device_pda1">
			<text>\n \nEin "Persönlicher Digitaler Assistent"\n \nEs ist ein kompakter, tragbarer Computer, der neben vielen anderen Programmen hauptsächlich für die persönliche Aufgaben, Karten- und Nachrichtenverwaltung benutzt wird.\n \nDie Bedienung erfolgt über ein berührungsempfindliches LC-Display. Viele PDAs beherrschen auch eine Handschrifterkennung. Anfang der 1990er Jahre verwendete Apple für sein neu eingeführtes Newton MessagePad erstmals die Bezeichnung PDA. Seit Ende der 1990er Jahre wurde die Bezeichnung im deutschen Sprachraum oft synonym für alle tragbaren Kleincomputer benutzt.\n \nHeute spielen klassische PDAs am Markt praktisch keine Rolle mehr, sie sind durch Smartphones, die zusätzlich die Funktionen von Mobiltelefonen haben, und Tablet-PCs mit größeren Bildschirmen ersetzt. Diese Geräte verfügen, im Gegensatz zu PDAs, in der Regel auch über einen mobilen Internetzugang.\n \nIm Gegensatz zu den PDA's in der Zone. Diese beherbergen noch die alte Sendefrequenz womit sich Stalker in der Verstrahlten Zone austauschen oder Nachrichten versenden. Was Smartphones obsolet machen. Diese PDA's wurden auch über die Zeit weiterentwickelt und verfügen über zusätzliche integrierte ROM-Speichermodule. Sowie komplette Datenbanksätze der Umwelt und Tieren oder vernetzte Statistiken der Stalker untereinander.\n \nEs ist möglich komplette Daten Pakete in einem PDA hoch- und runterzuladen. Die "meisten" sind überwiegend jedoch nicht geschützt was ein Zugriff von außerhalb erlaubt. Spezielle PDA's besitzen ein weitere Sensor Technik die es den Stalker erlaubt andere Lebewesen in einem gewissen umkreis zu erkennen.\n \nAusserhalb der Zone wird die Existenz solcher PDA's verschwiegen. Alle Persönlichen Digitalen Assistenten werden vom Militär, da sie sich leicht aufspüren lassen, eingesammelt.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_device_pda_npc">
			<text>\n \nEin "Persönlicher Digitaler Assistent"\n \nEs ist ein kompakter, tragbarer Computer, der neben vielen anderen Programmen hauptsächlich für die persönliche Aufgaben, Karten- und Nachrichtenverwaltung benutzt wird.\n \nDie "PDA Militär" Variante wurde eigens für die Zone, für das Militärpersonal, entworfen. Es besitzt alle Eigenschaften und Merkmale wie der Normale PDA.\n \nMeist Technik versierte Stalker sind immer auf der Suche nach solchen Geräten. Da sie in der Regel  aktualisierte und Streng geheime Informationen über die Verstrahlte Zone enthalten sowie die Bewegungs Daten des Militärpersonals und anderer "Interessante Personen".</text>
		</string>
		<string id="super_gauss">
			<text>Munition: Supergauss</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_super_gauss">
			<text>%c[221,255,193,255]Munition\n%c[255,255,255,210]Kaliber® : %c[1,168,255,210]Energiezelle\n%c[255,255,255,210]Waffen®® : \n%c[1,168,255,210]%c[default]\n \nEnergiezellen in einem Magazin. Als Energiequelle dient ein eingekapseltes Stück des Artefakts "Mondlicht". Unglaubliche Durchschlagskraft.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="strelok_pda_name">
			<text>Strelok's PDA</text>
		</string>
		<string id="strelok_pda_desc">
			<text>\n \nStrelok's PDA.\nViele würden gerne diesen PDA in die Hände bekommen. Enthält eine Fülle von Informationen - dennoch, fast alles ist bestens verschlüsselt.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="wpn-ak47">
			<text>-- WIRD NICHT BENUTZT --</text>
		</string>
		<string id="Hello_sak">
			<text>%c[255,255,128,128]\nViele Grüße von Sak!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="kodes">
			<text>Türschloss Kombinationen</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ways_info_door_sak_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nSak gab mir eine Schlosskombination für die Tür eines kleinen Bunkers, in der Nähe der Straßenabzweigung nach Prypjat.\n \nDas ist die Ziffernfolge: 1287975.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dead_monolit_title">
			<text>Informationen von einem Toten Monolither</text>
		</string>
		<string id="dead_monolit_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nIch hab einige vermoderte Dokumente gefunden in den verblichene Fotos und sonstige Tabellen und Kritzeleien drin sind. Sieht aus wie ein "Laboratorium" und auf dem anderen Foto ist wohl "Limansk" abgebildetet.\n \nDer Rest ist unmöglich zu Lesen. Es gibt noch einen Code .. '8-8-6-6-7-7'. Könnte ein Türcode sein.\n \nWer bitte würde ein Sicherheits Türcode auf ein dieser Notiz-Zettel Schreiben..</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_ways">
			<text>Entdeckte Level-Übergänge</text>
		</string>
<!-- AR -->
		<string id="enc_info_red_battery_text">
			<text>\n \nRubin-Batterie Modifkation\n%c[221,255,193,255]Körperliche Eigenschaften\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vital Gesundheit : %c[255,1,255,1]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vital Blutung®®® : %c[default]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vital Ausdauer®® : %c[255,1,255,1]+182\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vital Hunger®®®® : %c[default]n/a\n%c[default]\n \n%c[221,255,193,255]Schutz und Resistenz\n%c[255,255,255,210]Strahlung®®®®®®® : %c[255,255,1,1]+10\n%c[255,255,255,210]Verbrennung®®®®® : %c[default]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]Elektroschock®®® : %c[255,1,255,1]+16 %\n%c[255,255,255,210]Chemisch Verbre. : %c[default]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]PSI Telepatie®®® : %c[default]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vor Reißwunden®® : %c[default]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vor Projektile®® : %c[255,1,255,1]+2 %\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vor Explosion®®® : %c[255,1,255,1]+5 %\n%c[255,255,255,210]Aufprall Schutz® : %c[255,1,255,1]+8 %\n%c[default]\n \n%c[221,255,193,255]Artefakt Trans-und MesoMutation\n%c[255,255,255,210]Benötigte Zeit®® : %c[255,224,224,160]5 Minuten\n%c[255,255,255,210]Wirkung Positiv® : %c[255,1,255,1]99%\n%c[255,255,255,210]Wirkung Negativ® : %c[255,255,1,1]1%\n%c[255,255,255,210]Ursprung®®®®®®®® : %c[255,1,255,1]Batterie\n%c[255,255,255,210]Anomalie Abhängig: %c[255,1,255,1]Eissturz\n%c[default]\n \nEinzigartiges Artefakt, das einer normalen "Batterie" im Aussehen ähnelt, komplett rot ist. Es ist Radioaktiv und strahlt einemenge Licht aus. Hat einen positiven Effekt auf die Wiederherstellung der Ausdauer und bietet einigen Schutz vor Stößen. Das "Rubin Batterie" Artefakt sollte die Effekte der Anomalien "Elektra" und "Vortex" liquidieren. Wenn man eine "Batterie" in die Anomalie "Eisschrank" wirft, kann man eine "Rubin-Batterie" bekommen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_info_red_spring_text">
			<text>\n \nRubin-Sprungfeder Modifkation\n%c[221,255,193,255]Körperliche Eigenschaften\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vital Gesundheit : %c[default]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vital Blutung®®® : %c[default]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vital Ausdauer®® : %c[default]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vital Hunger®®®® : %c[default]n/a\n%c[default]\n \n%c[221,255,193,255]Schutz und Resistenz\n%c[255,255,255,210]Strahlung®®®®®®® : %c[255,255,1,1]+5\n%c[255,255,255,210]Verbrennung®®®®® : %c[default]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]Elektroschock®®® : %c[default]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]Chemisch Verbre. : %c[default]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]PSI Telepatie®®® : %c[default]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vor Reißwunden®® : %c[default]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vor Projektile®® : %c[255,1,255,1]+4 %\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vor Explosion®®® : %c[255,1,255,1]+6 %\n%c[255,255,255,210]Aufprall Schutz® : %c[255,1,255,1]+16 %\n%c[default]\n \n%c[221,255,193,255]Artefakt Trans-und MesoMutation\n%c[255,255,255,210]Benötigte Zeit®® : %c[255,224,224,160]5 Minuten\n%c[255,255,255,210]Wirkung Positiv® : %c[255,1,255,1]99%\n%c[255,255,255,210]Wirkung Negativ® : %c[255,1,255,1]1%\n%c[255,255,255,210]Ursprung®®®®®®®® : %c[255,1,255,1]Sprungfeder\n%c[255,255,255,210]Anomalie Abhängig: %c[255,1,255,1]Eissturz\n%c[default]\n \nEinzigartiges Artefakt, das einer "Sprungfeder" im Aussehen ähnelt, rot leuchtend. Etwas radioaktiv und strahlt Licht aus. Bietet Schutz von Aufprallen. Das "Rubin-Springfeder" Artefakt kann die Effekte der Karussel-Anomalie liquidieren\n Wird geformt, wenn man das  "Sprungfeder" Artefakt in die Anomalie "Eissturz" wirft, bekommt man das Artefakt "Rubin-Sprungfeder" </text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_info_red_pellicle_text">
			<text>\n \nRubin-Pellicula Modifkation\n%c[221,255,193,255]Körperliche Eigenschaften\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vital Gesundheit : %c[255,1,255,1]+700 %\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vital Blutung®®® : %c[255,1,255,1]-33 %\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vital Ausdauer®® : %c[default]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vital Hunger®®®® : %c[default]n/a\n%c[default]\n \n%c[221,255,193,255]Schutz und Resistenz\n%c[255,255,255,210]Strahlung®®®®®®® : %c[255,255,1,1]+5\n%c[255,255,255,210]Verbrennung®®®®® : %c[default]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]Elektroschock®®® : %c[default]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]Chemisch Verbre. : %c[default]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]PSI Telepatie®®® : %c[default]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vor Reißwunden®® : %c[default]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vor Projektile®® : %c[255,255,1,1]-50 %\n%c[255,255,255,210]Vor Explosion®®® : %c[default]n/a\n%c[255,255,255,210]Aufprall Schutz® : %c[255,1,255,1]+5 %\n%c[default]\n \n%c[221,255,193,255]Artefakt Trans-und MesoMutation\n%c[255,255,255,210]Benötigte Zeit®® : %c[255,224,224,160]5 Minuten%c[255,255,255,210]Wirkung Positiv® : %c[255,1,255,1]99 %\n%c[255,255,255,210]Wirkung Negativ® : %c[255,255,1,1]1 %\n%c[255,255,255,210]Ursprung®®®®®®®® : %c[255,1,255,1]Pellicula\n%c[255,255,255,210]Anomalie Abhängig: %c[255,1,255,1]EisSturz\n%c[default]\n \nEinzigartiges Artefakt, aber etwas Radioaktiv. Hat ein paar  bemerkenswerte Eigenschaften wie schnell heilenden "kräfte" sowie eine schnell Heilende wirkung auf offene Wunden. Das Artefakt hat eine magnetische wirkung auf Metallische Objekte.\n \nArtefakt "Rubin-Pellicula" kann die Anomalie "Sprungbrett" liquidieren.\nWenn man das Artefakt  "Pellicula" in die Anomalie "EisSturz" wirft, bekommt man dadurch ein "Rubin-Pellicula"</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_enc_info_way100a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nIm Agroprom gibt es einen Übergang zum Kordon.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_enc_info_way101a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nIm Kordon gibt es einen Übergang zum Agroprom.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_enc_info_way102a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nAus Agroprom kann man nach Jantar gelangen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_enc_info_way103a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nIm Jantar-Sumpf gibt es einen direkten Übergang nach Agroprom.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_enc_info_way104a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nVon der Basis in der Rostok-Fabrik gelangen die Söldner zum Blockposten bei den Armeelagerhäusern.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_enc_info_way105a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nBei den Armeelagerhäusern gibt es einen direkten Weg ins Wildgebiet.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_enc_info_way106a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nVom Forschungszentrum im Jantar kann man zum Hirnschmelzer gelangen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_enc_info_way107a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nEs gibt einen Übergang vom Radar zum Dunklen Tal.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_enc_info_way108a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nEs wurde ein direkter Weg vom Radar nach Jantar entdeckt.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_enc_info_way109a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nEs gibt eine Möglichkeit aus dem Dunklen Tal zum Hirnschmelzer zu gelangen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_enc_info_way110a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nEs gibt ein Übergang von den Armee-Lager-Häusern zum Dunklen Tal.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_enc_info_way111a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nLukasch erzählte, das es ein Übergang aus der Freiheits-Basis zum Dunklen Tal gibt.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_enc_info_way112a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nDer Informant Snitch hat mir Informationen über einen Übergang von Radar zu den Armee-Lagerhäusern verkauft. Huckster, hat es so gemacht ... Und wohin gehst du ??</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_enc_info_way112b_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \n"Führer" in den Sümpfen zeigte mir eine Spur zum Alten Dorf</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_enc_info_way113a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nÜbergang zu Armeelagerhäusern</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_enc_info_way114a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nÜbergang zur Rostok-Fabrik</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_enc_info_way_false_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nÜbergang zum Tschernobyl AKW</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ways_info_way_false_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \nEs gibt eine Klasse der Anomalien, deren Wirkungsweise unbegreiflich ist\n \nAls Beispiel dafür kann eine Anomalie dienen, die Stalker "Teleport" nennen. Diese Anomalie kann, in einer fast nicht messbaren Zeitspanne, alles, was in ihr Inneres Gravitations Feld kommt, über große Entfernungen bewegen.\n \nDabei wirken auf das zu transportierende Objekt keinerlei Physische Kräfte ein. Gerüchten zufolge, gibt's nicht weit von der Bar - bei den Armeelagerhäusern - eine solche Anomalie, die einen direkt zum sagenumwobenen Monolithen teleportiert...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ways_info_way100a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \nAn den Kommandant des Truppen-Kontingentes "Schutzkordon".\n \nBericht\n \nAm 14.03.2012, gegen 2200 bei dem Abend-Appell, wurde entdeckt, das drei Soldaten meiner Abteilung, die auf dem Gebiet des ehemaligen Agroprom-Instituts stationiert ist, fehlten. Bei der Befragung anderer Soldaten kamen folgende Fakten zu Tage - die verschwundenen Dienstleistenden haben schon mehrmals die fehlenden Kontrollen seitens Unteroffiziere ausgenutzt und einen gewissen "Sidorowitsch" besucht, der ihnen alkoholische Getränke und berauschende Substanzen geliefert hat.\n \nDen Berichten anderer Dienstleistenden nach, haben die Verschwundenen während der Patrouillen einen unbekannten Durchgang nach "Kordon" gefunden. Die Lage und Koordinaten sind auf der beigelegten Karte gekennzeichnet. Die von mir durchgeführten Maßnahmen zur Suche nach vermissten Dienstleistenden haben keine Resultate gebracht.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ways_info_way101a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \n"Führer" berichtete:\n \nNicht weit hinter der ehemaligen Farm gibt es einen geheimen Übergang zum Agroprom Institut.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ways_info_way102a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nAls Dank für das Artefakt, womit die Wissenschaftler im Bunker ihre Experiemente nachgehen können. Bekam  ich die Info für einen gänzlich unbekannten Übergang zwischen Agroprom Forschungsinstitut und dem Mobil-Labor im Jantar-Sumpf hingewiesen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ways_info_way103a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nAus den Dokumenten, welche aus der Militärbasis im Agroprom gestohlen wurden, geht hervor, das die sie geplant haben, tiefer in die Zone vorzudringen. Und zwar durch einen wieder benutzbaren Weg, der durch das "X-16 Forschungszentrum" führt.\n \n Nicht weit vom mobilen Labor im Jantar-Sumpf.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ways_info_way104a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nBei der Durchsuchung des Söldner "Ara" wurde eine Karte mit einem geheimen Pfad gefunden. Diesen nutzten die Söldner, um von ihrer Basis, im Wildgebiet, weiter in die Zone vorzudringen- Richtung Armeelagerhäusern.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ways_info_way105a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nKull:\n \nDie Vernehmung eines gefangenen Söldners (jetzt begraben an den Koordinaten im beigefügten Diagramm) zeigt  Informationen über die Existenz eines verborgenen direkten Weges, von den Armee-Lagerhäusern bis zur Haupt-Söldner-Basis im Wildgebiet</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ways_info_way106a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nBei der Leiche des Wissenschaftlers, der den Auswirkungen des "Hirnschmelzers" im Roten Wald erlag, wurde eine Karte gefunden.\n \nAuf dieser ist ein Übergang vermerkt, der vom "Laboratorium X-16" in die direkte Nähe der Emitter-Antenne von Radar führt.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ways_info_way107a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nBei dem Blockposten der "Monolith"-Fraktion, dem Ausgang aus dem X-16 Labor (der von den Monolither gesprengt wurde) wurden jede Menge Dokumente zurückgelassen. Zwischen anderen wissenschaftlichen Daten befindet sich auch die Information über den zusätzlichen Übergang ins Dunkle Tal.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ways_info_way108a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nIn den entschlüsselten Daten, die Sidorowitsch an den Wirt übergab, steht: das Militär wird bald ein grandiosen Durchbruch ins Herz der Zone starten. Man fand heraus, das beim  Psi-emitter direkt aus dem X-16 Labor - Jantar erreichbar ist.\n \n Also kann man viel schneller und direkter die ausgestorbene Stadt Prypjat erreichen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ways_info_way109a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nBei einer Razzia der "Wächter" im Gebiet des X-18 Labors wurde ein Metall-Aktenkoffer mit Dokumenten entdeckt. Nachdem man die Informationen teilweise entschlüsselt hat, wurde es klar - die Militärs planen einen massiven Durchbruch ins Zentrum der Zone. Einer der Hauptwege wird dabei ein Übergang, der sich im Dunklen Tal befindet und direkt zum Radar-System führt.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ways_info_way110a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nLukasch, der "Freiheit"-Anführer, informierte mich über den Durchgang aus dem Dunklen Tal direkt in zu den Armee-Lagerhäuser in ihren Camp, den die Fraktionsmitglieder aktiv nutzen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ways_info_way111a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nIn Dankbarkeit für die erbrachten Leistungen gab Lukash mir die Erlaubnis, die geheime Passage aus dem Lager der "Freiheit" ins Dunkle Tal zu nutzen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ways_info_way112a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nVon einem Informanten hab ich die Übergangs  Koordinaten von Radar zu den Armee-Lagerhäuser.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ways_info_way113a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nInformationen von Mojito erhalten in Bezug auf einen Übergang mit dem Ziel zu den Armee-Lagerhäusern.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ways_info_way114a_text">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nDer Wirt hat mir Infos über die Übergangsmöglichkeit zur Rostok-Fabrik auf meinem PDA hochgeladen.\n \n \n \n \n \n(Marty2base, das muss überprüft werden weil der Titel "Vom Sumpf zum alten Dorf" nicht mit dem Inhalt übereinstimmt.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_quest_case_03_desc">
			<text>Scholar's Dokumente</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_quest_case_03_name">
			<text>Scholars Dokumente</text>
		</string>
		<string id="playboy_desc">
			<text>\n \nPlayboy ist ein US-amerikanisches Männermagazin, das primär für erotische Fotografie bzw. Aktfotografie bekannt ist, sich in seinen Artikeln aber auch mit verschiedensten Lifestyle-Themen beschäftigt.\n \nHerausgeber der amerikanischen Ausgabe ist das Unternehmen "Playboy Enterprises", das von Hugh Hefner gegründet und später von seiner Tochter Christie Hefner geleitet wurde. Es erscheint mittlerweile jeweils als Lizenzprodukt in der Landessprache und mit eigenen Themen in über 30 Ländern.\n \nDie erste Ausgabe erschien im Dezember 1953 in den Vereinigten Staaten und enthielt ein aufklappbares Blatt (Centerfold), auf dem Marilyn Monroe recht freizügig posierte, daneben eine Sherlock-Holmes-Geschichte, einen Artikel über die Dorsey-Brüder (Jimmy und Tommy) und einen Bericht über das Tisch-Design im modernen Büro. Von den 70.000 Exemplaren der Startauflage wurden 54.175 zum Preis von 0,50 US-Dollar verkauft.\n \nUrsprünglich sollte die Zeitschrift Stag Party ("Junggesellen-Party“) heißen, was aus markenrechtlichen Gründen jedoch nicht möglich war. Ein Freund des Herausgebers Hugh Hefner schlug dann den Namen Playboy vor.\n \nZu seinem Höhepunkt im Jahr 1975 hatte das Magazin für "Alles, was Männern Spaß macht“ in den Vereinigten Staaten eine reguläre Auflage von 5,6 Millionen Exemplaren. Die Ausgabe vom November 1972 verkaufte sogar eine einmalige Auflage von 7 Millionen Heften.\n \n Anfang der 1970er Jahre begann das Heft mit fremdsprachigen Ausgaben in europäischen Ländern, die ersten erschienen in Deutschland, Italien und Frankreich. Weitere internationale Ausgaben folgten.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="wpn_vintorez_m1">
			<text>-- WIRD NICHT BENUTZT? --</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_wpn_vintorez_m1">
			<text>-- WIRD NICHT BENUTZT? --</text>
		</string>
		<string id="playboy_name">
			<text>Der Playboy</text>
		</string>
		<string id="playboy_kruglov_desc">
			<text>\n \nPlayboy ist ein US-amerikanisches Männermagazin, das primär für erotische Fotografie bzw. Aktfotografie bekannt ist, sich in seinen Artikeln aber auch mit verschiedensten Lifestyle-Themen beschäftigt.\n \nHerausgeber der amerikanischen Ausgabe ist das Unternehmen "Playboy Enterprises", das von Hugh Hefner gegründet und später von seiner Tochter Christie Hefner geleitet wurde. Es erscheint mittlerweile jeweils als Lizenzprodukt in der Landessprache und mit eigenen Themen in über 30 Ländern.\n \nDie erste Ausgabe erschien im Dezember 1953 in den Vereinigten Staaten und enthielt ein aufklappbares Blatt (Centerfold), auf dem Marilyn Monroe recht freizügig posierte, daneben eine Sherlock-Holmes-Geschichte, einen Artikel über die Dorsey-Brüder (Jimmy und Tommy) und einen Bericht über das Tisch-Design im modernen Büro. Von den 70.000 Exemplaren der Startauflage wurden 54.175 zum Preis von 0,50 US-Dollar verkauft.\n \nUrsprünglich sollte die Zeitschrift Stag Party ("Junggesellen-Party“) heißen, was aus markenrechtlichen Gründen jedoch nicht möglich war. Ein Freund des Herausgebers Hugh Hefner schlug dann den Namen Playboy vor.\n \nZu seinem Höhepunkt im Jahr 1975 hatte das Magazin für "Alles, was Männern Spaß macht“ in den Vereinigten Staaten eine reguläre Auflage von 5,6 Millionen Exemplaren. Die Ausgabe vom November 1972 verkaufte sogar eine einmalige Auflage von 7 Millionen Heften.\n \n Anfang der 1970er Jahre begann das Heft mit fremdsprachigen Ausgaben in europäischen Ländern, die ersten erschienen in Deutschland, Italien und Frankreich. Weitere internationale Ausgaben folgten.\n \nKruglow kann, von Zeit zur Zeit, neue Ausgaben besorgen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="playboy_kruglov_name">
			<text>Playboy Sammlung (2006)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="outfit_soldiersak_desc">
			<text>-- WIRD NICHT BENUTZT --</text>
		</string>
		<string id="outfit_soldiersak_name">
			<text>-- WIRD NICHT BENUTZT --</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_861_dialog_0">
			<text>Ich brauche echt eine bessere Waffe. Gibt es irgendwelche besonderen Jobs, die ich tun kann?.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_861_dialog_1">
			<text>Nun.. Ich hätte da was für dich. Einer der Stalker war mit einem wichtigen Dokument zu mir unterwegs. Allerdings tappte er auf den weg in eine Anomalie. Er ist am Leben aber verlor das Dokument. Im moment ist er nicht in der Lage auch nur zu Krabbeln und ich kann die Rookies hier im Dorf nicht alleine lassen.\n \nWenn du das Dokument für mich findest, schenke ich dir eine "AK-74U". Das Dokument sollte irgendwo direkt Nördlich im Tunnel unter den Eisenbahngleisen liegen...\n \nWäre das Ok?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_861_dialog_2">
			<text>Na sicher.. warum nicht. Wenn die Dokumente dort liegen bringe ich sie dir.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_861_dialog_3">
			<text>Tut mir leid "Wolf", aber das ist nichts für mich.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_862_dialog_0">
			<text>Hey Wolf. Alles ruhig? Hast du was Neues?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_862_dialog_1">
			<text>Na ja.. Das Militär beim Posten dort unten ist nervös mit dem Zeigefinger, die "Wildschweine" und "Fleisch" statten uns ab und zu ein Besuch ab, Baby Sitter für die Neulinge spielen und hin und wieder Schlechten Wodka trinken. Halt ein Typischer Tag in der Zone - aber sonst - alles normal und ruhig...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_862_dialog_2">
			<text>Hier, ich hab ein Dokument gefunden. Meintest du das..?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_862_dialog_3">
			<text>Ja, genau, das ist es. Hier hast du die "AK-74U". Munition ist leider recht knapp, Ich konnte ein Magazin entbehren...\n \nVersuch mit "Kusnezow" zu reden, vielleicht kann er mit weiterer Munition  aushelfen...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_escape_lager_volk_document">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nWolf bat mich, ihm ein Dokument widerzubeschaffen welches in Kordon, Nördlich im Tunnel unter den Eisenbahngleisen zu finden sein soll. Damit hätte ich dann eine anständige "AK-74U".\n \nKein Problem...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_quest_case_02_desc">
			<text>\n \nFeuerfester Aktenkoffer mit Dokumenten.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_quest_case_02_name">
			<text>Militär-Dokumente</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_quest_case_06_desc">
			<text>\n \nEin Metall-Aktenkoffer.\n \nDer Fahnenflüchtige beim "Alten Trailer" in den "Sümpfen" sagte, das in diesem Koffer sich Hochbrisante Daten über die Zone befinden, die für den Kommandanten der Basis zugestellt wurden. Elektronisch abgeschlossen. Kann man entweder durch "Bruteforce" oder des jeweiligen "Codes" öffnen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_quest_case_06_name">
			<text>Dokumente aus der Militär-Basis</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_quest_sak_plan_name">
			<text>Sack mit "Gras"</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_quest_sak_plan_desc">
			<text>\n \nEin in wasserdichtes Sack verpacktes, hochwertiges "Afghan Kush Marijuana".</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_escort_captive_name">
			<text>Max Lubero</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_resiver_name">
			<text>Militär-Funkgerät</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_resiver_desc">
			<text>\n \nEin simples Armee-Funkgerät. Die veralterte Lampen-Bauweise macht dieses aber am widerstandsfähigsten gegen verschiedene Strahlungsarten der in der Zone.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_resiver_yantar_name">
			<text>Überwachungseinheit</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_resiver_yantar_desc">
			<text>\n \nIn ein einfaches Armee-Funkgerät modernes Überwachungssystem, das die Frequenzen der regulären UKW-Funkgeräte überwacht.\n \nDieses Konstruktion ermöglicht Fernüberwachung und kann in manchen Fällen eine genaue Ortung der gefundenen Teleporter, in der gesamten Zone aufspüren.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_case_esc_name">
			<text>Dokumente vom Außenposten</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_document_desc">
			<text>\n \nIn dem Dokument gibt es Infos über einen gefundenen Übergang.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_document_name">
			<text>Geheimes Dokument</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_rad_document6_desc">
			<text>\n \nDokumente mit Aufträgen und Notizen. Es könnte in diesem  alten Stapel von Papieren was nützliches dabei sein?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_rad_document6_name">
			<text>Mappe mit Dokumenten</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_rad_document7_desc">
			<text>\n \nMilitärbefehle der letzten sechs Monaten.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_rad_document7_name">
			<text>Mappe mit Dokumenten</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_document2_desc">
			<text>\n \nIn diesem Dokument sind Informationen über die möglichkeit einer Artefakt-Umwandlung enthalten.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_document2_name">
			<text>Dokumente und eine nicht lesbare Disk</text>
		</string>
		<string id="garbage_pda_name">
			<text>PDA mit wichtigen Informationen</text>
		</string>
		<string id="garbage_pda_desc">
			<text>\n \nPDA von der "Müllhalde" aus dem Lager der Banditen gefunden. Beeinhaltet nützliche Informationen zur Umwandlung eines Artefakts.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inventory_sakbox_01_name">
			<text>Kiste mit Munition</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inventory_sakbox_01_desc">
			<text>\n \nSchwere Holzkiste mit Muntion.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inventory_sakbox_02_name">
			<text>Metall-Kiste</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inventory_sakbox_02_desc">
			<text>\n \nMetall Kiste mit einem Set von Werkzeugen</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inventory_sakbox_03_name">
			<text>Tresor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inventory_sakbox_03_desc">
			<text>\n \nFeuerfester, gepanzerter Tresor. Codierter Magnetverschluss. Nur mir einem Gasbrenner zu öffnen. Was drin ist, weißt keiner...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inventory_sakbox_04_name">
			<text>Kleine Kiste</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inventory_sakbox_04_desc">
			<text>\n \nMetallkiste</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inventory_sakbox_05_name">
			<text>Schutzbehälter</text>
		</string>
		<string id="inventory_sakbox_05_desc">
			<text>\n \nEin Laborbehälter aus Metall. Dient dem Transport gefährlicher oder zerbrechlicher Substanzen und Gegenstände. In der Zone wird er  für den Transport von Artefakten mit unbekannten Eigenschaften benutzt.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_book1_name">
			<text>Buch</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_book1_desc">
			<text>\n \Wissenschaftliches Buch. Schwere Kost.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_book2_name">
			<text>Notizbuch</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_book2_desc">
			<text>\n \nNotizbuch, voll mit Formeln und Tabellen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_book3_name">
			<text>Buch</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_book3_desc">
			<text>\n \nEin unscheinbares Buch mit zerrissenen Seiten, die an den Rändern hervorstehen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="stukach_book_name">
			<text>Tagebuch</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doktor_book_desc">
			<text>\n \nDas Notizbuch des Sumpfdoktors. Den Einträgen nach zu urteilen - war er vor kurzem hier!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doktor_book_name">
			<text>Doktors Tagesplaner</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_computer_desc">
			<text>\n \nEin Computer aus dem Busbahnhof von Prypjat. Enthält wichtige Informationen, die nötig sind, um eine Teleportation zu berechnen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_computer_name">
			<text>Laptop</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_diplomat_desc">
			<text>\n \nEin Laptop aud dem "X-16 Labor". Enthält detaillierte seismologische und geologische Karten vom Jantar und umgebung.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="scaintist_pda_name">
			<text>PDA eines Wissenschaftlers</text>
		</string>
		<string id="scaintist_pda_desc">
			<text>\n \nPDA des Wissenschaftlers, der in Prypjat ums Leben kam. Enthält Informationen, die "Mojito" interessieren.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_diplomat_name">
			<text>Aktenkoffer mit Dokumenten</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_notebook_desc">
			<text>\n \nEin Laptop aus dem "X-18 Labor". Trotz der Feuchtigkeit ist das Ding ist noch funktionstüchig... Auf der Festplatte sind seismologische Karten der Armeelagerhäuser gespeichert.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_notebook_name">
			<text>Laptop mit wichtigen Daten</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_decoder1_name">
			<text>Kruglows Gerät</text>
		</string>
		<string id="item_decoder1_desc">
			<text>\n \nEin kompliziertes Mess- und Umwandlungsgerät.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agroprom_pda_name">
			<text>Mole's PDA</text>
		</string>
		<string id="agroprom_pda_desc">
			<text>\n \nEin PDA der einem Stalker mit dem Spitznamen Mole (Maulwurf) gehört.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="und_pda_name">
			<text>Max Lubero's PDA</text>
		</string>
		<string id="und_pda_desc">
			<text>\n \nMax Luber behauptet, das auf diesem PDA viele "Wächter"-Geheimnisse gespeichert sind.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="volkodav_pda_name">
			<text>PDA von Wolfhound</text>
		</string>
		<string id="volkodav_pda_desc">
			<text>\n \nZwischen den ganzen verschlüsselten Daten gibt es auch eine Beschreibung der Artefakt-Modifikation.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ara_pda_name">
			<text>Söldners PDA</text>
		</string>
		<string id="ara_pda_desc">
			<text>\n \nSöldner "Ara" hat viele Geheimnisse seiner Fraktion aufbewahrt, unter anderem die Beschreibung eines geheimen Übergangs zwischen Armeelagerhäusern und dem Wildgebiet.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="rad_pda_name">
			<text>PDA eines unbekannten Monolith-Anhängers</text>
		</string>
		<string id="rad_pda_desc">
			<text>\n \nIn der Nähe des Hirnschmelzers gefundener PDA. Zwischen dem ganzen religiösen Absurdum fand sich ein Rezept für Artefakt-Transmutation...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="quest_manycase_01_desc">
			<text>\n \nStahl-Aktenkoffer mit Codeschloss. Inhalt - Geld.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="quest_manycase_01_name">
			<text>Stahl-Aktenkoffer</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_esc_provodnik_groza">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nEin Stalker mit dem Namen "Führer" hat mich gebeten, ihm eine gute Waffe zu finden. Sturmgewehr "Thunder Assault" ist genau das Richtige.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_yan_scientist_find_af_dummy_glassbeads">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nProf. Sacharow braucht für eine Reihe von Experimenten ein seltenes Artefakt - "Mamas Perlen". Als Dank dafür, wird er Koordinaten eines neuentdeckten Übergangs verraten.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_yan_scientist_find_case">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nProf. Sacharow berichtete, das man dem Militär einen Metall-Aktenkoffer entwendet hat, in dem, unter anderem, auch Daten über dir Erforschung der Wege in die "tiefere" Zone liegen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_bar_dolg_leader_find_case">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nGeneral Woronin braucht dringend die Metallkiste mit Dokumenten, die im Dunklen Tal verloren wurde. Was in dieser Kiste ist - unbekannt...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_mil_lukash_find_dinamit">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nDer Anführer der "Freiheit"-Fraktion braucht Dynamit. Damit wird, vielleicht, ein Weg ins Dunkle Tal frei gemacht. Lukash sagte, das man Dynamit in Kordon im Lager der Neulinge finden kann. Wo genau - tja...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_esc_reward_case">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nIn der Kiste,die ich von der Militärbasis in Agroprom gestohlen habe, liegen ausschließlich verschlüsselte Dokumente die nur der Wirt in Rostok entziffern kann.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_esc_tolik_five_teily">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nTolik möchtet fünf Hundeschwänze haben. Er braucht diese für seine Artefakt-Modifikationen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_111_dialog_0">
			<text>Was gibt's denn noch? Willst du mich was fragen?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_111_dialog_1">
			<text>Ich traf vor kurzem einen erfahrenen Stalker, als wir zusammen ein getrunken haben, erzählte er mir über die Möglichkeit das Artefakt "Fleischklumpen" aus zwei anderen - zu bekommen. Dafür braucht man noch ein Hundeschwanz. Ich wollte ja welche besorgen - aber du siehst ja. Ich bin grade so am Leben geblieben. Wenn du mir so um 5 Stück von den Schwänzen bringst, erzähl ich dir wie das geht...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_111_dialog_2">
			<text>Gut, dann werd ich mal die blinden Biester ein bisschen rumscheuchen...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_111_dialog_3">
			<text>Nein, keine Zeit für so einen Qutsch..</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_112_dialog_0">
			<text>Hallo. Ich bring dir die Hundeschwänze...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_112_dialog_1">
			<text>Danke, Gezeichneter. Ich kann dir nicht genug danken!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_112_dialog_2">
			<text>Pack ein, solange sie noch nicht stinken...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_112_dialog_3">
			<text>Hier... Ich hab mir aufgeschrieben, wie man ein "Fleischklumpen" kochen kann... Hab's aber selber noch nicht versucht...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_121_dialog_0">
			<text>Wie kann ich dir helfen?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_121_dialog_1">
			<text>Ich und die Jungs versuchen dieses Gebiet zu kontrollieren und debei es von den Banditen und Mutanten zu beschützen. Dafür helfen Wolf und andere erfahrene Stalker uns mit Lebensmitel, Infos und anderen Sachen aus. NUr leider nicht was unsere Ausrüstung und Waffen angeht, das ist nicht gerade das beste, auch wenn man hier nicht viel Munition verbrät. \n \nWenn du eine Möglichkeit siehst, kannst du mir ein "TOZ-34" Jagdgewehr besorgen? Für unsere Aktion hier ist es die passende Waffe... Und ich erzähl dir dafür, wie man aus einem billigen Artefakt - ein höherwertiges bekommt...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_121_dialog_2">
			<text>Alles klar - mache ich. ich sah eins bei Sidorowitsch.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_121_dialog_3">
			<text>Beweg dein Arsch selbst. Bin doch nicht dein Lakei...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_122_dialog_0">
			<text>Grüß dich noch mal... Wie ist die Lage? Her ist das Jagdgewehr.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_122_dialog_1">
			<text>Genau im richtigen Moment. Die Banditen verursachen wieder Probleme ...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_122_dialog_2">
			<text>Ok .. Hier hast du es. Braucht ihr Hilfe?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_122_dialog_3">
			<text>Nein, wir schaffen das schon, aber danke - Warte, ich wollte dir doch noch erzählen, wie man das Arttefakt "Reglette" bekommt. Also: du nimmst eine "Qualle", "Gepresstes", ein Hundeschwanz und Stück ein Wurst .. so um die 300 Gramm... Lach nicht, das ist ernst!  Wirfst das alles in die "Vortex" Anomalie, und so nach 10 Minuten ist die "Reglette" fertig. Ich hab's schon mal selbst gemacht - glaub mir.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_esc_petruha_toz">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nPetruha benötigt mehr Feuerkraft bei wenig Muntion. Er bat mich um ein "TOZ-34" Jagdgewehr, welches ihm bei der Verteidigung gegen die Banditen und Mutanten, bei der Autowerkstatt, von Nutzen wäre...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_131_dialog_0">
			<text>Hast du irgendwelche Informationen über - sogenannte Artefakt-Modifikation?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_131_dialog_1">
			<text>Oh ja - Hatte einen besoffenen Banditen belauscht, wie er rumprallte, das er bald reich wäre... Das man aus einer "Qualle" ein "cooleres" Artefakt machen kann.\n \nWollen wir es versuchen? Wenn du eine "Qualle" besorgst, erzähl ich dir wie es geht...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_131_dialog_2">
			<text>Interessant, lass uns das versuchen...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_131_dialog_3">
			<text>Ach Quatsch, Da hast du dich verhört...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_132_dialog_0">
			<text>Wie geht's? Ich hab hier eine "Qualle" gefunden...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_132_dialog_1">
			<text>Toll, dann werde ich mal versuchen diese - Transmutation, ist wohl ein Fachjargon für Modifkation - zu machen...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_132_dialog_2">
			<text>Klar! .. also Hier. Und wie geht es nun weiter?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_132_dialog_3">
			<text>O-K-A-Y .. Also der Bandit erzählte das man je eins von den Artefakten "Qualle" und "Steinblut" in die Anomlie "Karussell" wirft. Und jetzt komms .. dazu noch ein Verband und eine Konserve. Was dabei rauskommt - keien Ahnung. Das konnt ich nicht mehr verstehen. Ist aber sicher nützlich...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_esc_shustryi_medusa">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nNimble möchte die Artefakt-Modifikation ausprobieren, über die er von einem Banditen hörte. Dafür braucht er das Artefakt "Qualle"\n \n \n \n \n \ntex_esc_shustryi_medusa (Doppelt?)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_esc_shustryi_Jellyfish">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nNimble möchte die Artefakt-Modifikation ausprobieren, über die er von einem Banditen hörte. Dafür braucht er das Artefakt "Qualle"\n \n \n \n \n \ntex_esc_shustryi_Jellyfish (Doppelt?)</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_141_dialog_0">
			<text>Major..? Sagen sie, wie wäre es mit einem Geschäft? Ich möchte nicht repektlos erscheinen aber sie und ihre Jungs scheinen da ja ein kleinen wenig Bedarf an Alkohol zu haben. 1 Flasche? .. Kommen sie ... da geht mehr - interessiert?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_141_dialog_1">
			<text>Hmm... Pass auf... Ich hab bald Geburtstag. Eine runde Zahl. Das möchte ich richtig feiern. Zu essen gibt's genug, aber kaum was zum Aufwärmen.\n \nSelbst kann ich nicht zum Händler - bin ja im Dienst. Wenn du mir eine halbe Kiste Wodka bringst, also 10 Flaschen, dann können wir hier abfeiern. Mal sehen .. Munition hätte ich für dich - zum Beispiel. Und eventuell auch Informationen. \n \nZum beispiel haben wir vor kurzem einen "Runner" verhaftet. Das sind die die versuchen entweder Links oder Rechts über die Gleise zu laufen und hoffen nicht erwischt zu werden. Er brabbelte, das man eine "Qualle" zum "Dornenkristall" verwandeln könnte.\n \nWenn du mehr wissen willst - besorg den Wodka.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_141_dialog_2">
			<text>Halbe Kiste also... So schwer wird es schon nicht sein, diese Menge zu besorgen. Und neugierig auf diese Artefakt-Umwandlung bin ich auch.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_141_dialog_3">
			<text>Neee, das ist mir die Mühe nicht Wert. Entschuldigen sie die Störung...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_142_dialog_0">
			<text>Seien Sie gegrüßt und herzlichen Glückwunsch!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_142_dialog_1">
			<text>Oha, da hat jemand wort gehalten. Hast du etwas was für mich?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_142_dialog_2">
			<text>Ja, hier. 10 Flaschen. Nix selbstgebranntes, alles Original.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_142_dialog_3">
			<text>Sehr schön! JUNGS HIER GIBST WAS ZU TRINKEN!\n \nDein Gesicht werde ich mir merken, auf dich ist wohl verlass. Also wenn du mal was brauchst... Hier hast du zwei - nein - drei Packungen Munition. Panzerbrechend. Ach ja, und das versprochene Rezept... Hol mal dein PDA raus, wir sollten nicht zu lange quatschen und wie gesagt wenn du irgendwelche Ausrüstung von mir in Zukunft haben willst, vergesse nicht den Wodka mitzubringen.\n \nEs gibt noch eine kleine Sache die ich mit dir besprechen möchte, aber das kann warten ...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_esc_bridge_vodka">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nMajor Kusnezow kann was über Artefakt-Modifikationen erzählen und mich mit Munition versorgen. Als Gegenleistung für eine halbe Kiste Wodka.\n \n10 Flaschen werden sicher kein Problem sein. </text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_161_dialog_0">
			<text>Brauchst du noch ein Medikit?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_161_dialog_1">
			<text>Sag lieber nichts... Diese blinden Hunde mutieren ständig weiter. Eine kleine Wunde reicht um draufzugehen, wenn man diese nicht sofort behandelt. \n \nWenn du einverstanden wärst, würde ich dir für 12 Standart-Medikits ein Rezept einer Artefakt-Transmutation zukommen lassen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_161_dialog_2">
			<text>Gut, werde ich besorgen. Tja, die Zone... Je weiter, desto schlimmer.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_161_dialog_3">
			<text>Tut mir leid Fox, aber ich muss weiter. Du schaffst das schon ...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_162_dialog_0">
			<text>Hey Fox, ich hab dir die Medikits mitgebracht, wie versprochen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_162_dialog_1">
			<text>Ausgezeichnet. Da sind Armee-Medkits? Richtig?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_162_dialog_2">
			<text>Ja, klar. 110% - Diese wolltest du ja. Das habe ich gefühlt und Armee-Medikits gibst hier in Hülle und Fülle - alter? Natürlch nur die Normalen Standard Medikits.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_162_dialog_3">
			<text>Oh .. Na gut! Sorry, mein Fehler.\n \nHier Schreib dir mal das Rezept auf - du wirfst nacheinander in die "Elektra" Anomalie ein "Steinblut", eine "Qualle" und ein Hundeschwanz und das alles wird mit einem halben Liter Wodka übergossen. Nach 10-15 Minuten bekommst du das Artefakt "Feuerball"!\n \nNur Standard Medikits ...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_esc_fox_medkit">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \n"Fox" braucht Medikits. So mindestens 10 Stück.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_211_dialog_0">
			<text>Hast du gesagt "Danke?" Tut mir leid - ich habe dich nicht gehört. Wie oft habe ich dich von den Toten zurückgebracht?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_211_dialog_1">
			<text>Schau mich doch an... Ich bin ganz neu hier. Keiner beachtet mich. Und mit einer modifiziertern Waffe wäre ich schon jemand... \n \nGute Munition ist hier kaum aufzutreiben, aber Patronen für PM-Pistolen gibt es wie Sand am Meer. Man erzählt, das ein Waffenmeister aus der Zone die MP5-Maschinenpistolen für solche Patronen umbaut... Ich weiß genau, das ein Stalker, der so eine Maschinenpistole hatte, vor kurzem verreckt ist. Im Eisenbahntunnel, der von der Müllhalde zum Agroprom führt... Kannst du sie mir besorgen?\n \nIch begleiche meine Schuld bestimmt und werde dir über erzählen, wie man z.b ein Artefakt modifiziert.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_211_dialog_2">
			<text>Im Tunnel also... Na gut, liegt eh auf meinem Weg.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_211_dialog_3">
			<text>Ich verspreche nichts. Wenns klappt, dann klappt...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_212_dialog_0">
			<text>Rate mal, wo ich gewesen bin ...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_212_dialog_1">
			<text>Hast du die Waffe?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_212_dialog_2">
			<text>Gefunden, ausprobiert... Nicht schlecht... Hier hast du die...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_212_dialog_3">
			<text>Mit dieser Waffe werde ich König der Müllhalde sein... Mit einem "Danke" wird man ja nicht satt - und du schaust auch schon ganz komisch ..hier is das Artefakt-Rezept. Hab ich dir Hochgeladen...\n \nUnd hör mal, Gezeichneter... Kann ich dich um noch ein Gefallen bitten?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_gar_dram_novice_mp5_m1">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nJurik, ein Anfänger von der Müllhalde, möchtet eine für PM-Munition modifizierte MP5 haben.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_811_dialog_0">
			<text>Was ist das nur für ein Tag?! Jeder will was von mir... Was ist?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_811_dialog_1">
			<text>Ich bin erst seit gestern aus Kordon raus, kenne mich noch kaum aus... Ich wollte allen beweisen, das ich es drauf habe, und siehe da - bin sofort Banditen in die Arme gelaufen. Wenn ich leer zurückkehre, werd ich zum Gespöt anderer Anfänger... Wenn ich aber wenigstens mit einem Mutantenteil, zum Beispiel einer Hand des Bürers, im Lager ankomme... Dann muß ich mich nicht so schämen... Hilfst du mir? \n \nUnd ich erzähle dir von einem Speziellen Artefakt...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_811_dialog_2">
			<text>Von einem Bürer?! Du hast Wünsche... Anfänger... Na ja, wenn sich eine Möglichkeit ergibt, dann bring ich's dir.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_811_dialog_3">
			<text>Sorry, Yurek, aber so kannst du dir kein Respekt verdienen... Das mußt du schon selbst machen... Werd erwachsen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_812_dialog_0">
			<text>Hey, Yurek. Brauchts du noch die Hand des Bürers?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_812_dialog_1">
			<text>Ja! Natürlich! Hast du denn eine?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_812_dialog_2">
			<text>Hier, fang! .. Gut.. Jetzt kannst du sagen, du hast dir eine eingefangen!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_812_dialog_3">
			<text>Hey... Jetzt kann ich im Lager stolz Geschichten erzählen... Über dich, natürlich... \n \nAch ja, wegen dem Speziellen Artefakt - ich hab mal die Banditen bespitzelt, die erzählten, das hier in der Nähe, im Wäldchen hinter dem Sumpf, ein Artefakt "Smaragd-Qualle" liegt. Da gibt's eine Menge Chimeras und andere Mutanten, darum wollten sie da nicht hin...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_gar_dram_novice_burer_hand">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nYurek, ein Anfänger von der Müllhalde, bittet mich weil er zu feige ist eine Hand des Bürers zu besorgen...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_831_dialog_0">
			<text>Was für ein Geschäft hast du für mich?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_831_dialog_1">
			<text>Ich hörte, das du unserem "Alten", dem Feldwebel, zur Heilung verhelfen möchtest. Tue uns doch auch ein Gefallen. \n \nMan kann die Widerstandsfähigkeit des Körpers gegen Strahlung und Anomalien erhöhen... Dafür muß man einen halben Liter Likör aus Wodka und Wildschweinhufen "auf Ex" trinken... Wir sind hier acht Mann, wenn du uns acht Hufen und acht Flaschen Wodka bringst - schenken wir dir ein sehr nützliches und teures Artefakt... \n \nAbgemacht?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_831_dialog_2">
			<text>Na gut, den Gefallen tue ich euch... Was man sich alles ausdenkt, um sich zu besaufen...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_831_dialog_3">
			<text>Max, anstatt am Lagerfeuer rumzusitzen, kannst du doch dein Arsch bewegen und die Schweine selber schiessen...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_832_dialog_0">
			<text>Verdammt, Bist du auch mal aufgestanden, solange ich weg war?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_832_dialog_1">
			<text>Mach kein Lärm, Gezeichneter... Ich meditiere.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_832_dialog_2">
			<text>Hier, deine Pullen und die Hufen. Nicht das ich hier immer einen Lieferanten spielen muß...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_832_dialog_3">
			<text>Fein, Bruder... Jetzt werden wir zu Terminatoren! Hier ist unser Geschenk für dich.\n \nEin "Rubin-Häutchen" - es heilt dich ruck-zuck... Und damit du es weißt - dieses rotes "Häutchen" kannst du aus einem einfachen bekommen. Du wirfst es in den "Eisschrank" und dann kommt dieses "Rubinchen" raus.\n \nFast hätte ich's vergessen - "Rubin-Häutchen" kann auch eine Anomalie vernichten - hab nur vergessen, welche...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_val_pula_boar_leg">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nPrapor bittet mich 8 Wildschweinhufen und 8 Flaschen Wodka zu sammeln. Verspricht dafür ein ungewöhnliches Artefakt als Belohnung.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_221_dialog_0">
			<text>Was ist mit deinem Anzug passiert?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_221_dialog_1">
			<text>Der ist sogut wie durch...habe ihn von einer Leiche. Der ist  schon total durchgetragen und die Panzerplatten verdienen den Namen nicht mehr. Es gab mal eine Stalker-Gruppe, die hatten immer modifizierte Anzüge an. Manche davon liegen immer noch in der Zone versteckt. Wenn du für mich so ein Stalker-Anzug findest, würde ich dir dafür eine nützliche Information geben.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_221_dialog_2">
			<text>Modifiziertern Stalker-Anzug? Gut, bring ich dir, wenn ich's finde.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_221_dialog_3">
			<text>Wenn ich ein in die Hände bekomme, behalte ich den lieber für mich.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_222_dialog_0">
			<text>Na, Bes? Noch am Leben? Das ist schön...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_222_dialog_1">
			<text>Noch ja... Mein Anzug sieht aus wie ein Sieb.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_222_dialog_2">
			<text>Ich hab dir einen neuen mitgebracht... Hier.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_222_dialog_3">
			<text>Du bist in Ordnung, Gezeichneter! Super...Also hör zu und schreib's dir auf - man bekommt ein "Schleim"-Artefakt aus einer "Qualle", in dem man die zusammen mit einem Hundeschwanz, einem Verband und einer Konservendose in die Anomalie "Vortex" wirft. Alles klar..</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_gar_hellcar_outfit">
			<text>"Bes", der Anführer der Stalker bei der Müllhalde, möchte einen neuen Speziellen Stalker-Anzug.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_311_dialog_0">
			<text>Und sonst alles okay??</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_311_dialog_1">
			<text>Mein Rücken bringt mich noch um... Ob es dieses Wetter hier ist, oder sonst was, weiß ich nicht... Wenn so ein Schuss kommt - bin ich steif wie ein Spatenstiel... Die Jungs lachen, aber die wissen nicht, wie das ist... Vor kurzem war hier ein alter Stalker - man nennt ihn "Prowodnik" - schon mal getroffen? Er hat mir geraten ein Likör aus Fleischaugen einzunehmen, sagte das es sehr gut hilft bei Rückenschmerzen...\n \nWenn du mir drei, nein, lieber vier Fleischaugen bringst, werde ich dich gut entlohnen...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_311_dialog_2">
			<text>Fleischaugen? Werde ich besorgen...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_311_dialog_3">
			<text>Sind doch alles Lügen... Außerdem hab ich keine Zeit...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_312_dialog_0">
			<text>Was macht dein Rücken?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_312_dialog_1">
			<text>Geht's grad noch so... Was ist mit den Augen?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_312_dialog_2">
			<text>Hier, schauen dich an...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_312_dialog_3">
			<text>Danke dir... Du, junger Spund, verstehst es noch nicht, wie es ist, mit kaputten Rücken beim Blockposten Dienst zu schieben...So, ich hab hier ein Rezeptchen aufgeschrieben, verlier's nicht. Und ich werd mal das Likör aufsetzen...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_gar_dolg_flesh_eye">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nPrapor, Wächter-Kommandeur auf der Müllhalde, möchtet vier Fleischaugen haben...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_321_dialog_0">
			<text>Was ist? Hat der Augen-Likör nicht geholfen?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_321_dialog_1">
			<text>Keine Ahnung... Vielleicht brauch ich noch mehr davon... Der Doktor sagte was von einer Salbe die aus einem Blutsauger-Tentakel hergestellt wird , die soll sehr gut helfen... Traust du dir zu, 3 Stück davon zu besorgen? Die Bezahlung wird schon stimmen...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_321_dialog_2">
			<text>Blutsauger-Tentakeln? Nett! Ich kann's ja versuchen...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_321_dialog_3">
			<text>Tut mir leid. Wegen deinem Rücken werde ich mich nicht mit Blutsaugern anlegen.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_322_dialog_0">
			<text>Wie läuft's? Klappt die Kampfstellung?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_322_dialog_1">
			<text>Wäre schön.. Meine Hoffnungen beruhen alle nun auf die - Wundersalbe...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_322_dialog_2">
			<text>Hier hast du die Tentakeln, aber, meiner Meinung nach, machst du es nur schlimmer...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_322_dialog_3">
			<text>Schlimmer geht's eh nicht mehr, vielleicht hilft's... Gib mal dein PDA her, kriegst von mir ein Rezept über Artefakt Modifikation von "Gepresstes" zum "Blitz"...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_322_dialog_4">
			<text>Nun ... Gute Besserung...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_gar_dolg_krovosos_jaw">
			<text>\n \n \n \n \n \nPrapor, Wächter-Kommandeur auf der Müllhalde, möchte drei Blutsauger-Tentakeln haben...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_711_dialog_0">
			<text>Gesundheit wünsch ich dir! Wie geht's?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_711_dialog_1">
			<text>The Brainiacs in the back room at the Bar say that a belt made from Pseudodogs' tails will somehow radiate heat to the body's core. Can you bring me five of them? In exchange, I'll give you a rare artefact</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_711_dialog_2">
			<text>Yes these tails as dirt, bring it, do not worry</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_711_dialog_3">
			<text>I'm sorry, but I've no intention of getting myself ripped to bits just to keep someone warm...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_712_dialog_0">
			<text>What about you? I looked in the firing position</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_712_dialog_1">
			<text>It's starting to get cold at night, we need to find ways to keep warm</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_712_dialog_2">
			<text>Here are your tails, and you have an artefact for me?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_712_dialog_3">
			<text>Oh yes, please take it! With my thanks!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_gar_dolg_psevdodog_tail">
			<text>Prapor, the Duty Commander in the Garbage, has asked me to bring him five Pseudodog tails</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_821_dialog_0">
			<text>If it's all the same to you, I need to talk with Petrenko</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_821_dialog_1">
			<text>alls agree ?!! Do you have to hold cops ?!\nWhile,\nThere is one option.\nWhen we examined the scene where the helicopter crash in the Forgotten Forest, I saw there was an interesting artefact, but to take it did not work, the military arrived. And it is not so far from the entrance to the location, near the three red barrels. But there's one problem, there are many mutants, and mines to come across.\nSince then, I dreamt that damned green stuff.\nCan you bring? there are other rare ones that might interest you as well...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_821_dialog_2">
			<text>I'll go and check it out for you</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_821_dialog_3">
			<text>And you say no cops. I'm going to talk to the bartender instead</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_822_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello Sergeant. Why the red eyes?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_822_dialog_1">
			<text>I slept badly. Old, unpleasant dreams...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_822_dialog_2">
			<text>Keep your riddle, sleep well</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_822_dialog_3">
			<text>Till my dying day I will appreciate, Green plague.\nSo your gift, I think, be useful.\nYou can take. Friend</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_bar_dolg_base_guard_art">
			<text>\nSergeant Plichko, head of Duty territory, spotted an unusual artefact in the Forgotten Forest, not far from the entrance by the three red barrels. For this, Plichko promises a reward of an artefact modification Recipe, and permanent access to the Duty base</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_851_dialog_0">
			<text>May have a case there?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_851_dialog_1">
			<text>There is one option.\nWhen we last tried to get into the X-16, I thought I saw an unusual artefact. We then fought off the Zombies right at the exit from the factory. There at the far wall, right, as viewed from the entrance, is a green construction trailer and inside it was something. At this time the controller has brought us to pass the buck and had to move very quickly.\nCan you bring? I have a new model of anomaly detector, which can determine the type of anomalies</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_851_dialog_2">
			<text>I need to visit Yantar anyway... Sure</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_851_dialog_3">
			<text>pass my regards to the controller, I'm not trying</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_852_dialog_0">
			<text>Hi Master of science</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_852_dialog_1">
			<text>And hello to you, Don Quixote Zonovsky</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_852_dialog_2">
			<text>Keep your mystery, Guide</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_852_dialog_3">
			<text>Op-pa, so that's what you're like. Emerald.\nKeep decoder, I think, useful</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_yan_kruglov_green_art">
			<text>\nKruglov saw an unusual artefact in the factory Yantar (from the entrance to the factory, right to the end, in the construction trailer). If you bring this artefact, he promises to give you the new anomaly detector</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_841_dialog_0">
			<text>What else?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_841_dialog_1">
			<text>We sent for slaughter, so I rest awhile. To return to the mainland and to prove it, I need an order, which we then gave. To my knowledge, all the orders were stored in a metal safe. The captain kept it on the second floor of the complex. If you got hold of this folder with the orders, then I can quietly dissapear. As a thanks I can offer a very rare artefact, Ruby Battery. Well?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_841_dialog_2">
			<text>Anything to get you out of here... eh?.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_841_dialog_3">
			<text>No man, Agroprom is too hot for me</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_842_dialog_0">
			<text>Hi soldier. Any news?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_842_dialog_1">
			<text>What? All bad?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_842_dialog_2">
			<text>Contrary, all is well. I found these instructions, keep them</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_842_dialog_3">
			<text>Till my dying day I will appreciate this.\nSo you're gift, I think, will be useful.\nWe will not meet again. Farewell</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_ratcatcher_order">
			<text>\ndeserter requests for him to steal the wrongful orders from his superiors. According to a deserter, a folder with the orders kept in a metal safe, on the second floor of the Agricultural Industry</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_251_dialog_0">
			<text>What matter? Do not keep</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_251_dialog_1">
			<text>I have a couple of days ago, sat in the railway tunnel, in that opposite the entrance to the plant. SOS received from the local guys and pulled to the rescue, but in the confusion charges dropped his PDA. Then warriors came down. Not until I was, maybe shuffling back and forth on the fast, can you find it?. But look out, area was full of anomalies</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_251_dialog_2">
			<text>If I find it, I'll let you know</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_251_dialog_3">
			<text>Anomalies? No, I have my own paths to follow</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_252_dialog_0">
			<text>I found your PDA</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_252_dialog_1">
			<text>Not damaged?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_252_dialog_2">
			<text>No stop. Check it</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_252_dialog_3">
			<text>Unbelievable, even the batteries are not exhausted. Come on your own, and I promise you the recipe for the Slime artefact</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_agr_krot_PDA">
			<text>\nMole requests to find his PDA, which he dropped in a railway tunnel outside the entrance to Agroprom</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_871_dialog_0">
			<text>Hi Wolf! What are you doing here ?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_871_dialog_1">
			<text>Hi Marked One. So, look for business from here, in the case of breaking the barrier should cause reinforcements from the bar. Tolik, became faint and fell somewhere with the radio, this radio is crucial for monitoring the military. Can you learn about Tolik? I'll let you in on a big secret, how you can eliminate the anomalies, if they are in the way</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_871_dialog_2">
			<text>Perhaps even a Mincer? Okay I'll find this poor guy</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_871_dialog_3">
			<text>I think Tolik will soon be dead</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_872_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello Wolf, I found Tolik</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_872_dialog_1">
			<text>What's wrong with him? Where's the radio tranceiver?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_872_dialog_2">
			<text>Here, hold. And Tolik, weak-willed, I saw so bloodsucking flashed his heels, mind screwed, release started</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_872_dialog_3">
			<text>Ha, that I overcame, emissions often go.\nSo, about anomalies: I only know as electricity discharge, be it Ruby Battery roll.\nMaybe with other anomalies can be so do you need to look for ways?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_873_dialog_0">
			<text>Tolik! Why are you sitting there! Wolf is waiting for your ass and the portable radio in the warehouses!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_873_dialog_1">
			<text>Forgive me, I do not think that in a trouble I caused. On the way to me, threw two no, four bloodsuckers! I put down three, but ran out of ammunition and then my knife broke. Barely alive, gone. Now here's nerves vodka corrected, do not want 300 grams?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_873_dialog_2">
			<text>Well Tolik, nerves of steel. Where's the transceiver?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_873_dialog_3">
			<text>Yes there somewhere, for hangars at dump passes trench in which pipe lying around, tractor... I guess there is, if bloodsuckers themselves have not taken, and-and-a, sorry</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_mil_volk_resiver">
			<text>Wolf is trying to monitor the military, and ideally needs a proper army radio transceiver. Tolik was supposed to bring him one, but has not been in touch. I need to find out what happened to it, and deliver it to Wolf</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_431_dialog_0">
			<text>Wow! The guys at the Barrier ask for ammunition as if they feel every shot fired</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_431_dialog_1">
			<text>Heh. And the ammunition is in trouble. End They've got more than NATO weapons, but here in the warehouses only to the Kalash Zinc. Sidor has promised to send the box, the other, but you need to find him a courier. I promised him a new artefact, let the pen, and cartridges. Can hit the road? But not for just. Here to me from all sides flocking information, there are some unusual recipies available</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_431_dialog_2">
			<text>Do not pay it, doing the right thing. I'll go</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_431_dialog_3">
			<text>No, I'm not going</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_432_dialog_0">
			<text>E-me! Keep cartridges. Box. Severe infection!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_432_dialog_1">
			<text>need? What caliber?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_432_dialog_2">
			<text>Written, 5.56, but what's inside, not tested</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_432_dialog_3">
			<text>Yes, those that need. Give me your PDA - I promised you the recipe for the Slime artefact. If you're interested, I have other recipes you can earn, too</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_433_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello Sydor, all sitting there guzzling booze, cannot fool the tank</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_433_dialog_1">
			<text>Bring worms, and you have the same will be. From what has come?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_433_dialog_2">
			<text>Miser sent you a rare artefact, I do not know what, in the sealed box. Asks for NATO ammunition</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_433_dialog_3">
			<text>Yes, he has contacted by radio. Keep the box, look, do not fall, heh, heh, heh</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_mil_Svoboda_trader_ammo">
			<text>\nCartridges at the end of the block office near the Barrier. Sidorovich asked Miser to exchange a rare artefact for a box of cartridges</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_411_dialog_0">
			<text>You said, there are recipes?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_411_dialog_1">
			<text>There. Here a small business. From the knowledgeable people I have information, a group of young military researchers worked with the artefact Cobblestone. They investigated its anti-gravity properties and the applicability of it. The work is not finished, they were lured to America. But two pilot suits with this effect still exist. As usual with the military, about these suits, no one remembers, thrown into an attic and forgotten. Care to steal them for me?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_411_dialog_2">
			<text>Interesting, be sure to see, what it is</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_411_dialog_3">
			<text>contact with the military reluctant to</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_412_dialog_0">
			<text>I found these suits, awsome things!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_412_dialog_1">
			<text>And what properties?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_412_dialog_2">
			<text>allows users to raise an additional 170 kg, but the heavy. Even harmful effects due to their enhancements</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_412_dialog_3">
			<text>OK! Thank you, leave yourself alone, can be useful. Recipie has been added</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_mil_Svoboda_trader_outfit">
			<text>\nMiser drew a diagram on how to get to the unique anti-gravity suits. Let me clarify tho: because of the unexplored properties, they tend to fall through the thin wooden floor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_451_dialog_0">
			<text>You said there are recipes?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_451_dialog_1">
			<text>There. The guys we have brave, risky. But sometimes they want to thoroughly relax. Treated with vodka, but now rumor, for Agroprom as a result of mutation common hemp acquired special properties, smoke and more three times become, almost through the objects you see. A sense. There, one man moved, mowing it dries. Since fasting had trouble eating rats, drinking swamp water. Take him genuine human food, twenty cans of canned goods, bread and vodka. He'll give you a bag of high quality grass</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_451_dialog_2">
			<text>Stronger than three times?! Wow, try</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_451_dialog_3">
			<text>What are you! Drug couriers to make me want to!!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_452_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello, drug lords, Keep your 'Plan'</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_452_dialog_1">
			<text>Like grass? Inserts?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_452_dialog_2">
			<text>himself try, I do not want to become an experimental rat</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_452_dialog_3">
			<text>Okay, Okay, try. Take a recipe, more I do not have</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_mil_Svoboda_trader_plan">
			<text>trader Liberty eager to try new, unique herb from the Agroprom! I want twenty cans, twenty loaves, twenty sticks of sausage and five bottles of vodka. In exchange for this Ill give you a bag</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_453_dialog_0">
			<text>Greetings, brave man. They say the grass is radiated?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_453_dialog_1">
			<text>CRYPTO?! WOW! Give me some papers!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_453_dialog_2">
			<text>Cmon, do not be a nuisance. I've brought you munchies, absolutely healthy food</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_453_dialog_3">
			<text>Seriously? Though the man himself feel, and how the dog. If you are interested in the grass, directly opposite the entrance lies a bag that's dry.\nCan you ask?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_421_dialog_0">
			<text>Who else can I help out?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_421_dialog_1">
			<text>You know Bes, commander of the neutrals in the dump? His unit has run out of ammunition, I have here the bandits' caches, including a box of ammunition. Take it to Bes for me? But remember, it's one HEAVY box. And he can do a lot of wandering in the Zone!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_421_dialog_2">
			<text>Yes, and I'm not weak, I'll help the stalkers</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_421_dialog_3">
			<text>my Lab to look for</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_422_dialog_0">
			<text>Hi Bes, here, bullet cartridges for you</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_422_dialog_1">
			<text>Just in time! Bandits already showin thier ugly muts!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_422_dialog_2">
			<text>Keep the box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_422_dialog_3">
			<text>Thank you, yes, more. Here, a recipe for converting artefacts</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_val_pula_ammo">
			<text>Bullet sends ammunition to you Bes, commander of the detachment of the neutrals in the Garbage</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_461_dialog_00">
			<text>not be able to help me find a PDA?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_461_dialog_0">
			<text>Where did you plant it?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_461_dialog_1">
			<text>me in the Agricultural Industry, captured in a dungeon. And my PDA, I specifically had hidden there, I thought: it's the end for me, but the PDA has information that should not fall into hands of bandits. I have him on the stairs, near a small corridor with anomalies to the left, there Shemka. Verney, eh? I am in gratitude, conversion recipe: artefacts Stone Blood and Fireball, to a Soul you'll get</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_461_dialog_2">
			<text>interesting recipe. Try</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_461_dialog_3">
			<text>my lab to look for</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_462_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello, barely found your PDA</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_462_dialog_1">
			<text>man</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_462_dialog_2">
			<text>Take</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_462_dialog_3">
			<text>my gratitude has no limits! Give communication code, Salt will you a way to convert.\nCan you even one little crank?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_val_escort_PDA">
			<text>\nReturn Dolgovs PDA, which he hid in a basement of the Agricultural Industry. According to Dolgov, PDA should be at the top of the stairwell, which runs near the hole in the wall, diverting into the hallway with Electro anomalies</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_351_dialog_0">
			<text>I can, why not, if the award is appropriate</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_351_dialog_1">
			<text>Do not worry, do not hurt. I heard that you can convert artefacts? I know a couple of ways, For example: how to get Gravi from Medusa. Okay, to business, there is an interesting novelty in the field of modern weapons, a Gauss Pistol. Who and how it did, it is a separate topic for discussion. We have learned now, where you can find a prototype of the pistol, in the deserted pig farm in the Dark Valley</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_351_dialog_2">
			<text>Gauss-Pistol? Strange sounding toy!. I'll try to find it</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_351_dialog_3">
			<text>Sorry, next time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_352_dialog_0">
			<text>Good morning! Is Gauss time!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_352_dialog_1">
			<text>found means. Complications?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_352_dialog_2">
			<text>But no, in general, although there partying a few shady characters, but I agreed with them</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_352_dialog_3">
			<text>debt in debt will remain. Let's code of communication, a way to convert salt you</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_bar_dolg_petrenko_gaussgan">
			<text>\nIn the area of the former pig farm in the Dark Valley is the prototype Gauss-Pistol, Petrenko requests to find and get them back into debt</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_551_dialog_0">
			<text>I heard, you're looking for something?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_551_dialog_1">
			<text>I received a new recipe, but have not yet tested. You can get the Moonlight from the Flash. But now Flash I have none. Try to get me this artefact, and I'll share with you a recipe</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_551_dialog_2">
			<text>But these Flashes are like dirt, you got it</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_551_dialog_3">
			<text>Sorry, next time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_552_dialog_0">
			<text>Here Flash, looks like the shining'</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_552_dialog_1">
			<text>found Means. Quick as diarrhea!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_552_dialog_2">
			<text>Only without insults. Let's recipe</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_552_dialog_3">
			<text>Okay, this is a joke. Add recipe,\nfor speed. Bonus to you. Add or so just remember, you can get a rare artefact from the usual Spring, for this it needs to be thrown into Snowballs, and thus, Ruby Spring resolves the path of Whirligig.\nIf you're so responsible, may have turn one piece of business?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_bar_dolg_petrenko_electra_flash">
			<text>\nPetrenko wants you to find him a Flash artefact</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_521_dialog_0">
			<text>Hi. Will I be able to repair this gun and get this armor patched?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_521_dialog_1">
			<text>While I can not, not the necessary tools here. Sidorovich promised to gather toolkits, said, long enough. But at the same time want him to convey a unique artefact, can you courier for me? Ill give you a way to convert Flash into Soul!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_521_dialog_2">
			<text>Why not, give</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_521_dialog_3">
			<text>not before me now, hear, all crammed to the Monolith</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_522_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello Syak. I brought tools</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_522_dialog_1">
			<text>Excellent, now rework can be done. But at the same time will make you fraternal fitting for the work. I have one exclusive suit. Sorry to give. For a bank. Well so be it, keep</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_522_dialog_2">
			<text>Okay, take your box</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_522_dialog_3">
			<text>Wow! It's heavy! There is much info recorded, here it is, on the screen of my PDA.\nIf you need to hide anything, or there to hide from the weather, use a small shelter, which is located opposite the turn to Pripyat. There, before beginning to enter the laboratory X-10, but during one of the emission twisted deep into the gateway and not get. Code to an external door 1287975</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_sak_repair_box">
			<text>\nSyak, a trader from the Radar, can make repairs, but you need to bring Sidorovich a box with the necessary tools</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_561_dialog_0">
			<text>There are interesting recipes?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_561_dialog_1">
			<text>There are, as not to be. There is a way to convert Medusa into a Goldfish! If interested, try find a Goldfish, I want that to compare with what happens, the same properties or not</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_561_dialog_2">
			<text>About what? We'll try to find you a Fish</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_561_dialog_3">
			<text>Oh, what do I need it</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_562_dialog_0">
			<text>With all respect, is Goldfish!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_562_dialog_1">
			<text>Come on, come on. Let's see, different or not</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_562_dialog_2">
			<text>Hold</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_562_dialog_3">
			<text>Get your PDA, connect, I swing you the recipe</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_sak_gold_fish">
			<text>\nSyak, a trader from the Radar, wants me to bring him a Goldfish artefact</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_631_dialog_0">
			<text>There are interesting recipes?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_631_dialog_1">
			<text>In Greece, everything is. There's a way to convert a Goldfish to a Glassbeads! Not bad, huh? And now the problem: from the laboratory to the X-18 scientists abandoned a small Safe, bring it here. To my knowledge, there is something inside that I really want! You bring?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_631_dialog_2">
			<text>A Glassbeads, you say? Okay, I'll find one for you</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_631_dialog_3">
			<text>I have a Glassbeads for you</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_632_dialog_0">
			<text>Well, you fellow, Syak, little Safe... Half a ton of weight!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_632_dialog_1">
			<text>Come to exaggerate it. Couldn't be more than 200 kg</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_632_dialog_2">
			<text>Take care. Bros-ah-ah-yu!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_632_dialog_3">
			<text>What are you, my port inventory! Be careful! Okay, write another recepie</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_sak_find_seif">
			<text>\nSyak, a trader in the Radar, asked me to bring safe from laboratory X-18</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_651_dialog_0">
			<text>There are interesting recipes?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_651_dialog_1">
			<text>last known to me. Is there a way to convert Night Star into a Battery! Interested? The task is not difficult: I agreed with Miser on the radio, he has a new model of Armor, but, something does not work. I need it for research, can repair. Take money to Miser?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_651_dialog_2">
			<text>new model, I'll take it</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_651_dialog_3">
			<text>Battery, yes, she tries need</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_652_dialog_0">
			<text>I brought Armor, just super!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_652_dialog_1">
			<text>Come here</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_652_dialog_2">
			<text>Hold</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_652_dialog_3">
			<text>Yes. Well, infection. I'll see what happened to him. While getting the recipe</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_sak_reward_outfit">
			<text>\nSyak, a trader in the Radar, asked me to exchange money with Miser for a new model of armor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_523_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello Sydor, all sitting there reekin a booze, hard to notice, NOT!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_523_dialog_1">
			<text>Bring Worms, and you will have the same. From what has come?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_523_dialog_2">
			<text>Syak you sent a rare artefact, I do not know what, in the sealed box. He asks him to buy an instrument, any</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_523_dialog_3">
			<text>Yes, he has contacted by radio. Keep the box, look, do not fall. heh, heh, heh</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_653_dialog_0">
			<text>Good Narko, I thought you were already flying</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_653_dialog_1">
			<text>fly with you, all completely smoked</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_653_dialog_2">
			<text>Syak Salvage sent to you, you said he promised Armor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_653_dialog_3">
			<text>Yes, he contacted me by radio. Here it is, SEVA-10, the fly did not sit well. Only the system waste output has a hiccup. If crap ones pants, then, in deep shit he will be going!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_643_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello, Mug Tenacious. Here I have for you good artefact</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_643_dialog_1">
			<text>Where? What kind of artefact?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_643_dialog_2">
			<text>Kruglov handed, said good</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_643_dialog_3">
			<text>Aaaa, This. Well, take your money. Scientists, pancakes, the same swindler like everyone else!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_663_dialog_0">
			<text>Good evening, Professor, I am in agreement with Petrenko</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_663_dialog_1">
			<text>Aaa, unusual artefact?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_663_dialog_2">
			<text>Petrenko said there was still such</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_663_dialog_3">
			<text>Yes, judging by the description, nonsense! I promised him a new Exoskeleton for his brother, take it</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_0">
			<text>Don't smart people say that information is the best investment?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_2">
			<text>Can you tell me the way to Freedom's base?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_90">
			<text>I've heard there's a way to get straight down into the Sarcophagus. Is this true?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_93">
			<text>Well you say so, not one piece of information, besides very expensive.\nseems to be in stock anomaly, Jumper is called, and the one could throw, not in the Sarcophagus, no! But very close to him</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_94">
			<text>How expensive?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_30">
			<text>held in the Radar at the Army Warehouses, and could not get back. Would you know how to get it back?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_3">
			<text>Most certainly. For the right price...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_41">
			<text>Forget it. I'll find it myself...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_42">
			<text>How much?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_5">
			<text>100,000 roubles for this information. Are you interested?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_55">
			<text>For this valuable information, 150,000 roubles. Are you interested?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_95">
			<text>At the moment this is exclusive information. The more people buy it, the cheaper it gets until it becomes common knowledge. That's how it works. It all depends on who wants to be first. If it's you, the price is 400,000 roubles</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_61">
			<text>No, leave it. I'll manage somehow...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_62">
			<text>Yes, please...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_92">
			<text>grandmother is not a problem, the main thing that all of the concepts was, keep</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_7">
			<text>I think you made the right choice...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_8">
			<text>I hope so...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_1">
			<text>What are you looking for?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_10">
			<text>Do you have any cheap Recipes for transforming artefacts?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_12">
			<text>I don't need anything, thanks...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_11">
			<text>Yes, I do. 30,000 roubles. Agreed?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_141">
			<text>Agreed...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_142">
			<text>Thanks, but not enough money at the moment...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_20">
			<text>Do you have any other Recipes for transforming artefacts?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_21">
			<text>I've a Recipe for making a Dummy if you're interested, but it's 50,000 roubles. Agreed?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_241">
			<text>Agreed...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_15">
			<text>There you go. I've uploaded the data to your PDA</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_53_61_dialog_16">
			<text>Excellent</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_541_dialog_000">
			<text>Greetings, Kruglov</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_541_dialog_00">
			<text>Marked One, you're there in the Laboratory, is it not there?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_541_dialog_0">
			<text>What decoder?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_541_dialog_1">
			<text>Sugars, Ghost gave him a new model decoder with the function of the triangulation of the disturbing effects of alternating-gradient wave Psi-emissions</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_541_dialog_11">
			<text>Um, okay... So?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_541_dialog_12">
			<text>In general, a small box with the numbers, when the specter of the last time the connection went out. Said that is located near the main control office. Look there if you bring I'll share with you a recipe for transforming Gravi into Goldfish</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_541_dialog_2">
			<text>Okay, walk, like there is now a purpose</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_541_dialog_3">
			<text>What, are you crazy? I bid zombies to fight</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_542_dialog_0">
			<text>I found your 'precious'. This?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_542_dialog_1">
			<text>Nuka</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_542_dialog_2">
			<text>Hold</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_542_dialog_3">
			<text>He's the most, thanks to all of our science. Add recepies. Another walk to Sidorovich?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_yan_kruglov_decoder">
			<text>\nKruglov is looking for a lost decoder. According to him, the decoder can be in the laboratory of X-16 near the main control panel</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_641_dialog_0">
			<text>Why?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_641_dialog_1">
			<text>Well. I understand you're not one to blab. You see, I'm sitting on a bare salary. Sakharov especially does not pamper. And then recently I found an artefact, with unusual properties. I got in touch with all stages, he agreed to pay a pretty penny. He had to pass a container with artefacts, well, and I payed. In the area it has become known that you have the money, not greedy, are interested in more unusual, so I'll recepie show, as a Bun could boil</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_641_dialog_2">
			<text>Okay, maintaining native science</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_641_dialog_3">
			<text>Her children, their affairs they themselves arranged</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_642_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_642_dialog_1">
			<text>Well? All right?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_642_dialog_2">
			<text>Normally, keep your money</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_642_dialog_3">
			<text>Thank you, if that be, always just ask. Added recipie</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_yan_kruglov_art">
			<text>\nKruglov wants to earn. Sent a unique artefact to Sidorovich, requests to bring payment</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_621_dialog_0">
			<text>What is required?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_621_dialog_1">
			<text>Some time after the second release, several groups of scientists continued to work in secret laboratories. Their observations and conclusions would very much help in the process of cognition of the anomalous Zone. If you can, try to check the laboratory X-18, X-16 and a laboratory in the Radar. Judging from the fragmentary information that survived, several notebooks and manuscripts still exist. For a fee not to worry, there is a recipe for artefact Pellicle, it will be yours</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_621_dialog_2">
			<text>And share the findings? Well</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_621_dialog_3">
			<text>Sorry, I can not do this</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_622_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello, Professor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_622_dialog_1">
			<text>What? Is that it?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_622_dialog_2">
			<text>Yes, this is the book and a couple of manuscripts</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_622_dialog_3">
			<text>So, we must carefully examine. The recipe you have earned, this is exactly. Load the memory.\nYes, there is much necessary information. Describes how to use the teleport. Nothing, a</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_yan_scientist_books">
			<text>\nSakharov asked to check the laboratories X-16, X-18 and a laboratory in the Radar, to bring all the manuscripts and books that are there. According to preliminary data in the X-18 book, should be in a room with a refrigerator. The X-16 book may be in the room where I linked to Ghost the last time out. The laboratory notebook in the Radar may be near the main control panel</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_661_dialog_0">
			<text>What is required?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_661_dialog_1">
			<text>Sakharov has two Exoskeletons, I arranged with him to exchange the pair for a rare artefact. You work by courier? I'll share a recipe with you</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_661_dialog_2">
			<text>These recipes are killing me... Okay, I'll be your mule...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_661_dialog_3">
			<text>Find another</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_662_dialog_0">
			<text>you, I absolutely welcome</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_662_dialog_1">
			<text>Op-PA, our runner. How it hangin?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_662_dialog_2">
			<text>fetched, so they both</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_662_dialog_3">
			<text>Well thanks to the debt you have, you'll be presented at the Encouragements. Get your PDA, write a prescription</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_bar_dolg_petrenko_exo">
			<text>\nIn exchange for two Exoskeletons from Sakharov, Petrenko will give you a rare artefact</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_511_dialog_0">
			<text>I'm listening</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_511_dialog_1">
			<text>alone will remain between us? Can you pass one thing to Miser?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_511_dialog_2">
			<text>Sure, why not.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_511_dialog_3">
			<text>Find another</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_512_dialog_0">
			<text>Well. I brought you something</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_512_dialog_1">
			<text>not yell. Let us so that nobody saw</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_512_dialog_2">
			<text>Here's your money</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_512_dialog_3">
			<text>OK. Get your PDA, write a prescription</text>
		</string>
		<string id="playboy_dialog_0">
			<text>Greetings, soldier</text>
		</string>
		<string id="playboy_dialog_1">
			<text>Listen, you lot where Mota, can you find me one Vesh</text>
		</string>
		<string id="playboy_dialog_4">
			<text>And what is a Vesh? And what I get for this?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="playboy_dialog_5">
			<text>Do not worry, does not hurt. I know where a unique Vintorez is to find.\nI need a magazine, Playboy, do not think, not because of my aunts. I just got one recipe written, I really want. A few days ago I sat with Baldy, tired of vodka. I woke up, and the magazine, then no. I remember, I'm on the entire Bar aunts there praised, that's who then appeared. There three charming brunettes on the cover. Well?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="playboy_dialog_2">
			<text>right, gets caught, mags, will try to bring</text>
		</string>
		<string id="playboy_dialog_3">
			<text>Find another</text>
		</string>
		<string id="playboy2_dialog_0">
			<text>Well. I brought you something</text>
		</string>
		<string id="playboy2_dialog_1">
			<text>Okay, this?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="playboy2_dialog_2">
			<text>Well you said three brunettes?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="playboy2_dialog_3">
			<text>Yes they are, my beautiful, Ugh! what.\nWell, then, at the Agricultural Industry in the commanders base is a safe, in which he holds the most unique things, there must be the Vintorez</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_bar_ivancov_playboy">
			<text>\nIvantsov, lost Playboy magazine with information recorded in the recipe for the return promise to tell where to get a unique VCC Vintorez. On the cover of the magazine, three charming brunettes</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_513_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello, Sailor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_513_dialog_1">
			<text>What have you got?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_513_dialog_2">
			<text>little man out of debt, Captain Ivantsov, says hello and asks him to pour weighty MNT</text>
		</string>
		<string id="artmod_513_dialog_3">
			<text>long, ept. Grandmother that everyone loves. Let this Vesch</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_hello_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello Marked One. Come, let's talk</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_hello_dialog_1">
			<text>Hi Marked One, heard a lot of flattering things about you. Want to know a way to convert an artefact?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_hello_dialog_2">
			<text>Well, Marked One, what have you brought?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_hello_dialog_3">
			<text>Well there is something I can do?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_hello_dialog_4">
			<text>In the process</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_hello_dialog_5">
			<text>Later on I will give</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_hello_dialog_6">
			<text>Hello, Warrior</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_repair_0">
			<text>Can you repair armor?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_repair_1">
			<text>Let's see, ta-aak, can do it, but need the money. Have you?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_repair_4">
			<text>Yes, here it is, repair</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_repair_5">
			<text>Blinn, I am stranded</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_repair_7">
			<text>Well, the mind can not be said that the new, but all the protective functions are working properly</text>
		</string>
		<string id="sak_repair_9">
			<text>Thank you, I hope, not the last time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_bar_ivancov_rg6">
			<text>Ivantsov, behind the Command Duty, maintains contact with Freedom. Miser wants to sell a RG-6 Grenade launcher to the trader in Liberty. He promises to provide a Transmutation recipe</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod">
			<text>Artefact Modification</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_mincer_meat_mosquito_bald_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Meat Chunk' artefact can be produced in a Springboard anomaly with just four ingredients:\nQuirk\nStone Blood\nVodka\nDog tail.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_electra_sparkler_mosquito_bald_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Sparkler' artefact can be produced in a Springboard anomaly with just four ingredients:\nDroplet\nSausage\nBandage\nDog tail.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_ameba_slug_mosquito_bald_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Slug' artefact can be produced in a Springboard anomaly with just four ingredients:\nDroplet\nMedusa\nVodka\nBandage.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_cristall_mosquito_bald_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Crystal' artefact can be produced in a Springboard anomaly with just four ingredients:\nMeat Chunk\nFireball\nQuirk\nFlesh eye.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_rusty_sea_urchin_mosquito_bald_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Urchin' artefact can be produced in a Springboard anomaly with just four ingredients:\nSlime\nCrystal Thorn\nStone Blood\nBloodsucker tentacles.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_dummy_dummy_mosquito_bald_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Dummy' artefact can be produced in a Springboard anomaly with just four ingredients:\nNight Star\nMeat Chunk\nCrystal\nMica.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_ameba_slug_gravi_zone_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Slug' artefact can be produced in a Vortex anomaly with just four ingredients:\nQuirk\nMedusa\nSausage\nDog tail.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_ameba_slime_gravi_zone_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Slime' artefact can be produced in a Vortex anomaly with just four ingredients:\nMedusa\nCan of food\nBandage\nDog tail.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_electra_flash_gravi_zone_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Flash' artefact can be produced in a Vortex anomaly with just four ingredients:\nQuirk\nStone Blood\nDog tail\nVodka.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_night_star_gravi_zone_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Night Star' artefact can be produced in a Vortex anomaly with just four ingredients:\nThorn\nCrystal Thorn\nMedusa\nPseudodog tail.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_soul_gravi_zone_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Soul' artefact can be produced in a Vortex anomaly with just four ingredients:\nFlash\nSlug\nStone Flower\nSnork leg.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_dummy_pellicle_gravi_zone_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Pellicle' artefact can be produced in a Vortex anomaly with just four ingredients:\nSoul\nGoldfish\nCrystal\nMica.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_cristall_flower_mincer_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Stone Flower' artefact can be produced in a Whirligig anomaly with just four ingredients:\nStone Blood\nBandage\nMedusa\nCan of food.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_drops_mincer_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Droplet' artefact can be produced in a Whirligig anomaly with just four ingredients:\nQuirk\nVodka\nBandage\nDog tail.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_rusty_kristall_mincer_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Crystal Thorn' artefact can be produced in a Whirligig anomaly with just four ingredients:\nSparkler\nMedusa\nCan of food\nDog tail.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_electra_moonlight_mincer_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Moonlight' artefact can be produced in a Whirligig anomaly with just four ingredients:\nFireball\nSlug\nStone Blood\nBloodsucker tentacles.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_ameba_slug_mincer_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Mica' artefact can be produced in a Whirligig anomaly with just four ingredients:\nFlash\nFireball\nQuirk\nPseudodog tail.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_dummy_glassbeads_mincer_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Glassbeads' artefact can be produced in a Whirligig anomaly with just four ingredients:\nNight Star\nGoldfish\nUrchin\nMica.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_rusty_kristall_buzz_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Crystal Thorn' artefact can be produced in a Fruit Punch anomaly with just four ingredients:\nSparkler\nDroplet\nMedusa\nBread.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_rusty_thorn_buzz_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Thorn' artefact can be produced in a Fruit Punch anomaly with just four ingredients:\nStone Blood\nBread\nBandage\nDog tail.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_fireball_buzz_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Fireball' artefact can be produced in a Fruit Punch anomaly with just four ingredients:\nThorn\nQuirk\nSnork leg\nBread.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_cristall_buzz_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Crystal' artefact can be produced in a Fountain anomaly with just four ingredients:\nStone Flower\nFireball\nMedusa\nBloodsucker tentacles.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_night_star_buzz_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Goldfish' artefact can be produced in a Fruit Punch anomaly with just four ingredients:\nGravi\nFlash\nStone Blood\nPseudodog tail.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_fuzz_kolobok_buzz_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Kolobok' artefact can be produced in a Fruit Punch anomaly with just four ingredients:\nUrchin\nMoonlight\nSoul\nNight Star.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_electra_flash_zharka_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Flash' artefact can be produced in a Burner anomaly with just four ingredients:\nMedusa\nQuirk\nThorn\nVodka.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_ameba_slime_zharka_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Slime' artefact can be produced in a Burner anomaly with just four ingredients:\nMedusa\nStone Blood\nSausage\nDog tail.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_gravi_zharka_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Gravi' artefact can be produced in a Burner anomaly with just four ingredients:\nMedusa\nStone Blood\nBandage\nCan of food.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_night_star_zharka_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Night Star' artefact can be produced in a Burner anomaly with just four ingredients:\nCrystal Thorn\nFlash\nQuirk\nSnork leg.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_electra_moonlight_zharka_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Moonlight' artefact can be produced in a Burner anomaly with just four ingredients:\nGravi\nFlash\nMedusa\nBloodsucker tentacles.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_dummy_battery_zharka_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Battery' artefact can be produced in a Burner anomaly with just four ingredients:\nFlash\nMica\nVodka\nDog tail.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_medusa_galant_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Medusa' artefact can be produced in an Electro anomaly with just four ingredients:\nTushkano head\nBandage\nCan of food\nDog tail.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_fireball_galant_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Fireball' artefact can be produced in an Electro anomaly with just four ingredients:\nMedusa\nStone Blood\nDog tail\nVodka.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_cristall_flower_galant_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Stone Flower' artefact can be produced in an Electro anomaly with just four ingredients:\nQuirk\nThorn\nCan of food\nDog tail.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_ameba_mica_galant_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Mica' artefact can be produced in an Electro anomaly with just four ingredients:\nSlime\nMedusa\nThorn\nSausage.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_electra_moonlight_galant_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Soul' artefact can be produced in an Electro anomaly with just four ingredients:\nGravi\nFireball\nStone Blood\nPseudodog tail.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_gold_fish_galant_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Goldfish' artefact can be produced in an Electro anomaly with just four ingredients:\nMedusa\nStone Flower\nThorn\nFlesh eye.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_Jellyfish_galant_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Medusa' artefact can be produced in an Electro anomaly with just four ingredients:\nTushkano head\nCan of food\nBandage\nDog tail.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_info_artmod_vyvert_buzz_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Quirk' artefact can be produced in a Fruit Punch anomaly with just four ingredients:\nTushkano head\nCan of food\nBandage\nDog tail.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_artmod_dummy_spring_galant_text">
			<text>\n.\nThe 'Spring' artefact can be produced in an Electro anomaly with just four ingredients:\nStone Flower\nCrystal\nPseudodog tail\nCan of food.\nTransformation should occur within 5-10 minutes Zone Time</text>
		</string>
<!-- AR -->
		<string id="enc_artmod_life_heart_ice_zone_text">
			<text>%c[default]\nunique, very rare artefact. It has truly miraculous properties - to resurrect the dead! The only drawback - a huge burden.\n.\nArtefact can be produced by combining four artefacts in a Snow anomaly\nNight Star, Goldfish, Urchin, and Dummy.\n%c[255,255,255,255]Time for transmutation %c[255,224,224,160]5 minutes Zone Time\n%c[255,255,255,255]Probability of successful transmutation %c[255,1,255,1] 100% %c[default]</text>
		</string>
		<string id="af_life_heart">
			<text>The heart</text>
		</string>
		<string id="af_life_heart_s">
			<text>The heart</text>
		</string>
		<string id="af_life_heart_desc">
			<text>\n.\nunique, very rare artefact. It has truly miraculous properties - to resurrect the dead! The only drawback - a large burden</text>
		</string>
		<string id="af_medusa_emerald">
			<text>Emerald jellyfish</text>
		</string>
		<string id="af_medusa_emerald_s">
			<text>'Emerald'</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_af_medusa_green">
			<text>\n.\nUnique artefact. In appearance, the usual 'Medusa', but green. Is not radioactive, emits a weak light. There is a perception that it is a result of combining the two anomalies - 'Springboard' and 'Fruit Punch. Adds protection from bullet impacts, but drops her from the mutants and anomalies</text>
		</string>
		<string id="af_Jellyfish">
			<text>Emerald Medusa</text>
		</string>
		<string id="af_Jellyfish_green">
			<text>\n.\nunique artefact, seemingly ordinary "Medusa", but green. It is not radioactive, emits a weak light. Thought to appear as a result of combining the two anomalies - 'Springboard' and 'brawn'. Adds protection from bullet impacts, but reduces it from mutants and anomalies</text>
		</string>
		<string id="af_vyvert_emerald">
			<text>Emerald Quirk</text>
		</string>
		<string id="af_vyvert_emerald_s">
			<text>Emerald Quirk</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_af_vyvert_green">
			<text>\n.\nunique artefact, seemingly ordinary "Quirk", but green. It is not radioactive, emits a weak light. It is believed that he appears as a result of combining two anomalies - 'Springboard' and 'brawn'. Pretty good protection against mutants, but reduces the protection from bullet impacts</text>
		</string>
		<string id="af_blood_emerald">
			<text>The Emerald Stone Blood</text>
		</string>
		<string id="af_blood_emerald_s">
			<text>Emerald Stone</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_af_blood_green">
			<text>\n.\nunique artefact, seemingly normal "Stone Blood", but green. It is not radioactive, emits a weak light. There is a perception that it appears as a result of combining the two anomalies - Whirligig anomaly and "brawn". Pretty good protection against anomalies, but also reduces protection from bullet impacts</text>
		</string>
		<string id="af_pellicle">
			<text>Ruby Pellicle</text>
		</string>
		<string id="af_pellicle_s">
			<text>Ruby Pellicle</text>
		</string>
		<string id="af_pellicle_red">
			<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+5\n%c[default]\nunique artefact in appearance resembles a regular "Pellicle", but red. Slightly radioactive, emits light. Perhaps transmutes from the "Pellicles" by ingestion of an anomaly "Snow." Has the effect of the rapid healing of open wounds, little protection against anomalies but significantly reduces the protection of bullet impacts</text>
		</string>
		<string id="af_red_spring">
			<text>Ruby spring</text>
		</string>
		<string id="af_red_spring_s">
			<text>Ruby spring</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_af_red_spring">
			<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+5\n%c[default]\nunique artefacts, resembles normal "Spring" but red. Slightly radioactive, emits light. Perhaps transmutes from the "spring" if it enters the anomaly of "Snow". Has the effect of protection against impact</text>
		</string>
		<string id="af_red_battery">
			<text>Ruby battery</text>
		</string>
		<string id="af_red_battery_s">
			<text>Ruby battery</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_af_red_battery">
			<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+10\n%c[default]\nunique artefact in appearance resembles a regular "battery", but red. Slightly radioactive, emits light. Perhaps transmutes from the "Batteries" if it enters the anomaly of "Snow". Has the effect of restoration of forces, protection from electro anomalies and a little protection from shock impacts</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_detector_sak">
			<text>Universal Anomaly detector</text>
		</string>
		<string id="st_detector_sak_s">
			<text>Anomaly detector</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_equipment_devic_detect_sak">
			<text>Detector, the latest development in the field of digital research into paranormal phenomena, to detect and identify virtually any anomaly</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_teleport_11">
			<text>is my stash... There are rifles in the safe for you. Can you take it, though it is heavy... What's next on your list? Watching found my notebook... I'm there a lot of their guesses presented and examined?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_teleport_21">
			<text>it you son... I what?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_teleport_12">
			<text>not know about your stash... for the rifle - thanks, have a look. On Hold your book, I have not read it, do not have the habit of reading other's diaries...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_teleport_13">
			<text>Okay, do not worry, come in a glass of tea, sit down, have a chat...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_teleport_22">
			<text>Hello father, I want to before the last jerk to the monolith forces tunnel, get better equipment, weapons... Maybe the trail to find out the secret, will not be able to help?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_teleport_23">
			<text>No you can not without these risky trips... Okay, I've got some type of information, to share with you...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_1drug_0">
			<text>Thanks... What is your best man can not see - you do with your dog were inseparable?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_1drug_1">
			<text>Vanished my "Druzhok"... And so many years together... Ehh... In the dark valley of the bandits shot at me greatly, two days unconscious in a swamp lain, woke up - only a pool of blood near...\nAnd the heart does not believe my best friend is no longer... I hear you've had to deal with the prisoner of the bandits, Max Lubero, he did not say anything? The rumor was - he saw some unusual pseudodog, could be him?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_1drug_2">
			<text>Max I did not say anything, I have a thing for him, I'll go - at the same time and can find out about man's best friend...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_1drug_3">
			<text>No, he said nothing... Perhaps more witnesses...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_1drug_4">
			<text>not you heard? Killed Lubero...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_2drug_0">
			<text>Hello, Doctor, I have good news...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_2drug_1">
			<text>news? What?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_2drug_2">
			<text>your Druzhoks lives, Max pulled him from the cage... Now he's at the dump, at a checkpoint near the Dolg outpost</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_2drug_3">
			<text>Thank God... i need to go for my Druzhoks... A bit later.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_3drug_0">
			<text>Hi Max, how is your health?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_3drug_1">
			<text>Thank you, apparently your prayers... I what?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_3drug_2">
			<text>Max, you have not seen the bandits, pseudodog unusual, say so - a few non-aggressive? The doctor lost his friend, the rumor was - the bandits have him...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_3drug_3">
			<text>Ha, did not see... With me he runs out the gate at the Bar... sweet... We have been feeding it here... But he misses something...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_3drug_4">
			<text>on bog Dr. misses apparently... Tell the doctor, let them rejoice...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_doctor_drug">
			<text>Doctor puppy picked up by the best man murdered females pseudodog, nourished... And this dog was gone... It is rumored that Max Lubero heard about loyal Druzhok...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_01_dialog_0">
			<text>Jumper configure... but how?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_01_dialog_1">
			<text>you see a colleague, quite accurately describes how to configure, but this requires data disturbing influences in the area - where neobhoimo fall. We have built the necessary equipment to vacuum tube transmitter, now you have this unit delivered to the area, which we might call the reception... Yes.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_01_dialog_4">
			<text>And what is the place to be, and how difficult this is your thing?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_01_dialog_5">
			<text>Let's first try to set up a teleport a short distance, say - Army warehouses... Try to install the device, it is not heavy - only 25 kg, the water tower in the village... as it is there... stalkers name of the village bloodsuckers...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_01_dialog_2">
			<text>So what? You will be here to Svoboda jump? Let's try...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_01_dialog_3">
			<text>sorry Professor, I can not yet...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_yan_scientist_teleport_01">
			<text>Sakharov argues that if you set his camera on top of the water tower in the village of bloodsuckers, you will immediately move from Yantar to the army warehouses...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_02_dialog_0">
			<text>Where else can set up a teleport?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_02_dialog_1">
			<text>Let's try longer distances, say - Cordon. Set the unit in the car, which at the railway bridge and... back...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_02_dialog_2">
			<text>Okay. Let your machine...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_02_dialog_3">
			<text>Forgive Professor, how can something then...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_yan_scientist_teleport_02">
			<text>Sakharov argues that if you set his camera on the train, which hangs in the ruined railway bridge, you will immediately move from Yantar to Cordon...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_03_dialog_0">
			<text>And closer to the center of the zone can be accessed through the teleport?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_03_dialog_1">
			<text>closer to the center - the more disturbing effects... But let's try. Place the appliance on the central square behind the statue of Lenin, a small reinforced concrete construction...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_03_dialog_2">
			<text>well. Let your machine...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_03_dialog_3">
			<text>I probably first explored everything there...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_yan_scientist_teleport_03">
			<text>Sakharov argues that if you set his camera on the central square behind the statue of Lenin, a small reinforced concrete structure, which covers stormwater runoff, it will be possible from Yantar immediately move to Pripyat...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_0">
			<text>Professor, let's use the teleport...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_1">
			<text>Hmm... Where would you like to teleport?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_2">
			<text>a good idea to get into the camp svoboda...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_3">
			<text>By Sidorovich need to Cordon...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_4">
			<text>to the center of the zone closer to Pripyat least...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_21">
			<text>Well, we can already do... To activate the teleport requires a Soul artefact...\nDo you have one?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_22">
			<text>Yes, there...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_23">
			<text>Sorry, I don't have one...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_221">
			<text>excellent, setting the teleport takes a long time, but it is, as you know, money...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_222">
			<text>And how much will I owe you ?...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_223">
			<text>It depends on the accuracy of the settings...\nCareful alignment requires very careful calculations and will cost you... mmm-m... 10000...\nA rough calculation, so to speak - by eye, only 2500...\nHow do you prefer?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_224">
			<text>Let accurately, the money I have no problem...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_225">
			<text>you Cast me to the location, and then I'll look...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_226">
			<text>Oh, I like some legs... rough it...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_25">
			<text>You will not regret the money spent, you'll land gently to the former army depots to deliver...\nYou can go, teleport will be there and ready, behind the bunker, on an island in the middle of the swamp...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_26">
			<text>See for yourself... On location, we will throw you, but there...\nYou can go, teleport will be ready, behind the bunker, on an island in the middle of the swamp...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_31">
			<text>By Sidorovich? You can, hello there it... To activate the teleport requires a Crystal artefact...\nIs it you?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_32">
			<text>Here it is...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_33">
			<text>Blinn, I do not have "Crystal"...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_321">
			<text>excellent, setting the teleport takes a long time, but it is, as you know, money...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_322">
			<text>And how much will I owe you ?...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_323">
			<text>It depends on the accuracy of the settings...\nCareful alignment requires very deep payments and will cost you... mmm-m... in 15000...\ncruder calculation, so to speak - by eye, only 5000...\nHow do you prefer?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_324">
			<text>Let accurately, the money I have no problem...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_325">
			<text>you Cast me to the location, and then I'll look...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_326">
			<text>Oh, I like some legs... rough it...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_35">
			<text>You will not regret the money spent, you'll land gently near the camp newcomers teleport...\nYou can go, teleport will be there and ready, behind the bunker on an island in the middle of the swamp...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_36">
			<text>See for yourself... On location Cordon then we will let down, but there...\nYou can go, teleport ready, behind the bunker on an island in the middle of the swamp...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_41">
			<text>Pripyat... You and Pripyat... To activate the teleport requires a Moonlight artefact...\nIs it you?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_42">
			<text>Yes, there...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_43">
			<text>That's because, I do not have a "Moonlight"...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_421">
			<text>excellent, setting the teleport takes a long time, but it is, as you know, money...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_422">
			<text>And how much will I owe you ?...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_423">
			<text>It depends on the accuracy of the settings...\nCareful alignment requires very deep payments and will cost you... mmm-m... to 20000...\ncruder calculation, so to speak - by eye, only 9000...\nHow do you prefer?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_424">
			<text>Let accurately, the money I have no problem...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_425">
			<text>you Cast me to the location, and then Ill look...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_426">
			<text>Oh, I like some legs... rough it...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_45">
			<text>You will not regret the money spent, well try you in a safe place to teleport...\nYou can go teleport will be there and ready, behind the bunker, on an island in the middle of the swamp...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_yantar_dialog_46">
			<text>at Risk, dear... In Pripyat possible, so to speak, and get stuck...\nYou can go, teleport ready, behind the bunker, on an island in the middle of the swamp...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_04_dialog_0">
			<text>You? Teleport? How do you know that?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_04_dialog_1">
			<text>Let's just say, know for my knowledge of several people have been killed...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_04_dialog_6">
			<text>Come on, I was just, to come up... Well, let's try...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_04_dialog_7">
			<text>Generally you will need to do something that...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_04_dialog_8">
			<text>Yeah, I knew it! And how much you pour ?...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_04_dialog_9">
			<text>While not at all, to set the teleport need detailed seismic maps of the terrain where he is going transfer.\nI do know where you can get a map of the Base of Liberty and surrounding areas...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_04_dialog_4">
			<text>And where is it?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_04_dialog_5">
			<text>the laboratory X-18, which in the Dark Valley, where it was at the lower levels of the laptop with the data must be detailed seismological and geological mapping of the area... If you bring - then we will have the ability to customize teleport...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_04_dialog_2">
			<text>So what? You will be here to Svoboda fly? Let's try...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_04_dialog_3">
			<text>Oh it nafik... I'll manage, I do...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_fanat_teleport_04">
			<text>\nFanatic said that he could set up a teleport to jump from Cordon to the Army Warehouses. To do this, find the laptop in Lab X-18 with a detailed map of the Warehouses</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_042_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello Fanatic, I found the laptop...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_042_dialog_1">
			<text>Is it working? Did you try it?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_042_dialog_2">
			<text>I booted it up to the BIOS, but I didn't go any further... It must have been lying there for years, though. There were cobwebs all over it, but it looks hopeful...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_042_dialog_3">
			<text>Oh, it works... Thank you!... There's our map!...\nRight, to activate the teleport to the Army Warehouses will need a Soul artefact. Please accept this one as a gift, should you ever need to use it...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_05_dialog_0">
			<text>Can you travel anywhere else?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_05_dialog_1">
			<text>Well, it could be configured to Yantar swamp, but again I'll need a map...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_05_dialog_4">
			<text>Ah-ah! I know - Marked One features are much, bring those traits that?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_05_dialog_5">
			<text>Well-ell, yes... And you never just wanted to? In general, a laptop in the laboratory of X-16, go?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_05_dialog_2">
			<text>Damn You Bes, I'll go!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_05_dialog_3">
			<text>Listen himself stamp your...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_fanat_teleport_05">
			<text>fan said that could set up a teleport to jump from Cordon to Yantar. To do this, find the laboratory X-16, a laptop with the geological map of the area of Yantar</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_052_dialog_0">
			<text>Good times Bes, here's your bag...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_052_dialog_1">
			<text>and Che is all wet? In what some snot...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_052_dialog_2">
			<text>Listen, I'm probably not going to the grocery database...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_052_dialog_3">
			<text>Okay, okay, chill out... Here's "Mica", with the help of a teleport at Yantar opens...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_06_dialog_0">
			<text>Hey, right in the sarcophagus can be reached?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_06_dialog_1">
			<text>probably can only data out there, and I do not know where to get...\nAnd this is where the geological survey of Pripyat is - I know...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_06_dialog_4">
			<text>Ha! Certainly in most Pripyat...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_06_dialog_5">
			<text>Exactly! You'll be there, look in the building of the bus station, computer data such as should have been preserved...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_06_dialog_2">
			<text>Okay, still in the wrong direction, look!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_06_dialog_3">
			<text>If get to Pripyat, things to do will...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_fanat_teleport_06">
			<text>Fanatic said that he could set up a teleport to jump from Cordon to Pripyat. For this you want to find a bus station building in Pripyat computer geologic terrain map of Yantar</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_062_dialog_0">
			<text>Fanatic... I came back...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_062_dialog_1">
			<text>Hello, yes... Well, you look - natural dead...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_062_dialog_2">
			<text>I'm tired... Take comp...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_062_dialog_3">
			<text>Chill, Marked One, here we have quiet... Take this "Moonlight", come in handy when artificially produced in Pripyat dive...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_0">
			<text>Come on, teleport me...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_1">
			<text>And where are you skiing pricked?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_2">
			<text>Come on warehouses, we'll see how things are there...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_3">
			<text>By Professor need to Yantar...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_4">
			<text>In Pripyat, Marsh Doctor want to see...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_21">
			<text>to create a teleport needs a Soul artefact...\nAvailable?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_22">
			<text>Yes, there...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_23">
			<text>Pipets, I sold the "Soul "...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_221">
			<text>Come... here guys help me with the calculations Bubble throw them.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_222">
			<text>only children? Okay, how much...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_223">
			<text>Vanka calculator will calculate everything exactly, but he wants 9000 for his work...\nSanya Baska, a hangover can be a bit wrong - and asks all 2500...\nDo you like?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_224">
			<text>with a hangover... Vlipnesh in the wall of any kind, let Vanka thinks...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_225">
			<text>What difference does it hold here two and a half pieces...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_226">
			<text>Well guys and appetites with you, he'll get there</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_25">
			<text>Well, right! Our calculator will get you directly to the base of Liberty!\nTeleport on the side of railway paintings, like passest - expand the tower to the right, from afar you'll see...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_26">
			<text>see myself... Sanya course Baska, but after yesterday...\nTeleport on the side of railway paintings, like go over - turn right, from afar you'll see...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_31">
			<text>Sakharov? Here too, the martyr of science, sitting there in the swamp, radioactive mosquito feeds... To create a teleport need artefact "Mica"...\nnot lost?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_32">
			<text>Here it is...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_33">
			<text>that he did not say I drove it.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_321">
			<text>Come... here guys help me with the calculations Bubble throw them.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_322">
			<text>And how much will I owe you ?...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_323">
			<text>Vanka Calculator, local Ig Nobel Prize winner, will calculate everything accurately, but takes over the work 15000...\nSanya Baska, suffering after last night, may be a bit wrong - and asks only 5000...\nYou decide.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_324">
			<text>Baska, Calculator, you will let us accurately count...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_325">
			<text>Blinn little money, so let the minimum...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_326">
			<text>Oh, take the long way...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_35">
			<text>correctly decided... Our Vanka clever devil... His wife with her lover caught, killed both as a pig... And so would have just had a Nobel Prize...\nTopa, teleport to the side glands, keep right and you'll see...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_36">
			<text>You're a master of himself... Sanya course brainy guy, but it provides - whether it is healthy...\nTopa, teleport to the side glands, keep right and you'll see...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_41">
			<text>Pripyat... You and Pripyat... Requires a Moonlight artefact...\nDo not feel sorry for?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_42">
			<text>sorry, but I make it fast...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_43">
			<text>No, not give useful to me "Moonlight"...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_421">
			<text>I am not a mathematician, big-headed guys think... Salvage them...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_422">
			<text>Babble... How much money do you need?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_423">
			<text>We have two smart guys have - Ivan Calculator and Sanya Baska...\nVanek, he almost never makes mistakes, but wants money... 30000...\nSankas been all counts, but yesterday he Sidor art rare dragged... Well, said the whole evening, he agrees to 10000...\nI do not advise it, up to you.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_424">
			<text>I myself with a hangover, I think out of this, so... Let more expensive, but just</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_425">
			<text>It attendants see I would have said, the hell with it - though not exactly...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_426">
			<text>Make it the long way...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_45">
			<text>Well, correctly, that is money - ugh and pound, but is guaranteed a safe place to find oneself...\nCome on, move, go over the railway, turn right, walk through a bit and you'll see a teleport...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_escape_dialog_46">
			<text>Yes, it would be attendants see, we would not be here talking to you talk...\nCome on, move, go over the railway, turn right, walk through a bit and you'll see a teleport... Good luck...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_07_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello narkosha like grass?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_07_dialog_1">
			<text>Grass - Uleta! Vkurili we are with Max and cook grass and opened to us the truth... It turns out you can teleport to configure where you want...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_07_dialog_4">
			<text>To finish my! Threw you a thing...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_07_dialog_6">
			<text>But you do not drive... No noodle... I tried... By Sidor rewind, and back - for half an hour turned...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_07_dialog_7">
			<text>I just have to Cordon Quick...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_07_dialog_8">
			<text>Just so - even cats are not born... Give me seven clutches chimera, then we'll talk...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_07_dialog_9">
			<text>Why seven that?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_07_dialog_5">
			<text>you that the oak crashed... Seven - the magic number!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_07_dialog_2">
			<text>Well, if the magic... Try typing...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_07_dialog_3">
			<text>their brains ventilated...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_mil_trader_teleport_07">
			<text>Miser promises to set up a teleport to move from stocks to Cordon, if he bring seven clutches chimera</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_072_dialog_0">
			<text>Amateur magic, I brought your claws...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_072_dialog_1">
			<text>Wow, hang on a wall - is a positive aura...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_072_dialog_2">
			<text>Aura... Kuri smaller and purer aura will...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_072_dialog_3">
			<text>Well, his wife teach soup cooking... Come when you want to hit the road Cordon...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_08_dialog_0">
			<text>Hi Max, Miser says you have fouled transitions do ?.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_08_dialog_1">
			<text>was the case, he did not expect such an effect from the banal side posts, just in my brain clicked something and began to know how to calculate the teleport to Yantar...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_08_dialog_4">
			<text>And how would I go to quickly get? I tell you what you want you pirate...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_08_dialog_5">
			<text>But I do not need anything grub enough, vodka is, the air fresh... Baba would, but where do you take it...\nThough... dashed to Kruglov, he promised a fresh issue Playboy throw, look at the heavenly creatures...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_08_dialog_2">
			<text>Here fartsa pancake, okay...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_08_dialog_3">
			<text>Well you give... Like a real man...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_mil_max_teleport_08">
			<text>\nMax promises to set up a teleport to move from the warehouse to Yantar, when he brought from Kruglov magazines "PlayBoy"</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_082_dialog_0">
			<text>Here magazines with the beautiful...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_082_dialog_1">
			<text>Thanks Marked One, or have forgotten - who's - Women...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_082_dialog_2">
			<text>oh, remember...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_082_dialog_3">
			<text>approach, when you want to hit the road Yantar...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_083_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello, scientist...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_083_dialog_1">
			<text>Healthy Marked One, as life...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_083_dialog_2">
			<text>said you have magazines, Playboy...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_083_dialog_3">
			<text>Well, if Playboy are interested in, then health in order... Here you are, for 2006 only have...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_09_dialog_0">
			<text>Hey Cook! You hear me? Miser said do you know about the teleport...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_09_dialog_1">
			<text>A? Che? Who are you? What teleport? Ah, but if I know, is...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_09_dialog_4">
			<text>Maybe you bubble for the correction of health? I would need to Pripyat...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_09_dialog_5">
			<text>It would be nice... Bubble, but better Ten... And tushkano, as starters...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_09_dialog_2">
			<text>Ok, maybe their brains, and you will be added...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_09_dialog_3">
			<text>Back to you soon on the vodka... Walking, whether that...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_mil_cook_teleport_09">
			<text>\nCook promises to set up a teleport to move from warehouses in Pripyat, need to bring him 10 bottles of vodka and 10 tushkano brains</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_092_dialog_0">
			<text>Er-y! Dear!... Eyes wipe...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_092_dialog_1">
			<text>Che do you want... Shouting about here, people think you're preventing us...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_092_dialog_2">
			<text>Keep holy water and a snack... How are things with teleport ?...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_092_dialog_3">
			<text>After approaches, I have right now, not in the form...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_skraga_dialog_0">
			<text>Come miser, do it, teleport need...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_skraga_dialog_1">
			<text>And where are you skiing pricked?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_skraga_dialog_2">
			<text>Come to Cordon to have a conversation Sidor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_skraga_dialog_21">
			<text>To teleport to needs a Crystal artefact...\nAvailable?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_skraga_dialog_22">
			<text>Well... Yes, there is such... Done when will be?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_skraga_dialog_23">
			<text>But you have there been? Okay, then I'll come...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_skraga_dialog_221">
			<text>not hurry... We must still figure out that you would not be smeared on the walls of which anything should be as follows, brains pep... Weeds are something money...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_skraga_dialog_222">
			<text>I told you a whole bag fetched! Where do you...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_skraga_dialog_223">
			<text>from the bag only memories... Good grass is a lot of money. To properly should be not less than 9000...\nWell, if sensitive to risk it and try for 2500.\nDo you like?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_skraga_dialog_224">
			<text>At a pancake, drug... Okay, you have good grass...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_skraga_dialog_225">
			<text>Listen, here's 2500, and that's enough babble...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_skraga_dialog_226">
			<text>I'm not going to contact nark, he'd get himself...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_skraga_dialog_25">
			<text>Thanks... Do not be sorry, I'm straight to the closet in Sidor let down...\nTopa, fly... Teleport opposite the main entrance to the base... Across the street, pass over and see...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_skraga_dialog_26">
			<text>greedy you become... Ok, maybe next time you'll be generous...\nTopa, fly... Teleport opposite the main entrance to the base... where two or three singles hang out...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_povar_dialog_0">
			<text>you alive or not, wipe the eyes teleport need...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_povar_dialog_1">
			<text>What sort of teleport, fuck off, eh?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_povar_dialog_2">
			<text>In Pripyat I need, you said - you can organize...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_povar_dialog_21">
			<text>From since landed... Need an artefact of "Moonlight", and I have it no...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_povar_dialog_3">
			<text>Listen, friend... Not in Sawston I am today... Come then...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_povar_dialog_22">
			<text>I have a "Moonlight", let's step on it...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_povar_dialog_23">
			<text>Wait here, I find - bring...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_povar_dialog_221">
			<text>Okay, okay... Toka better have brains shake... Good to smoke marijuana... Weeds are something money...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_povar_dialog_222">
			<text>Everyone pancake Bubble tries to snatch... How much?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_povar_dialog_223">
			<text>good grass big money is. To a good estimate payment and all you need is not less than 15000...\nAnd if you're not afraid to risk it and try a sack for 5000.\nDo you like?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_povar_dialog_224">
			<text>At a pancake, drug... Okay, you have good grass...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_povar_dialog_225">
			<text>Listen, here's 5000, and that's enough babble...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_povar_dialog_226">
			<text>I'm not going to contact nark, he'd get himself...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_povar_dialog_25">
			<text>That guy... You'll be in Pripyat, hello Doctor Give...\nliner goes, do not be late for boarding... Move to teleport - in front of the main gate...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_povar_dialog_26">
			<text>might not come back, my nerves to shake...\nTeleport opposite the main entrance to the base.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_max_dialog_0">
			<text>Hey Max, you need to fly to Yantar...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_max_dialog_1">
			<text>And what you can not sit on the ground...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_max_dialog_2">
			<text>I can not sit on the ground - not the nature...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_max_dialog_21">
			<text>Ah, nature... A Mica artefact is needed...\nI do not have, do you?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_max_dialog_22">
			<text>There are of course, there... Can going to blaze?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_max_dialog_23">
			<text>did not think it will take - sold...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_max_dialog_221">
			<text>No, I will not... I was just simply, for the company once... And for mental work will take the money... Because any work should be rewarded...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_max_dialog_222">
			<text>And what do you have to pay?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_max_dialog_223">
			<text>If strongly used brain, and is guaranteed to throw you in a safe place then 9000...\nAnd if not very afraid - that 2500 will suffice.\nDecide...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_max_dialog_224">
			<text>Let's a good job try...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_max_dialog_225">
			<text>Listen, here's 2500, at the place I'll look myself</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_max_dialog_226">
			<text>Take care of me the money, he'll go...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_max_dialog_25">
			<text>reward for good - a decent job...\nMove to teleport. Opposite the main entrance to the base... Across the street, pass over and see...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_max_dialog_26">
			<text>Alive reach the bottom, and worked there myself...\nsteps... Teleport opposite the main entrance to the base.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_0">
			<text>Father, I teleport to...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_1">
			<text>Where are you going to again... Sit down and talk...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_2">
			<text>Sorry, I need to get to Cordon...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_3">
			<text>By Professor need to go to Yantar...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_4">
			<text>In Bar want to go, a couple of tender to the bartender...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_21">
			<text>Do you remember that to create a teleport you need a Crystal artefact...\nDo not lose it?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_22">
			<text>No, not lost... Here it is...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_23">
			<text>Oh, I completely forgot about that...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_221">
			<text>Do you need two or three artefacts, to fine-tune... I regularly bring... Only the money they want, how you work...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_222">
			<text>Yes I understand of course, how much?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_223">
			<text>For the absolute best guidance needed artefacts for an amount not less than 30000...\nTo determine the location coordinates only a mere 10000...\nDo you like?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_224">
			<text>But money is not a problem, come closer to the camp...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_225">
			<text>Sorry, strained with the money, try cheaper...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_226">
			<text>Very little money, screw 'em - then I'll drop</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_25">
			<text>I'll do a closer... You do not tarry there, I'll wait for you here.\nTeleport on the square in the storm sewer under the monument to Lenin</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_26">
			<text>Nothing on Cordon not so dangerous, will deal...\nTeleport on the square in the storm sewer under the monument to Lenin</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_31">
			<text>Sakharov? Here too, the martyr of science, sitting there in the swamp, radioactive mosquito food... To create a teleport you require a Mica artefact...\nDo not lose it</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_32">
			<text>Here it is...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_33">
			<text>that he did not say I drove it.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_321">
			<text>Do you need two or three artefacts, to fine-tune... I regularly bring... Only the money they want, how you work...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_322">
			<text>How much is required?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_323">
			<text>For the absolute best guidance artefacts for an amount not less than 15000...\nTo determine the location coordinates only 5000...\nWith money like?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_324">
			<text>Money - garbage, let's accurately, in a safe place...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_325">
			<text>Money ran out, only the approximate location of missing</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_326">
			<text>Most have no money, need a little extra money stalking</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_35">
			<text>Right, money can not buy happiness...\nTeleport on the square in the storm sewer under the monument to Lenin</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_36">
			<text>Yes, on the spot, I think he will deal. Good luck!\nTeleport on the square in the storm sewer under the monument to Lenin</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_41">
			<text>Well in Bar does not work, but you can throw at warehouses. Requires a Soul artefact...\nDo not feel sorry for?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_42">
			<text>Sorry, but I make it fast...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_43">
			<text>I'll think I...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_421">
			<text>Do you need two or three artefacts, to fine-tune... I sometimes sell...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_422">
			<text>And for what amount?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_423">
			<text>For moving in exactly the safest place guidance necessary artefacts in an amount not less than 10000...\nTo determine the location coordinates only 5000...\nI think not very many?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_424">
			<text>Yes, not much. And through the radar does not stomp...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_425">
			<text>Not much, but I'm grounded for now, only 5000 pull...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_426">
			<text>money, absolutely not, go, can I find - valuable...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_45">
			<text>Hi there guys out of debt transfer. Good luck!\nTeleport on the square in the storm sewer under the monument to Lenin</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_take_teleport_46">
			<text>Yes, on the spot, I think he will deal. Good luck!\nTeleport on the square in the storm sewer under the Lenin monument.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_10_dialog_0">
			<text>Help me with one thing, they say - it is possible to teleport to...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_10_dialog_1">
			<text>Yes - you can, if they were not so expensive, then all would enjoy...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_10_dialog_4">
			<text>And what is needed for this? Well, at least, if I want to fly Cordon...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_10_dialog_5">
			<text>Well firstly need the artefact, which this gives rise to teleport. For each locality it your own. No known artefacts for Cordon, Yantar, army depots and, in fact, Pripyat.\nSecond need calculation point of arrival, and then you can understand - takes you back to the stone where ever... Different people have different count. Who math calls for help, and who - otherworldly forces. I'm about halfway - use a unique artefact. For example to calibrate the teleport at Cordon needs a 'Ruby Spring'. This is a very rare artefact, but Syak promised that he would give it to me... I like that pulled him out of one scrape... Go to it...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_10_dialog_2">
			<text>Okay, I'll go long, I have not seen Syak...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_10_dialog_3">
			<text>No, do not go, can then...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_doktor_teleport_10">
			<text>\nThe Doctor needs a unique Ruby Spring artefact. with its help he can teleport to calculate the cordon. Springs had promised to give Syak, a trader from the Radar</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_102_dialog_0">
			<text>Here I am, hello Doctor...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_102_dialog_1">
			<text>back? How are you?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_102_dialog_2">
			<text>had a Syaka it to you "ruby spring" passed</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_102_dialog_3">
			<text>Well, now you can hit the road to Cordon. I have a "Crystal" is, hold here...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_103_dialog_0">
			<text>welcome Syak, long not seen...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_103_dialog_1">
			<text>Healthy Marked One, as life...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_103_dialog_2">
			<text>Doctor sent to you, says you have "Ruby spring"?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_103_dialog_3">
			<text>Yes, yes, of course, for all the doctors are... Here, hello him to convey...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_11_dialog_0">
			<text>Where else can use the teleport to get?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_11_dialog_1">
			<text>As I said, this still possible on Yantar and Warehouses teleport</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_11_dialog_4">
			<text>So what's the problem? You can now see Kruglov?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_11_dialog_5">
			<text>To calculate Zabroski at Yantar needs a "Ruby battery". This is a very rare artefact... If you have no "Batteries", then I think, Kruglov knows - where to find it... He boasted as much over a glass of tea... Go to him...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_11_dialog_2">
			<text>thought teleport to use, but oh well, so he'd get...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_11_dialog_3">
			<text>No, do not go, can then...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_doktor_teleport_11">
			<text>\nThe Doctor needs a unique artefact, Ruby Battery, with its help he can calculate the teleport at Yantar. Kruglov knows where to find this artefact</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_112_dialog_0">
			<text>Here I am, hello Doctor...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_112_dialog_1">
			<text>Back? How are you?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_112_dialog_2">
			<text>I found "Ruby battery", here it is</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_112_dialog_3">
			<text>Well, now you can teleport to Yantar. I have a "Mica", here take it...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_113_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello, martyr of science, had not seen each...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_113_dialog_1">
			<text>Healthy Marked One, as life...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_113_dialog_2">
			<text>Doctor sent you, says you have "Ruby battery"?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_113_dialog_3">
			<text>No, I do not have... I have heard that there is one place on the radar screen, where this artefact sometimes appears...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_113_dialog_4">
			<text>And where is that?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_113_dialog_5">
			<text>If you go from warehouses along the way, before turning to the left, there is a small safe wooded corner for a couple of boulders... They look...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_113_dialog_6">
			<text>Thanks, I'll try to find it...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_12_dialog_0">
			<text>And how do you get to the warehouses?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_12_dialog_1">
			<text>To calculate you also need a unique artefact</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_12_dialog_4">
			<text>Which?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_12_dialog_5">
			<text>To calculate Zabroski Warehouses need to "Ruby Pellicle". This is a very rare artefact... If you do not have this artefact, then I think Baldy can know - where to find it... He is constantly in Bar drunk... Go to it...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_12_dialog_2">
			<text>thought teleport to use, but oh well, so he'd get...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_12_dialog_3">
			<text>No, do not go, can then...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_doktor_teleport_12">
			<text>\nThe Doctor needs a unique Ruby Pellicle artefact, with its help he can calculate the teleport to the warehouses. Baldy knows where to find this artefact</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_122_dialog_0">
			<text>Here I am, hello Doctor...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_122_dialog_1">
			<text>Back? How are you?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_122_dialog_2">
			<text>I found "Ruby Pellicle", here it is</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_122_dialog_3">
			<text>Well, now you can teleport to warehouses. I have a "soul", here take it...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_123_dialog_0">
			<text>Big guy can be a couple of words...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_123_dialog_1">
			<text>And you do not get sick, he wanted?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_123_dialog_2">
			<text>Doctor sent to you, says you have "Ruby Pellicle"?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_123_dialog_3">
			<text>No, I do not have now... I stashed it in wild territory, in a secluded place... I will tell you where, if you give me an artefact of "symbiote"...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_123_dialog_4">
			<text>I have a "symbiote", take it...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_123_dialog_5">
			<text>Then listen, I put the artefact on the roof of this small transformer station just above the underground passage located between the railroad tracks...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_123_dialog_6">
			<text>Thanks, I'll try to find it...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="teleport_123_dialog_7">
			<text>No I do not have "symbiote" but I know how to make one... Don't go anywhere, I'll be back.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_11_dialog_0">
			<text>So what? Is there information on "Living Heart"?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_11_dialog_1">
			<text>Not so fast son... There are a few hints and a lot of encrypted text...\nMentioned the Living Heart artefact, which can give life back... This artefact is not found in finished form, it must modify several components...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_11_dialog_2">
			<text>And what are the components?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_11_dialog_3">
			<text>First - "Golden Fish", on the other said nothing, only very brief phrase that one of those traders may know...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_11_dialog_4">
			<text>Traders? Who? Sidor? Sak? Can Miser?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_11_dialog_5">
			<text>Miser? No, it is unlikely... And he and Sak and Petrenko recently in jail... But Sidorovich and Bartender, yes, they know a lot... And Sakharovs not forget, though he learned, and information traded in a long time...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_11_dialog_6">
			<text>So Sidorovich, bartender and Sakharov... Okay, Im going to shake the can and see what falls out...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_11_dialog_7">
			<text>Go... Meanwhile I will try to decipher somebody else... Come back</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_11_dialog_8">
			<text>I'll be back soon!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_51_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello, Dr... I'm back.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_51_dialog_1">
			<text>Hello, sonny. I see in good health and apparently with good news?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_51_dialog_2">
			<text>I found the components of "living heart"!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_51_dialog_3">
			<text>Excellent, good luck... Don't keep to yourself, what?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_51_dialog_4">
			<text>A 'Goldfish' still needs an 'Urchin', a 'Night Star', and a 'Dummy', but how it's transmuted - no one said...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_51_dialog_5">
			<text>In this I can help you... I decrypted a piece of text saying: ingredients must be thrown into the anomaly "Snow".</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_51_dialog_6">
			<text>In "snowballs" it means... And how do you activate the "Living Heart"?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_51_dialog_7">
			<text>Rumored - to put it right on the chest of the deceased and, if his soul is pure, then it returns life to the body...\nthe return of your memory is not always definite...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_51_dialog_8">
			<text>Thank you for your humanity...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_21_dialog_0">
			<text>Hey bartender, can I talk to you...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_21_dialog_1">
			<text>And to you greetings... I've heard - you've been in the Sarcophagus? Seen any Monolith?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_21_dialog_2">
			<text>I saw some monolith, nothing special - Kamenyuki lights and noise in my head.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_21_dialog_3">
			<text>A desire to trade something?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_21_dialog_4">
			<text>No, wise men dissuaded me... I came to you about something else...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_21_dialog_5">
			<text>I'm listening</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_21_dialog_6">
			<text>There's a rumor that you are familiar with the components of the recipe for conversion of the Living Heart artefact?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_21_dialog_7">
			<text>Nonsense... I've heard about half an ear about this artefact... It seems that some want to throw something far...\nBUT! About one component I precisely know...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_21_dialog_8">
			<text>And what component?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_21_dialog_9">
			<text>Well... Information just does not flow out of my mouth... Want to know - do the work...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_21_dialog_10">
			<text>And what you need?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_21_dialog_11">
			<text>I was asked to find a man... Academic... He disappeared somewhere in Pripyat with important data...\nIf you find out about his fate and bring back this data, you can learn about the required artefact...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_21_dialog_12">
			<text>Okay, I find this scientist...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_21_dialog_13">
			<text>Come back later to this conversation</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_22_dialog_0">
			<text>So I'm back, hello...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_22_dialog_1">
			<text>Hello... What happened to the scientist then?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_22_dialog_2">
			<text>I found him, apparently he and the controller did not get along - died of starvation... He has a PDA that's only been...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_22_dialog_3">
			<text>Hm... AREA... No one - so would get another... Thank you... I have heard that "The heart" with the Night Star artefact gets... That's it...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_22_dialog_4">
			<text>"Night Star" means... Well, good luck...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_31_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello Professor... Can I ask you some questions?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_31_dialog_1">
			<text>Hello, long time no see... Been in the Chernobyl nuclear power plant have you?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_31_dialog_2">
			<text>Yes, ran... Didn't see much no time to...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_31_dialog_3">
			<text>Pity the information from there is lacking... And you wanted to know?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_31_dialog_4">
			<text>In Sarcophagus I found PDA experienced stalker, and this PDA refers to an artefact resuscitating...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_31_dialog_5">
			<text>Ah-ah! "The heart"? We heard about this... Even trying to collect more accurate information, but failed...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_31_dialog_6">
			<text>Yet know all the components of the recipe changes, you do not know?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_31_dialog_7">
			<text>We were able to accurately determine only one ingredient...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_31_dialog_8">
			<text>And what is it?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_31_dialog_9">
			<text>You see, I certainly will give you this information, but I wish that you would help me get data on the situation near Chernobyl...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_31_dialog_10">
			<text>How?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_31_dialog_11">
			<text>Install monitoring unit as close to the station. Better even within...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_31_dialog_12">
			<text>Again Chernobyl... Well, let's block</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_31_dialog_13">
			<text>Professor, I'd rest a bit...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_32_dialog_0">
			<text>So I'm back, hello.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_32_dialog_1">
			<text>Hello... Thank you for the work, the data we have is.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_32_dialog_2">
			<text>You're welcome, what's with the ingredients?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_32_dialog_3">
			<text>Probably the main component to be converted into "Living Heart" is an Urchin artefact...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_32_dialog_4">
			<text>'Urchin'. Say goodbye...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_41_dialog_0">
			<text>Hello Sidor... How's life?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_41_dialog_1">
			<text>Cool and you, muzzle with a crack... It must be what?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_41_dialog_2">
			<text>Not rude, healthier you will... On the "living heart" that you know?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_41_dialog_3">
			<text>Well, basically the same as everyone - there is an artefact that can resurrect the dead... Nobody really saw it, just rumors... It seems to be to throw some artefacts in some anomalies and thus did not think about death, then these artefacts are transformed into "The heart"...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_41_dialog_4">
			<text>And what artefact's that?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_41_dialog_5">
			<text>God knows... I only know that Ghost is looking for a single artefact, for the "Living Heart "...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_41_dialog_6">
			<text>And what is it?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_41_dialog_7">
			<text>So, harsh and ungrateful, just for what he said...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_41_dialog_8">
			<text>How much do you want?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_41_dialog_9">
			<text>Money??? Money here are - for me ugh and rub... Now, if one found a Night Star and braught it to me, then it will be possible to talk...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_41_dialog_10">
			<text>Which artefact and where?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_41_dialog_11">
			<text>In the Radar, deep in the rusty forest disappeared one experienced stalker... His artefact was amusing, though very dangerous and harmful to health...\nIn general you need to find the container with this artefact... Where exactly - I do not know...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_41_dialog_12">
			<text>Here Blinn... Nothing just do not get... Already in the way...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_41_dialog_13">
			<text>For the money she is not, well, well... Sidor then.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_42_dialog_0">
			<text>I have the box...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_42_dialog_1">
			<text>And what I do... He brought it?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_42_dialog_2">
			<text>Here's your box, barely found it... Tell me about "The heart"!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_42_dialog_3">
			<text>Ghosts searching for the artefact Pops, said that Strelok...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="about_life_heart_42_dialog_4">
			<text>"Miming"... For me ?.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="strelok_pda1_dialog_0">
			<text>Ehh... How many good men taken by the Zone...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="strelok_pda1_dialog_1">
			<text>is exactly... I thought, and you too will not see more...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="strelok_pda1_dialog_2">
			<text>Yes-ah... Sorry - no one can return...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="strelok_pda1_dialog_3">
			<text>In fact, a persistent rumor goes - there is a special miracle artefact, "The heart" is called... And like you have in your PDA, even the way it was for...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="strelok_pda1_dialog_4">
			<text>I? In this PDA?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="strelok_pda1_dialog_5">
			<text>No not in this, in which you are with me in the last sortie of the Chernobyl took! Maybe he'll be able to find...\nAnd more... I do not know exactly where your old PDA - in Sarcophagus or not... At least search it must be exactly there.\nWhen going to something in the sarcophagus?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="strelok_pda1_dialog_6">
			<text>thought with the dawn, tomorrow...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="strelok_pda1_dialog_7">
			<text>where emissions are often, but you can predict the window between them... Now is the time to go - can not wait until tomorrow</text>
		</string>
		<string id="strelok_pda1_dialog_8">
			<text>Okay, then I go, I hope I'll see you...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="strelok_pda2_dialog_0">
			<text>Here I am Doctor! I've got the "Emerald Medusa"</text>
		</string>
		<string id="strelok_pda2_dialog_1">
			<text>excellent, judging by the intensity of abnormal vibration of surfaces, if you go right now - you will have about an hour before the next release... So delay not...\nAbout "Goldfish" do not forget...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="strelok_pda2_dialog_2">
			<text>Well, never forget... I ran...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="strelok_pda3_dialog_0">
			<text>Doctor, I found the PDA. It turns out I left it with the miner! But I can't read it...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="strelok_pda3_dialog_1">
			<text>Here... Let me try...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="strelok_pda3_dialog_2">
			<text>take it.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="strelok_pda_info_text">
			<text>Fixed teleport at Monolith, activated goldfish. To do this, stand directly in front of monolith and throw the artefact in. Open teleport entered into which you find yourself in a hangar Chernobyl...\nGood luck to you, an unknown stalker...\n.\nStrelok</text>
		</string>
		<string id="enc_strelok_pda_text">
			<text>To open the Sarcophagus teleport to NPP1 you need to throw a Goldfish into the Monolith...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_about_life_heart">
			<text>Strelok's PDA mentions that the ingredients for "Living Heart" is known by traders. You should try to find out everything Barman, Sakharov and Sidorovich know. Then, talk with The Doctor</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_life_heart_sahar">
			<text>Sakharov sent a set of monitoring unit near Chernobyl. This unit should be installed in the hangar (where the entrance to the Sarcophagus) near the railway wagon. In gratitude, Sakharov will tell you everything he knows about the 'Living Heart'</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_life_heart_sidor">
			<text>Sidorovich gives nothing for nothing... He agreed to exchange the information available to him on the "living heart" on the container with the artefact, which was lost in the woods rusty, on the radar</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_life_heart_barman">
			<text>Bartender can tell ingredient recipe for "Living Heart", but he needs to know the fate of the scientist, who disappeared along with the data collected in Pripyat...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_strelok_pda">
			<text>The doctor has information that Strelok knew about how to obtain the artefact "Living Heart". This information should be on Strelok's PDA. It may be located in the Sarcophagus, somewhere near the famous monolith, but the information may be incorrect</text>
		</string>
		<string id="tex_strelok_pda2">
			<text>The Doctor can calculate the time between emissions, but he needs an Emerald Medusa artefact. There is only one place where you can find this artefact...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_dialog_start_11">
			<text>Hello, how do you feel?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_dialog_start_12">
			<text>I feel like shit, actually... And who are you then?... the Doctor? The Astrologer sends his greetings - he said that he'll meet you just north of the railway bridge... at the abandoned farm... do you know me?... have we met before?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_dialog_start_13">
			<text>Yes, I am the Doctor... many call me the Swamp Doctor. I lived in the swamp for a while... which is what the Cordon used to be. Who are you?! yes, I know who you are... but, until you remember yourself I will not say... There is a cave, a lone Miner resides there... his name is "Shakhtar" whom you must find. Be wary of the burning gas, and the mutants... as they are aplenty. Drink this here concoction I've made from some swamp grasses... it will help you... remember... a cave... find the Miner... he will help you further... and as for me... I must go and meet with the Astrologer</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_dialog_start_21">
			<text>Hello again Marked One. Did you find what you were looking for?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_dialog_start_22">
			<text>No, I don't remember much... but, I had this dream about a Cave... I gave "Shakhtar" the things he requested... said he needed. Have you ever heard about such a Cave?!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="doctor_dialog_start_23">
			<text>I have heard of it... but, first you must try to remember who you are... Will you find come find me then? I'm going with Zvedochet on an excursion to the center of the Zone...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_bandit_dialog_0">
			<text>What!?... pretty shitty, actually... and you?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_bandit_dialog_1">
			<text>Help me man, you will not regret it!!</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_bandit_dialog_2">
			<text>Fuck you... Everyone's better off with you dead...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_bandit_dialog_3">
			<text>Here, take this medkit...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_bandit_dialog_4">
			<text>I wish I could help you, but I just used my last medkit</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_bandit_dialog_5">
			<text>You're all right, Stalker... If you are interested, talk with Borov, our leader. He runs things from our base in the Dark Valley...</text>
		</string>
		<string id="val_bandit_dialog_6">
			<text>Borov? I'll have a word with him... when I see him</text>
		</string>
	</string_table>
<!--Created/Modified with S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Dialog Extended Editor by Marty Sheppard/ Version: 0.96i ( 2017/02/17) =!!= Last changed: 18.03.2017 22:19:53 -->
